<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="239"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-239/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_239">
        <num>239</num>
        <heading>Albert Einstein chairs in science and Albert Schweitzer chairs in the humanities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 239. Albert Einstein chairs in science and Albert Schweitzer chairs\nin the humanities.  1.  Legislative finding and declaration of policy.\nThe public and private colleges in this state enjoy a well-deserved\nreputation for academic excellence and intellectual vitality.  For them\nto preserve and further enhance their great stature they must compete\nwith colleges in other states and countries to attract the world's most\ndistinguished and renowned scholars.  The presence of these giants of\nscience and the humanities at institutions of learning in this state\nstrengthens and stimulates the academic community of the entire state.\nTheir presence in this state also serves to attract exceptional faculty\nmembers, research scholars and students to colleges and research\nfacilities in this state and nurtures the development of graduate work\nin science and the humanities in colleges in this state which do not now\nhave such programs.  All of this helps to create an atmosphere of\nintellectual, scientific and cultural vigor conducive to the attraction\nof new atomic, space, technological and other industries to this state.\nThe people of the entire state benefit from the resulting state-wide\nintellectual, cultural and economic growth.  The great cost attendant\nupon attracting such world famous figures, compensating them and\nproviding them with necessary staff and facilities is beyond the\nfinancial means of most colleges.  The legislature finds that in order\nto meet this need a program of distinguished chairs should be\nestablished within the university of the state of New York, under the\njurisdiction of the regents.\n  2. There are hereby established in the university of the state of New\nYork, under the jurisdiction of the regents, two distinguished chairs,\none of which shall be known as the Albert Einstein chair in science and\none of which shall be known as the Albert Schweitzer chair in the\nhumanities.  One additional such Einstein chair and one additional such\nSchweitzer chair shall be established during each of the fiscal years\ncommencing April first, nineteen hundred sixty-five, nineteen hundred\nsixty-six, nineteen hundred sixty-seven and nineteen hundred\nsixty-eight, until a total of ten such chairs has been established.  The\nregents shall determine the fields of knowledge to be included within\nthe terms science and humanities as used in this section.\n  3. The regents are hereby authorized, within appropriations made\ntherefor, to contract with outstanding scholars to fill the Albert\nEinstein chairs in science and the Albert Schweitzer chairs in the\nhumanities established by this section, on such terms and conditions and\nfor such duration as may be agreed upon by the parties.\n  4. The regents are hereby authorized, within appropriations made\ntherefor, to contract with any college in this state on such terms and\nconditions and for such duration as may be agreed upon by the parties,\nin relation to the provision of proper facilities, equipment, supplies,\nprofessional assistants, clerical and other personnel and such other\nservices as may be necessary or appropriate to enable the holder of an\nAlbert Einstein chair in science or an Albert Schweitzer chair in the\nhumanities to carry out his work in connection therewith and to give\neffect to the purposes for which such chair was established as set forth\nin subdivision one of this section.  Every college in this state is\nhereby authorized to enter into such a contract with the regents.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>