<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2502"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2502"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-11-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2502"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2502/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2502/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2502">
        <num>2502</num>
        <heading>Board of education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2502. Board of education. 1. The board of education of each city\nschool district shall constitute a body corporate.\n  2. Each board of education shall consist of five, seven or nine\nmembers, to be known as members of the board of education. In the city\nof Albany, such board shall consist of seven members; and in the city of\nRensselaer, such board shall consist of five members; subject, however,\nto any increase or decrease of the number of members of such board as\nprovided pursuant to the provisions of paragraph a of subdivision four\nof this section. Members of such board shall be elected by the qualified\nvoters at large of the school district at annual school elections, under\nthe provisions of article fifty-three of this chapter; provided,\nhowever, each board of education may upon its own motion, and shall upon\na written petition, subscribed by not less than five hundred qualified\nvoters of the district, cause to be submitted at the annual school\nelection a proposition to consider each vacancy upon the board of\neducation a separate specific office requiring a separate petition to\nnominate a candidate to each separate office in accordance with the\nprovisions of article fifty-three of this chapter.\n  3. The full term of office of a member of the board of education shall\nbe three or five years, as the district may determine, except the full\nterm of office of a member of the board of education in the city of\nAlbany shall be four years; provided, however, that the term of office\nof each incumbent member of the city of Albany board on the effective\ndate of this amendment shall not be decreased, and provided further,\nthat one or more of the vacancies filled after this change to four year\nterms shall be for terms of two or three years only in order that, as\nnearly as possible, an equal number of members shall be elected to the\nboard each year. Any such school district may decrease the full term of\na member of the board of education to three years or increase the full\nterm of a member of the board of education to five years by adopting a\nproposition at any regular meeting or election to do so; provided,\nhowever, that the term of office of each incumbent member of the board\nof education shall not be increased or decreased thereby; and provided,\nfurther, that whenever a proposition shall be adopted to increase the\nterm of office from three years to five years, or to decrease the term\nof office from five years to three years, such proposition shall provide\nthat one or more of the vacancies to be filled, during each of the three\nyears next succeeding the adoption of such proposition, shall be for\nthree or four years only in order that, as nearly as possible, an equal\nnumber of trustees shall be elected to the board each year. The board of\neducation in the city of Peekskill may, by adopting a resolution,\ndecrease the full term of a member of the board of education to two\nyears in order that, as nearly as possible, an equal number of trustees\nshall be elected to the board each year; provided, however, that the\nterm of office of each incumbent member of the board of education shall\nnot be decreased thereby.\n  4. a. Each board of education may upon its own motion, and shall upon\na written petition, subscribed by not less than five hundred qualified\nvoters of the district, cause to be submitted at the annual school\nelection a proposition to increase or decrease the number of members of\nsuch board to a number specified in subdivision two of this section; or\na proposition to increase or decrease the term of office of members of\nthe board of education in accordance with subdivision three of this\nsection.\n  b. The notice of any annual school election at which a proposition\nshall be submitted pursuant to paragraph a of this subdivision shall\ninclude a statement that such proposition will be so submitted. In the\nevent that the board of education fails or refuses to include such\ninformation in such notice, the commissioner of education may prescribe\nthe manner in which notice of the submission of such a proposition shall\nbe given.\n  c. Upon the adoption of a proposition to increase or decrease the\nnumber of members of the board of education the members of such board\nthen in office shall continue in office for the balance of their\nrespective terms. If the proposition so adopted requires an increase in\nthe number of board members, a sufficient number of members of such\nboard shall be elected at the annual election immediately succeeding the\nelection at which such proposition was submitted, to effect the\nnecessary increase. If the proposition so adopted requires a decrease in\nthe number of board members, no election of board members shall be held\nin such district until the election of a member or members shall be\nnecessary to maintain the number specified in such proposition. The\noffices of those members whose terms so expire without the election of a\nsuccessor shall terminate with the expiration of such term.  Succeeding\nmembers of such board shall be elected at annual school elections in\nsuch years and in such numbers and for such terms of office as shall be\ndetermined by resolution of the board of education and approved by the\ncommissioner of education, so that as soon as practicable:\n  (1) The terms of office of all members of such board shall be five\nyears or three years, as the district shall have determined;\n  (2) The number of members elected to and serving on such board shall\nequal the number of members specified in such proposition; and\n  (3) As nearly as possible, an equal number of members of the board of\neducation will be elected each year.\n  d. A resolution adopted pursuant to paragraph c of this subdivision,\nwhich shall be subject to approval by the commissioner of education,\nshall be placed on file in the office of the clerk of the school\ndistrict and shall be a public record.\n  5. a. The members of a board of education of a school district which\nafter July first, nineteen hundred fifty, shall become a city school\ndistrict, as defined in subdivision sixteen of section two of this\nchapter, shall continue in office until the expiration of their\nrespective terms of office in those cases where such terms of office\nexpire with the thirtieth day in June and in all other cases such\nmembers shall continue in office until July first next succeeding the\ndate upon which their respective terms of office would have otherwise\nexpired.\n  b. If the total number of members elected to serve on any such board\nof education shall be either five, seven or nine, such board shall\ncontinue to be composed of five, seven or nine members, as the case may\nbe, subject to change in accordance with subdivision four of this\nsection.\n  c. If the total number of members elected to serve on any such board\nof education shall be other than five, seven or nine, such board of\neducation shall cause to be submitted at the next succeeding annual\nschool election, held in accordance with article fifty-three of this\nchapter, propositions to determine whether the number of members of such\nboard shall be five, seven or nine. If the proposition adopted thereat\nrequires an increase in the number of board members, a sufficient number\nof members of such board shall be elected at the annual election\nimmediately succeeding the election at which such proposition was\nsubmitted, to effect the necessary increase. If the proposition so\nadopted requires a decrease in the number of board members, no election\nof board members shall be held in such district until the election of a\nmember or members shall be necessary to maintain the number specified in\nsuch proposition. The offices of those members whose terms so expire\nwithout the election of a successor shall terminate with the expiration\nof such term. Thereafter, such board of education shall be composed of\nthe number of members specified in the proposition for which the\ngreatest number of valid votes shall have been cast, subject to change\nin accordance with subdivision four of this section.\n  d. Succeeding members of any such board of education shall be elected\nat annual school elections in such years and in such numbers and for\nsuch terms of office as shall be determined by resolution of the board\nof education and approved by the commissioner of education so that as\nsoon as practicable:\n  (1) The terms of office of all members shall be five years or three\nyears, as the district shall determine;\n  (2) As nearly as possible, an equal number of the members of the board\nof education shall be elected each year; and\n  (3) In the case of boards of education coming under the provisions of\nparagraph c of this subdivision, the number of members elected to and\nserving on any such board shall equal the number specified in the\nproposition adopted pursuant to paragraph c of this subdivision.\n  e. A resolution adopted pursuant to paragraph d of this subdivision,\nwhich shall be subject to approval by the commissioner of education,\nshall be placed on file in the office of the clerk of the school\ndistrict and shall be a public record.\n  6. Whenever a vacancy shall occur or exist in the office of member of\nthe board of education, except by reason of expiration of term or of an\nincrease in the number of members of such board, a majority of the\nremaining members of such board may appoint a qualified person to fill\nthe vacancy. The person so appointed shall hold office until the next\nregular school district election, and the person elected to fill such\nvacancy shall take office immediately upon the filing of his official\noath of office with the district clerk.\n  7. No person shall be eligible to the office of member of the board of\neducation who is not a qualified voter of the city school district and\nwho has not been a resident of such district for a period of at least\none year immediately precedi</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>