<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2525"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2525"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-01-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2525"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2525/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2525/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2525/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2525/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2525">
        <num>2525</num>
        <heading>Audit of claims</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2525. Audit of claims. 1. The board of education, in considering any\nclaim, may require any person presenting the same to be sworn before it\nor before any member thereof and to give testimony relative to the\njustness and accuracy of such claim, and may take evidence and examine\nwitnesses under oath in respect to the claim, and for that purpose may\nissue subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses. When a claim has been\nfinally audited by the board of education the clerk of such board shall\nendorse thereon or attach thereto a certificate of such audit and file\nthe same as a public record in his or her office. When any claim has\nbeen so audited and a certificate thereof so filed, the clerk of the\nboard of education shall draw a warrant specifying the name of the\nclaimant, the amount allowed and the fund, function and object\nchargeable therewith and such other information as may be deemed\nnecessary and essential, directed to the treasurer of the district,\nauthorizing and directing him or her to pay to the claimant the amount\nallowed upon his or her claim. A copy of such warrant shall be filed in\nthe office of the clerk.\n  2. In a city school district in which the office of claims auditor has\nbeen created, the claims auditor in considering a claim, may require any\nperson presenting the same to be sworn before him or her and to give\ntestimony relative to the justness and accuracy of such claim, and may\ntake evidence and examine witnesses under oath in respect to the claim,\nand for that purpose may issue subpoenas for the attendance of\nwitnesses. When a claim has been finally audited by the claims auditor\nhe or she shall endorse thereon or attach thereto a certificate of such\naudit and file the same as a public record in his or her office. When\nany claim has been so audited and a certificate thereof so filed, the\nclaims auditor shall draw a warrant specifying the number of the claim,\nthe name of the claimant, the amount allowed and the fund, function and\nobject chargeable therewith and such other information as may be deemed\nnecessary or essential, directed to the treasurer of the district,\nauthorizing and directing him or her to pay to the claimant the amount\nallowed upon his or her claim. A copy of such warrant shall be filed in\nthe office of the clerk.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>