<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2552"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2552"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2552"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2552/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2552/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2552/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2552/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2552">
        <num>2552</num>
        <heading>Board of education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2552. Board of education. The board of education of each such city\nschool district is hereby continued. The educational affairs in each\nsuch city school district shall be under the general management and\ncontrol of a board of education to consist of not less than three and\nnot more than nine members, to be chosen as hereinafter provided, and to\nbe known as members of the board of education, except that the board of\neducation of the city school district of the city of New York shall be\nconstituted as provided in article fifty-two-A of this title. The number\nof members on the board of education of each such city school district\nshall continue to be as follows, provided that student ex officio board\nmembers as described in subdivision eleven of section twenty-five\nhundred fifty-three of this article shall not be considered board\nmembers for purposes of this section:\n  a. City school district of the city of Buffalo: nine members.\n  b. City school district of the city of Rochester: seven members.\n  c. City school district of the city of Syracuse: seven members.\n  d. City school district of the city of Yonkers: nine members.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>