<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2553"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2553"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2553"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2553/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2553/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2553/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2553/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2553">
        <num>2553</num>
        <heading>Board of education; eligibility; how chosen; term of office; vacancies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members of the board of education of the city school\ndistrict of the city of Rochester shall be elected by the qualified\nvoters of such city as provided herein.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members of the board of education shall be elected at large\nthroughout the city by the qualified voters at a general election.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such elections for such officers shall be governed by the\nprovisions of the election law in the same manner as candidates for\noffice generally to be elected by the voters of the city of Rochester;\nprovided, however, that each such candidate shall be required to file\npetitions containing at least one thousand signatures.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall be eligible for the office of members of such\nboard of education who is not a qualified voter under section 5-102 of\nthe election law of such city school district. No person shall hold at\nthe same time the office of member of the board of education and any\nother elective office nor shall he be a candidate for any other elective\noffice at the same time he is a candidate for the office of member of\nsuch board of education.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The term of office of each member of such board shall be four\nyears, commencing on the first day of January following his election.\nThe candidates receiving a plurality of the votes cast respectively for\nthe several offices shall be declared elected. Where more than one\noffice is to be filled by such election and there is a variance in the\nlength of the terms, the candidate receiving the largest number of votes\nshall be entitled to the longest term and the candidates receiving the\nnext highest number of votes shall be entitled, in decreasing order of\nthe respective number of votes to the several offices, in decreasing\norder of the length of such terms or unexpired portions of terms.\nWhenever a vacancy shall occur or exist in the office of member of the\nboard of education except by reason of expiration of term, such vacancy\nshall be filled by the president of the board of education by\nappointment of a nominee of the members of the board of education of the\nsame political affiliation as the person who vacated the office and such\nnominee shall be elected by the majority vote of the board of education;\nif the board shall not have filled the vacancy within thirty days from\nthe date the vacancy occurred, then the president of the board shall\nfill the vacancy from the same political party as that of the person who\nvacated the office. However, if the vacancy shall occur in the office of\nmember of the board of education filled by an incumbent elected on a\nnon-partisan or an independent basis, such vacancy shall be filled,\nafter nomination by the president of the board of education, by majority\nvote of the remaining members of the board of education. A person\nappointed to fill a vacancy shall hold office to and including the\nthirty-first day of December next succeeding the first general election\nfollowing such vacancy, at which a successor must be elected for the\nremainder of the unexpired term, if any.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members so elected to the board of education shall convene on\nthe first business day in January of each year at the time of the\ncommencement of their term of office and select from their members a\npresident who shall serve for a term of one year or such other term, not\nexceeding the term of his office, as may be fixed by the rules and\nregulations of the board.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The election of members of the board of education of the school\ndistrict of Rochester shall take place at a general election to be held\nin such city when an incumbent's term expires, and the first election\nhereinunder shall take place in November of nineteen hundred eighty-one.\nSuch election shall be conducted by the board of elections of the county\nof Monroe in the same manner as general elections are conducted by it.\nThe results of such elections, after canvassing, shall be certified and\nreported by the board of elections to the board of education of such\ncity. The clerk or other appropriate officer of the board of education\nshall within twenty-four hours after the receipt of such certification\nby the board of elections serve a written notice either personally or by\nmail upon each person declared to be elected as a member of the board of\neducation informing him of his election and the length of his term.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the present\nmembers of said board of education shall serve the full terms for which\nthey were elected. Vacancies which may occur in the board shall be\nfilled as provided herein, except, that the vacancies created by the\nexpansion of the board of education from five to seven members, as\nprovided herein, shall be filled at the next general election.\n  10. a. The members of the board of education of the city school\ndistrict of the city of Buffalo shall be elected by the qualified voters\nof such city as provided herein.\n  b. The common council of the city of Buffalo shall within three months\nof the operative date of this paragraph of this section of this act\ndefine and publish by local law boundaries of each of six city school\nsubdistricts which said subdistricts shall be contiguous and each of\nwhich shall contain as nearly as possible the same number of\ninhabitants. The boundaries of the said city school subdistricts may\nthereafter be redefined by the board of education of the city school\ndistrict of the city of Buffalo by resolution, after a public hearing\nthereon, at intervals of not less than five years and such resolution\nmust be passed at least eight months prior to the next election for\nschool board member or members.\n  c. The members of the board of education of the city school district\nof the city of Buffalo shall be elected as follows: one member from each\nof such six city school subdistricts within such city by the qualified\nvoters therein and three members of such board of education shall be\nchosen by the qualified voters at large within such city.\n  d.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2553__subsec_h__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such election for such office shall be governed by the\nprovisions of the election law in the same manner as candidates for\noffice generally to be elected by the voters of the city of Buffalo.\nNotwithstanding section 6-142 of the election law, each such candidate\nfor election as a member of the board of education from a city school\nsubdistrict shall be required to file a petition containing signatures\nof at least two hundred registered voters of such city school\nsubdistrict in which he is a candidate and each candidate for election\nto the board of education by the voters at large shall be required to\nfile a petition containing the signatures of at least four hundred\nregistered voters of the city of Buffalo.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2553__subsec_h__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No petition shall contain any political party or independent body\nname or label. Each petition shall contain the name of only one\ncandidate and such petition shall be filed with the board of elections\nof the county of Erie not earlier than twenty-four weeks before, and not\nlater than twenty-three weeks preceding the date on which an election\nshall be held. A certificate of acceptance or declination of any\nindividual so nominated shall be filed not later than the third day\nafter the twenty-third Tuesday preceding the election.\n  e. No person shall hold at the same time the office of member of the\nboard of education of the city of Buffalo and any other elective office\nnor shall he be a candidate for any other elective office at the same\ntime he is a candidate for the office of member of such board of\neducation.\n  f. Petitions for the nomination of members of such school board shall\nbe on white paper containing the required signatures of qualified voters\nof the city of Buff...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2553__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the provisions of the election law\nwith respect to acceptances by candidates nominated by independent\nnominating petitions shall apply to candidates nominated by petitions\nfor members of such board of education.\n  j. Objections to petitions for the nomination of members of such board\nof education, procedures and remedies applicable to such objections\nshall be made pursuant to section 6-154 of the election law.\n  k. The board of elections shall cause to be printed official ballots\ncontaining the names of all candidates as above provided, except that\nthe board may refuse to have the names of ineligible candidates placed\non such ballots. The names of the candidates shall be arranged according\nto lot, and shall not bear the designation of any political party or\nindependent body, name or emblem. Blank spaces shall be provided so that\nvoters may vote for candidates who have not been nominated for the\noffices to be filled at such elections. The form of such ballots shall\nconform substantially to the form of ballots used at general elections\nas prescribed in the election law.\n  l. Voting for the election of members of such board of education shall\nbe by voting machine and shall be governed by the applicable provisions\nof the election law with respect to voting machines.\n  m. If a candidate, after a petition in his behalf shall have been duly\nfiled with the board of elections, and prior to the date of the\nelection, shall decline to accept the nomination, die, remove from the\nschool district, accept another office, or become otherwise disqualified\nfor such city school district office, such vacancy shall be filled by\nthe committee on vacancies pursuant to the election law.\n  n. The term of office of each member of such board from a city school\nsubdistrict shall be three years, and the term of office of each such\nmember of the board elected at large shall be for five years. Of the\ncandidates to be elected for membership on the b...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>