<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2554-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2554-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2554_C">
        <num>2554-C</num>
        <heading>Identification photos of senior high school, junior high school or intermediate school students in the city school district of the city o...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2554-c. Identification photos of senior high school, junior high\nschool or intermediate school students in the city school district of\nthe city of New York. Upon the recommendation of the principal of a\nsenior high school, junior high school or intermediate school and\nsubject to the approval of the community superintendent for junior high\nschools or intermediate schools and chancellor for senior high schools,\nstudents enrolled in a senior high school, junior high school or\nintermediate school may be required to be photographed for purposes of\nidentification. The principal of such school may designate the\nphotographer to be used, but the student may not be charged for the cost\nof such photograph. If required by the principal, such photograph shall\nbe taken within three months after the student's admission to such\nschool. Such photograph shall be kept within the school at a place\ndesignated by the principal. At the discretion of the principal, and\nsubject to the approval of the community superintendent for junior high\nschools or intermediate schools and chancellor for senior high schools,\nan identification card bearing a photograph of each student may also be\nrequired to be kept on the person of such student during hours when the\nstudent is attending such school.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>