<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2564"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2564"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2564"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2564/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2564/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2564/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2564/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2564">
        <num>2564</num>
        <heading>Local school board districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2564. Local school board districts.  1. The board of education of\nthe city school district of the city of New York, by resolution duly\nadopted, shall divide the city school district into such number of local\nschool board districts as such board in its discretion may determine.\nThe board of education may from time to time alter the boundaries of\nsuch districts, consolidate two or more districts or parts thereof, or\ndivide any such district or districts as it shall consider necessary.\nFor the purposes of this section, a school decentralization\ndemonstration project in existence on April first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-eight shall be deemed to be a local school board district.\n  2. Such board of education, upon the establishment of such local\nschool board districts, shall have the power to appoint, or provide for\nthe election of, and remove at its pleasure, a local school board for\neach such local school board district, which shall consist of such\nnumber of members as the board shall determine from time to time.\n  3. The board of education, with the approval of the regents, shall\nhave the power to delegate to such local school boards any or all of its\nfunctions, powers, obligations and duties in connection with the\noperation of the schools and programs under its jurisdiction, and may\nmodify or rescind any function, power, obligation and duty so delegated.\n  4. In accordance with rules and regulations to be promulgated by the\nboard of education, each such local school board shall have the power to\nemploy a local superintendent of schools upon such terms and conditions\nas such local school board shall determine. Such employment shall be by\ncontract at an annual rate of compensation not in excess of thirty\nthousand dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>