<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2566"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2566"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2566"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2566/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2566/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2566/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2566/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2566">
        <num>2566</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of superintendent of schools</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2566. Powers and duties of superintendent of schools. The\nsuperintendent of schools of a city shall possess, subject to the\nby-laws of the board of education, the following powers and be charged\nwith the following duties:\n  1. To be the chief executive officer of such board and the educational\nsystem, and to have a seat on the board of education and the right to\nspeak on all matters before the board, but not to vote.\n  2. To enforce all provisions of law and all rules and regulations\nrelating to the management of the schools and other educational, social\nand recreational activities under the direction of the board of\neducation.\n  3. In a city having a population of one million or more, to exercise\nsuch administrative and ministerial powers of such board as may be\ndelegated to him by regulation and by-laws of such board in such manner\nand with the same force and effect as if such powers were given to him\nby the provisions of the education law.\n  4. To prepare the content of each course of study authorized by the\nboard of education. The content of each such course shall be submitted\nto the board of education for its approval and, when thus approved, the\nsuperintendent shall cause such courses of study to be used in the\ngrades, classes and schools for which they are authorized.\n  5. To recommend suitable lists of textbooks to be used in the schools.\n  6. To have supervision and direction of associate, assistant, district\nand other superintendents, directors, supervisors, principals, teachers,\nlecturers, medical inspectors, nurses, claims auditors, deputy claims\nauditors, attendance officers, janitors and other persons employed in\nthe management of the schools or the other educational activities of the\ncity authorized by this chapter and under the direction and management\nof the board of education, except that in the city school districts of\nthe cities of Buffalo, Rochester, and Syracuse to also appoint, within\nthe amounts budgeted therefor, such associate, assistant and district\nsuperintendents and all other supervising staff who are excluded from\nthe right to bargain collectively pursuant to article fourteen of the\ncivil service law; to transfer teachers from one school to another, or\nfrom one grade of the course of study to another grade in such course,\nand to report immediately such transfers to said board for its\nconsideration and action; to report to said board of education\nviolations of regulations and cases of insubordination, and to suspend\nan associate, assistant, district or other superintendent, director,\nsupervisor, expert, principal, teacher or other employee until the next\nregular meeting of the board, when all facts relating to the case shall\nbe submitted to the board for its consideration and action.\n  7. To have supervision and direction over the enforcement and\nobservance of the courses of study, the examination and promotion of\npupils, and over all other matters pertaining to playgrounds, medical\ninspection, recreation and social center work, libraries, lectures and\nall other educational activities and interest under the management,\ndirection and control of the board of education.\n  8. To issue such licenses to teachers, principals, directors, school\npsychiatrists, school psychologists, school medical inspectors, school\naurists, school psychiatric social workers, school social case workers,\nresearch assistants, teacher-clerks, school clerks, clerical assistants,\nindustrial or trade helpers in vocational schools, school librarians,\nlaboratory assistants, placement and investigation assistants, financial\nassistants, machine shop assistants, tool boys, and other members of the\nteaching and supervising staff as may be required under the by-laws and\nregulations of the board of education in cities in which such board\nrequires its teachers to hold qualifications in addition to or in\nadvance of or different from, where such qualifications are not provided\nby the commissioner, the minimum qualifications required under this\nchapter. All such licenses issued prior to the first day of December,\nnineteen hundred thirty-four, and all appointments made or hereafter\nmade pursuant to such licenses are hereby authorized and validated\nagainst any statutory provision, omission, or irregularity, provided the\nexamination for such license was conducted by the board of examiners in\naccordance with the by-laws and regulations of the board of education,\nnotwithstanding the invalidity of any such by-laws and regulations. All\nsuch licenses issued by the chancellor prior to the effective date of a\nchapter of the laws of 1990, entitled "AN ACT to amend the education law\nand the administrative code of the city of New York, in relation to\nappointment of teaching service personnel by abolishing the board of\nexaminers in cities having a population of one million or more and to\nrepeal certain provisions of the education law relating thereto" and all\nappointments made or hereafter made pursuant to such licenses are hereby\nauthorized and validated, notwithstanding any provision of statute or\nregulation to the contrary. Nothing in this chapter shall affect the\nrights of persons serving pursuant to appropriate licenses issued prior\nto the effective date of a chapter of the laws of 1990, entitled "AN ACT\nto amend the education law and the administrative code of the city of\nNew York, in relation to appointment of teaching service personnel by\nabolishing the board of examiners in cities having a population of one\nmillion or more and to repeal certain provisions of the education law\nrelating thereto" or require them to obtain certifications or licenses\nnot previously required of them.\n  9. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, the provisions\nof subdivision six of this section relating to the transfer of teachers\nmay be modified by an agreement that is collectively negotiated pursuant\nto the provisions of article fourteen of the civil service law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>