<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2567"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2567"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2567"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2567/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2567/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2567/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2567/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2567">
        <num>2567</num>
        <heading>Protection of rights exercised under licenses issued by a board of education in a city having a population of one million or more</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2567. Protection of rights exercised under licenses issued by a\nboard of education in a city having a population of one million or more.\nNo person shall forfeit any right given to him under a license issued by\na board of education in a city having a population of one million or\nmore, pursuant to this chapter, because of absence while in service in\nthe armed forces of the United States or in the service of the American\nRed Cross. Any person may at any time within six months after his\ndischarge from service in the armed forces of the United States or the\nAmerican Red Cross make application to the license issuing authority by\naffidavit setting forth that he or she has been in service in the armed\nforces of the United States or the American Red Cross during world war\nII and has been discharged from such service and that he desires the\nlicense theretofore issued to him or to her to be reissued as of the\ndate of such application, and it shall be the duty of the licensing\nauthority to reinstate such license as of the date on which application\nis made.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>