<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2575-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2575_F">
        <num>2575-F</num>
        <heading>Transfer of employees represented by the united federation of teachers to the New York city teachers' retirement system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2575-f. Transfer of employees represented by the united federation\nof teachers to the New York city teachers' retirement system. Any\nemployee represented by the united federation of teachers who is a\nmember of the New York city board of education retirement system shall\nhave the right to transfer their membership to the teachers' retirement\nsystem of the City of New York. To affect such a transfer, a member must\ngive notice to the New York city board of education retirement system,\nwithin one year of such member becoming eligible for membership in the\nsaid teachers' retirement system, of such member's intention to transfer\nto the said teachers' retirement system. Membership in the united\nfederation of teachers is not required to be covered under this section.\nUpon receipt of such notice, the New York city board of education system\nshall transfer to such teachers' retirement system the reserve on such\nmembers' benefits in the manner provided by subdivisions c and d of\nsection forty-three of the retirement and social security law and\nnotwithstanding subdivision l of such section. The former system shall\nalso transfer to the latter system the member's contributions, which\nshall become such member's contributions in the latter system. A person\nso transferring shall be deemed to have been a member of the system to\nwhich such member has transferred during the entire period of membership\nservice credited to such member in the system from which such member has\ntransferred. Such transferee shall be entitled to all the rights,\nprivileges and benefits of the system to which they have transferred.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>