<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2575-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2575_D">
        <num>2575-D</num>
        <heading>Payment of benefits by board of education retirement system of the city of New York in cases where workmen's compensation is or may be pa...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2575-d. Payment of benefits by board of education retirement system\nof the city of New York in cases where workmen's compensation is or may\nbe payable; reimbursement of such retirement system from workmen's\ncompensation awards. The rules and regulations for the government,\nmanagement and control of the board of education retirement system of\nthe city of New York may be amended pursuant to the provisions of\nsubdivision two of section twenty-five hundred seventy-five of this\nchapter to provide that:\n  (1) the retirement board of such retirement system, pending the final\ndetermination of a claim for workmen's compensation benefits, may\nauthorize payment of all or any part of benefits which are payable under\nsuch rules and regulations and with respect to which benefits\nlimitations or restrictions based on workmen's compensation benefits are\napplicable under such rules and regulations; and\n  (2) in the event that such authorization is granted by the retirement\nboard, such retirement system shall be entitled to reimbursement out of\nthe unpaid installment or installments of compensation due under the\nworkmen's compensation law provided that claim therefor is filed with\nthe workmen's compensation board, together with proof of the fact and\namount of payment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>