<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2575-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2575-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2575_B">
        <num>2575-B</num>
        <heading>Transfer of attendance teachers and specially certificated attendance officers to the New York City teachers' retirement system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2575-b.  Transfer of attendance teachers and specially certificated\nattendance officers to the New York City teachers' retirement system.\nAny attendance teacher or specially certificated attendance officer who\nis a member of the board of education retirement system of the City of\nNew York shall have the right to transfer his membership to the\nteachers' retirement system of the City of New York.  In order to effect\nsuch transfer, such member must given notice to the board of education\nretirement system of the City of New York, on or before December\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, of his intention to transfer\nto the said teachers' retirement system.  Upon receipt of such notice,\nthe board of education retirement system shall transfer to such\nteachers' retirement system the reserves, including the reserve for\nincreased take-home pay, on such member's benefits in the manner\nprovided by section forty-three of the retirement and social security\nlaw.  The former system shall also transfer to the latter system the\nmember's accumulated deductions which shall become such member's\naccumulated deductions in the latter system.  A person so transferring\nshall be deemed to have been a member of the system to which he has\ntransferred during the entire period of membership service credited to\nhim in the system from which he has transferred.  Such transferee shall\nbe entitled to all the rights, privileges and benefits of the system to\nwhich he has transferred.  Upon his retirement, the mortality table in\neffect in the teachers' retirement system of the City of New York on the\ndate when he last became a member of the board of education retirement\nsystem shall apply.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>