<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2576"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2576"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2576"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2576/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2576/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2576/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2576/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2576">
        <num>2576</num>
        <heading>Annual estimate</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2576__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"city funds" shall mean funds of the city of New York derived from\nany source except funds contained within the capital budget and funds\nderived from any federal, state or private sources over which the city\nhas no discretion.\n  (ii) "city amount" shall mean the total amount of expenditures funded\nby city funds for the support of the city school district of the city of\nNew York, not including city payments to bond or note holders for debt\nservice or payments for pension benefits for employees of such district,\nas contained within the budget as adopted by the city of New York.\n  (iii) "base year" shall mean the fiscal year immediately preceding the\nfiscal year for which the budget referred to in subparagraph (ii) of\nthis paragraph is adopted. The initial base year shall be fiscal year\nending June thirtieth, two thousand three.\n  b. The city amount in a budget adopted by the council pursuant to\nsection two hundred fifty-four of the New York city charter shall not be\nless than the city amount appropriated in the base year as determined at\nthe time of adoption of the budget for the ensuing fiscal year and shall\nbe consistent with the requirements of the certification described in\nsubdivision six of section two hundred eleven-d of this chapter.\nProvided, however, in the event the total amount of city funds relied\nupon to balance such budget is lower than the total amount of city funds\nappropriated in the base year, determined at the time of adoption of\nsuch budget pursuant to a process developed by the department in\nconsultation with the city of New York and the labor organization\nrepresenting teachers that identifies a methodology for the allocation\nof appropriations between fiscal years and prescribes a form upon the\napproval of the director of budget for the certifications required by\nthis subdivision, the city amount may be reduced by up to the same\npercentage as the overall percentage decrease in city funds between the\nbase year and the ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2576__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in\ncompliance with this paragraph; (ii) consistent with the requirements of\nsubdivision six of section two hundred eleven-d of this chapter; and\n(iii) sufficient to ensure individual schools can meet the class size\ncompliance targets set forth in subdivision two of section two hundred\neleven-d of this chapter. If a budget is adopted pursuant to section two\nhundred fifty-four of the New York city charter or certified pursuant to\nsection two hundred fifty-six of such charter in violation of this\nparagraph, the council shall have sixty days to adopt a budget compliant\nwith this paragraph and have such budget certified in accordance with\nthe provisions of this paragraph. Should the budget not be adopted and\ncertified within sixty days, the amount by which the budget is\nnon-compliant shall be withheld from the foundation aid allotment until\nsuch time as the budget is certified as compliant with this paragraph.\n  c. Actual budget expenditures shall be certified in October following\nthe close of the fiscal year to ensure compliance with paragraph b of\nthis subdivision. If the budget expenditures are not compliant with\nparagraph b of this subdivision, the council will appropriate funds in\nthe amount of the discrepancy as part of the November modification,\npursuant to subdivision b of section one hundred seven of the New York\ncity charter.\n  5-b. a. For the purposes of this subdivision, the terms:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2576__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"city funds" shall mean funds of each city having a population of\none hundred twenty-five thousand or more inhabitants and less than one\nmillion inhabitants derived from any source except funds contained\nwithin the capital budget, funds from county sales tax revenues shared\nwith such city, funds derived from any federal source and funds derived\nfrom any state or private sources over which the city has no discretion,\nas defined pursuant to regulations developed by the commissioner and\napproved by the director of the budget.\n  (ii) "city amount" shall mean the total amount of expenditures funded\nby city funds for the support of the city school district of each city\nhaving a population of one hundred twenty-five thousand or more\ninhabitants and less than one million inhabitants, not including city\npayments to bond or note holders for debt service payments of such\ndistrict, as contained within the budget as adopted by such city.\n  (iii) "base year" shall mean the fiscal year immediately preceding the\nfiscal year for which the budget referred to in subparagraph (ii) of\nthis paragraph is adopted. The initial base year shall be the fiscal\nyear ending June thirtieth, two thousand seven.\n  b. The city amount shall not be less than the city amount appropriated\nin the base year determined at the time of adoption of the budget for\nthe ensuing fiscal year, and shall not be less than the city amount\nexpended in the base year determined as of the end of the school year.\nProvided, however, in the event the total amount of city funds relied\nupon to balance such budget is lower than the total amount of city funds\nappropriated in the base year, as determined at the time of adoption of\nsuch budget, the city amount may be reduced by up to the same percentage\nas the overall percentage decrease in city funds between the base year\nand the ensuing fiscal year.\n  c. Upon the enactment of a city budget, for the two thousand nine--two\nthousand ten school year budge...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>