<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2580"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2580"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-01-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2580"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2580/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2580/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2580/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2580/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2580">
        <num>2580</num>
        <heading>Funds; custody and disbursement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2580. Funds; custody and disbursement. 1. Public moneys apportioned\nto a city by the state and all funds raised or collected by the\nauthorities in a city for school purposes or to be used by the board of\neducation for any purpose authorized in this chapter, or any other funds\nbelonging to a city and received from any source whatsoever for similar\npurposes, shall be paid into the treasury of such city and shall be\ncredited to the board of education. The funds so received into such\ntreasury shall be kept separate and distinct from any other funds\nreceived into the said treasury. The officer having the charge thereof\nshall give such additional security for the safe custody thereof as the\ncorporate authorities of such city shall require.\n  2. Such funds shall be disbursed by authority of the board of\neducation upon written orders drawn on the city treasurer or other\nfiscal officer of the city. Such orders shall be signed by the\nsuperintendent of schools and the secretary of the board of education or\nsuch other officers as the board may authorize. If a claims auditor\nshall have been appointed, orders shall be signed by the claims auditor;\nprovided, however, that the board may require, in addition, the\nsignature of such other officer or officers as it may by resolution\ndirect. Orders shall be numbered consecutively and shall specify the\npurpose for which they are drawn and the person or corporation to whom\nthey are payable.\n  3. Fixed salaries, principal of and interest on indebtedness and\namounts becoming due upon lawful contracts for periods exceeding one\nyear may be disbursed without prior audit of the board of education. By\nresolution duly adopted, the board may determine to enter into a\ncontract to provide for the deposit of the periodic payroll of the\nschool district in a bank or trust company for disbursal by it in\naccordance with provisions of section ninety-six-b of the banking law.\n  4. It shall be unlawful for a city treasurer or other officer having\nthe custody of such city funds to permit their use for any purpose other\nthan that for which they are lawfully authorized; they shall be paid out\nonly on audit of the board of education or as otherwise provided herein.\nPayments from such funds shall be made only by checks signed by the\ntreasurer or other custodian of such moneys and payable to the person or\npersons entitled thereto and countersigned either by the comptroller, or\nin a city having no comptroller, by an officer designated by the officer\nor body having the general control of the financial affairs of such\ncity. The board of education of such city shall make, in addition to\nsuch classification of its funds and accounts as it desires for its own\nuse and information, such further classification of the funds under its\nmanagement and control and of the disbursements thereof as the\ncomptroller of the city, or the officer or body having the general\ncontrol of the financial affairs of such city, shall require, and such\nboard shall furnish such data in relation to such funds and their\ndisbursements as the comptroller or such other financial officer or body\nof the city shall require.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>