<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2590-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2590_K">
        <num>2590-K</num>
        <heading>Contracts with city university of New York for administration of high schools</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2590-k. Contracts with city university of New York for\nadministration of high schools.  1. The city board and the city\nuniversity of New York are hereby authorized and empowered to enter into\na contract or contracts whereby such university will administer not more\nthan five high schools under the jurisdiction of the city board selected\nfrom among those schools which exhibit the greatest degree of\ndisadvantage as measured by such factors as the proportion of students\nearning general diplomas, the percentage of students reading below grade\nlevel, the attrition rate, the proportion of students residing in\nofficially designated poverty areas, and similar measures.\n  2. Such contract may provide for the delegation by the city board of\nany of its functions, powers, and duties or of a community board, or\nthose of the chancellor or a community superintendent, in connection\nwith the operation of such high schools, to the city university of New\nYork, except the power to appoint or terminate the employment of any\nemployee.  The terms and conditions of employment shall continue to\nremain under the jurisdiction of the city board.\n  3. The provisions of section sixty-two hundred nine of this chapter\nwith respect to the apportionment of public school moneys shall be\napplicable to the high schools included in any such contract or\ncontracts.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>