<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2590-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2590_D">
        <num>2590-D</num>
        <heading>By-laws; regulations and decisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2590-d. By-laws; regulations and decisions. 1. The city board and\nthe chancellor shall prescribe such by-laws and regulations as may be\nnecessary to make effectual the provisions of this chapter and for the\nconduct of the proceedings of said board consistent with the\nrequirements of this article. The city board by-laws shall include a\nprocess by which any member of the city board may request that items be\nplaced on the city board's agenda. Such request may be made at a city\nboard regular public meeting or prior to such meeting. If a member of\nthe city board requests that an item be placed on the agenda at a\nregular public meeting of the city board, then the chairperson shall\nrespond to the request at such meeting. If a member of the city board\nrequests that an item be placed on the agenda at any time prior to a\nregular public meeting of the city board, then the chairperson shall\nrespond to the request at any time prior to the subsequent regular\npublic meeting. Said by-laws and regulations shall be published and\nindexed and revised at least annually. Copies of such by-laws and\nregulations shall be made available for public inspection via the city\nboard's official internet web site, at the offices of the city board,\neach community council, the office of the commissioner of education, and\nthe legislative library in Albany, and at such other places as the city\nboard may deem proper.\n  2. Each community council shall prescribe such by-laws and regulations\nas may be necessary to make effectual the provisions of this chapter and\nfor the conduct of the proceedings of said board. Such by-laws and\nregulations shall be filed with the city board and the commissioner of\neducation and shall be made available for inspection by the public at\nthe offices of the community council. Such by-laws shall include, but\nnot be limited to the following requirements:\n  a. that there shall be a parents' association or a parent-teachers'\nassociation in each school under its jurisdiction;\n  b. that the council, the community superintendent and the principal of\neach school shall have regular communication with all parents'\nassociations and parent-teachers' associations within the community\ndistrict, and meet with their elected officers at least quarterly during\nthe school year, to the end that such associations are provided with\nfull factual information pertaining to matters of pupil achievement,\nincluding but not limited to: annual reading scores, comparison of the\nachievement of pupils in comparable grades and schools, as well as the\nrecord of achievement of the same children as they progress through the\nschool; provided, however, that such record and scores shall not be\ndisclosed in a manner which will identify individual pupils.\n  c. that community councils develop and implement a process consistent\nwith procedures which shall be developed by the chancellor for community\ninput in connection with the annual evaluation of the district\nsuperintendent and other instructional supervisors assigned or appointed\nto the district by the chancellor.\n  d. that all meetings of the community council be subject to article\nseven of the public officers law.\n  3. Copies of all written decisions rendered by the city board acting\nas an appeal board pursuant to subdivision ten of section twenty-five\nhundred ninety-g and copies of all written decisions rendered by the\nchancellor pursuant to section twenty-five hundred ninety-l shall be\npublished, indexed and revised at least semi-annually. Copies of said\ndecisions shall be made available for public inspection at the offices\nof the city board, each community council, the office of the\ncommissioner of education, and at such other places as the city board\nshall deem proper.\n  * NB Effective until June 30, 2026\n  * ยง 2590-d. By-laws; regulations and decisions. 1. The city board and\nthe chancellor shall prescribe such by-laws and regulations as may be\nnecessary to make effectual the provisions of this chapter and for the\nconduct of the proceedings of said board. Said by-laws and regulations\nshall be published and indexed and revised at least annually. Copies of\nsuch by-laws and regulations shall be made available for public\ninspection at the offices of the city board, each community board, the\noffice of the commissioner of education, and the legislative library in\nAlbany, and at such other places as the city board may deem proper.\n  2. Each community board shall prescribe such by-laws and regulations\nas may be necessary to make effectual the provisions of this chapter and\nfor the conduct of the proceedings of said board. Such by-laws and\nregulations shall be filed with the city board and the commissioner of\neducation and shall be made available for inspection by the public at\nthe offices of the community board. Such by-laws shall include, but not\nbe limited to the following requirements:\n  a. that there shall be a parents' association or a parent-teachers'\nassociation in each school under its jurisdiction;\n  b. that the board, the community superintendent and the principal of\neach school shall have regular communication with all parents'\nassociations and parent-teachers' associations within the community\ndistrict, and meet with their elected officers at least quarterly during\nthe school year, to the end that such associations are provided with\nfull factual information pertaining to matters of pupil achievement,\nincluding but not limited to: annual reading scores, comparison of the\nachievement of pupils in comparable grades and schools, as well as the\nrecord of achievement of the same children as they progress through the\nschool; provided, however, that such record and scores shall not be\ndisclosed in a manner which will identify individual pupils.\n  c. that districts implement a process for community involvement in\nconnection with the periodic recommendation of superintendent candidates\nto the chancellor pursuant to regulations of the chancellor, subject to\nthe review and approval of the chancellor, and such involvement in\nconnection with the periodic review of the superintendent's performance.\n  d. that all meetings of the community board be subject to article\nseven of the public officers law.\n  3. Copies of all written decisions rendered by the city board acting\nas an appeal board pursuant to subdivision ten of section twenty-five\nhundred ninety-g and copies of all written decisions rendered by the\nchancellor pursuant to section twenty-five hundred ninety-l shall be\npublished, indexed and revised at least semi-annually. Copies of said\ndecisions shall be made available for public inspection at the offices\nof the city board, each community board, the office of the commissioner\nof education, and at such other places as the city board shall deem\nproper.\n  * NB Effective June 30, 2026\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>