<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2590-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2590-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2590_H">
        <num>2590-H</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of chancellor</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>academic and vocational senior high schools until such time as the\nsame may be transferred to the jurisdiction of appropriate community\ndistrict education councils pursuant to this article;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all specialized senior high schools. The special high schools\nshall include the present schools known as:\n  The Bronx High School of Science, Stuyvesant High School, Brooklyn\nTechnical High School, Fiorello H. LaGuardia High School of Music and\nthe Arts in the borough of Manhattan, and such further schools which the\ncity board may designate from time to time. The special schools shall be\npermitted to maintain a discovery program in accordance with the law in\neffect on the date preceding the effective date of this section;\nadmissions to the special schools shall be conducted in accordance with\nthe law in effect on the date preceding the effective date of this\nsection;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all special education programs and services conducted pursuant to\nthis chapter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>subject to the provisions of section twenty-five hundred ninety-i\nof this article, devolving powers to the schools, city-wide programs for\ncity-wide services to a substantial number of persons from more than one\ncommunity district, including transportation; food services; payroll and\npersonnel functions, including pension and retirement services; and\nenforcement of laws and regulations promoting equal opportunity in\nemployment, access to public accommodations and facilities, equal\nopportunity in education, and preventing and addressing unlawful\ndiscrimination; provided, however, that a community district may also\noperate within its district programs which provide similar services\notherwise authorized by this article.\n  2. Establish, control and operate new schools or programs of the types\nspecified in subdivision one of this section, or to discontinue any such\nschools and programs as he or she may determine; provided, however, that\nthe chancellor shall consult with the affected community district\neducation council before:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>substantially expanding or reducing such an existing school or\nprogram within a community district;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>initially utilizing a community district school or facility for\nsuch a school or program;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>instituting any new program within a community district.\n  2-a.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, prepare\nan educational impact statement regarding any proposed school closing or\nsignificant change in school utilization, including the phase-out, grade\nreconfiguration, re-siting, or co-location of schools, for any public\nschool located within the city district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such educational impact statement shall include the following\ninformation regarding the proposed school closing or significant change\nin school utilization:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the current and projected pupil enrollment of the affected school,\nthe prospective need for such school building, the ramifications of such\nschool closing or significant change in school utilization upon the\ncommunity, initial costs and savings resulting from such school closing\nor significant change in school utilization, the potential disposability\nof any closed school;\n  (ii) the impacts of the proposed school closing or significant change\nin school utilization to any affected students;\n  (iii) an outline of any proposed or potential use of the school\nbuilding for other educational programs or administrative services;\n  (iv) the effect of such school closing or significant change in school\nutilization on personnel needs, the costs of instruction,\nadministration, transportation, and other support services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the type, age, and physical condition of such school building,\nmaintenance, and energy costs, recent or planned improvements to such\nschool building, and such building's special features;\n  (vi) the ability of other schools in the affected community district\nto accommodate pupils following the school closure or significant change\nin school utilization; and\n  (vii) information regarding such school's academic performance\nincluding whether such school has been identified as a school under\nregistration review or has been identified as a school requiring\nacademic progress, a school in need of improvement, or a school in\ncorrective action or restructuring status.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such educational impact statement shall be made publicly\navailable, including via the city board's official internet website, and\na copy shall also be filed with the city board, the impacted community\ncouncil, community boards, community superintendent, and school based\nmanagement team at least six months in advance of the first day of\nschool in the succeeding school year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No sooner than thirty days, but no later than forty-five days\nfollowing the filing of the educational impact statement, the chancellor\nor deputy chancellor, or in the case of a proposed significant change in\nschool utilization the chancellor or his or her designee, shall hold a\njoint public hearing with the impacted community council and school\nbased management team, at the school that is subject to the proposed\nschool closing or significant change in school utilization, and shall\nallow all interested parties an opportunity to present comments or\nconcerns regarding the proposed school closing or significant change in\nschool utilization. The chancellor shall ensure that notice of such\nhearing is widely and conspicuously posted in such a manner to maximize\nthe number of affected individuals that receive notice, including\nproviding notice to affected parents and students, and shall also notify\nmembers of the community boards and the elected state and local\nofficials who represent the affected community district.\n  (d-1) So long as the revised proposal does not impact any school other\nthan a school that was identified in the initial educational impact\nstatement, the chancellor, after receiving public input, may\nsubstantially revise the proposed school closing or significant change\nin school utilization provided that the chancellor shall prepare a\nrevised educational impact statement, in the form prescribed in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, and publish and file such educational\nimpact statement in the same manner as prescribed in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision. No sooner than fifteen days following the filing of\nsuch revised educational impact statement, the chancellor or deputy\nchancellor, or in the case of a significant change in school utilization\nthe chancellor or his or her designee, shall hold a joint public hearing\nwith the impacted community council and school based management team, at\nthe school that is subject to the proposed school closing or significant\nchange in school utilization and shall allow all interested parties an\nopportunity to present comments and concerns regarding such proposal.\nThe chancellor shall ensure that notice of such hearing is widely and\nconspicuously posted in such a manner to maximize the number of affected\nindividuals that receive notice, including providing notice to affected\nparents and students, and shall also notify members of the community\nboards and the elected state and local officials who represent the\naffected community district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision,\nall proposed school closings or significant changes in school\nutilization shall be approved by the city board pursuant to section\ntwenty-five hundred ninety-g of this article and shall not take effect\nuntil all the provisions of this subdivision have been satisfied and the\nschool year in which such city board approval was granted, has ended.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that the chancellor determines that a school closing\nor significant change in school utilization is immediately necessary for\nthe preservation of student health, safety or general welfare, the\nchancellor may temporarily close a public school or adopt a significant\nchange in the school's utilization on an emergency basis. Such emergency\nschool closing or significant change in school utilization shall only\nremain in effect for six months, during such time the chancellor shall\ncomply with the requirements of this subdivision in order for such\nschool closure or significant change in school utilization to extend\nbeyond the six month period.\n  3. Subject to the approval of the city board, develop a plan to\nprovide for the establishment of comprehensive high schools within the\ncity district so that every community district shall have available to\nits graduates further education and a comprehensive high school. Such\nplan may provide for the conversion of academic and vocational high\nschools and may be amended or modified from time to time.\n  4. Appoint teacher-aides for the schools and programs under his or her\njurisdiction within the budgetary allocation therefor.\n  5. Retain jurisdiction over all employees who are required in\nconnection with the performance of duties with respect to the design,\nconstruction, operation and maintenance of all school buildings in the\ncity school district. Such employees shall have all rights accorded them\nunder the provisions of the civil service law, including manner of\nappointment, classification, promotion, transfer and removal including\nan opportunity to be heard provided, however, that each custodian shall\nbe responsible for the performance of his or her duties to the principal\nof the school who shall be responsible to the district superintendent.\n  6. Employ or retain counsel subject to the powers and duties of the\ncorporation counsel of the city of New York to be his or her attorney\nand counse...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>compliance with such educational standards and other requirements,\nand\n  (ii) the educational effectiveness of such schools and programs, in a\nmanner not inconsistent with the policies of the city board.\n  9. Furnish community district education councils and the city board\nperiodically with the results of such examinations and evaluations and\nto make the same public.\n  10. Require each community superintendent to make an annual report\ncovering all matters relating to schools under the district's\njurisdiction including, but not limited to, the evaluation of the\neducational effectiveness of such schools and programs connected\ntherewith.\n  11. Require such community district education council or\nsuperintendent to make such number of periodic reports as may be\nnecessary to accomplish the purposes of this chapter.\n  13. Perform the following functions throughout the city district;\nprovided, however, that the chancellor and any community district\neducation council may agree that any such function may be appropriately\nperformed by the community district education council with respect to\nthe schools and programs under its jurisdiction:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Technical assistance to community districts and schools;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such warehouse space on a regional basis as he or she determines\nto be necessary or appropriate after consultation with the community\nsuperintendents;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Purchasing services on a city-wide, regional or community district\nbasis subject to subdivision thirty-six of this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Reinforce and foster connections to institutions of higher\neducation to promote student achievement.\n  14. Develop and furnish pre-service and in-service training programs\nfor principals and other employees throughout the city district. In\naddition, the chancellor shall prepare and annually update a training\nplan for participating parents, and school personnel, which shall\ninclude, at minimum, such training as may be required for exercise of\ntheir responsibilities, full participation and compliance with the\nprovisions of this section. The chancellor shall, in addition, within\namounts appropriated, allocate sufficient funds directly and to the\nsuperintendents for teacher and principal training to meet identified\nneeds for school improvement.\n  15. Promote the involvement and appropriate input of all members of\nthe school community pursuant to the provisions of this article,\nincluding parents, teachers, and other school personnel, including:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establishing a parents' association or a parent-teachers'\nassociation in each public school under the chancellor's jurisdiction;\nand ensuring that the districts and charter schools located within the\ncity district do the same; the chancellor shall ensure that meetings of\nsuch parents' associations or parent-teachers' associations shall comply\nwith section four hundred fourteen of this chapter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pursuant to a plan prepared in consultation with associations of\nparents, and representatives of teachers, supervisors, paraprofessionals\nand other school personnel within the city district, and promulgated no\nlater than January thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ntaking all necessary steps to ensure that no later than October first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-nine, the city district and the community\ndistricts are in full compliance, and remain in compliance thereafter,\nwith state and federal law and regulations concerning school-based\nmanagement and shared decision-making, including section 100.11 of the\ncommissioner's regulations, in a manner which balances participation by\nparents with participation by school personnel in advising in the\ndecisions devolved to schools pursuant to sections twenty-five hundred\nninety-i and twenty-five hundred ninety-r of this article, and (ii)\npursuant to such plan providing for appropriate training to any parent\nand school personnel who participate in the school based management and\nshared decision-making process;\n  (b-1) school based management teams developed pursuant to paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall possess the following powers and duties:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>develop an annual school comprehensive educational plan and\nconsult on the school-based budget pursuant to section twenty-five\nhundred ninety-r of this article. Such school comprehensive educational\nplan shall be developed concurrently with the development of the\nschool-based budget so that it may inform the decision-making process\nand result in the alignment of the comprehensive educational plan and\nthe school-based budget for the ensuing school year. Such plan shall be\nsubmitted to the community superintendent along with the principal's\nwritten justification demonstrating that the school-based budget\nproposal is aligned with the school's comprehensive educational plan and\nthe school based management team's response to such justification\npursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section twenty-five\nhundred ninety-f of this article. In the case of specialized, academic,\nvocational, and other high schools that are not under the jurisdiction\nof a community superintendent, such plan shall be submitted to the\nchancellor pursuant to subdivision e of section twenty-five hundred\nninety-r of this article. The chancellor shall ensure that the\ncomprehensive educational plan of every school within the city district\nis easily accessible and be made available for public inspection\nincluding via the city board's official internet website;\n  (ii) hold at least one meeting per month during the school year. Each\nmonthly meeting shall be held at a time that is convenient for the\nparent representatives;\n  (iii) provide notice of monthly meetings that is consistent with the\nopen meetings law;\n  (iv) have parent members of such teams make recommendations,\nconsistent with the chancellor's regulations, on the selection of the\nschool principal and have all members be consulted prior to the\nappointment of any principal candidate to its school;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>undergo initial and ongoing training that will allow its members\nto carry out their duties effectively;\n  (vi) dispute any decision made by the principal to the community\nsuperintendent pursuant to section twenty-five hundred ninety-f of this\narticle where members of the school based management team, other than\nthe principal, reach a consensus that the decision is inconsistent with\nthe goals and policies set forth in the school's existing comprehensive\neducational plan; and\n  (vii) provide to the community superintendent an annual assessment of\nthe school principal's record of developing an effective shared\ndecision-making relationship with school based management team members;\nand\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>developing, in consultation with associations of parents in the\ncity district, and implementing no later than October first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-eight, a parental bill of rights which provides for, at\nminimum:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reasonable access by parents, persons in parental relation and\nguardians to schools, classrooms, and academic and attendance records of\ntheir own children, consistent with federal and state laws, provided\nthat such access does not disrupt or interfere with the regular school\nprocess;\n  (ii) the rights of parents, persons in parental relation and guardians\nto take legal action and appeal the decisions of the school\nadministration, as authorized by law;\n  (iii) the right of parents, persons in parental relation and guardians\nto have information on their own child's educational materials;\n  (iv) access to and information about all public meetings, hearings of\nthe chancellor, the city board, the community superintendents, the\ncommunity district education councils, and the schools; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>access to information regarding programs that allow students to\napply for admission where appropriate to schools outside a student's own\nattendance zone; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require each public school under the chancellor's jurisdiction to\nhave a parent coordinator who shall be responsible for engaging with and\ninvolving parents in the school community by working with the school\nprincipal, school personnel, school based management team, parent\nassociations, and community groups to identify parent and related school\nand community issues. The community district education council of each\nschool shall be consulted prior to the selection of the parent\ncoordinator. Such consultation shall include an opportunity for the\ncommunity district education council to meet with the final candidate or\ncandidates the school principal is considering selecting and to provide\nfeedback to the principal prior to the selection being made.\n  The chancellor shall by rule or regulation provide for the involvement\nincluding membership, in any parents' association or parent-teacher\nassociation established pursuant to this subdivision, of a grandparent\nwho is in parental relation to a child who attends a school within the\njurisdiction of the community school district. For purposes of this\nsubdivision, a grandparent shall be considered to be in parental\nrelation to a child when such grandparent has assumed care of such child\nbecause such child's parents are not available due to death,\nimprisonment, mental illness, living outside the state, abandonment of\nthe child, or other circumstances. A determination of whether a\ngrandparent is in parental relation to a child shall be based upon the\nindividual circumstances surrounding guardianship and custodial care of\nsuch child.\n  16. Promulgate such rules and regulations as he or she may determine\nto be necessary or convenient to accomplish the purposes of this act,\nnot inconsistent with the provisions of this article and the city-wide\neducational policies of the city board.\n  16-a. Create standards, policies, and objectives and promulgate\nregulations directly related to maintaining the internal f...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such policy shall specifically include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a competitive sealed bidding process for the awarding of contracts\nin which sealed bids are publicly solicited and opened and that a\ncontract is awarded to the lowest responsive, responsible bidder;\n  (ii) processes for awarding contracts using alternatives to\ncompetitive sealed bidding where competitive sealed bidding is not\npracticable or not advantageous, in which case the most competitive\nalternative method of procurement, which is appropriate under the\ncircumstances, shall be used consistent with the requirements of\nsubparagraph (vii) of this paragraph;\n  * (iii) measures to enhance the ability of minority and women owned\nbusiness enterprises pursuant to section thirteen hundred four of the\nNew York city charter and a certified business as defined in section\nthree hundred ten of the executive law, including firms certified\npursuant to article fifteen-A of the executive law and firms certified\nas minority and women owned business enterprises pursuant to section\nthirteen hundred four of the New York city charter, to compete for\ncontracts and to ensure their meaningful participation in the\nprocurement process. The school district shall have the authority to use\nthe same measures, to enhance minority and women owned business\nenterprise participation as are available to the city of New York\npursuant to article five-A of the general municipal law, section\nthirteen hundred four of the New York city charter, paragraphs one and\ntwo of subdivision i of section three hundred eleven of the New York\ncity charter, and section 6-129 of the administrative code of the city\nof New York;\n  * NB Effective until February 22, 2024\n  * (iii) measures to enhance the ability of minority and women owned\nbusiness enterprises pursuant to section thirteen hundred four of the\nNew York city charter and a certified business as defined in section\nthree hundred ten of the executive law, including firms certified\npursuant to article fifteen-A of the executive law an...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>standards and procedures to be used in determining whether bidders\nare responsible;\n  (vi) circumstances under which procurement may be used for the\nprovision of technical, consultant or personal services;\n  (vii) requiring written justification for the basis, including the\nefficiency, benefit, and necessity, for awarding a contract using\nprocurement methods other than competitive sealed bidding including\ncompetitive sealed proposals and sole source contracts, and for awarding\ntechnical, consultant, or personal services contracts, franchises,\nrevocable consents, or concessions. Such written justification shall be\nfiled with the comptroller of the city of New York along with the\ncorresponding contract, franchise, revocable consent, or concession;\n  (viii) maintaining a file for every contract franchise, revocable\nconsent, and concession containing information pertaining to the\nsolicitation, award and management of every such contract or agreement.\nSuch file shall contain copies of each determination, writing or filing\nrequired by this subdivision and shall be open to public inspection with\nadequate protection for information which is confidential;\n  (ix) a process for the filing of all contracts, franchises, revocable\nconsents, and concessions with the comptroller of the city of New York;\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a process for emergency procurement in the case of an unforeseen\ndanger to life, safety, property or a necessary service provided that\nsuch procurement shall be made with such competition as is practicable\nunder the circumstances and that a written determination of the basis\nfor the emergency procurement shall be required and filed with the\ncomptroller of the city of New York when such emergency contract is\nfiled with such comptroller; and\n  * NB Effective until May 15, 2024\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a process for emergency procurement in the case of an unforeseen\ndanger to life, safety, property or a necessary service provided that\nsuch procurement shall be made with such competition as is practicable\nunder the circumstances and that a written determination of the basis\nfor the emergency procurement shall be required and filed with the\ncomptroller of the city of New York when such emergency contract is\nfiled with such comptroller;\n  * NB Effective May 15, 2024 and until May 15, 2029 or until sb 36\nexpires, whichever is sooner\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a process for emergency procurement in the case of an unforeseen\ndanger to life, safety, property or a necessary service provided that\nsuch procurement shall be made with such competition as is practicable\nunder the circumstances and that a written determination of the basis\nfor the emergency procurement shall be required and filed with the\ncomptroller of the city of New York when such emergency contract is\nfiled with such comptroller; and\n  * NB Effective May 15, 2029 if sb 36 is still in effect\n  * (xi) procedures for the fair and equitable resolution of contract\ndisputes.\n  * NB Effective until May 15, 2024\n  * (xi) procedures for the fair and equitable resolution of contract\ndisputes; and\n  * NB Effective May 15, 2024 and until May 15, 2029 or until sb 36\nexpires, whichever is sooner\n  * (xi) procedures for the fair and equitable resolution of contract\ndisputes.\n  * NB Effective May 15, 2029 if sb 36 is still in effect\n  * (xii) employment goals established in accordance with the program\nestablished pursuant to section thirty-five hundred two of the New York\ncity charter, including but not limited to employment goals established\npursuant to paragraph seven of subdivision a and the corresponding best\nefforts provisions set forth in subdivision d of such section; provided,\nhowever, that where a provision of such section requires action by the\ndirector of the office of community hiring and workforce development,\nsuch action shall not be taken by the director of the office of\ncommunity hiring and workforce development but shall be taken by the\nchancellor or his or her designee.\n  * NB Effective May 15, 2024\n  * NB Repealed May 15, 2029 or upon the repeal of sb 36, whichever is\nearlier\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Consistent with the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision such policy shall also include:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>standards for quality,\nfunction, and utility of all material goods, supplies, and services\npurchased by the chancellor, superintendents, or schools; (ii)\nregulations which enable superintendents and schools to purchase\nmaterial goods, supplies, and services directly from vendors or\nsuppliers when such products are available at prices or other terms more\neconomically beneficial for the purposes of the acquiring superintendent\nor school; and (iii) regulations shall include repair services and\nbuilding supplies, as defined in such regulations, for expenditures from\neach district's minor repair and purchasing funds pursuant to section\ntwenty-five hundred ninety-r of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The chancellor shall be responsible for certifying that the\nprocedural requisites pursuant to this subdivision and section\ntwenty-five hundred ninety-g of this article have been met, prior to the\nfiling any contract awarded by a procurement method other than\ncompetitive sealed bidding, or prior to filing any technical,\nconsultant, or personal services contract, franchise, revocable consent,\nor concession with the comptroller of the city of New York. The\ncorporation counsel for the city of New York shall certify prior to the\nfiling of such contract or agreement with the comptroller of the city of\nNew York, that the city district has legal authority to award each such\ncontract or agreement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No contract, franchise, revocable consent or concession shall\nbe implemented until a copy has been filed with the comptroller of the\ncity of New York and either such comptroller has registered it or thirty\ndays have elapsed from the date of filing, whichever is sooner, unless\nan objection has been filed pursuant to subparagraph (iii) of this\nparagraph, or the comptroller of the city of New York has grounds for\nnot registering such contract or agreement under subparagraph (ii) of\nthis paragraph.\n  (ii) Subject to the provisions of subparagraph (iii) of this\nparagraph, the comptroller of the city of New York shall register such\ncontract or agreement within thirty days unless such comptroller has\ninformation indicating that:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>there remains no unexpended and unapplied balance of the\nappropriation or fund applicable thereto, sufficient to pay the\nestimated expense of executing such contract or agreement;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a certification required pursuant to this paragraph has not been\nmade; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the proposed vendor has been debarred by the city of New York.\n  (iii) The comptroller of the city of New York may, within thirty days\nof the date of filing of the contract, franchise, revocable consent or\nconcession with his or her office, object in writing to the registration\nof such contract or agreement, if in such comptroller's judgment there\nis sufficient reason to believe that there is possible corruption in the\nletting of such contract or agreement or that the proposed contractor is\ninvolved in corrupt activity. Such objection shall be delivered within\nsuch thirty day period to the mayor of the city of New York setting\nforth in detail the grounds for the New York city comptroller's\ndetermination. The mayor of the city of New York may require\nregistration of the contract or agreement despite the New York city\ncomptroller's objections if the mayor of the city of New York has\nresponded to such comptroller's objections in writing, indicating:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the corrective actions if any, that have been taken or will be\ntaken in response to such comptroller's objections, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the reasons why the mayor of the city of New York disagrees with\nsuch comptroller's objections.\n  Such response by the mayor of the city of New York shall not serve as\nthe basis for further objection by the New York city comptroller, and\nsuch comptroller shall register the contract, franchise, revocable\nconsent or concession within ten days of receipt of the mayor of the\ncity of New York's response.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The requirements of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision\nshall not apply to an emergency contract awarded pursuant to\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, provided that the\nchancellor shall comply with the requirements of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision as soon as practicable.\n  37. Establish guidelines and a system of internal controls, including\ninternal administrative controls and internal accounting controls, with\nprovisions for internal audits, as such terms are defined in section\nnine hundred fifty of the executive law. Such system shall also include\na system of internal control review designed to identify weaknesses and\nidentify actions to rectify them; a clear and concise statement of the\ngenerally applicable management policies and standards made available to\neach officer and employee relevant to fiscal and expenditure control, in\naddition to education and training efforts to ensure adequate\nunderstanding of internal control standards and evaluation techniques;\nand the designation of an internal control officer for each community\ndistrict, each of whom shall report to the chancellor and the auditor\ngeneral, to execute a regular internal audit function, which shall\noperate in accordance with generally accepted governmental auditing\nstandards. The internal auditors for the community districts shall\noperate in cooperation with the auditor general, appointed by the\nchancellor, who shall, in addition to the functions of the internal\nauditors, monitor and conduct random audits of school districts at least\nonce every two years for fraud, waste, and mismanagement.\nNotwithstanding any provision of state law or state or city regulation,\nthe internal auditors, and the auditor general, shall be entitled, upon\ntheir request, to all and any documents and materials bearing in their\njudgment on the finances and cost-effectiveness of the schools and the\nschool districts that is in the possession of the community districts,\nthe schools, or any officer thereof.\n  38. To exercise all of the duties and responsibilities of the\nemploying board as set forth in section three thousand twenty-a of this\nchapter with respect to any member of the teaching or supervisory staff\nof school...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section\nthree thousand twenty-a of this chapter.\n  ** 39.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prescribe regulations and by-laws requiring members of the\ncity board, the chancellor, and any other officer or employee in schools\nand programs under the jurisdiction of the city board and the chancellor\nto make annual written disclosure to the chancellor, of the following\ninformation:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the employment by the city school board or any community district\neducation council of any person related within the third degree of\nconsanguinity or affinity to the person making disclosure, including the\nemployment of any such person for which a two-thirds vote was required\nunder paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of section twenty-five hundred\nninety-j of this article, with a notation of the date such vote was\ntaken.\n  (ii) the source of any income, reimbursement, gift, or other form of\ncompensation for services rendered, together with a description of such\nservices.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The chancellor shall review, at least once annually, compliance\nwith the requirements of subdivisions five and six of section\ntwenty-five hundred ninety-e of this article and regulations or by-laws\nprescribed in this subdivision. Any community district education council\nmember, community superintendent, or other officer or employee required\nto make disclosure, who fails to make such disclosure, shall be notified\nin writing of his or her failure to do so and given thirty days within\nwhich to comply.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Willful failure to make full and timely disclosure shall\nconstitute cause for removal from office of any member of the city board\nor for any other officer or employee disciplinary action and such other\npenalty as may be provided by law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Disclosures made pursuant to the requirements of this subdivision\nand any notification of failure to make disclosures shall be made\navailable for public inspection during regular business hours on regular\nbusiness days.\n  ** NB There are 2 sb</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_e__subsec_39">
            <num>(39)</num>
            <content>
              <p>'s\n  ** 39. To enter an agreement, in his or her discretion, with the city\nof New York for the installation and use of school bus photo violation\nmonitoring systems pursuant to section eleven hundred seventy-four-a of\nthe vehicle and traffic law, provided that the purchase, lease,\ninstallation, operation and maintenance, or any other costs associated\nwith such cameras shall not be considered an aidable expense pursuant to\nsection thirty-six hundred twenty-three-a of this chapter.\n  ** NB There are 2 sb</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_e__subsec_39">
            <num>(39)</num>
            <content>
              <p>'s\n  ** NB Repealed December 1, 2029\n  40.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prescribe regulations and by-laws requiring members of the\ncity board, the chancellor, and, for good cause shown, any other officer\nor employee in schools and programs under the jurisdiction of the city\nboard and the chancellor, to submit to the chancellor, in the discretion\nof the chancellor, financial reports for themselves and their spouses.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The frequency and period of coverage, the designation of persons\nto submit such reports by name, title, or income level, or by a\ncombination thereof, and the content of such reports, including minimum\ndollar amounts, shall be determined by the chancellor, and such reports\nmay include but not necessarily be limited to the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>amount and source of income for services rendered, together with a\ndescription of such services;\n  (ii) amount and source of gifts, capital gains, reimbursements for\nexpenditures, and honoraria;\n  (iii) investments in securities and real property;\n  (iv) amount of debts and names of creditors;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>outstanding loans and other forms of indebtedness due to person\nreporting or spouse, by name and amounts; and\n  (vi) trusts and other fiduciary relationships and their assets in\nwhich a beneficial interest is held.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Willful failure to file required financial reports shall\nconstitute cause for removal from office of any member of the city board\nor for any other officer or employee disciplinary action and such other\npenalty as may be provided by law.\n  41. Appoint and set salaries for staff in non-represented managerial\ntitles.\n  42.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To dispose of such personal property used in the schools and\nother buildings of the city of New York under the charge of the city\nboard as shall no longer be required for use therein. Such disposition\nshall be made in the name of the city of New York and for such city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The chancellor may sell, at prices as may be agreed upon, such\nmanufactured articles or other products of any school of the district,\nday and evening, as may not be utilized by the city board, and all\nmoneys realized by the sale thereof shall be paid into the city treasury\nand shall at once be appropriated by the city to a special fund to be\nadministered by the city board for such purposes as such board, in its\ndiscretion, may determine. All other moneys realized by the sale of\npersonal property shall be paid into the city treasury and shall at once\nbe appropriated by the city to the special school fund of the city board\nfor use in the borough in which the property sold was situated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such method of disposal shall be deemed not to apply to the\ndisposition of school books pursuant to subdivision forty-three of this\nsection.\n  43. To dispose of, to the best advantage of the city of New York,\neither by sale or on the basis of money allowance for waste paper, all\nbooks delivered to the several public schools of such city that have\nbeen discarded either by reason of being obsolete, no longer required by\nthe course of study, worn by long usage, or mutilated by accident. If\ndisposal is made by sale, it shall be to the highest bidder, and the\nmoney realized shall be paid into the city treasury and shall at once be\nappropriated by the city to the special school fund of the city board\nentitled "supplies". If disposal is made on the basis of money allowance\nfor waste paper, it shall be to the highest bidder. Such discarded books\nmay be disposed of without public advertisement or entry into a formal\ncontract. Should the discarded books be in such condition that no sale\nor exchange can be made, or should there be reason to believe that such\ndiscarded books have become infected through disease among the pupils,\nor should the superintendent of schools certify that such discarded\nbooks contain erroneous, inaccurate, obsolete, or antiquated subject\nmatter, illustrations, maps, charts, or other material, the committee on\nsupplies of the board of education, if such books cannot be sold, given\naway, or otherwise salvaged as waste paper without danger to the public\nhealth, may authorize their destruction by fire, in which event the\nsuperintendent of school supplies shall obtain and file in his or her\noffice a certificate that such books have been so destroyed, signed by\nthe principal of the school in which the books are located.\n  44. To provide the proper book or books in which he or she shall cause\nthe class teachers under the direction and supervision of the principal\nto enter the names, ages, and residences of the pupils attending the\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>academic and vocational senior high schools until such time as the\nsame may be transferred to the jurisdiction of appropriate community\nboards pursuant to this article;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all specialized senior high schools. The special high schools\nshall include the present schools known as:\n  The Bronx High School of Science, Stuyvesant High School, Brooklyn\nTechnical High School, Fiorello H. LaGuardia High School of Music and\nthe Arts in the borough of Manhattan, and such further schools which the\ncity board may designate from time to time. The special schools shall be\npermitted to maintain a discovery program in accordance with the law in\neffect on the date preceding the effective date of this section;\nadmissions to the special schools shall be conducted in accordance with\nthe law in effect on the date preceding the effective date of this\nsection;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all special education programs and services conducted pursuant to\nthis chapter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>subject to the provisions of section twenty-five hundred ninety-i\nof this article, devolving powers to the schools, city-wide programs for\ncity-wide services to a substantial number of persons from more than one\ncommunity district, including transportation; food services; payroll and\npersonnel functions, including pension and retirement services; and\nenforcement of laws and regulations promoting equal opportunity in\nemployment, access to public accommodations and facilities, equal\nopportunity in education, and preventing and addressing unlawful\ndiscrimination; provided, however, that a community district may also\noperate within its district programs which provide similar services\notherwise authorized by this article.\n  2. Establish, control and operate new schools or programs of the types\nspecified in subdivision one of this section, or to discontinue any such\nschools and programs as he or she may determine; provided, however, that\nhe shall consult with the affected community board before:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>substantially expanding or reducing such an existing school or\nprogram within a community district;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>initially utilizing a community district school or facility for\nsuch a school or program;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>instituting any new program within a community district.\n  3. Subject to the approval of the city board, develop a plan to\nprovide for the establishment of comprehensive high schools within the\ncity district so that every community district shall have available to\nits graduates further education and a comprehensive high school. Such\nplan may provide for the conversion of academic and vocational high\nschools and may be amended or modified from time to time.\n  4. Appoint teacher-aides for the schools and programs under his or her\njurisdiction within the budgetary allocation therefor.\n  5. Retain jurisdiction over all employees who are required in\nconnection with the performance of duties with respect to the design,\nconstruction, operation and maintenance of all school buildings in the\ncity school district. Such employees shall have all rights accorded them\nunder the provisions of the civil service law, including manner of\nappointment, classification, promotion, transfer and removal including\nan opportunity to be heard provided, however, that each custodian shall\nbe responsible for the performance of his duties to the principal of the\nschool who shall be responsible to the district superintendent.\n  6. Employ or retain counsel subject to the powers and duties of the\ncorporation counsel of the city of New York to be his or her attorney\nand counsel pursuant to subdivision a of section three hundred\nninety-four of the New York city charter; provided, however, that in\nactions or proceedings between the city board or the chancellor and one\nor more community boards, the city board or the chancellor shall be\nrepresented by the corporation counsel of the city of New York.\n  7. To continue existing voluntary programs or to establish new\nprograms under which students may choose to attend a public school in\nanother community district.\n  8. Promulgate minimum clear educational standards, curriculum\nrequirements and frameworks, and mandatory educational...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>compliance with such educational standards and other requirements,\nand\n  (ii) the educational effectiveness of such schools and programs, in a\nmanner not inconsistent with the policies of the city board.\n  9. Furnish community boards and the city board periodically with the\nresults of such examinations and evaluations and to make the same\npublic.\n  10. Require each community superintendent to make an annual report\ncovering all matters relating to schools under the district's\njurisdiction including, but not limited to, the evaluation of the\neducational effectiveness of such schools and programs connected\ntherewith.\n  11. Require such community board or superintendent to make such number\nof periodic reports as may be necessary to accomplish the purposes of\nthis chapter.\n  13. Perform the following functions throughout the city district;\nprovided, however, that the chancellor and any community board may agree\nthat any such function may be appropriately performed by the community\nboard with respect to the schools and programs under its jurisdiction:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Technical assistance to community districts and schools;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such warehouse space on a regional basis as he or she determines\nto be necessary or appropriate after consultation with the community\nsuperintendents;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Purchasing services on a city-wide, regional or community district\nbasis subject to subdivision thirty-six of this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Reinforce and foster connections to institutions of higher\neducation to promote student achievement.\n  14. Develop and furnish pre-service and in-service training programs\nfor principals and other employees throughout the city district. In\naddition, the chancellor shall prepare and annually update a training\nplan for participating parents, and school personnel, which shall\ninclude, at minimum, such training as may be required for exercise of\ntheir responsibilities, full participation and compliance with the\nprovisions of this section. The chancellor shall, in addition, within\namounts appropriated, allocate sufficient funds directly and to the\nsuperintendents for teacher and principal training to meet identified\nneeds for school improvement.\n  15. Promote the involvement and appropriate input of all members of\nthe school community pursuant to the provisions of this article,\nincluding parents, teachers, and other school personnel, including:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establishing a parents' association or a parent-teachers'\nassociation in each school under the chancellor's jurisdiction; and\nensuring that the districts do the same;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pursuant to a plan prepared in consultation with associations of\nparents, and representatives of teachers, supervisors, paraprofessionals\nand other school personnel within the city district, and promulgated no\nlater than January thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ntaking all necessary steps to ensure that no later than October first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-nine, the city district and the community\ndistricts are in full compliance, and remain in compliance thereafter,\nwith state and federal law and regulations concerning school-based\nmanagement and shared decision-making, including section 100.11 of the\ncommissioner's regulations, in a manner which balances participation by\nparents with participation by school personnel in advising in the\ndecisions devolved to schools pursuant to sections twenty five hundred\nninety-i and twenty-five hundred ninety-r of this article, and (ii)\npursuant to such plan providing for appropriate training to any parent\nand school personnel who participate in the school-based management and\nshared decision-making process; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>developing, in consultation with associations of parents in the\ncity district, and implementing no later than October first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-eight, a parental bill of rights which provides for, at\nminimum:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reasonable access by parents, persons in parental relation and\nguardians to schools, classrooms, and academic and attendance records of\ntheir own children, consistent with federal and state laws, provided\nthat such access does not disrupt or interfere with the regular school\nprocess;\n  (ii) the rights of parents, persons in parental relation and guardians\nto take legal action and appeal the decisions of the school\nadministration, as authorized by law;\n  (iii) the right of parents, persons in parental relation and guardians\nto have information on their own child's educational materials;\n  (iv) access to and information about all public meetings, hearings of\nthe chancellor, the city board, the community superintendents, the\ncommunity boards, and the schools; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>access to information regarding programs that allow students to\napply for admission where appropriate to schools outside a student's own\nattendance zone.\n  The chancellor shall by rule or regulation provide for the involvement\nincluding membership, in any parents' association or parent-teacher\nassociation established pursuant to this subdivision, of a grandparent\nwho is in parental relation to a child who attends a school within the\njurisdiction of the community school district. For purposes of this\nsubdivision, a grandparent shall be considered to be in parental\nrelation to a child when such grandparent has assumed care of such child\nbecause such child's parents are not available due to death,\nimprisonment, mental illness, living outside the state, abandonment of\nthe child, or other circumstances. A determination of whether a\ngrandparent is in parental relation to a child shall be based upon the\nindividual circumstances surrounding guardianship and custodial care of\nsuch child.\n  16. Promulgate such rules and regulations as he or she may determine\nto be necessary or convenient to accomplish the purposes of this act,\nnot inconsistent with the provisions of this article and the policies of\nthe city board.\n  17. Possess those powers and duties described in section twenty-five\nhundred fifty-four of this chapter, the exercise of which shall be in a\nmanner not inconsistent with the provisions of this article and the\npolicies of the city board.\n  18. Possess those powers and duties contained in section nine hundred\ntwelve of this chapter and those provisions of article fifteen thereof\nwhich relate to non-public schools, those powers and duties contained in\nsection five hundred twenty-two of the New York city charter and those\npowers and duties contained in article seventy-three of this chapter,\nthe exercise of which shall be in a manner not inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this article and the policies of the city board.\n  19. Delegate an...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>standards for quality, function and utility of all material\ngoods, supplies and services purchased by the chancellor,\nsuperintendents or schools;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>regulations for the purchase of material\ngoods, supplies and services by the chancellor, the superintendents and\nthe schools, including clearly articulated procedures which require a\nclear statement of product specifications, requirements or work to be\nperformed, a documentable process of soliciting bids, proposals or other\noffers, and a balanced and fair method, established in advance of\nreceipt of offers, for evaluating offers and awarding contracts;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nregulations which enable superintendents and schools to purchase\nmaterial goods, supplies and services directly from vendors or suppliers\nwhen such products are available at prices or other terms more\neconomically beneficial for the purposes of the acquiring superintendent\nor school; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2590_H__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>regulations shall include repair services and\nbuilding supplies, as defined in such regulations, for expenditures from\neach district's minor repair and purchasing funds pursuant to section\ntwenty-five hundred ninety-r of this article.\n  37. Establish, subject to the approval of the city board, guidelines\nand a system of internal controls, including internal administrative\ncontrols and internal accounting controls, with provisions for internal\naudits, as such terms are defined in section nine hundred fifty of the\nexecutive law. Such system shall also include a system of internal\ncontrol review designed to identify weaknesses and identify actions to\nrectify them; a clear and concise statement of the generally applicable\nmanagement policies and standards made available to each officer and\nemployee relevant to fiscal and expenditure control, in addition to\neducation and training efforts to ensure adequate understanding of\ninternal control standards and evaluation techniques; and the\ndesignation of an internal control officer for each community district,\neach of whom shall report to the chancellor and the auditor general, to\nexecute a regular internal audit function which shall operate in\naccordance with generally accepted governmental auditing standards. The\ninternal auditors for the community districts shall operate in\ncooperation with the auditor general, appointed by the chancellor\nsubject to the approval of the city board, who shall, in addition to the\nfunctions of the internal auditors, monitor and conduct random audits of\nschool districts at least once every two years for fraud, waste and\nmismanagement. Notwithstanding any provision of state law or state, city\nor city board regulation, the internal auditors, and the auditor\ngeneral, shall be entitled, upon their request, to all and any documents\nand materials bearing in their judgment on the finances and\ncost-effectiveness of the schools and the school districts that is in\nthe possessi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>