<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-268"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-268"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="268"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-268/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-268/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-268/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-268/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_268">
        <num>268</num>
        <heading>Abolition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 268. Abolition.  Any library established by public vote of any\nmunicipality or district, or by vote of the common council of any city,\nor by vote of the board of trustees of any village, or by action of\nschool authorities, or by vote of the tribal government of an Indian\nreservation, or under section two hundred fifty-five of this chapter,\nmay be abolished by majority vote at an election, or at a meeting of the\nelectors duly held, provided that due public notice of the proposed\naction shall have been given, or by vote of such tribal government.  If\nany such library is abolished, its property shall be used first to\nreturn to the regents, for the benefit of other free association or\npublic or school libraries in that locality, the equivalent of such sums\nas it may have received from the state or from other sources as gifts\nfor public use.  After such return any remaining property may be used as\ndirected in the vote abolishing the library, but if the entire library\nproperty does not exceed in value the amount of such gifts, it may be\ntransferred to the regents for public use, and the trustees shall\nthereupon be free from further responsibility.  No abolition of a public\nlibrary shall be lawful until the regents grant a certificate that its\nassets have been properly distributed and its abolition completed in\naccordance with law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>