<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-284"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-284"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="284"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-284/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-284/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-284/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-284/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_284">
        <num>284</num>
        <heading>State aid for school library systems</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 284. State aid for school library systems. 1. Each school library\nsystem established pursuant to section two hundred eighty-two of this\npart and operating under a plan approved by the commissioner shall be\neligible to receive funding under this section consisting of the\nfollowing amounts:\n  a. Each school library system with a public and nonpublic school\nenrollment of less than one hundred thousand students shall receive a\nbase grant of eighty-three thousand dollars;\n  b. Each school library system with a public and nonpublic school\nenrollment of one hundred thousand students but less than two hundred\nthousand students shall receive a base grant of ninety thousand dollars;\n  c. Each school library system with a public and nonpublic school\nenrollment of two hundred thousand students but less than five hundred\nthousand students shall receive a base grant of one hundred twenty-three\nthousand dollars; and\n  d. Each school library system with a public and nonpublic school\nenrollment of more than five hundred thousand students shall receive a\nbase grant of eight hundred ninety-seven thousand dollars.\n  e. In addition to the base grant provided in paragraph a, b, c or d of\nthis subdivision, each school library system shall receive annually:\n  (1) twenty-nine cents per student enrolled in the public and nonpublic\nschools located within such system, and\n  (2) five hundred dollars per public school district located within\nsuch system, and a minimum of four thousand three hundred dollars per\nsystem located within a board of cooperative educational services area,\nor five thousand dollars per city school district of a city with a\npopulation of one hundred twenty-five thousand inhabitants or more, and\n  (3) two dollars and forty-five cents per square mile of the school\nlibrary system.\n  f. In addition to any other sum provided in this subdivision, any\nschool library system formed through an act of merger since January\nfirst, nineteen hundred eighty-four shall receive fifty thousand dollars\nannually for each approved act of merger, provided, however, that any\nschool library system formed through an act of merger on or after April\nfirst, two thousand eight shall receive ninety thousand dollars annually\nfor each approved act of merger.\n  g. In addition to any other sum provided in this subdivision, each\nschool library system shall be eligible to receive annually an\nautomation grant amounting to ten percent of the total aid produced for\nthat system by adding the base grant provided by paragraph a, b, c or d\nof this subdivision to the additional aid provided by paragraphs e and f\nof this subdivision.\n  2. Before a school library system shall be entitled to receive\noperating funds, such system shall submit a plan of library service to\nthe commissioner for approval. The commissioner shall establish\nstandards of service for school library systems by regulation. Such\nregulations shall contain standards relating to: system staffing; union\ncatalog and data-base development; interlibrary loan; communications and\ndelivery; governance and advisory committees; membership criteria and\nthe means of relating district library resources and programs to those\nof the system; non-public school participation; and procedures for\nsubmission and approval of plans and certification of membership.\n  3. The moneys made available pursuant to this section shall be\ndistributed to each school library system whose plan of service has been\napproved under the provisions of subdivision two of this section.\n  4. Each school library system receiving state aid pursuant to this\nsection shall furnish such information regarding its library service as\nthe commissioner may from time to time require to determine whether it\nis operating in accordance with its plan and the standards of service\nthe commissioner has established. The commissioner may at any time after\naffording notice and an opportunity to be heard, revoke approval of a\nplan of library service if the commissioner finds that the school\nlibrary system no longer conforms to its approved plan, the provisions\nof this section or the regulations promulgated by the commissioner\nhereunder; or, in the case of provisional approval, if such school\nlibrary system no longer conforms to the agreement, plans or conditions\nupon which such provisional approval was based. In such case a school\nlibrary system shall not thereafter be entitled to state aid pursuant to\nthis section unless and until its plan of library service is again\napproved by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>