<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-285"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-285"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="285"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-285/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-285/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-285/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-285/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_285">
        <num>285</num>
        <heading>State aid for cooperation with correctional facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 285. State aid for cooperation with correctional facilities. 1. Each\npublic library system operating under an approved plan of service which\nhas a state correctional facility or facilities within its area of\nservice shall be awarded an annual grant of nine dollars twenty-five\ncents per capita for the incarcerated individual population of such\nfacility or facilities to make available to the incarcerated individual\npopulation of such facility or facilities, in direct coordination with\nthe correctional facilities libraries, the library resources of such\nsystem. The commissioner shall adopt any regulations necessary to carry\nout the purposes and provisions of this subdivision.\n  2. The commissioner is authorized to expend up to one hundred\nseventy-five thousand dollars annually to provide grants to public\nlibrary systems operating under an approved plan of service for\nprovision of services to county jail facilities. Such formula grants\nshall assist the library system in making available to the incarcerated\nindividual population of such facility or facilities the library\nresources of such system. Such grants shall be available to each public\nlibrary system in such manner as to insure that the ratio of the amount\neach system is eligible to receive equals the ratio of the number of\nincarcerated individuals served by the county jail facility to the total\nnumber of incarcerated individuals served by county jail facilities in\nthe state as of July first of the year preceding the calendar year in\nwhich the state aid to public library systems is to be paid.\nIncarcerated individual populations shall be certified by the New York\nstate commission of correction. The commissioner shall adopt any\nregulations necessary to carry out the purposes and provisions of this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>