<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2857"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2857"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2857"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2857/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2857/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2857/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-2857/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2857">
        <num>2857</num>
        <heading>Notice; review and assessment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a charter school report card, which shall include measures of the\ncomparative academic and fiscal performance of the school, as prescribed\nby the commissioner in regulations adopted for such purpose. Such\nmeasures shall include, but not be limited to, graduation rates, dropout\nrates, performance of students on standardized tests, college entry\nrates, total spending per pupil and administrative spending per pupil.\nSuch measures shall be presented in a format that is easily comparable\nto similar public schools. In addition, the charter school shall ensure\nthat such information is easily accessible to the community including\nmaking it publicly available by transmitting it to local newspapers of\ngeneral circulation and making it available for distribution at board of\ntrustee meetings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>discussion of the progress made towards achievement of the goals\nset forth in the charter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a certified financial statement setting forth, by appropriate\ncategories, the revenues and expenditures for the preceding school year,\nincluding a copy of the most recent independent fiscal audit of the\nschool and any audit conducted by the comptroller of the state of New\nYork.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>efforts taken by the charter school in the existing school year,\nand a plan for efforts to be taken in the succeeding school year, to\nmeet or exceed enrollment and retention targets set by the board of\nregents or the board of trustees of the state university of New York, as\napplicable, of students with disabilities, English language learners,\nand students who are eligible applicants for the free and reduced price\nlunch program established pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four\nof section twenty-eight hundred fifty-one of this article.\n  3. The board of regents shall report annually to the governor, the\ntemporary president of the senate, and the speaker of the assembly the\nfollowing information:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The number, distribution, and a brief description of new charter\nschools established during the preceding year;\n  (a-1) A list including the number of charter schools closed during the\npreceding year, and a brief description of the reasons therefor\nincluding, but not limited to, non-renewal of the charter or revocation\nof the charter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department's assessment of the current and projected\nprogrammatic and fiscal impact of charter schools on the delivery of\nservices by school districts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The academic progress of students attending charter schools, as\nmeasured against comparable public and nonpublic schools with similar\nstudent population characteristics wherever practicable;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A list of all actions taken by a charter entity on charter\napplication and the rationale for the renewal or revocation of any\ncharters; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2857__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any other information regarding charter schools that the board of\nregents deems necessary.\n  The format for this annual report shall be developed in consultation\nwith representatives of school districts and charter school officials.\n  4. The board of regents shall review the educational effectiveness of\nthe charter school approach authorized by this article and the effect of\ncharter schools on the public and nonpublic school systems. Not later\nthan December thirty-first, two thousand three, the board of regents\nshall report to the governor, the temporary president of the senate, the\nspeaker of the assembly and the board of regents with recommendations to\nmodify, expand, or terminate that approach. Such report shall include,\nfor each charter school, a copy of the school's mission statement,\nattendance statistics and dropout rates, student performance on\nstandardized assessment tests, projections of financial stability, and,\nwherever practicable, comparisons to other public schools.\n  5. The board of regents shall on an annual basis review and make\navailable to school districts best educational practices employed by\ncharter schools.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>