<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3007"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3007"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3007"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3007">
        <num>3007</num>
        <heading>Endorsement of foreign certificates and diplomas</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3007. Endorsement of foreign certificates and diplomas. The\ncommissioner of education may in his discretion endorse:\n  1. A diploma issued by a normal school or teachers college of another\nstate.\n  2. A certificate issued by the chief educational officer or state\nboard of another state.\n  Such endorsement confers on the holder of such diploma or certificate\nthe privileges conferred by law on the holder of the diploma of a state\nteachers college or state college for teachers or state certificate\nissued in this state. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the\ncommissioner shall require that any person seeking endorsement of a\nforeign certificate or diploma, on or after January first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-one, shall have completed two hours of coursework or\ntraining regarding the identification and reporting of child abuse and\nmaltreatment. The coursework or training shall be obtained from an\ninstitution or provider which has been approved by the department to\nprovide such course work or training. The coursework or training shall\ninclude information regarding the physical and behavioral indicators of\nchild abuse and maltreatment and the statutory reporting requirements\nset out in sections four hundred thirteen through four hundred twenty of\nthe social services law, including but not limited to, when and how a\nreport must be made, what other actions the reporter is mandated or\nauthorized to take, the legal protections afforded reporters, and the\nconsequences for failing to report. Each applicant shall provide the\ndepartment with documentation showing that he or she has completed the\nrequired training.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>