<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3012-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3012-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3012_D">
        <num>3012-D</num>
        <heading>Annual teacher and principal evaluations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3012_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>another state; (ii) an institution of higher education; or\n(iii) a commercial or not-for-profit entity, provided that such entity\nmust be objective and may not have a conflict of interest or appearance\nof a conflict of interest; such definition may include tests or\nassessments that have been previously designed or acquired by local\ndistricts, but only if the state education department significantly\nmodifies growth targets or scoring bands for such tests or assessments\nor otherwise adapts the test or assessment to the state education\ndepartment's requirements.\n  3. Ratings. The annual evaluations conducted pursuant to this section\nshall rate teacher and principal effectiveness using the following\ncategories: highly effective or "H", effective or "E", developing or "D"\nand ineffective or "I".\n  4. Categories. The annual evaluation system shall consist of multiple\nmeasures in two categories: student performance and teacher\nobservations.\n  a. Student performance category. Such category shall have at least one\nsubcomponent and an optional second subcomponent as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_D__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the first subcomponent, a teacher shall have a student\nlearning objective (SLO) consistent with a goal-setting process\ndetermined or developed by the commissioner, that results in a student\ngrowth score; provided that, for any teacher whose course ends in a\nstate-created or administered assessment, such assessment may be used as\nthe underlying assessment for such SLO;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_D__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the optional second subcomponent, a district may locally\nselect a second measure in accordance with this subparagraph. Such\nsecond measure shall apply in a consistent manner, to the extent\npracticable, across the district and be either: (A) based on a\nstate-created or administered test, or (B) based on a state-designed\nsupplemental assessment. The optional second subcomponent shall provide\noptions for multiple assessment measures that are aligned to existing\nclassroom and school best practices and take into consideration the\nrecommendations in the testing reduction report as required by section\none of subpart F of part EE of chapter fifty-six of the laws of two\nthousand fifteen which added this section regarding the reduction of\nunnecessary additional testing.\n  The commissioner shall determine the weights and scoring ranges for\nthe subcomponent or subcomponents of the student performance category\nthat shall result in a combined category rating. The commissioner shall...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_D__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a subcomponent\nbased on classroom observations conducted by a principal or other\ntrained administrator and must also include</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3012_D__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a subcomponent based on\nclassroom observations by an impartial independent trained evaluator or\nevaluators selected by the district. An independent trained evaluator\nmay be employed within the school district, but not the same school\nbuilding, as the teacher being evaluated. Such category may also include\na subcomponent based on classroom observations conducted by a trained\npeer teacher rated effective or highly effective from the same school or\nfrom another school in the district.\n  The commissioner shall determine the weights, and/or weighting options\nand scoring ranges for the subcomponents of the observations category\nthat result in a combined category rating. The commissioner shall also\ndetermine the minimum number of observations to be conducted annually,\nincluding frequency and duration, and any parameters therefor. The\ncommissioner shall set such weights and scores consistent with the terms\ncontained herein.\n  5. Rating determination. The overall rating determina...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>