<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3015"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3015"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3015"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3015/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3015/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3015/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3015/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3015">
        <num>3015</num>
        <heading>Teacher's salary when payable</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3015. Teacher's salary when payable.  1. In school districts\nemploying fewer than eight teachers, the salary of any teacher so\nemployed shall be due and payable at least as often as once each\ncalendar month of the term of employment.\n  2. In school districts employing eight or more teachers, the salary of\na teacher employed for a full school year shall be due and payable\nwithin such school year in not less than ten installments.  If a teacher\nis employed in any such district after July first in any school year,\nthe amount of the salary that the school authorities agree at the time\nof employment to pay such teacher for the balance of that school year\nshall be due and payable within the school year at least as often as\nonce each calendar month that he is so employed.  Nothing contained in\nthis subdivision shall be construed to alter the provisions of sections\ntwenty-five hundred nine, twenty-five hundred seventy-three, three\nthousand twelve, and three thousand thirteen of this chapter.\n  3. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to authorize\npayment in advance of rendering service to the school district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>