<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3030"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3030"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3030"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3030/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3030/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3030/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3030/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3030">
        <num>3030</num>
        <heading>Interstate agreement on qualifications of educational personnel</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3030__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Its duration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3030__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The criteria to be applied by an originating state in qualifying\neducational personnel for acceptance by a receiving state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3030__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such waivers, substitutions, and conditional acceptances as shall\naid the practical effectuation of the contract without sacrifice of\nbasic educational standards.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3030__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any other necessary matters.\n  3. No contract made pursuant to this agreement shall be for a term\nlonger than five years but any such contract may be renewed for like or\nlesser periods.\n  4. Any contract dealing with acceptance of educational personnel on\nthe basis of their having completed an educational program shall specify\nthe earliest date or dates on which originating state approval of the\nprogram or programs involved can have occurred. No contract made\npursuant to this agreement shall require acceptance by a receiving state\nof any persons qualified because of successful completion of a program\nprior to January first, nineteen hundred fifty-four.\n  5. The certification or other acceptance of a person who has been\naccepted pursuant to the terms of a contract shall not be revoked or\notherwise impaired because the contract has expired or been terminated.\nHowever, any certificate or other qualifying document may be revoked or\nsuspended on any ground which would be sufficient for revocation or\nsuspension of a certificate or other qualifying document initially\ngranted or approved in the receiving state.\n  6. A contract committee composed of the designated state officials of\nthe contracting states or their representatives shall keep the contract\nunder continuous review, study means of improving its administration,\nand report no less frequently than once a year to the heads of the\nappropriate education agencies of the contracting states.\n                               Article IV\n                     Approved and Accepted Programs\n  1. Nothing in this Agreement shall be construed to repeal or otherwise\nmodify any law or regulation of a party State relating to the approval\nof programs of educational preparation having effect solely on the\nqualification of educational personnel within that State.\n  2. To the extent that contracts made pursuant to this Agreement deal\nwith the educational requirements for the proper qualification of\neducation...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>