<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3035"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3035"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3035"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3035/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3035/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3035/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3035/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3035">
        <num>3035</num>
        <heading>Duties of commissioner; submission of fingerprints</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3035__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Clearance. After receipt of a criminal history record from the\ndivision of criminal justice services and the federal bureau of\ninvestigation the commissioner shall promptly notify the appropriate\nschool district, charter school, board of cooperative educational\nservices, or nonpublic or private elementary or secondary school whether\nthe prospective employee to which such report relates is cleared for\nemployment based upon his or her criminal history. All determinations to\ngrant or deny clearance for employment pursuant to this paragraph shall\nbe performed in accordance with subdivision sixteen of section two\nhundred ninety-six of the executive law and article twenty-three-A of\nthe correction law. When the commissioner denies a prospective employee\nclearance for employment, such prospective employee shall be afforded\nnotice and the right to be heard and offer proof in opposition to such\ndetermination in accordance with the regulations of the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3035__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conditional clearance. When the commissioner receives a request\nfor a determination on the conditional clearance of a prospective\nemployee, the commissioner, after receipt of a criminal history record\nfrom the division of criminal justice services, shall promptly notify\nthe prospective employee and the appropriate school district, charter\nschool, board of cooperative educational services, or nonpublic or\nprivate elementary or secondary school that the prospective employee to\nwhich such report relates is conditionally cleared for employment based\nupon his or her criminal history or that more time is needed to make the\ndetermination. If the commissioner determines that more time is needed,\nthe notification shall include a good faith estimate of the amount of\nadditional time needed. Such notification shall be made within fifteen\nbusiness days after the commissioner receives the prospective employee's\nfingerprints. All determinations to grant or deny conditional clearance\nfor employment pursuant to this paragraph shall be performed in\naccordance with subdivision sixteen of section two hundred ninety-six of\nthe executive law and article twenty-three-A of the correction law.\n  3-a. Upon request from a prospective employee who has been cleared by\nthe commissioner for employment and/or certification, the commissioner\nshall have the authority to forward a copy of such criminal history\nrecord to the city school district of the city of New York by the most\nexpeditious means available. Furthermore, upon notification that such\nprospective employee is employed by the city school district of the city\nof New York, the division of criminal justice services shall have the\nauthority to provide subsequent criminal history notifications directly\nto the city school district of the city of New York. Upon request from a\nprospective employee who has been cleared for licensure and/or\nemployment by the city school district of the city of New York, such\nschool distr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3035__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the fees associated\nwith an employee participating in a public assistance employment\nprogram, pursuant to title nine-B of article five of the social services\nlaw, or receiving employment services through the federal temporary\nassistance for needy families block grant pursuant to appropriations to\nthe office of temporary disability assistance, shall be paid by the\nsocial services district making such employment placement or assignment\nand the cost of such fees, if not subject to full reimbursement under\nsuch federal block grant, shall be deemed to be an employment services\nadministrative expense. In no event shall such a participant described\nherein be required to personally pay any fee imposed by the division of\ncriminal justice services or the federal bureau of investigation or any\nother fee for the purpose of conducting a criminal history records\nsearch; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3035__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any prospective employee, including, notwithstanding any\nprovision of law to the contrary, a prospective employee applying for a\nposition in a school district within a city with a population of one\nmillion or more, may submit a request to a governing body of a school\ndistrict, on a form prescribed by the commissioner, that the fees\nimposed for conducting a criminal history records check be waived. Such\ngoverning body may grant such a request if such governing body\ndetermines that payment of such a fee would impose an unreasonable\nfinancial hardship on the applicant or his or her family and, upon such\ndetermination, the governing body shall pay such fee on behalf of the\nprospective employee to the appropriate authority.\n  5. The commissioner and the division of criminal justice services\nshall enter into an agreement for the purposes of implementing the\nprovisions of this section.\n  6. Nothing in this section shall be construed or interpreted to alter\nor in any way diminish the integrity of collective bargaining agreements\nnegotiated between an employer and any certified or authorized\ncollective bargaining agent, with respect to payment of fees for\ncriminal history records searches, nor to diminish any rights pursuant\nto such agreements.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>