<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="307"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_307">
        <num>307</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of real property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 307.  Acquisition of real property.  1.  The commissioner of\neducation, when an appropriation therefor has been made by the\nlegislature, may acquire any real property which he may deem necessary\nfor the purposes of a state educational institution by purchase or\npursuant to the provisions of the eminent domain procedure law the title\nto which shall be taken in the name of and be vested in the people of\nthe state of New York; provided, however, that no real property shall be\nso acquired by purchase unless the title thereto shall be approved by\nthe attorney general.\n  2.  Whenever real property is to be so acquired pursuant to the\nprovisions of the eminent domain procedure law, by appropriation, the\ncommissioner of education shall cause to be made by the state department\nof transportation an accurate acquisition map.  With respect to any real\nproperty or any easement to be so acquired for state university\npurposes, the state university trustees may cause the map, description\nand survey contemplated by this subdivision, and any changes,\nalterations or modifications in such map contemplated by subdivision\nfive of this section, to be made by the state department of\ntransportation or, with the approval of the director of the budget, by a\nlicensed professional engineer or a licensed land surveyor, and the\nstate commissioner of transportation and the state university trustees\nmay each authorize the state university construction fund to act as\nagent in making such map, description and survey.\n  3. On the approval of such map by the commissioner, the original\ntracing of such map shall be filed in the main office of the department\npursuant to the provisions of the eminent domain procedure law. With\nrespect to any real property or easement to be so acquired for state\nuniversity purposes, the original tracing of such map shall be filed in\nthe office of the state university trustees.\n  4. If the commissioner shall determine, prior to the filing of such\nmap in the office of the clerk or register of the county, that changes,\nalterations or modifications of such map as filed in the main office of\nthe department should be made, he or she shall, subject to the\nprovisions of article two of the eminent domain procedure law, if\napplicable, direct the preparation by the department of transportation\nof an amended map. On the approval of such amended map by the\ncommissioner, it shall be filed in the main office of the department and\nthe amended map shall thereupon in all respects and for all purposes\nsupersede the map previously filed. With respect to any real property or\nany easement to be so acquired for state university purposes, upon the\napproval of such amended map by the state university trustees, it shall\nbe filed in the office of the state university trustees and the amended\nmap shall thereupon in all respects and for all purposes supersede the\nmap previously filed.\n  5. If the commissioner shall determine, prior to the filing of a copy\nof such acquisition map in the office of the county clerk or register as\nprovided in section four hundred two of the eminent domain procedure\nlaw, that such map should be withdrawn, he or she may file a certificate\nof withdrawal in the offices of the department and of the department of\nlaw.  Upon the filing of such certificate of withdrawal, the map to\nwhich it refers shall be cancelled and all rights thereunder shall cease\nand determine.\n  6.  The commissioner shall deliver to the attorney general a copy of\nsuch acquisition map, whereupon it shall be the duty  of the attorney\ngeneral to advise and certify to the commissioner the names of the\nowners of the property, easements, interests or rights described in the\nsaid acquisition map, including the owners of any right, title or\ninterest therein, pursuant to the requirements of section four hundred\nthree of the eminent domain procedure law.\n  7.  If, at or after the vesting of title to such property in the\npeople of the state of New York, as provided in the eminent domain\nprocedure law, the commissioner of education shall deem it necessary to\ncause the removal of an owner or occupant from any real property so\nacquired, he may cause such owner or occupant to be removed therefrom by\nproceeding in accordance with section four hundred five of the eminent\ndomain procedure law.  The proceeding shall be brought in the name of\nthe commissioner of education as agent of the state and the attorney\ngeneral shall represent the petitioner in the proceedings.  No execution\nshall issue for costs, if any, awarded against the state or the\ncommissioner of education, but they shall be part of the costs of the\nacquisition of the real property and be paid in like manner.\nProceedings may be brought separately against one or more of the owners\nor occupants of any such property, or one proceeding may be brought\nagainst all or several of the owners or occupants of any or all such\nproperty within the territorial jurisdiction of the same court, justice\nor judge; a final judgment shall be made for immediate removal of\npersons defaulting in appearance or in answering, or withdrawing their\nanswers, if any, without awaiting the trial or decision of issues raised\nby contestants, if any.\n  8.  Upon making any agreement provided for in section three hundred\nfour of the eminent domain procedure law the commissioner of education\nor such trustees of the state university of New York, as the case may\nbe, shall deliver to the comptroller such agreement and a certificate\nstating the amount due such owner or owners thereunder on account of\nsuch appropriation of his or their property and the amount so fixed\nshall be paid out of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller\nfrom moneys appropriated for the acquisition of such real property, but\nnot until there shall have been filed with the comptroller a certificate\nof the attorney general showing the person or persons claiming the\namount so agreed upon to be legally entitled thereto.\n  9.  Application for reimbursement of incidental expenses as provided\nin section seven hundred two of the eminent domain procedure law shall\nbe made to the commissioner upon forms prescribed by him and shall be\naccompanied by such information and evidence as the commissioner may\nrequire.  Upon approval of such application, the commissioner shall\ndeliver a copy thereof to the comptroller together with a certificate\nstating the amount due thereof, and the amount so fixed shall be paid\nout of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from monies\nappropriated for the acquisition of property under this section.\n  10.  The commissioner of education and the trustees of the state\nuniversity of New York, with the approval of the director of the budget,\nshall establish and may from time to time amend rules and regulations\nauthorizing the payment of actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses of occupants of property acquired pursuant to this section; of\nactual direct losses of tangible personal property as a result of moving\nor discontinuing a business or farm operation, but not exceeding an\namount equal to the reasonable expenses that would have been required to\nrelocate such property, as determined by the commissioner of education\nand the trustees of the state university of New York; and actual\nreasonable expenses in searching for a replacement business or farm; or\nin hardship cases for the advance payment of such expenses and losses.\nFor the purposes of making payment of such expenses and losses only the\nterm "business" means any lawful activity conducted primarily for\nassisting in the purchase, sale, resale, manufacture, processing or\nmarketing of products, commodities, personal property or services by the\nerection and maintenance of an outdoor advertising display or displays,\nwhether or not such display or displays are located on the premises on\nwhich any of the above activities are conducted.  Such rules and\nregulations may further define the terms used in this subdivision.  In\nlieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving expenses, any such\ndisplaced owner or tenant of residential property may elect to accept a\nmoving expense allowance, plus a dislocation allowance, determined in\naccordance with a schedule prepared by the commissioner of education and\nthe trustees of the state university of New York and made a part of such\nrules and regulations.  In lieu of such actual reasonable and necessary\nmoving expenses, any such displaced owner or tenant of commercial\nproperty who relocates or discontinues his business or farm operation\nmay elect to accept a fixed relocation payment in an amount equal to the\naverage annual net earnings of the business or farm operation, except\nthat such payment shall be not less than two thousand five hundred\ndollars nor more than ten thousand dollars.  In the case of a business,\nno such fixed relocation payment shall be made unless the commissioner\nof education or, in the case of an acquisition, for the purposes of the\nstate university, the trustees of the state university of New York find\nand determine that the business cannot be relocated without a\nsubstantial loss of its existing patronage, and that the business is not\na part of a commercial enterprise having at least one other\nestablishment, which is not being acquired by the state or the United\nStates, which is engaged in the same or similar business.  In the case\nof a business which is to be discontinued but for which the findings and\ndeterminations set forth above cannot be made, the commissioner or the\ntrustees of the state university of New York may prepare an estimate of\nwhat the actual reasonable and necessary moving expenses, exclusive of\nany storage charges, would be if the business were to be relocated and\nenter into an agreed settlement with the owner of such business for an\namount not to exceed such est</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>