<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-309-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-309-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="309-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-309-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-309-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-309-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-309-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_309_A">
        <num>309-A</num>
        <heading>Twenty-first century schools program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_309_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the student\nachievement standards described pursuant to paragraph b of subdivision\none of this section represent high, internationally competitive\nstandards for student knowledge and skills, (ii) that the mechanisms for\nassessing student achievement pursuant to such paragraph b are fair,\nreliable and valid; and (iii) the plan is designed to provide all\nstudents with educational services of a quality at least as high as\nthose offered under existing practices, without regard to economic\nbackground, race, gender, ethnicity, disability or limited English\nproficiency;\n  b. the potential of the school plan for use as a model to be\nreplicated by other similarly situated schools and the probability of\nsuccess in substantially improving levels of achievement for all\nstudents, without regard to economic background, race, gender,\nethnicity, disability or limited English proficiency;\n  c. evidence and strength of support for the proposal among teachers,\nparents and staff;\n  d. use of nationally recognized school restructuring and improvement\nmodels and reliance upon research-based strategies for improving student\nachievement; and\n  e. changes in local policies to provide the school or schools with\nadditional enhanced flexibility.\n  The commissioner shall designate twenty-first century schools after\nconsultation with the twenty-first century schools committee established\npursuant to subdivision six of this section. The commissioner shall, to\nthe extent practicable, provide for designation of schools located in a\nmixture of urban, rural and suburban settings. The commissioner shall\ntake specific actions to encourage applications from schools located in\neconomically and socially distressed communities.\n  3. Exemption from regulation. A school designated as a twenty-first\ncentury school shall:\n  a. be exempt from complying with rules of the board and regulations of\nthe commissioner to the extent necessary to implement an approved\ntwenty-first centur...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_309_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>protect\nthe health, safety and civil rights of students and staff, (ii)\nimplement the requirements of federal law or regulation, (iii) provide\nfor teacher, staff and parent participation and involvement, maintenance\nof effort or equitable participation of students and staff in nonpublic\nschools, (iv) require the use of certified teachers, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_309_A__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pertain to\nattendance of pupils; further, nothing herein shall be construed to\nexempt a twenty-first century school or its governing district from\ncomplying with the provisions of titles two and four of this chapter,\nwith the requirement to offer students the opportunity to meet all the\nrequirements for and receive a regents high school diploma or with\nrequirements to reporting data necessary for the computation of state\naid.\n  On or by October first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, the commissioner\nshall promulgate and provide to the governor, the temporary president of\nthe senate and the speaker of the assembly a preliminary list of all\nrequirements from which twenty-first century schools shall be required\nto request specific exemption as provided in paragraph b of this\nsubdivision and with which twenty-first century schools shall be\nrequired to comply as provided in paragraph c of this subdivision. The\ncommissioner shall promulgate a final list of all such requirements on\nNovember first, nineteen hundred ninety-four. The commissioner shall\nrevise such list as needed and, in each case, shall provide a\npreliminary revised list to the governor, the temporary president of the\nsenate and the speaker of the assembly at least thirty days prior to\npromulgating a final revised list.\n  4. School evaluations and reports. Each school designated as a\ntwenty-first century school shall annually review its effectiveness in\nimproving student performance and enabling all students to achieve to\nhigh internationally competitive standards and shall report the results\nof this review to the commissioner by September first next succeeding\neach year of operation as a twenty-first century school. Prior to the\nstart of a school's third year of operation as a twenty-first century\nschool, the school and the commissioner shall jointly review the\nschool's performance to identify areas in need of improvement and to\ndevelop revisions to the school's twenty-first centu...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>