<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-316"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-316"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="316"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-316/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-316/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-316/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-316/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_316">
        <num>316</num>
        <heading>Teacher resource and computer training centers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_316__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a school district with a teacher population of one thousand or\nmore;\n  (ii) a school district with a teacher population of five hundred or\nmore but less than one thousand;\n  (iii) a school district with a teacher population of less than five\nhundred;\n  (iv) a board of cooperative educational services; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_316__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a consortium of two or more school districts and/or boards of\ncooperative educational services.\n  3. Each such application shall be reviewed by the state professional\nstandards and practices board for teaching. The board shall in each\ninstance recommend to the commissioner action, as appropriate, including\nspecific reasons when it is negative. Any school district, board of\ncooperative educational services or consortium whose original\napplication is rejected may resubmit a revised application for further\nreview. Notwithstanding any other provision to the contrary, an\napplication to continue a teacher resource center which was in operation\nprior to the nineteen hundred eighty-four--nineteen hundred eighty-five\nschool year shall be deemed automatically approved.\n  4. The commissioner shall establish criteria and standards by which\napplications shall be evaluated which shall include provisions for\nfurnishing technical assistance and information provided by the\ndepartment through the facilities of the proposed teacher resource\ncenter, provided, however, that such criteria and standards shall be\nconsistent with federal regulations which were applicable to teacher\nresource centers in operation during the nineteen hundred eighty-two\ncalendar year.\n  5. Any school district, board of cooperative educational services or\nconsortium having an application approved under this section may\ncollaborate, consult and contract with an approved institution of higher\neducation in New York state to carry out activities under or provide\ntechnical assistance in connection with such application. Each\napplication shall be reviewed by the professional practices subcommittee\nof the state professional standards and practices board for teaching.\n  6. Each teacher resource and computer training center shall be\noperated by a board, the majority of which shall be composed of\nelementary and secondary school teachers representative of teachers\nserved by the teacher resourc...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>