<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3206"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3206">
        <num>3206</num>
        <heading>Attendance of minors upon part time instruction</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3206. Attendance of minors upon part time instruction.  1. The board\nof education of a city or district shall have power to require each\nemployed minor from sixteen to seventeen years of age to attend upon\npart time instruction in accordance with the provisions of this section.\n  2. A minor who is a graduate of a four-year high school course of\nstudy shall not be required to attend upon part time instruction.\n  3. The attendance of an employed minor required to attend upon part\ntime instruction by a board of education in accordance with the\nprovisions of this section shall be for not less than four, nor more\nthan eight hours per week, and on such day or days of the week as the\nschool authorities may determine.\n  4. An employed minor, while temporarily unemployed, or a minor\nattending part time school under the provisions of subdivision two,\nparagraph b, of section thirty-two hundred five, required to attend part\ntime instruction by a board of education in accordance with the\nprovisions of this section, shall attend upon part time instruction for\nnot less than twenty hours a week. An employed minor shall be deemed to\nbe temporarily unemployed until he reenters lawful employment or attends\nupon full time day instruction.\n  5. The absence of an employed minor during a rush season may be\npermitted by the school authorities on condition that the minor attend a\ngreater number of hours per week thereafter until the absence is made\nup, and provided that the minor's employer is a party to such an\nagreement.\n  6. An absence due to unlawful cause may be required to be made up by\nattendance in excess of the number of hours per week otherwise required.\n  7. The school authorities of a city or district shall have power after\na hearing to establish a half-time system or program of employment and\nrequired attendance at part time schools for minors who are included by\nthe provisions of this section.\n  8. Each minor above the age of sixteen years and under the age of\neighteen years, who is not in regular full-time day attendance at a\npublic, private or parochial school or who is regularly and lawfully\nemployed in some occupation or service, unless such minor has completed\na four year secondary course of instruction approved by the regents of\nthe university, shall attend a part-time school or class in the city or\ndistrict in which such minor resides or may be employed, provided the\nboard of education of such city or district has enacted appropriate\nrules and regulations requiring attendance at such part-time schools\nunder the provisions of section forty-six hundred one. Such attendance\nshall be subject to the provisions of article ninety-three of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>