<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3214"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3214"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3214"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3214">
        <num>3214</num>
        <heading>Student placement, suspensions and transfers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"firearm" shall mean a firearm as defined in subsection a of\nsection nine hundred twenty-one of title eighteen of the United States\nCode; and\n  (ii) "weapon" shall be as defined in paragraph 2 of subsection g of\nsection nine hundred thirty of title eighteen of the United States Code.\n  e. Procedure after suspension. Where a pupil has been suspended\npursuant to this subdivision and said pupil is of compulsory attendance\nage, immediate steps shall be taken for his or her attendance upon\ninstruction elsewhere or for supervision or detention of said pupil\npursuant to the provisions of article seven of the family court act.\nWhere a pupil has been suspended for cause, the suspension may be\nrevoked by the board of education whenever it appears to be for the best\ninterest of the school and the pupil to do so. The board of education\nmay also condition a student's early return to school and suspension\nrevocation on the pupil's voluntary participation in counseling or\nspecialized classes, including anger management or dispute resolution,\nwhere applicable.\n  f. Whenever the term "board of education or superintendent of schools"\nis used in this subdivision, it shall be deemed to include community\nboards of education and community superintendents governing community\ndistricts in accordance with the provisions of article fifty-two-A of\nthis chapter.\n  * g. Discipline of students with disabilities and students presumed to\nhave a disability for discipline purposes.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of this subdivision to the contrary, a student with a\ndisability as such term is defined in section forty-four hundred one of\nthis chapter and a student presumed to have a disability for discipline\npurposes, may be suspended or removed from his or her current\neducational placement for violation of school rules only in accordance\nwith the procedures established in this section, the regulations of the\ncommissioner implementing this paragraph, and subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nfourteen hundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States code and\nthe federal regulations implementing such statute, as such federal law\nand regulations are from time to time amended. Nothing in this paragraph\nshall be construed to confer greater rights on such students than are\nconferred under applicable federal law and regulations, or to limit the\nability of a school district to change the educational placement of a\nstudent with a disability in accordance with the procedures in article\neighty-nine of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this paragraph:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a "student presumed to have a disability for discipline purposes"\nshall mean a student who the school district is deemed to have knowledge\nwas a student with a disability before the behavior that precipitated\ndisciplinary action under the criteria in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section\nfourteen hundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States code and\nthe federal regulations implementing such statute; and\n  (ii) a "manifestation team" means a representative of the school\ndistrict, the parent or person in parental relation, and relevant\nmembers of the committee on special education, as determined by the\nparent or person in parental relation and the district.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In applying the federal law consistent with this section:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the event of a conflict between the procedures established in\nthis section and those established in subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen\nhundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States code and the\nfederal regulations implementing such statute, such federal statute and\nregulations shall govern.\n  (ii) the trustees or board of education of any school district, a\ndistrict superintendent of schools or a building principal shall have\nauthority to order the placement of a student with a disability into an\nappropriate interim alternative educational setting, another setting or\nsuspension for a period not to exceed five consecutive school days where\nsuch student is suspended pursuant to this subdivision and, except as\notherwise provided in clause (vi) of this subparagraph, the suspension\ndoes not result in a change in placement under federal law.\n  (iii) the superintendent of schools of a school district, either\ndirectly or upon recommendation of a hearing officer designated pursuant\nto paragraph c of this subdivision, may order the placement of a student\nwith a disability into an interim alternative educational setting,\nanother setting or suspension for up to ten consecutive school days,\ninclusive of any period in which the student is placed in an appropriate\ninterim alternative educational setting, another setting or suspension\npursuant to clause (ii) of this subparagraph for the behavior, where the\nsuperintendent determines in accordance with the procedures set forth in\nthis subdivision that the student has engaged in behavior that warrants\na suspension, and, except as otherwise provided in clause (vi) of this\nsubparagraph, the suspension does not result in a change in placement\nunder federal law.\n  (iv) the superintendent of schools of a school district, either\ndirectly or upon recommendation of a hearing officer designated pursuant\nto paragraph c of this subdivision, may order the change in placement of\na student with a disability to an interim alternative educational\nsetting for up to forty-five school days under the circumstances\nspecified in sub...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(G) of section fourteen hundred fifteen of\ntitle twenty of the United States code and the federal regulations\nimplementing such statute or a longer period where authorized by federal\nlaw under the circumstances specified in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(C) of section\nfourteen hundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States code and\nthe federal regulations implementing such statute, but in neither case\nshall such period exceed the period of suspension ordered by a\nsuperintendent in accordance with this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the terms "day," "business day," and "school day" shall be as\ndefined in section 300.11 of title thirty-four of the code of federal\nregulations.\n  (vi) notwithstanding any other provision of this subdivision to the\ncontrary, upon a determination by a manifestation team that the behavior\nof a student with a disability was not a manifestation of the student's\ndisability, such student may be disciplined pursuant to this section in\nthe same manner and for the same duration as a nondisabled student,\nexcept that such student shall continue to receive services to the\nextent required under federal law and regulations, and such services may\nbe provided in an interim alternative educational setting.\n  (vii) an impartial hearing officer appointed pursuant to subdivision\none of section forty-four hundred four of this chapter may order a\nchange in placement of a student with a disability to an appropriate\ninterim alternative educational setting for not more than forty-five\nschool days under the circumstances specified in subsections</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section fourteen hundred fifteen of title twenty of the United\nStates code and the federal regulations implementing such statutes,\nprovided that such procedure may be repeated, as necessary.\n  (viii) nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the\nsuspension or removal of a student with a disability from his or her\ncurrent educational placement for violation of school rules following a\ndetermination by a manifestation team that the behavior is a\nmanifestation of the student's disability, except as authorized under\nfederal law and regulations.\n  (ix) the commissioner shall implement this paragraph by adopting\nregulations which coordinate the procedures required for discipline of\nstudents with disabilities, and students presumed to have a disability\nfor discipline purposes, pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen\nhundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States code and the\nfederal regulations implementing such statute, with the general\nprocedures for student discipline under this section.\n  * NB Effective until June 30, 2027\n  * g. Discipline of students with disabilities and students presumed to\nhave a disability for discipline purposes.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of this subdivision to the contrary, a student with a\ndisability as such term is defined in section forty-four hundred one of\nthis chapter and a student presumed to have a disability for discipline\npurposes, may be suspended or removed from his or her current\neducational placement for violation of school rules only in accordance\nwith the procedures established in this section, the regulations of the\ncommissioner implementing this paragraph, and subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nfourteen hundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States code and\nthe federal regulations implementing such statute, as such federal law\nand regulations are from time to time amended. Nothing in this paragraph\nshall be construed to confer greater rights on such students than are\nconferred under applicable federal law and regulations, or to limit the\nability of a school district to change the educational placement of a\nstudent with a disability in accordance with the procedures in article\neighty-nine of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this paragraph, a "student presumed to have a\ndisability for discipline purposes" shall mean a student who the school\ndistrict is deemed to have knowledge was a student with a disability\nbefore the behavior that precipitated disciplinary action under the\ncriteria in subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of section fourteen hundred fifteen of\ntitle twenty of the United States code and the federal regulations\nimplementing such statute.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In applying the federal law consistent with this section:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the event of a conflict between the procedures established in\nthis section and those established in subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen\nhundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States code and the\nfederal regulations implementing such statute, such federal statute and\nregulations shall govern.\n  (ii) the trustees or board of education of any school district, a\ndistrict superintendent of schools or a building principal shall have\nauthority to order the placement of a student with a disability into an\nappropriate interim alternative educational setting, another setting or\nsuspension for a period not to exceed five consecutive school days where\nsuch student is suspended pursuant to this subdivision and, except as\notherwise provided in clause (vi) of this subparagraph, the suspension\ndoes not result in a change in placement under federal law.\n  (iii) the superintendent of schools of a school district, either\ndirectly or upon recommendation of a hearing officer designated pursuant\nto paragraph c of this subdivision, may order the placement of a student\nwith a disability into an interim alternative educational setting,\nanother setting or suspension for up to ten consecutive school days,\ninclusive of any period in which the student is placed in an appropriate\ninterim alternative educational placement, another setting or suspension\npursuant to clause (ii) of this subparagraph for the behavior, where the\nsuperintendent determines in accordance with the procedures set forth in\nthis subdivision that the student has engaged in behavior that warrants\na suspension, and, except as otherwise provided in clause (vi) of this\nsubparagraph, the suspension does not result in a change in placement\nunder federal law.\n  (iv) the superintendent of schools of a school district, either\ndirectly or upon recommendation of a hearing officer designated pursuant\nto paragraph c of this subdivision, may order the change in placement of\na student with a disability to an interim alternative educational\nsetting for up to forty-five days, but not to exceed the period of\nsuspension o...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of\nsection fourteen hundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States\ncode and the federal regulations implementing such statute.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the terms "day," "business day," and "school day" shall be as\ndefined in section 300.9 of title thirty-four of the code of federal\nregulations.\n  (vi) notwithstanding any other provision of this subdivision to the\ncontrary, upon a determination by the committee on special education\nthat the behavior of a student with a disability was not a manifestation\nof the student's disability, such student may be disciplined pursuant to\nthis section in the same manner as a nondisabled student, except that\nsuch student shall continue to receive services to the extent required\nunder federal law and regulations.\n  (vii) an impartial hearing officer appointed pursuant to subdivision\none of section forty-four hundred four of this chapter may order a\nchange in placement of a student with a disability to an appropriate\ninterim alternative educational setting for not more than forty-five\ndays under the circumstances specified in subsections</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3214__subsec_k__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nof section fourteen hundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States\ncode and the federal regulations implementing such statutes, provided\nthat such procedure may be repeated, as necessary.\n  (viii) nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the\nsuspension or removal of a student with a disability from his or her\ncurrent educational placement for violation of school rules following a\ndetermination by the committee on special education that the behavior is\na manifestation of the student's disability, except as authorized under\nfederal law and regulations.\n  (ix) the commissioner shall implement this paragraph by adopting\nregulations which coordinate the procedures required for discipline of\nstudents with disabilities, and students presumed to have a disability\nfor discipline purposes, pursuant to subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen\nhundred fifteen of title twenty of the United States code and the\nfederal regulations implementing such statute, with the general\nprocedures for student discipline under this section.\n  * NB Effective June 30, 2027\n  3-a. Teacher removal of a disruptive pupil. In addition, any teacher\nshall have the power and authority to remove a disruptive pupil, as\ndefined in subdivision two-a of this section, from such teacher's\nclassroom consistent with discipline measures contained in the code of\nconduct adopted by the board pursuant to section twenty-eight hundred\none of this chapter. The school authorities of any school district shall\nestablish policies and procedures to ensure the provision of continued\neducational programming and activities for students removed from the\nclassroom pursuant to this subdivision and provided further that nothing\nin this subdivision shall authorize the removal of a pupil in violation\nof any state or federal law or regulation. No pupil shall return to the\nclassroom until the principal makes a final determination pursuant to\nparagraph c of this subdivision, or the period of removal expires,\nwhichever is less.\n  a. Such teacher shall inform the pupil and the school principal of the\nreasons for the removal. If the teacher finds that the pupil's continued\npresence in the classroom does not pose a continuing danger to persons\nor property and does not present an ongoing threat of disruption to the\nacademic process, the teacher shall, prior to removing the student from\nthe classroom, provide the student with an explanation of the basis for\nthe removal and allow the pupil to informally present the pupil's\nversion of relevant events. In all other cases, the teacher shall\nprovide the pupil with an explanation of the basis for the removal and\nan informal opportunity to be heard within twenty-four hours of the\npupil's removal, provided that if such twenty-four hour period does not\nend on a school day, it sha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3214__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubparagraph three of paragraph g of subdivision three of this section.\n  c. The principal shall not set aside the discipline imposed by the\nteacher unless the principal finds that the charges against the pupil\nare not supported by substantial evidence or that the pupil's removal is\notherwise in violation of law or that the conduct warrants suspension\nfrom school pursuant to this section and a suspension will be imposed.\nThe principal's determination made pursuant to this paragraph shall be\nmade by the close of business on the school day next succeeding the end\nof the forty-eight hour period for an informal hearing contained in\nparagraph b of this subdivision.\n  d. The principal may, in his or her discretion, designate a school\ndistrict administrator, to carry out the functions required of the\nprincipal under this subdivision.\n  4. Expense. a. The expense attending the commitment and costs of\nmaintenance of any school delinquent shall be a charge against the city\nor district where he resides, if such city or district employs a\nsuperintendent of schools; otherwise it shall be a county charge.\n  b. The school authorities may institute proceedings before a court\nhaving jurisdiction to determine the liability of a person in parental\nrelation to contribute towards the maintenance of a school delinquent\nunder sixteen years of age ordered to attend upon instruction under\nconfinement. If the court shall find the person in parental relation\nable to contribute towards the maintenance of such a minor, it may issue\nan order fixing the amount to be paid weekly.\n  5. Involuntary transfers of pupils who have not been determined to be\na student with a disability or a student presumed to have a disability\nfor discipline purposes.\n  a. The board of education, board of trustees or sole trustee, the\nsuperintendent of schools, or district superintendent of schools may\ntransfer a pupil who has not been determined to be a student with a\ndisability as defi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>