<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3215-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3215-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3215-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3215-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3215-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3215-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3215-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3215_A">
        <num>3215-A</num>
        <heading>General certification provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3215-a. General certification provisions. 1. Certificating\nofficials.  Employment certificates or permits shall be issued by the\nchancellor in the city school district of the city of New York, and by\nthe superintendent of schools in other school districts, provided that\nthe district superintendent of schools may issue such certificates or\npermits for students attending classes operated by a board of\ncooperative educational services, and the principal of a nonpublic\nsecondary school may issue such certificates or permits for students\nattending such school. The chancellor in New York city, or elsewhere the\nsuperintendent of schools or district superintendent of schools may\ndesignate in writing the principal of the public school the minor\nattends or last attended or other public school official to act as\ncertificating official in his stead. During the months of July and\nAugust, and at other times in extraordinary circumstances and\nemergencies, one or more public school officials shall be designated in\nwriting by the chancellor in New York city and elsewhere by the\nsuperintendent or district superintendent to act as certificating\nofficials. The designation or authorization of certificating officials\nin public schools shall be subject to such limitations or standards as\nmay be prescribed by the chancellor in New York city and elsewhere by\nthe superintendent or district superintendent.\n  2. Revocation. Employment certificates or permits may be revoked for\ncause by the chancellor in New York city and elsewhere by the\nsuperintendent of schools or the district superintendent of schools\nwithin their respective jurisdictions, or, by a principal of a nonpublic\nsecondary school for a student attending such school. Where a student\nwho is required to attend school pursuant to section thirty-two hundred\nfive of this article has failed no less than four academic courses in\none semester, the chancellor in New York city, and elsewhere the\nsuperintendent of schools or the district superintendent of schools\nwithin their respective jurisdictions, or a principal of a nonpublic\nsecondary school may revoke such student's employment certificate or\npermit. In determining whether to revoke an employment certificate or\npermit, the chancellor in New York city, and elsewhere the\nsuperintendent of schools or the district superintendent of schools\nwithin their respective jurisdictions, or a principal of a nonpublic\nsecondary school, shall consider, (1) an evaluation of the student's\noverall academic performance and past academic record; (2) an\nexamination of the student's attendance record; (3) the economic need of\nthe student's family for the income provided by the student; (4) the\nwillingness of the student to participate in a cooperative education\nprogram, work study program, school to work program or any other\nstructured program which provides a student with an opportunity to earn\nincome while earning academic credit; (5) such other factors as the\naforementioned officials identify; and (6) any material submitted by the\nstudent.\n  Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, nothing in this section\nshall be construed to prevent any student from obtaining an employment\ncertificate or permit for the purpose of working during the months of\nJuly and August.\n  3. Approval of form and contents. The commissioner of education shall\nprescribe or approve the form and contents of all certificates, permits,\nphysical examination records, and schooling records required by part one\nof this article. The form of such certificates and permits shall also be\nsubject to the approval of the industrial commissioner.\n  * NB Effective until May 9, 2027\n  * ยง 3215-a. General certification provisions. 1. Certificating\nofficials.  Employment certificates or permits shall be issued by the\ncommissioner of labor. The commissioner of labor may share the status of\na student's certificate or permit with the chancellor in the city school\ndistrict of the city of New York and elsewhere with the superintendent\nof schools or the district superintendent of schools within their\nrespective jurisdictions or with a principal of a nonpublic secondary\nschool for a student attending such school.\n  2. Revocation. Employment certificates or permits may be revoked by\nthe commissioner of labor pursuant to section one hundred thirty-five of\nthe labor law.\n  Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, nothing in this section\nshall be construed to prevent any student from obtaining an employment\ncertificate or permit for the purpose of working during the months of\nJuly and August.\n  3. Approval of form and contents. The commissioner of labor, in\nconsultation with the commissioner of education, shall prescribe the\nform and contents of all certificates, permits, and schooling records\nrequired by part one of this article for employment purposes and\nconsistent with section one hundred thirty-five of the labor law. Any\nemployment certificate or permit issued pursuant to this part shall be\nissued electronically within the database created and maintained by the\ndepartment of labor, in consultation with and with support from the\ndepartment, pursuant to section one hundred thirty-five of the labor\nlaw.\n  * NB Effective May 9, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>