<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3224"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3224"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3224"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3224">
        <num>3224</num>
        <heading>Temporary services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3224. Temporary services. a. If an employer is engaged in a\nbusiness of assigning employees for temporary services at another\nestablishment, and the employer compensates the employee for such\nservices rendered the employer shall keep on file in his office the\nemployment certificate and shall cause to be delivered to each\nestablishment where the child will perform his services a true copy of\nsuch employment certificate.  Such delivery shall be deemed compliance\nwith sections thirty-two hundred sixteen and thirty-two hundred\ntwenty-three of this chapter.  The owner of each establishment to which\nthe child is assigned shall keep on file in his office such copy of the\nemployment certificate, which shall be deemed compliance with sections\nthirty-two hundred sixteen and thirty-two hundred twenty-three of this\nchapter, and shall return such copy to the employer at the conclusion of\nthe child's assignment.  Such employer shall note on the original\nemployment certificate the existence of each copy.\n  b. As used in this section, the term "establishment" includes a\nfactory, mercantile establishment, business office, restaurant, hotel\nand any other trade, business or service.\n  c. The commissioner of education may promulgate rules and regulations\nas he deems necessary to insure that employment under the provisions of\nthis section shall not be harmful or undesirable from the point of view\nof the welfare, development, or proper education of the child.\n  * NB Effective until May 9, 2027\n  * ยง 3224. Temporary services. a. If an employer is engaged in a\nbusiness of assigning employees for temporary services at another\nestablishment, and the employer compensates the employee for such\nservices rendered the employer shall keep on file physically in office\nor electronically and readily accessible the employment certificate and\nshall cause to be delivered to each establishment where the child will\nperform the services a true copy of such employment certificate. Such\ndelivery shall be deemed compliance with sections thirty-two hundred\nsixteen and thirty-two hundred twenty-three of this part and section one\nhundred thirty-five of the labor law. The owner of each establishment to\nwhich the child is assigned shall also retain a copy of the employment\ncertificate and shall return such copy to the employer at the conclusion\nof the child's assignment. Such employer shall note on the original\nemployment certificate the existence of each copy.\n  b. As used in this section, the term "establishment" includes a\nfactory, mercantile establishment, business office, restaurant, hotel\nand any other trade, business or service.\n  c. The commissioner of education may promulgate rules and regulations\nas they deem necessary to ensure that employment under the provisions of\nthis section shall not be harmful or undesirable from the point of view\nof the welfare, development, or proper education of the child.\n  * NB Effective May 9, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>