<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3242"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3242"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3242"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3242/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3242/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3242/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3242/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3242">
        <num>3242</num>
        <heading>School census in school districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3242. School census in school districts. The trustees or board of\neducation of every school district may cause a census to be taken of all\nchildren between birth and eighteen years of age, including all such\nfacts and information as are required in the census provided for in\nsection thirty-two hundred forty-one of this part. Such census shall be\nprepared biennially for children between ages five and eighteen who are\nentitled to attend the public schools without payment of tuition in\nduplicate in their respective school districts, and one copy thereof\nfiled with the teacher or principal and the other copy filed with the\ndistrict superintendent or superintendent on or before the fifteenth day\nof October. For pre-school students from birth to five years of age,\nsuch census may be prepared and filed biennially on or before the\nfifteenth day of October. Such census shall include the reports and\ninformation required from cities as provided in section thirty-two\nhundred forty-one of this part. All information regarding a student with\na disability under the age of twenty-one years shall be filed annually\nwith the superintendent of the board of cooperative educational services\nof which said district may be a part.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>