<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3301"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3301">
        <num>3301</num>
        <heading>Purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3301. Purpose. It is the purpose of this compact to remove barriers\nto educational success imposed on children of military families because\nof frequent moves and deployment of their parents by:\n  1. Facilitating the timely enrollment of children of military families\nand ensuring that they are not placed at a disadvantage due to\ndifficulty in the transfer of education records from the previous school\ndistrict or districts or variations in entrance/age requirements.\n  2. Facilitating the student placement process through which children\nof military families are not disadvantaged by variations in attendance\nrequirements, scheduling, sequencing, grading, course content or\nassessment.\n  3. Facilitating the qualification and eligibility for enrollment,\neducational programs, and participation in extracurricular academic,\nathletic, and social activities.\n  4. Facilitating the on-time graduation of children of military\nfamilies.\n  5. Providing for the promulgation and enforcement of administrative\nrules implementing the provisions of this compact.\n  6. Providing for the uniform collection and sharing of information\nbetween and among member states, schools and military families under\nthis compact.\n  7. Promoting coordination between this compact and other compacts\naffecting military children.\n  8. Promoting flexibility and cooperation between the educational\nsystem, parents and the student in order to achieve educational success\nfor the student.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>