<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3305"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3305">
        <num>3305</num>
        <heading>Placement and attendance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In compliance with the federal requirements of the individuals\nwith disabilities education act, 20 U.S.C.A. section 1400 et seq, the\nreceiving state shall initially provide comparable services to a student\nwith disabilities based on his or her current individualized education\nprogram; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In compliance with the requirements of section 504 of the\nrehabilitation act, 29 U.S.C.A. section 794, and with title II of the\nAmericans with disabilities act, 42 U.S.C.A. sections 12131-12165, the\nreceiving state shall make reasonable accommodations and modifications\nto address the needs of incoming students with disabilities, subject to\nan existing 504 or title II plan, to provide the student with equal\naccess to education. This does not preclude the school in the receiving\nstate from performing subsequent evaluations to ensure appropriate\nplacement of the student.\n  4. Local educational agency administrative officials shall have\nflexibility in waiving course or program prerequisites, or other\npreconditions for placement in courses or programs offered under the\njurisdiction of the local educational agency.\n  5. A student whose parent or legal guardian is an active duty member\nof the uniformed services, as defined by the compact, and has been\ncalled to duty for, is on leave from, or immediately returned from\ndeployment to a combat zone or combat support posting, shall be granted\nadditional excused absences at the discretion of the local educational\nagency superintendent to visit with his or her parent or legal guardian\nrelative to such leave or deployment of the parent or guardian.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>