<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3308"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3308"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3308"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3308/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3308/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3308/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3308/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3308">
        <num>3308</num>
        <heading>State coordination</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3308. State coordination.  1. Each member state shall, through the\ncreation of a state council or use of an existing body or board, provide\nfor the coordination among its agencies of government, local educational\nagencies and military installations concerning the state's participation\nin, and compliance with, this compact and interstate commission\nactivities. In New York, the state council shall include the\ncommissioner or his or her designee, the commissioner of the New York\nstate department of veterans' services or his or her designee, the\nadjutant general of the state of New York or his or her designee, a\nsuperintendent of a school district with a high concentration of\nmilitary children appointed by the commissioner, a district\nsuperintendent of schools of a board of cooperative educational services\nserving an area with a high concentration of military children appointed\nby the commissioner, a representative from a military installation\nappointed by the governor, a representative of military families\nappointed by the governor, a public member appointed by the governor and\none representative each appointed by the speaker of the assembly, the\ntemporary president of the senate and the governor.\n  2. The state council of each member state shall appoint or designate a\nmilitary family education liaison to assist military families and the\nstate in facilitating the implementation of this compact.\n  3. The compact commissioner responsible for the administration and\nmanagement of the state's participation in the compact shall be\nappointed by the governor or as otherwise determined by each member\nstate.\n  4. The compact commissioner and the military family education liaison\ndesignated herein shall be ex-officio members of the state council,\nunless either is already a full voting member of the state council.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>