<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3316"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3316"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3316"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3316/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3316/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3316/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3316/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3316">
        <num>3316</num>
        <heading>Withdrawal and dissolution</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3316. Withdrawal and dissolution. 1. Once effective, the compact\nshall continue in force and remain binding upon each and every member\nstate; provided that a member state may withdraw from the compact by\nspecifically repealing the statute, which enacted the compact into law.\n  2. Withdrawal from this compact shall be by the enactment of a statute\nrepealing the same, but shall not take effect until written notice of\nthe withdrawal has been given by the withdrawing state to the governor\nof each other member jurisdiction.\n  3. The withdrawing state shall immediately notify the chairperson of\nthe interstate commission in writing upon the introduction of\nlegislation repealing this compact in the withdrawing state. The\ninterstate commission shall notify the other member states of the\nwithdrawing state's intent to withdraw within sixty days of its receipt\nthereof.\n  4. The withdrawing state is responsible for all assessments,\nobligations and liabilities incurred through the effective date of\nwithdrawal, including obligations, the performance of which extend\nbeyond the effective date of withdrawal.\n  5. Reinstatement following withdrawal of a member state shall occur\nupon the withdrawing state reenacting the compact or upon such later\ndate as determined by the interstate commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>