<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-354"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-354"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="354"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_354">
        <num>354</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of state university trustees-planning functions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 354. Powers and duties of state university trustees-planning\nfunctions. 1. The state university trustees shall, once every four\nyears, formulate a long-range state university plan or general revision\nthereof and make recommendations to the board of regents and the\ngovernor for the organization, development, coordination and expansion\nof the state university and for the establishment of community colleges\nin areas suitable for and in need of such institutions, which plan and\nrecommendations shall include the following:\n  a. plans for new curricula;\n  b. plans for new facilities;\n  c. plans for change in policies with respect to student admissions;\n  d. projected student enrollments; and\n  e. comments upon its relationship to other colleges and universities,\npublic, independent and proprietary, within the state.\n  f. For informational purposes only, projection standards and overall\nexpenditure projections of capital and operating costs. Prior to\ntransmitting their long-range state university plan or general revision\nthereof to the board of regents and the governor the state university\ntrustees may, after giving due notice, conduct one or more hearings on\nsuch plan.\n  1-a. The state university trustees shall organize or cause to be\norganized at a university or college of the state university an annual\nconference on the role of the universities, colleges and other\nfacilities on the local economies, social conditions and quality of life\nof host cities, towns and villages. Such conference shall rotate amongst\nthe individual universities and colleges and shall include but not be\nlimited to:\n  a. a review of significant partnering between universities, colleges\nand other institutions of the state university with their host\ncommunities;\n  b. presentations utilizing the expertise of the state university on\ntypes of projects, programs and administrative actions that could\nsupport the state university's mission stated in subdivision e-1 of\nsection three hundred fifty-one of this article; and\n  c. roundtable discussions between state university trustees, officers\nand faculty with county, city, town and local officials, business and\ncivic leaders relating to the purposes of the annual conference.\n  Each sponsoring university or college shall prepare and distribute a\nreport on the annual conference.\n  2. During the calendar year nineteen hundred sixty-four and each\nfourth year thereafter the state university trustees shall transmit\ntheir proposed plan or general revision thereof to the board of regents\nand the governor on or before the first day of June in each such year.\nSuch plan shall be reviewed by the board of regents and shall be subject\nto approval by such board. As approved by the board of regents and\nincorporated into the regents plan or general revision thereof for the\ndevelopment of higher education in the state and, upon approval\nthereafter by the governor, such plan shall guide and determine the\ndevelopment of the state university and its community colleges until\nsuch plan is modified or revised in the manner provided herein.\n  3. By the first day of June in nineteen hundred seventy-four and every\nfourth year thereafter, the state university trustees shall report in\nwriting to the board of regents, to the governor and to the legislature\non the progress made in carrying out their responsibilities under such\nplan and their general recommendations with respect to public higher\neducation, including recommendations as to modifications of such plan\nwhich the trustees deem essential to meet the then current demands upon\npublic higher education. The state university trustees may also at any\nother time propose modifications which they then deem essential or\ndesirable with respect to such plan. They may, after giving due notice,\nconduct one or more hearings on such modifications and shall transmit\ntheir recommendations therefor to the board of regents and the governor.\nSuch modifications shall be subject to approval by the regents and\nthereafter by the governor in the same manner as such plan or general\nrevisions thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>