<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="355-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_355_C">
        <num>355-C</num>
        <heading>College opportunity to prepare for employment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 355-c. College opportunity to prepare for employment.  1. The state\nuniversity is authorized to enter into an agreement with the department\nof social services for the establishment of the college opportunity to\nprepare for employment (COPE) program for the development of a program\nof allowable activities and services for eligible participants in the\nfederal job opportunity and basic skills (JOBS) program.\n  2. The state university shall identify such funds as necessary,\nincluding any private funds provided for the purpose of supporting\nemployment and training services, to be used on a matching basis\nconsistent with federal requirements.\n  3. Services may include, but are not limited to, high school\nequivalency, basic education, job skills training, English-as-a-second\nlanguage, job readiness training, job placement services, case\nmanagement, career counseling and assessment, employability planning,\nsupportive services such as child care, and a youth demonstration\nactivity providing an integrated program of high school equivalency,\noccupational training, work experience, and job placement.\n  4. The state university shall submit an annual evaluation and report\non the college opportunity to prepare for employment program to the\ngovernor, the speaker of the assembly, the temporary president of the\nsenate, the chairman  of the assembly ways and means committee, the\nchairman of the senate finance committee, and the chair of the\nlegislative commission on skills development and career education no\nlater than October thirty-first following the program year ending June\nthirtieth. The evaluation and report shall include, at a minimum, a\ndescription of services provided, participant characteristics, data on\nmeasures of educational and job skills gains, job development and\nplacement, and retention.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>