<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="355"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-355/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_355">
        <num>355</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of trustees--administrative and fiscal functions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such regulations shall further provide that the payment of\ntuition and fees by any student in any state-operated institution of the\nstate university who is a member or the spouse or the dependent of a\nmember of the armed forces of the United States on full-time active duty\nand stationed in this state, whether or not a resident of the state,\nshall be paid at a rate or charge no greater than that imposed for\nstudents thereat who are residents of this state.\n  (ii) Such regulations shall further provide that the payment of\ntuition and fees by any student who is not a resident of New York state\nshall be paid at a rate or charge no greater than that imposed for\nstudents who are residents of the state if such student is enrolled in\nan institution or educational unit of the state university and is\nattending such institution or educational unit in accordance with the\nfederal GI bills and in compliance with all applicable eligibility\nrequirements thereof.\n  (iii) Such regulations shall further provide that the payment of\ntuition and fees by any student who is not a resident of New York state\nshall be paid at a rate or charge no greater than that imposed for\nstudents who are residents of this state if such student is enrolled in\nan institution or educational unit of the state university and is the\nspouse or the dependent of a member of the armed forces of the United\nStates on full-time active duty and not stationed in this state\nimmediately following being stationed therein.\n  (3-a) Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation, the state university trustees shall be\nauthorized to set a reduced rate of tuition and/or fees, or to waive\ntuition and/or fees entirely, for students participating in any dual or\nconcurrent enrollment program with no reduction in other state, local,\nor other support for such students earning college credit that such\nhigher education partner would otherwise be eligible to rec...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The trustees shall not impose a differential tuition charge\nbased upon need or income. Except as hereinafter provided, all students\nenrolled in programs leading to like degrees at state-operated\ninstitutions of the state university shall be charged a uniform rate of\ntuition except for differential tuition rates based on state residency.\nProvided, however, that the trustees may authorize the presidents of the\ncolleges of technology and the colleges of agriculture and technology to\nset differing rates of tuition for each of the colleges for students\nenrolled in degree-granting programs leading to an associate degree and\nnon-degree granting programs so long as such tuition rate does not\nexceed the tuition rate charged to students who are enrolled in like\ndegree programs or degree-granting undergraduate programs leading to a\nbaccalaureate degree at other state-operated institutions of the state\nuniversity of New York. Notwithstanding any other provision of this\nsubparagraph, ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Commencing with the two thousand eleven--two thousand twelve\nacademic year and ending in the two thousand fifteen--two thousand\nsixteen academic year the state university of New York board of trustees\nshall be empowered to increase the resident undergraduate rate of\ntuition by not more than three hundred dollars over the resident\nundergraduate rate of tuition adopted by the board of trustees in the\nprior academic year, provided however that commencing with the two\nthousand eleven--two thousand twelve academic year and ending in the two\nthousand sixteen--two thousand seventeen academic year if the annual\nresident undergraduate rate of tuition would exceed five thousand\ndollars, then a tuition credit for each eligible student, as determined\nand calculated by the New York state higher education services\ncorporation pursuant to section six hundred eighty-nine-a of this title,\nshall be applied toward the tuition charged for each semester, quarter\nor term of study. Tuition for each semester, quarter or term of study\nshall not be due for any student eligible to receive such tuition credit\nuntil the tuition credit is calculated and applied against the tuition\ncharged for the corresponding semester, quarter or term.\n  (ii) Commencing with the two thousand seventeen--two thousand eighteen\nacademic year and ending in the two thousand twenty--two thousand\ntwenty-one academic year the state university of New York board of\ntrustees shall be empowered to increase the resident undergraduate rate\nof tuition by not more than two hundred dollars over the resident\nundergraduate rate of tuition adopted by the board of trustees in the\nprior academic year, provided, however that if the annual resident\nundergraduate rate of tuition would exceed five thousand dollars, then a\ntuition credit for each eligible student, as determined and calculated\nby the New York state higher education services corporation pursuant to\nsection six hundred eighty-nine-a of this title,...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Beginning in state fiscal year two thousand seventeen--two\nthousand eighteen and ending in state fiscal year two thousand\ntwenty--two thousand twenty-one, the state shall appropriate and make\navailable general fund operating support, including fringe benefits, for\nthe state university in an amount not less than the amount appropriated\nand made available in the prior state fiscal year; provided, however,\nthat if the governor declares a fiscal emergency, and communicates such\nemergency to the temporary president of the senate and speaker of the\nassembly, state support for operating expenses at the state university\nand city university may be reduced in a manner proportionate to one\nanother, and the aforementioned provisions shall not apply; provided\nfurther, the state shall appropriate and make available general fund\nsupport to fully fund the tuition credit pursuant to subdivision two of\nsection six hundred sixty-nine-h of this title.\n  (vi) For the state university fiscal years commencing two thousand\neleven--two thousand twelve and ending two thousand fifteen--two\nthousand sixteen, each university center may set aside a portion of its\ntuition revenues derived from tuition increases to provide increased\nfinancial aid for New York state resident undergraduate students whose\nnet taxable income is eighty thousand dollars or more subject to the\napproval of a NY-SUNY 2020 proposal by the governor and the chancellor\nof the state university of New York. Nothing in this paragraph shall be\nconstrued as to authorize that students whose net taxable income is\neighty thousand dollars or more are eligible for tuition assistance\nprogram awards pursuant to section six hundred sixty-seven of this\nchapter.\n  * NB Effective until July 1, 2027\n  *</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The trustees shall not impose a differential tuition charge\nbased upon need or income. All students enrolled in programs leading to\nlike degrees at state-operated institutions of the state university\nshall be charged a uniform rate of tuition except for differential\ntuition rates based on state residency. Provided, however, that the\ntrustees may authorize the presidents of the colleges of technology and\nthe colleges of agriculture and technology to set differing rates of\ntuition for each of the colleges for students enrolled in\ndegree-granting programs leading to an associate degree and non-degree\ngranting programs so long as such tuition rate does not exceed the\ntuition rate charged to students who are enrolled in like degree\nprograms or degree-granting undergraduate programs leading to a\nbaccalaureate degree at other state-operated institutions of the state\nuniversity of New York.  Notwithstanding any other provision of this\nsubparagraph, the trustees may authorize the ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_v__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The trustees shall further provide standards for the granting of\nadvanced standing to veterans applying for college admissions at the\nstate university, who have successfully completed United States Armed\nForces Institute or other comparable course work.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_v__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where an undergraduate state-operated institution of the state\nuniversity is located adjacent to another institution of higher\neducation and students of such undergraduate state operated institution\nare, under arrangements made by the state university, taking a\nsubstantial portion of their courses at such other institution, the\nstate university trustees may permit the students of such undergraduate\nstate-operated institution, subject to such conditions or limitations as\nthey deem advisable, to participate in the extra-curricular activities\nand utilize services of such other institution if those privileges are\nextended by such other institution.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_v__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In formulating the curriculum of each state-operated institution\nin the state university for professional education in medicine there\nshall be required and included in such curriculum and in the plans and\nrecommendations of the state university trustees formulated and\ntransmitted in pursuance of the provisions of section three hundred\nfifty-four of this chapter, courses and facilities, which in the\njudgment of the trustees shall be best suited to encourage and to\nimplement the study and preparation, by students desiring the same, for\nthe family practice of medicine. Such courses and facilities shall\ninclude: the establishment and maintenance of a department of family\npractice under the direction of a qualified family practitioner, courses\nof study under the supervision of qualified family practitioners, a\nfamily care program of study and clinical experience, a program of\npreceptorships, and a program of internships or family practice\nresidencies in the hospital or hospita...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_v__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such regulations shall further provide that the payment of tuition\nand fees by any student who is not a resident of New York state, other\nthan a non-immigrant noncitizen within the meaning of paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_v__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of\nsubsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 1101 of title 8 of the United States Code,\nshall be paid at a rate or charge no greater than that imposed for\nstudents who are residents of the state if such student:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>attended an approved New York high school for two or more years,\ngraduated from an approved New York high school and applied for\nattendance at an institution or educational unit of the state university\nwithin five years of receiving a New York state high school diploma; or\n  (ii) attended an approved New York state program for general\nequivalency diploma exam preparation, received a general equivalency\ndiploma issued within New York state and applied for attendance at an\ninstitution or educational unit of the state university within five\nyears of receiving a general equivalency diploma issued within New York\nstate; or\n  (iii) was enrolled in an institution or educational unit of the state\nuniversity in the fall semester or quarter of the two thousand one--two\nthousand two academic year and was authorized by such institution or\neducational unit to pay tuition at the rate or charge imposed for\nstudents who are residents of the state.\n  A student without lawful immigration status shall also be required to\nfile an affidavit with such institution or educational unit stating that\nthe student has filed an application to legalize his or her immigration\nstatus, or will file such an application as soon as he or she is\neligible to do so.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The trustees shall review any proposed community college tuition\nincrease and the justification for such increase. The justification\nprovided by the community college for such increase shall include a\ndetailed analysis of ongoing operating costs, capital, debt service\nexpenditures, and all revenues.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such regulations shall further provide that any student who is\nnot a legal resident of New York state but is a United States citizen, a\npermanent lawful resident, an individual who is granted U or T\nnon-immigrant status pursuant to the Victims of Trafficking and Violence\nProtection Act of 2000, a person granted temporary protected status\npursuant to the Federal Immigration Act of 1990, an individual of a\nclass of refugees paroled by the attorney general of the United States\nunder his or her parole authority pertaining to the admission of\nnoncitizens to the United States, or an applicant without lawful\nimmigration status may have the payment of tuition and other fees and\ncharges reduced by state-aided programs, scholarships or other financial\nassistance awarded under the provisions of articles thirteen,\nthirteen-A, fourteen and fourteen-A of this chapter, provided that the\nstudent meets the requirements set forth in subparagraph (ii) of\nparagraph a or subparagraph (ii) of ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this subparagraph, "Team USA athlete" means\nany student athlete who meets the eligibility standards defined and\napproved by the United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee and by\nthe national governing body for the sport in which the athlete competes.\n  (ii) Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation and pursuant to an appropriation and\nfunding being made for such purpose, such regulations shall further\nprovide that the payment of tuition and fees by any student who is not a\nresident of New York state shall be paid at a rate or charge no greater\nthan that imposed for students who are residents of this state if such\nstudent is enrolled in an institution or educational unit of the state\nuniversity, is a Team USA athlete, and is training in New York State in\nan elite level program approved by the United States Olympic and\nParalympic Committee.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2026\n  * NB There are 2 sbpar</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>'s\n  *</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any law, rule or regulation to the contrary,\nsuch regulations shall provide for eligibility of admission for students\nwho have completed an online high school program which</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has in excess\nof ten thousands students per year nationally complete such program,\n(ii) is located within the United States, and (iii) is accredited in\naccordance with paragraph four of appendix three hundred two of the Job\nCorps Policy and Requirements Handbook (Guidelines for the Ongoing\nQuality Monitoring of Job Corps High School Diploma (HSD) Programs), as\namended from time to time;\n  * NB Effective March 5, 2026\n  * NB There are 2 sbpar</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>'s\n  i. To lease to alumni associations of institutions of the state\nuniversity a portion of the grounds occupied by any institution of the\nstate university, for the erection thereon of dormitories to be used by\nstudents in attendance at such institutions. The terms of any lease and\nthe character of the building to be erected shall be determined by the\nstate university trustees. Such lease, prior to its execution, shall be\nsubmitted to the attorney general for his approval as to its form,\ncontents and legal effect. Nothing contained in this paragraph shall\naffect the provisions of any lease heretofore executed by a board of\nvisitors of any state-operated institution pursuant to law. The state\nuniversity trustees may similarly enter into an agreement with an alumni\nassociation of an institution of the state university to furnish heat\nfrom a central heating plant to any dormitory erected by such alumni\nassociation. Any such dormitory shall not be subject to taxation for any...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of section sixteen hundred\neighty-q of the public authorities law. All rights, title and interest\nin and to any moneys paid to or upon the order of the state university\nof New York pursuant to any agreement by and between the dormitory\nauthority and the state university of New York entered into pursuant to\nsubdivision two of section sixteen hundred eighty-q of the public\nauthorities law or pursuant to any agreement entered into pursuant to\nparagraph j of subdivision two of section sixteen hundred eighty of the\npublic authorities law shall vest in the state university of New York\nand be the absolute property of the state university of New York, and\nthe dormitory authority shall no longer have any interest in such\nmoneys.\n  z. In connection with business/university partnerships in support of\nthe corporate purposes of the state university, to participate in joint\nand cooperative arrangements with businesses that have located in a\ntax-free NY area approved pursuant to article twenty-one of the economic\ndevelopment law provided such arrangements are consistent with the\napproved plan for such tax-free NY area.\n  2-a. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule, or regulation\nto the contrary, the state university trustees charter school committee,\nas a charter entity, are further authorized and empowered, to promulgate\nregulations with respect to governance, structure and operations of\ncharter schools for which they are the charter entity pursuant to\nsection twenty-eight hundred fifty-one of this chapter.\n  3. The state university trustees shall adopt and implement a patent\npolicy for research conducted in university facilities which is\nconsistent with the university's mission of education, scholarly\nresearch and public service. Such policy shall be designed to encourage\nresearch activities which produce new knowledge which is of benefit to\nthe public and which may result in the development of new products and\nprocess...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Amounts appropriated for the programs or purposes or for any item\nor items within such programs or purposes of any individual\nstate-operated institution and the statutory or contract colleges of the\nstate university, including state university central administration\nwithin the schedules of such units or for any individual hospital within\nthe schedule of hospitals of the state university from a particular fund\nor funds in a fiscal year may be interchanged between such programs or\npurposes of such unit or hospital of state university, or between items\nwithin the same program or purpose, or with other items appropriated\nfrom such fund not in the same program or purpose, but which are\ncontained in the state comptroller's classification of items as last\npromulgated pursuant to a certificate of allocation. Such certificate\nshall be submitted by such units to the board of trustees of the state\nuniversity. Such certificate shall be submitted by the board of trustees\nto the state ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Amounts appropriated to state-operated institutions and statutory\nor contract colleges within the schedule of such units or to hospitals\nwithin the schedule of hospitals of the state university from a\nparticular fund or funds in a fiscal year for the programs or purposes\nof such units or hospitals of the state university may be transferred\nbetween and among such units or hospitals pursuant to a certificate of\nallocation, submitted directly by the state university to the state\ncomptroller, with copies of such certificates to be sent to the chairs\nof the senate finance committee and the assembly ways and means\ncommittee and the director of the budget for informational purposes\nonly. The total amount appropriated for any unit may not be decreased by\nmore than the aggregate of three percent of an appropriation for a unit\nor the aggregate of ten percent of an appropriation for a hospital.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Amounts appropriated for programs or purposes, or for any item\nwithin such programs or purposes, within the university-wide program\nschedule of state university from a particular fund or funds in a fiscal\nyear shall not be decreased by means of transfer or interchange by more\nthan the aggregate of four percent of an appropriation for a program or\npurpose within such schedule.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Amounts appropriated for hospitals within the hospital schedule of\nthe state university from a particular fund or funds in a fiscal year\nfor programs or purposes of such hospitals shall not be increased or\ndecreased by means of transfer or interchange from the amounts\nappropriated to the state-operated institutions and the statutory or\ncontract colleges, university-wide programs, or central administration\nof the state university. The aggregate appropriation for the hospital\nschedule shall not be increased or decreased by such transfers of\nappropriations.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Amounts appropriated for the central administration of the state\nuniversity within the central administration schedule from a particular\nfund or funds in a fiscal year for programs or purposes including, but\nnot limited to, administration of state-operated institutions and\nstatutory or contract colleges, university-wide programs, and hospitals\nof the state university shall not be increased by means of transfer or\ninterchange by more than five percent of the aggregate appropriation\nwithin such schedule.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this subdivision,\nwhenever the director of the budget, pursuant to section forty-nine of\nthe state finance law, shall establish an aggregate amount less than\nthat contained in the state operations appropriations act, the trustees\nmay transfer or interchange any or all of such lesser amount among any\nof the programs or purposes or items without regard to the restrictions\nprovided in this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_b__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On the fifteenth day of October, January, April and July of each\nyear, the state university shall provide the chair of the senate finance\ncommittee and the assembly ways and means committee, the state\ncomptroller and the director of the budget with quarterly reports of all\ntransfers or interchanges made by the state university pursuant to this\nsection, with such reports to include the program impact of each\ntransfer or interchange. The allocation of lump sum appropriations from\na fund or funds made to the state university for later distribution to\nstate operated institutions, statutory or contract colleges, hospitals\nand/or central administration of the state university or the allocation\nof lump sum appropriations made to all state departments and agencies\nfor later allocation for specific programs or purposes or units of the\nstate university shall not be deemed to be part of any total increase or\ndecrease authorized by this section.\n  5. Notwithstanding the provisions of...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>purchase materials, proprietary electronic information\nresources including but not limited to academic, professional, and\nindustry journals, reference handbooks and manuals, research tracking\ntools, indexes and abstracts; and equipment and supplies, including\ncomputer equipment and motor vehicles, where the amount for a single\npurchase does not exceed seventy-five thousand dollars, (ii) execute\ncontracts for services and construction contracts to an amount not\nexceeding seventy-five thousand dollars, and (iii) contract for printing\nto an amount not exceeding seventy-five thousand dollars, without prior\napproval by any other state officer or agency, but subject to rules and\nregulations of the state comptroller not otherwise inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this section and in accordance with the guidelines\npromulgated by the state university board of trustees after consultation\nwith the state comptroller. In addition, the trustees, after\nconsultation with the commissioner of general services, are authorized\nto annually negotiate with the state comptroller increases in the\naforementioned dollar limits and the exemption of any articles,\ncategories of articles, services, or commodities from these limits;\n  b. establish cash advance accounts for the purpose of purchasing\nmaterials, supplies, or services, for cash advances for travel expenses\nand per diem allowances, or for advance payment of wages and salary. The\naccount may be used to purchase such materials, supplies, or services\nwhere the amount of a single purchase does not exceed one thousand\ndollars, in accordance with such guidelines as shall be prescribed by\nthe state university trustees after consultation with the state\ncomptroller;\n  c. establish guidelines in consultation with the commissioner of\ngeneral services authorizing participation by the state university in\nprograms administered by the office of general services for the purchase\nof available New York state food products....</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that service as a board member or officer thereof shall not be used\nas a means for private benefit or inurement for the board member or\nofficer, a relative thereof, or any entity in which the board member or\nofficer, or relative thereof, has a business interest;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no board\nmember or officer who is a vendor of goods or services to the foundation\nor its affiliated corporation, or who has a business interest in such\nvendor, or whose relative has a business interest in such vendor, shall\nvote on, or participate in the foundation's administration of, any\ntransaction with such vendor; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a board member or officer shall\nadvise the chair of the foundation or its affiliated corporation of his\nor a relative's business interest in any such existing or proposed\nvendor with the foundation or its affiliate. The state university\ntrustees' guidelines shall define the nature of a business interest and\nthe closeness of a personal relation that bring a relationship within\nthe purposes of this subdivision.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2027\n  7. To refund or credit moneys paid to the state university for tuition\nor any other fee or charge imposed or received by the state university\ntrustees</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>where such moneys were not required by law or trustees'\nrule, to the extent of the amount paid;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>where such moneys were in\nexcess of the amount required by law or trustees' rule, to the extent of\nsuch excess;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>where registration or attendance at a state university\ninstitution is canceled or terminated prior to the expiration of an\nacademic term otherwise than by dismissal, to the extent prescribed by\nrule or otherwise by the state university trustees; provided, however,\nthat no moneys shall be refunded or credited unless application therefor\nis made within three years after receipt of such moneys by the state\nuniversity.\n  8. Except as otherwise provided herein, all moneys received by the\nstate university of New York and by state-operated institutions thereof\nfrom appropriations, tuition, fees, user charges, sales of products and\nservices and from all other sources, including sources and activities of\nthe state university which are intended by law to be self-supporting may\nbe credited to an appropriate fund or funds to be designated by the\nstate comptroller. The amounts so paid into such fund or funds which\nwere received by or for the state university shall be used for expenses...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an analysis of\nprivate enterprise, federal and any other appropriate financing\nstandards, (ii) the consideration of the period of economic life of\nprojects as related to the method of financing, and (iii) project cost\nranges for the methods of financing. Such plan specification and\ncategories of construction shall be defined by the trustees, in\nconsultation with the state university construction fund.\n  Such capital master plan report shall also include, for each project\nover one-million dollars, a description of the project; expected\nconstruction start date; any changes to the previously reported start or\nexpected completion dates; any changes to the expected cost of the\nproject; the total cash encumbered for the project for the year and the\ntotal to date for the project; and the total cash expended for the\nproject for the year and the total to date for the project.\n  All projects that are reported under this subdivision shall be\nidentified by campus, the name of the specific facility for which the\nallocation is provided and a description of what the project is that is\nbeing provided.\n  14. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local\nlaw or charter, the state university trustees shall prepare or cause to\nbe prepared a development and operation plan for a state university\nathletic facility, as defined in section sixteen hundred eighty-e of the\npublic authorities law. Such development and operation plan shall be\nsubmitted to the director of the budget for approval not later than the\nfifteenth day of September of the fiscal year of the state. The director\nof the budget shall file a copy of such plan and approval thereof with\nthe chairpersons of the senate finance committee and the assembly ways\nand means committee. No proposed amendment to the plan shall be\neffective until submitted by the state university trustees and approved\nby, the director of the budget and filed by the director with the\nchairpersons of the senate...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>revenue and expense estimates for the succeeding three year period\ncommencing in the year of the completion of construction and beneficial\noccupancy of the state university athletic facility;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the sources of revenues that are projected to be available to meet\nall costs of the operation, repair, maintenance and continuing use of\nthe state university athletic facility, and any net income remaining to\ncover subsequent annual debt service expenses, and evidence satisfactory\nto the state university of New York and the director of the budget that,\nconsistent with university and community use as set forth in this\nsection, revenues will be maximized and available when needed for the\nstate university athletic facility; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>plans for the development, operation, repair, maintenance and\ncontinuing use of the state university athletic facility under the care,\ncustody, and management of the state university to include, but not be\nlimited to, athletic competition of the state university of New York at\nBuffalo, amateur sports, appropriate community events, and activities\nthat generate support for facility operations.\n  15. State university fiscal year. Notwithstanding any provision of\nthis chapter, the state finance law, or any other law to the contrary,\non and after the first day of July, nineteen hundred ninety-three, the\nfiscal year of the state university of New York, for the purposes of the\nbudget, appropriations, receipts and disbursements of state moneys and\nall other revenues of the state university, financial reporting, and all\nother affairs of the state university which are regulated in accordance\nwith or are based on a fiscal year, shall begin with the first day of\nJuly and end with the next following thirtieth day of June.\nAppropriations made for the state university for whatever purpose on the\nbasis of the state university fiscal year which at the close of such\nfiscal year shall cease to have force and effect except as to\nliabilities already incurred thereunder shall as to such liabilities\ncontinue in force and effect until the next succeeding thirtieth day of\nSeptember, on which date such appropriation shall lapse and no money\nshall thereafter be paid out of the state treasury or any of its funds\nor any of the funds under its management pursuant to such appropriation.\n  16. Subject to laws and regulations applicable to the state university\nas a health care provider the state university trustees may:\n  a. Notwithstanding section one hundred sixty-three of the state\nfinance law, authorize contracts for a state university health care\nfacility for participation in managed care networks and other joint and\ncooperative arrangements with public, non-profit ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>. In\naddition, the commissioner of health shall provide for public comment\nwithin thirty days of a submission of any management contract required\nto be reviewed pursuant to regulation. The trustees may also authorize\ncontracts, including capitation contracts, for a state university health\ncare facility for the provision of general comprehensive and specialty\nhealth care services, directly or through contract with other service\nproviders or entities, including state university employees or entities\ncomprised thereof. Contracts authorized hereunder shall be:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_f__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>consistent with trustee guidelines respecting all terms and\nconditions necessary and appropriate for managed care and other network,\njoint or cooperative arrangements, including guidelines for comparative\nreview where appropriate;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_f__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>subject to laws and regulations applicable to the state university\nas a health care provider, including with respect to rates and\ncertificates of need; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_f__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>subject to article fourteen of the civil service law and the\napplicable provisions of agreements between the state and employee\norganizations pursuant to article fourteen of the civil service law.\n  b.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision two of section\none hundred twelve of the state finance law relating to the dollar\nthreshold requiring the comptroller's approval of contracts and\nsubdivision six of section one hundred sixty-three of the state finance\nlaw, authorize contracts for the purchase of goods and services for\nstate university health care facilities:\n  (A) for any contract which does not exceed one hundred fifty thousand\ndollars; or\n  (B) for joint or group purchasing arrangements which do not exceed one\nhundred fifty thousand dollars without prior approval by any other state\nofficer or agency in accordance with procedures and requirements found\nin paragraph a of subdivision five of this section.\n  (ii) contracts authorized hereunder shall be subject to article\nfourteen of the civil service law and the applicable provisions of\nagreements between the state and employee organizations pursuant to\narticle fourteen of the civil service law. The trustees are authorized\nto negotiate annually with the state comptroller increases in the\naforementioned dollar limits.\n  c. Authorize contracts for the acquisition, by purchase, lease,\nsublease, transfer of jurisdiction or otherwise, of facilities suitable\nfor the delivery of health care services and for the construction,\nrepair, maintenance, equipping, rehabilitation or improvement thereof.\nSuch contracts shall be subject to approval by the attorney general as\nto form and by the director of the budget and the state comptroller.\nContracts under this paragraph shall be funded from any moneys lawfully\navailable for the expenses of the health care facilities.\n  17. Investigation of crimes and crime reporting.  a. The board of\ntrustees of the state university of New York shall adopt rules requiring\nthat each institution of the state university, on or before January\nfirst, two thousand, adopt and implement a plan providing for the\ninvestigation of any violent felony offense occurring a...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inform each victim of a sexual\noffense of their options to notify proper law enforcement authorities,\nincluding on-campus and local police;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inform the victim of a sexual\noffense of the right to report or not to report such offense to local\nlaw enforcement agencies; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>offer the option to be assisted by\ncampus authorities in notifying such authorities, if the victim of\nsexual assault so chooses, all in compliance with applicable federal\nlaw, including, but not limited to, the federal Campus Sexual Assault\nVictims' Bill of Rights under Title 20 U.S. Code Section 1092</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n  b. As used in this subdivision, the following terms shall have the\nfollowing meanings:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Local law enforcement agencies" means any agency or agencies\nemploying peace officers or police officers for the enforcement of the\nlaws of the state, and which has or have jurisdiction under provisions\nof the criminal procedure law over offenses occurring at or on the\ngrounds of any institution subject to the provisions of this\nsubdivision.\n  (ii) "Missing student" means any student of an institution subject to\nthe provisions of this subdivision, who resides in a facility owned or\noperated by such institution and who is reported to such institution as\nmissing from his or her residence.\n  (iii) "Violent felony offense" means a violent felony offense as\ndefined in subdivision one of section 70.02 of the penal law.\n  18. Scholarships for academic achievement. a.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Beginning with the\ntwo thousand--two thousand one academic year and thereafter,\nscholarships for academic achievement shall be awarded to full-time\nstudents completing their sophomore and junior years of study at all\nstate university state operated campuses. Two thousand five hundred\nscholarships shall be awarded to students in the junior year of study\nand two thousand five hundred scholarships shall be awarded to students\nin the senior year of study.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Scholarships made to students in the junior year shall be to the\ntwo thousand five hundred students with the highest cumulative grade\npoint average at the end of such students sophomore year of study. Any\nstudent receiving such award shall be a New York state resident and\nshall have a minimum grade point average of 3.5. Such scholarship shall\nbe awarded at the beginning of the spring semester of such student's\njunior year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_355__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Scholarships made to students in the senior year will be to the\ntwo thousand five hundred students with the highest cumulative grade\npoint average at the end of such students' junior year of study. Any\nstudent receiving such award shall be a New York state resident and\nshall have a minimum grade point average of 3.5. Such scholarship shall\nbe awarded at the beginning of the spring semester of such students'\nsenior year.\n  b. Each individual state university of New York state operated campus\nshall receive no more than its pro rata share of awards than the\npercentage of such university's juniors and seniors represent of the\nentire system enrollment in the junior and senior classes.\n  c. Upon determination of the recipients of the annual awards, the\nchancellor shall notify the members of the state legislature of all\nrecipients who permanently reside within the district that such members\nrepresent.\n  19. The state university of New York shall provide the chairs of the\nassem...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_355__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision one of section one hundred forty-five of the public\nbuildings law.\n  21. The state university trustees shall adopt a policy requiring that\neach institution of the state university of New York collaborate with\nstudents, faculty and staff to encourage campuses to eliminate the use\nof certain plastic items generally recognized by the public as being\ndesigned for single use. Such plastic items may include, but shall not\nbe limited to, tableware, straws, stirrers, cups and food service\ncontainers. In establishing such a policy, the trustees shall consider\nthe following:\n  a. the availability of affordable alternatives;\n  b. the accessibility of alternatives to all students, faculty, and\nstaff;\n  c. an evaluation of the effectiveness of reusable alternatives; and\n  d. benchmarks for assessing progress.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>