<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3602-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3602_C">
        <num>3602-C</num>
        <heading>Apportionment of moneys to school districts for the provision of services to pupils attending nonpublic schools</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen\nhundred twelve of title twenty of the United States code, including but\nnot limited to, equitable provision of services, child find and\nconsultation requirements. The committee on special education of the\nschool district of location shall be responsible for evaluation and\npossible identification as a student with a disability of all students\nattending nonpublic schools located within the school district,\nincluding students who are not New York residents. The school district\nof location shall expend a proportionate amount of its federal funds\nmade available under part B of the individuals with disabilities\neducation act for the provision of services to students with\ndisabilities attending such nonpublic schools, including students who\nare not New York residents, provided that such federal funds may not be\nused for the cost of carrying out the child find requirement. School\ndistricts shall obtain parental consent prior to the release of\npersonally identifiable information concerning a student attending a\nnonpublic school from records collected or maintained pursuant to part B\nof the individuals with disabilities education act between such\nstudent's school district of residence and school district of location.\n  * NB Repealed June 30, 2027\n  * 2-b. The school district of location shall provide special education\nprograms and services to students with disabilities attending nonpublic\nschools in the school district who are not New York residents to the\nextent required under federal law and regulations and such students\nshall not have an individual right to receive special education programs\nand services pursuant to this section. The committee on special\neducation shall develop services plans for such students in accordance\nwith federal law and regulations. The provisions of subdivision two of\nthis section shall not apply to such students, except that due process\ncomplaints relating to compliance of the school district of lo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>