<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-07-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3602-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3602-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3602_D">
        <num>3602-D</num>
        <heading>Work-prep education program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Articulation agreement" shall mean a commitment between secondary\nand post-secondary institutions to a program designed to provide\nstudents with a non-duplicative sequence of courses leading to\ncompetencies, as demonstrated by an associate degree or certificate, in\nan occupationally oriented field.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Disadvantaged" shall mean individuals (other than handicapped\nindividuals) who have economic or academic disadvantages and who require\nspecial services and assistance in order to enable them to succeed in\nwork-prep programs. Such term includes individuals who are: members of\neconomically disadvantaged families as set forth in regulations\npromulgated by the department pursuant to sections sixty-four hundred\nfifty-one and sixty-four hundred fifty-two of this chapter or as set\nforth in the Federal Job Training Partnership Act of nineteen hundred\neighty-two (PL 97-300) (29 U.S.C.A. ยง 1501 et seq.); migrants; English\nlanguage learners; and individuals who are identified as potential\ndropouts from secondary school.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Work-prep education program" shall mean a combined secondary and\npost-secondary program which: leads to an associate degree or\ncertificate; provides preparation and establishes competencies in an\noccupationally oriented field; and leads to employment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Occupationally oriented field" shall mean applied science,\nengineering, health sciences, mechanical or industrial arts, and/or home\neconomics.\n  3. Work-prep education program.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall, out of\navailable funds pursuant to the Federal Carl D. Perkins Act (PL 98-524)\nand/or its successor, provide grants on a competitive basis, to pay the\ncost of activities authorized by this section to a consortia of:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>school districts, local education agencies and/or boards of\ncooperative educational services serving secondary students; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>post-secondary educational agencies which offer an associate\ndegree program or certificate program.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each consortia interested in initiating a work-prep program shall\nsubmit a five year plan for the development and implementation of\nwork-prep activities. At a minimum, the plan shall contain the\nfollowing:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>an articulation agreement between the participants in the\nconsortium;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>linkages between the two years of secondary school preceding\ngraduation and post-secondary study. Such linkage must incorporate a\nnext generation of required proficiency in an occupationally oriented\nfield leading to an associate degree or certificate in a specific career\nfield;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the development of work-prep education program curriculum\nappropriate to the needs of consortium participants, program\nparticipants, and the business community;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the development of specific measures to eliminate gender-based\nbias in occupational recruitment, counseling, instruction, and placement\nefforts;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the provision of in-service training for counselors designed to\nenable counselors to effectively: recruit students for work-prep\nprograms; ensure the student's successful completion of such programs;\nand assist in the student's employment placement; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>performance standards creating measures for evaluating program\nsuccess.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall give special consideration to applications\nwhich:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>provide for effective employment placement activities;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>demonstrate a commitment to continue such program activities;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>include the input of business, industry, labor unions, joint\napprenticeship committees, and employers conducting registered\napprenticeship programs, in its development; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>address the issues of dropout prevention, disadvantaged youths,\nand handicapped youths.\n  4. Apportionment of funds.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Allowable costs under this section\nshall include expenses related to the coordination, administration\nand/or delivery of the work-prep program such as: costs of assessment,\nguidance, and instructional materials; purchase of equipment; personal\nservices associated with joint curriculum planning and development\nactivities; and costs of in-service training for participating teachers\nand guidance counselors.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3602_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Moneys appropriated under this section shall be apportioned\nensuring an equitable distribution of assistance throughout the state\nand among both urban and rural participants.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>