<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-09-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3604"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3604">
        <num>3604</num>
        <heading>Conditions under which districts are entitled to apportionment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3604__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the school year in which such notification was received\nand (ii) the two succeeding school years, provided further that there\nshall be no interest penalty assessed against such district or collected\nby the state. Such request shall be made to the commissioner in such\nform as the commissioner shall prescribe, and shall be based on\ndocumentation that the total amount to be recovered is in excess of one\npercent of the district's total general fund expenditures for the\npreceding school year. The amount to be deducted in the first year shall\nbe the greater of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3604__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the sum of the amount of such excess payments that\nis recognized as a liability due to other governments by the district\nfor the preceding school year and the positive remainder of the\ndistrict's unreserved fund balance at the close of the preceding school\nyear less the product of the district's total general fund expenditures\nfor the preceding school year multiplied by five percent, or (ii)\none-third of such excess payments. The amount to be recovered in the\nsecond year shall equal the lesser of the remaining amount of such\nexcess payments to be recovered or one-third of such excess payments,\nand the remaining amount of such excess payments shall be recovered in\nthe third year. Provided further that, notwithstanding any other\nprovisions of this subdivision, any pending payment of moneys due to\nsuch district as a prior year adjustment payable pursuant to paragraph c\nof this subdivision for aid claims that had been previously paid as\ncurrent year aid payments in excess of the amount to which the district\nis entitled and for which recovery of excess payments is to be made\npursuant to this paragraph, shall be reduced at the time of actual\npayment by any remaining unrecovered balance of such excess payments,\nand the remaining scheduled deductions of such excess payments pursuant\nto this paragraph shall be reduced by the commissioner to reflect the\namount so recovered. The commissioner shall certify no payment to a\nschool district based on a claim submitted later than three years after\nthe close of the school year in which such payment was first to be made.\nFor claims for which payment is first to be made in the nineteen hundred\nninety-six--ninety-seven school year, the commissioner shall certify no\npayment to a school district based on a claim submitted later than two\nyears after the close of such school year. For claims for which payment\nis first to be made in the nineteen hundred ninety-seven--ninety-eight\nschool year and thereafter, the co...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3604__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for\nany day or days on which session had been previously scheduled but the\nsuperintendent was required to close the school or schools due to a\nproperly executed declaration of a state or local state of emergency\npursuant to article two-B of the executive law; or (ii) for up to five\ndays if he or she finds that the schools of the district were not in\nsession for one hundred eighty days because of extraordinarily adverse\nweather conditions, impairment of heating facilities, insufficiency of\nwater supply, shortage of fuel, lack of electricity, natural gas\nleakage, unacceptable levels of chemical substances, a credible threat\nto student safety as reasonably determined by a lead school official or\nthe destruction of a school building either in whole or in part, and if,\nfurther, the commissioner finds that such district cannot make up such\ndays of instruction by using for the secondary grades all scheduled\nvacation days which occur prior to the first scheduled regents\nexamination day in June, and for the elementary grades all scheduled\nvacation days which occur prior to the last scheduled regents\nexamination day in June; or (iii) for any day or days in the two\nthousand nineteen -- two thousand twenty school year on which session\nhad been previously scheduled but the chancellor of the city school\ndistrict of the city of New York or the superintendent of a district\nclosed the school or schools due to a determination by the chancellor or\nsuperintendent that it was in the best interest of public health or\nsafety of the school district to close the school or schools in response\nto the novel coronavirus, COVID-19. For the purposes of this\nsubdivision, "scheduled vacation days" shall mean days on which the\nschools of the district are not in session and for which no prohibition\nexists in subdivision eight of this section for them to be in session.\n  8. No school shall be in session on a Saturday, the first day of the\nsecond lunar month after the winte...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3604__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the expenditures which he\nestimates the district would have had to make or incur during the school\nyear upon which such apportionments are based if the district had fully\ncomplied with such requirements or if the district had maintained such\nprograms, and (ii) the expenditures actually made or incurred by the\ndistrict for such programs during the same school year.\n  11. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the commissioner shall\nwithhold the general fund apportionment due to any school district when\nsuch school district fails to submit by the date specified in section\nthirty-six hundred one of this part the reports required by the\ncommissioner to calculate such apportionments, until the time such\nreports have been submitted in proper fashion.\n  12. All the acts done and proceedings heretofore had and taken or\ncaused to be had and taken by the Center Moriches Union Free School\ndistrict and by all its officers or agents relating to or in connection\nwith certain transportation contractual obligations for regular student\ntransportation of the nineteen hundred ninety-nine--two thousand school\nyear, which was part of the two thousand--two thousand one state aid\nclaim submitted to the department by such school district, are hereby\nlegalized, validated, ratified and confirmed, notwithstanding any\nfailure to comply with the approval and filing provisions of this\nchapter or any other law or any other statutory authority, rule or\nregulation, other than those filing provisions defined in paragraph a of\nsubdivision five of this section, in relation to any omission, error,\ndefect, irregularity or illegality in such proceeding had and taken. For\nthe purpose of those filing provisions defined in such paragraph a of\nsubdivision five of this section, the district shall be deemed to have\nfiled such contract within one year after the close of the two\nthousand--two thousand one school year, and aid due and payable for such\nfiling shall be deemed to be...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>