<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3606"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3606"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3606"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3606">
        <num>3606</num>
        <heading>Nonresident academic attendance; manner of certifying and paying apportionment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3606. Nonresident academic attendance; manner of certifying and\npaying apportionment.  The commissioner of education immediately after\nmaking an apportionment shall certify, or cause to be certified, to the\ntreasurer, if there be one, otherwise to the disbursing officer or\ncollector of each school district or academy included in such\napportionment, except those located within the territory of the city of\nNew York, the amount of money which has been allotted to each said\nschool district or academy.  The payment of said allotment shall be made\nby the commissioner of taxation and finance directly to the treasurer,\nif there be one, otherwise to the disbursing officer or collector of\neach school district or academy named in the certificate of the\ncommissioner of education.  Any apportionment which shall be made to the\ncity school district of the city of New York shall be certified and paid\nto the commissioner of finance of the city of New York, and any\napportionment which shall be made to any private academy situated within\nthe territory of the city of New York, shall be certified and paid\ndirectly to the disbursing officer of the academy to which the\napportionment is made.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>