<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3609-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3609-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3609_B">
        <num>3609-B</num>
        <heading>Moneys apportioned for students with disabilities, when and how payable</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3609_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nlesser of (A) one hundred percent of the respective amount set forth for\neach school district as payable pursuant to this section in the school\naid computer listing for the current year, as defined in the opening\nparagraph of section thirty-six hundred nine-a of this article, or (B)\nthe apportionment calculated by the commissioner for the current year\nbased on data on file at the time the payment is processed plus (ii) the\nexcess cost aid setaside computed pursuant to subdivision four of\nsection thirty-six hundred two of this article, based on data utilized\nin producing such school aid listing for the current year. The\ndefinitions "base year" and "current year" as set forth in subdivision\none of section thirty-six hundred two of this article shall apply to\nthis section.\n  1. Assignment of certain moneys.  a. Any moneys to be apportioned by\nthe commissioner to school districts during the school year pursuant to\nthis section for services provided on or before June thirtieth, two\nthousand nine that were reimbursed by the state on or before April\nfirst, two thousand eleven shall, in the first instance, be designated\nas the state share of moneys due a school district pursuant to title XIX\nof the social security act, on account of school supportive health\nservices provided to students with disabilities in special education\nprograms pursuant to article eighty-nine of this chapter and to those\npupils who are qualified handicapped persons as defined in the federal\nrehabilitation act of nineteen hundred seventy-three, as amended. Some\nor all of such state share may be assigned on behalf of school districts\nto the department of health, as provided herein; any remaining state\nshare moneys shall be paid to school districts on the same schedule as\nthe federal share of such title XIX payments and shall be based on the\nmonthly report of the commissioner of health to the commissioner; and\nany remaining moneys to be apportioned to a school district pu...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3609_B__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>December payment. On or before December fifteenth, a portion shall\nbe paid equal to the positive remainder of twenty-five percent of the\nmoneys apportioned less any payments made pursuant to paragraph a of\nsubdivision one of this section for the current year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3609_B__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>March payment. On or before March fifteenth, a portion shall be\npaid equal to the positive remainder of seventy percent of the moneys\napportioned less any payments made pursuant to paragraph a of\nsubdivision one of this section and subparagraph one of this paragraph\nfor the current year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3609_B__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>June payment. On or before June fifteenth, a portion shall be paid\nequal to the positive remainder of eighty-five percent of the moneys\napportioned less any payments made pursuant to paragraph a of\nsubdivision one of this section and subparagraphs one and two of this\nparagraph for the current year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3609_B__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>August payment. To the extent that any moneys are owed to a school\ndistrict pursuant to this section, a portion shall be paid on or before\nAugust fifteenth equal to the positive remainder of one hundred percent\nof the moneys apportioned less any payments made pursuant to paragraph a\nof subdivision one of this section and subparagraphs one, two and three\nof this paragraph for the current year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3609_B__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Deferred September payment. Any amount payable to a school\ndistrict pursuant to this section which exceeded one hundred percent of\nthe respective amount set forth for such district as payable pursuant to\nthis section in the school aid computer listing for the current school\nyear shall be designated for payment for the month of September next\nfollowing the close of the current school year. Such payments shall be\nmade on the first state business day of the month of September, based on\ndata on file as of August first; provided however, that for the\nSeptember two thousand six payment such calculation shall be based on\nthe computer listing for the current year using data on file as of\nAugust first.\n  b. Such moneys shall be payable to the treasurer of each city school\ndistrict, and the treasurer of each union free school district and of\neach central school district and of each other school district, if there\nbe a treasurer, otherwise to the collector or other disbursing office...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>