<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3635"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3635"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3635"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3635/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3635/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3635/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3635/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3635">
        <num>3635</num>
        <heading>Transportation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3635__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>School districts providing transportation to a nonpublic school\nfor pupils living within a specified distance from such school shall\ndesignate one or more public schools as centralized pick-up points and\nshall provide transportation between such points and such nonpublic\nschools for students residing in the district who live too far from such\nnonpublic schools to qualify for transportation between home and school.\nThe district shall not be responsible for the provision of\ntransportation for pupils between their home and such pick-up points.\nThe district may provide school bus transportation to a pupil if the\nresidence of the pupil is located on an established route for the\ntransportation of pupils to the centralized pick-up point provided such\ntransportation does not result in additional costs to the district. The\ncost of providing transportation between such pick-up points and such\nnonpublic schools shall be an ordinary contingent expense.\n  (ii) A board of education may, at its discretion, provide\ntransportation for pupils residing within the district to a nonpublic\nschool located more than fifteen miles from the home of any such pupil\nprovided that such transportation has been provided to such nonpublic\nschool pursuant to this subdivision in at least one of the immediately\npreceding three school years and such transportation is provided from\none or more centralized pick-up points designated pursuant to this\nparagraph and that the distance from such pick-up points to the\nnonpublic school is not more than fifteen miles. The district shall not\nbe responsible for the provision of transportation for pupils between\npupils homes and such pick-up points. The cost of providing\ntransportation between such pick-up points and such nonpublic schools\nshall be an ordinary contingent expense.\n  c. The foregoing provisions of this subdivision shall not require\ntransportation to be provided for children residing within a city school\ndistrict, but if pr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3635__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph b of subdivision seven of\nsection thirty-six hundred two of this article.\n  g. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\ntrustees or board of education of any school district may, in its\ndiscretion, provide transportation for students attending a universal\npre-kindergarten program in addition to transportation funded by such\nprogram or transportation for students attending another district\nsponsored or district-run pre-kindergarten program, within mileage\nlimits established by the school district; if provided such\ntransportation shall be offered equally to all children in like\ncircumstances residing in the district. The cost of providing such\ntransportation shall be a charge upon the district and for purposes of\nsubdivision seven of section thirty-six hundred two of this chapter,\nsuch pupils shall be considered non allowable pupils and the costs of\ntheir transportation shall not be aidable.\n  2. A parent or guardian of a child residing in any school district, or\nany representative authorized by such parent or guardian, who desires\nfor a child during the next school year any transportation authorized or\ndirected by this chapter shall submit a written request therefor to the\nschool trustees or board of education of such district not later than\nthe first day of April preceding the next school year, provided,\nhowever, that a parent or guardian of a child not residing in the\ndistrict on such date shall submit a written request within thirty days\nafter establishing residence in the district. No late request of a\nparent or guardian for transportation shall be denied where a reasonable\nexplanation is provided for the delay. If the voters, school trustees,\nor board of education fail to provide the transportation authorized or\ndirected by this chapter after receiving such a request, such parent,\nguardian or representative, or any taxpayer residing in the district,\nmay appeal to the commissioner of education, as p...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3635__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision twenty of section\nthree hundred seventy-five of the vehicle and traffic law are not\notherwise provided for, such expenses shall be an ordinary contingent\nexpense of a school district.\n  7. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule or regulation,\nwhere a child is permitted by a school district or board of education to\nattend a public school other than the school to which they would\nnormally be assigned, a parent of such child may agree to waive\nprovision of transportation which would otherwise be required under this\nsection and no such transportation shall be required. Any agreement to\nwaive transportation must be renewed annually in writing.\n  * 8. a. The trustees or board of education of a school district may,\nat its discretion, provide student transportation based upon patterns of\nactual ridership. The actual ridership shall be determined by a school\ndistrict based upon documented history and experience that yields a\nconsistent pattern of eligible pupils not using district transportation;\nor modeling of future ridership; or the sharing of transportation\nregionally; or other criteria approved by the commissioner; provided\nhowever that any methodology shall require an additional ten percent in\nseating capacity above the number of seats derived using such\nmethodology which shall be available in case of unanticipated riders.\n  Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to reduce or relieve\nschool districts from the responsibility of providing transportation to\nstudents otherwise eligible for such transportation. Nothing in this\nsubdivision shall be construed to authorize a school district to have\nstanding passengers in violation of section thirty-six hundred\nthirty-five-c of this article, and unanticipated ridership shall not be\ndeemed an unforeseen occurrence for purposes of subdivision two of such\nsection after the first day in which such unanticipated ridership\noccurs.\n  Any school district that, at its discre...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>