<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3637"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3637"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3637"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3637/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3637/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3637/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3637/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3637">
        <num>3637</num>
        <heading>Idling school buses on school grounds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 3637. Idling school buses on school grounds. 1. On or before July\nfirst, two thousand eight, the commissioner shall promulgate regulations\nrequiring school districts to minimize, to the extent practicable, the\nidling of the engine of any school bus, as defined in section one\nhundred forty-two of the vehicle and traffic law, and other vehicles\nowned or leased by the school district while such bus or vehicle is\nparked or standing on school grounds, or in front of any school. Such\nregulations shall apply to school districts identified by the\ncommissioner, in consultation with the department of health, with a\nsignificant number of children with asthma and those other school\ndistricts deemed by the commissioner as appropriate.\n  2. Such regulations shall include, but not be limited to, a\nrequirement that the engines of all school buses and vehicles owned or\nleased by the school district be turned off while waiting for passengers\nto load or off load on school grounds. When necessary for heating,\nmechanical or emergency circumstances, the regulations may allow idling\nto the extent necessary to achieve such purpose. Provided, however, that\nsuch regulations shall not conflict with applicable state regulations\nand local laws.\n  3. School districts shall be required to annually provide their school\npersonnel with notice of the provisions of this section, and the\nregulations promulgated pursuant to this section by the commissioner.\nThe commissioner shall provide such notice for school districts to\ndisseminate.\n  * NB Repealed June 30, 2029\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>