<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3641-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3641_A">
        <num>3641-A</num>
        <heading>Excelsior scholars program for grade seven mathematics and science students</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3641-a. Excelsior scholars program for grade seven mathematics and\nscience students. The commissioner shall establish an excelsior scholars\nprogram for grade seven mathematics and science students pursuant to\nthis section and regulations of the commissioner adopted for such\npurpose. Within the amounts appropriated for this purpose, the\ncommissioner shall award grants on a competitive basis to public and\nindependent colleges and universities to conduct summer programs that\nshall provide advanced coursework in mathematics and science to students\ndesignated as excelsior scholars and, as funds permit, other\nhigh-performing students who have completed seventh grade.\n  1. Each year, the commissioner shall identify up to three thousand\nhigh performing seventh grade students in mathematics and science from\nstudents nominated by each public middle school, junior high school,\nintermediate school or junior/senior high school, or kindergarten\nthrough secondary school. The commissioner by regulation shall prescribe\nthe maximum number of students that may be nominated by each school,\nwhich may vary based on the size of the school, which shall include\nequal numbers of male and female students. After review by the\ncommissioner, qualified students shall be certified to the governor for\nrecognition as an excelsior scholar.\n  2. The commissioner shall conduct a competitive process under which\nfinancial grants are awarded to each college and university approved to\nprovide appropriate advanced coursework to excelsior scholars in the\nsummer months, subject to the availability of funds appropriated for\nsuch purpose.\n  3. The regulations of the commissioner shall provide for coordination\nof the program with the seven centers for excellence in technology and\nthe programs offered by such centers, to the extent practicable.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>