<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3641"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3641/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3641">
        <num>3641</num>
        <heading>Special apportionments and grants-in-aid to school districts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>school\ndistricts that operated half-day kindergarten programs in the two\nthousand six--two thousand seven school year and will continue to\noperate such half-day programs in the two thousand seven--two thousand\neight school year to plan for conversion to full-day kindergartens only\nin the school year next following the school year in which the planning\ngrant is received, but no later than the two thousand ten--two thousand\neleven school year, and (ii) school districts for planning grants for\nthe implementation or expansion of universal prekindergarten programs.\nThe commissioner shall prescribe the procedures and criteria for the\naward of such grants, which shall be available to school districts to\ndefray their additional costs for planning time, the cost of classroom\nmaterials, equipment, furniture and supplies not eligible for aid\npursuant to subdivisions six, six-a, six-b, six-c or six-f of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article, where such additional costs are\nincurred in planning for the facilities and staffing that will be needed\nfor such conversion, implementation or expansion. No school district may\nreceive more than one planning grant pursuant to this subdivision for\nconversion to full-day kindergarten. The commissioner shall be\nauthorized to adopt regulations to implement the provisions of this\nsubdivision.\n  3. Supplemental valuation impact grants.  a. In addition to\napportionments otherwise provided by section thirty-six hundred two of\nthis article, for aid payable in the two thousand eight--two thousand\nnine and two thousand nine--two thousand ten school years, the amounts\nspecified in paragraphs c and d of this subdivision shall be paid for\nthe purpose of providing additional funding for school districts which\nhave experienced a significant financial hardship caused by an\nextraordinary change in the taxable property valuation or extraordinary\njudgments resulting from tax certiorari proceedings.\n  b. The purpose of th...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall\ndevelop a building condition survey matrix which would be used to assist\npublic school districts to develop long range facilities plans in a\nconsistent format.\n  (1-a) Commencing no sooner than the first day in January, two thousand\ntwenty, the commissioner shall require school districts to conduct\nbuilding condition surveys every five years in accordance with\nregulations of the commissioner. Such regulations shall prescribe the\ndate or dates by which such surveys must be completed and submitted to\nthe department and shall provide for staggered implementation so that\nsuch surveys are distributed as evenly as possible throughout the\nfive-year period based on the number of public school buildings,\nprovided that such implementation schedule shall ensure that no region\nof the state is overrepresented in a given scheduled year and shall to\nthe extent practicable prioritize assigning to the first two years of\nsuch schedule those school districts with the...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner is hereby authorized to enter into the necessary\ncontractual agreements with architects and/or engineers to state-wide\ncontracts to provide building construction surveys on a regional basis\nfor a fixed fee per square foot. Such building condition surveys shall\nbe used to assist school districts with the development of their\nfive-year capital facilities plan.\n  5. School district management efficiency awards program. a. Within the\namount appropriated for such purpose, subject to a plan developed in\nconsultation with the secretary of state and approved by the director of\nthe budget, the commissioner shall award competitive grants pursuant to\nthis subdivision for achieving school district management efficiencies.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such plan shall include but not be limited to: the process by\nwhich a request for proposals is developed; the scoring rubric by which\nsuch proposals will be evaluated; the form and manner by which\napplications will be submitted; the manner by which calculation of the\namount of the award was determined, including establishing benchmarks\nbased on actual cost savings that must be met before any awards are\npaid; and the timeline for the issuance and review of applications to\nensure that grants will be first awarded within one hundred and twenty\ndays following the end of the two thousand eleven--two thousand twelve\nschool year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall be authorized, consistent with the plan\nrequired by this paragraph, to promulgate rules and regulations\nnecessary for the implementation of this subdivision.\n  b. A response to a request for proposals issued pursuant to this\nsubdivision may be submitted by a school district or jointly by two or\nmore school districts who have demonstrated to the satisfaction of the\ncommissioner that:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>one or more long term efficiencies in school district management,\noperations, procurement practices or other cost savings measures that\nhave not and will not result in an increase in cost to the state or\nlocality have been implemented;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such efficiencies have been implemented within two years prior to\na response to a request for proposals issued pursuant to this\nsubdivision or will be implemented during the current school year;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such efficiencies have resulted or will result in a significant\nreduction in total operating expenses compared to the prior year, in the\nadministrative component, or the equivalent, of the school district\nbudget, in transportation operating expenses, in transportation capital\nexpenses, and/or in other non-personal service costs included in the\nprogram component of the school district budget, or the equivalent,\ncompared to the prior year; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such efficiencies are expected to result in substantial and\nsustainable cost savings in future years; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if two or more school districts are applying jointly, and have\nentered a shared services agreement as authorized by law, that\nsignificant savings would result from such shared services; provided\nthat in no event shall districts that have entered into an aidable\ncooperative educational services agreement for any such services with a\nboard of cooperative educational services pursuant to section nineteen\nhundred fifty of this chapter be eligible for an award pursuant to this\nsubdivision for the same purpose, but may be eligible for an award\npursuant to this subdivision for another shared long term efficiency or\ncost saving measure. Provided however, a district which has received an\naward pursuant to the local government efficiency grant program\nauthorized by subdivision ten of section fifty-four of the state finance\nlaw, shall not be eligible to receive an award pursuant to this\nsubdivision for the same purpose, but may be eligible for an award\npursuant to this subdivision f...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>are innovative in the manner that the management or organizational\nstructure may be changed to generate significant savings while\nmaintaining or improving student achievement;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>have the participation\nof the teachers, parents and/or other stakeholders in the school\ndistrict;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>are measures or strategies that other school districts can\nreplicate; or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>have the greatest quantifiable savings that will be\nsustainable.\n  d. A school district that submits documentation that has been approved\nby the commissioner by September first, two thousand twelve\ndemonstrating that it has fully implemented new standards and procedures\nfor conducting annual professional performance reviews of classroom\nteachers and building principals to determine teacher and principal\neffectiveness, shall receive bonus points in the scoring of its grant\napplication.\n  e. A school district or school districts seeking a grant shall submit\nan application to the commissioner in a form and manner and by a date as\nprescribed by the commissioner. The commissioner may consult with any\nother state agency about such grants and each such agency shall\ncooperate in assisting in the analysis of grant applications.\n  f. The amount of the grant award, including the maximum grant amount\navailable to any district or districts, shall be determined by the\ncommissioner, c...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>develop a competitive request for proposals, which shall be\napproved by the director of the budget, to be issued on or before\nOctober first, two thousand eleven and shall ensure that grants will\nfirst be awarded pursuant to this subdivision during the two thousand\neleven-two thousand twelve school year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>create a peer review panel and process and a scoring rubric to be\nused in the evaluation of applications during such process. Such scoring\nrubric shall give priority to those eligible school districts that have\nthe most significant measurable improvements in academic achievement and\nstudent outcomes; and have (A) implemented rigorous programs to improve\nmiddle school student performance; (B) newly established or expanded\nparticipation in college level or early college programs; (C)\nsignificantly increased college admission rates; (D) exemplary career\nand technical education programs with a record of successful student\noutcomes; or (E) other innovative and replicable strategies for student\nachievement. Provided further that such rubric shall grant priority to\nthose eligible districts whose programs benefit students having the\ngreatest educational needs, including but not limited to:\n  (A) students within traditionally underserved student groups;\n  (B) students who are Engl...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>be authorized to promulgate rules and regulations necessary for\nthe implementation of this subdivision.\n  c. To be an eligible applicant, a school district must:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>have a race to the top final scope of work that was approved by\nthe commissioner by February fifteenth, two thousand eleven; and/or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>have demonstrated satisfactory progress, as determined by the\ncommissioner, towards implementation of elements such as high quality\nstudent assessments, use of data to improve instruction and student\nperformance, provision of professional development to improve teacher\nperformance; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>be among the school districts showing the greatest gains in\nstudent performance in its category of district in the prior school year\nas reflected by increases in student outcome, as well as other measures\nfor closing the achievement gap, improving high school performance and\ngraduation rates, and increasing college attendance and retention rates\nas compared to student performance in those areas in the applicable\nbaseline year.\n  d. For purposes of this subdivision:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"category of district" means:\n  (A) a high-need large city category consisting of city school\ndistricts having a population of one hundred twenty-five thousand\ninhabitants or more, provided that in the case of the city school\ndistrict of the city of New York the chancellor shall have the option of\napplying on behalf of one or more community school districts and/or\ndistrict seventy-five in lieu of applying on a citywide basis;\n  (B) a high-need urban-suburban category as defined by the commissioner\nbased upon the need/resource capacity index applicable to such school\ndistricts;\n  (C) a high-need rural category as defined by the commissioner based\nupon the need/resource capacity index applicable to such school\ndistricts;\n  (D) an average need category as defined by the commissioner based upon\nthe need/resource capacity index applicable to such school districts;\nand\n  (E) a low need category as defined by the commissioner based upon the\nneed/resource capacity index applic...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall establish a methodology for determining\nwhich districts in each category of district that have applied for a\nperformance improvement grant have shown the greatest achievement gains.\nProvided, however, that where a school district does not have the\nminimum number of students specified by the commissioner for\naccountability purposes (minimum "n" size) in one or more of the five\nsubgroups, such district shall not be disqualified from receiving a\ngrant, but a preference shall be given to districts within each category\nof district with the highest number of subgroups meeting such minimum\n"n" size.\n  e. The commissioner shall grant awards to the school districts, as\nrecommended by the peer review panel, among the various categories of\ndistricts and determine the amount of the grant award for each eligible\nschool district based upon the public school enrollment of the district,\nprovided that no district receiving a grant may be awarded more than\nforty per...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such plan shall include, but not be limited to:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The process by which a request for proposals will be developed;\n  (ii) The scoring rubric by which such proposals will be evaluated,\nprovided that such grants shall be awarded based on factors including,\nbut not limited to: measures of school district need; measures of the\nneed of students to be served by each of the school districts; the\nschool district's proposal to target the highest need schools and\nstudents; the sustainability of the proposed community schools program;\nand proposal quality;\n  (iii) The form and manner by which applications will be submitted;\n  (iv) The manner by which calculation of the amount of the award will\nbe determined;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The timeline for the issuance and review of applications; and\n  (vi) Program implementation phases that will trigger payment of set\npercentages of the total award.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In assessing proposal quality, the commissioner shall take into\naccount factors including, but not limited to:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The extent to which the school district's proposal would provide\nsuch community services through partnerships with local governments and\nnon-profit organizations;\n  (ii) The extent to which the proposal would provide for delivery of\nsuch services directly in school buildings;\n  (iii) The extent to which the proposal articulates how such services\nwould facilitate measurable improvement in student and family outcomes;\n  (iv) The extent to which the proposal articulates and identifies how\nexisting funding streams and programs would be used to provide such\ncommunity services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the extent to which the proposal ensures the safety of all\nstudents, staff and community members in school buildings used as\ncommunity hubs.\n  b. A response to a request for proposals issued pursuant to this\nsubdivision may be submitted by a single school district or jointly by a\nconsortium of two or more school districts, or in a city with a\npopulation of one million or more, an eligible entity.\n  c. The amount of the grant award shall be determined by the\ncommissioner, consistent with the plan developed pursuant to paragraph a\nof this subdivision, except that no single district may be awarded more\nthan forty percent of the total amount of grant awards made pursuant to\nthis subdivision; and provided further that the maximum award to any\nindividual community school site shall be five hundred thousand dollars;\nand provided further that the amount awarded will be paid out in set\npercentages over time upon successful implementation of each phase of a\nschool district's approved proposal set forth pursuant to paragraph a of\nthis subdivision; and provided further that none of the grants awarded\npursuant to this subdivision may be used to supplant existing funding.\n  6-b. Extended learning grants. a. Within the amount appropriated for\nsuch purpose, subject to a plan that is developed by the commissioner,\nand approved by the director of the budget, the commissioner shall award\ncompetitive planning and implementation grants pursuant to this\nsubdivision to eligible school districts or school districts in\ncollaboration with not-for-profit community based organizations that put\nforward a proposal to improve student outcomes by adding at least\ntwenty-five percent more time to the academic calendar by extending the\nschool day, school year, or some combination thereof, either\ndistrict-wide or in selected school buildings.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such plan shall include, but not be limited to:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The process by which a request for proposals will be developed;\n  (ii) The scoring rubric by which such proposals will be evaluated,\nprovided that priority shall be given to applicants based upon the\nschool district's proposal to target the schools and students with the\ngreatest need and upon proposal quality;\n  (iii) The form and manner by which applications will be submitted;\n  (iv) The timeline for the issuance and review of applications; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A requirement that school districts awarded grants under this\nsubdivision submit to an annual evaluation of performance and impact as\nrequired by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In assessing proposal quality in order to award implementation\ngrant funding, the commissioner shall take into account factors\nincluding, but not limited to:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the extent to which the school district's proposal would maximize\nthe use of the additional learning time through a comprehensive\nrestructuring of the school day and/or year;\n  (ii) how the additional learning time would be utilized, including but\nnot limited to additional time spent on core academics; and\n  (iii) the extent to which the proposal would provide additional\nlearning time for students in grades six through eight.\n  b. A school district's school-wide extended learning implementation\ngrant award shall equal its average daily attendance in the school-wide\nextended learning program multiplied by the expected cost per pupil of\nthe additional learning time. For purposes of this subdivision, the\nexpected cost per pupil of the additional learning time shall equal the\ngreater of fifteen hundred dollars or</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the quotient of</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the school\ndistrict's approved operating expense pursuant to paragraph t of\nsubdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this article for\nthe year prior to the base year divided by (ii) the district's public\nschool district enrollment pursuant to subparagraph two of paragraph n\nof such subdivision for the year prior to the base year multiplied by\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>ten percent (0.10), multiplied by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the quotient of</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\naverage of the national consumer price indexes determined by the United\nStates department of labor for the twelve month period preceding January\nfirst of the base year, divided by (ii) the average of the national\nconsumer price indexes determined by the United States department of\nlabor for the twelve month period preceding January first of the year\ntwo years prior to the base year.\n  c. In extraordinary cases, the commissioner may award a grant that\nexceeds the per pupil limit calculated pursuant to paragraph b of this\nsubdivision.\n  d. No district shall receive a grant in excess of the total actual\ngrant expenditures incurred by the district in the current year as\napproved by the commissioner.\n  e. No single district may be awarded more than forty percent of the\ntotal amount of grant awards made pursuant to this subdivision.\n  6-c. Teacher excellence fund. a. Within the amount appropriated for\nsuch purpose, subject to a request for proposals developed by the\ncommissioner and approved by the director of the budget, the\ncommissioner shall award teacher excellence fund grants pursuant to this\nsubdivision to eligible school districts, beginning in the two thousand\nfourteen--two thousand fifteen school year, to provide teacher\nexcellence fund performance awards to highly effective teachers.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Teacher excellence fund performance awards shall be allocated in\nan annual amount of up to twenty thousand dollars to eligible teachers\nrated as "highly effective" based on the most recent annual professional\nperformance review, in accordance with the requirements of section three\nthousand twelve-c of this chapter and regulations of the commissioner.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>On an annual basis, eligible school districts may submit an\napplication to the commissioner, in a form and manner prescribed by the\ncommissioner, to request funding pursuant to this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall make available such application on or\nbefore May fifteenth of the preceding school year and the commissioner\nshall issue preliminary teacher excellence fund grant awards on or\nbefore October fifteenth of the school year in which the eligible\nteacher shall receive a teacher excellence fund performance award.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Applications submitted by eligible school districts shall include\ninformation required by the commissioner including, but not limited to,\nthe extent to which the school district's plan is intended to recognize\nand reward highly-effective teachers:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in school buildings with the\ngreatest academic need; (ii) in difficult-to-staff subject or\ncertification areas and/or grade levels; and (iii) at critical points in\na teacher's career in order to encourage highly effective teachers to\nremain in the classroom.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall prioritize applications submitted by\neligible school districts based on factors including, but not limited\nto, the factors described in subparagraph four of this paragraph and the\nquality of the proposal.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the\nteacher excellence fund performance awards provided by this subdivision\nshall be in addition to, and shall not be considered part of, a\nteacher's basic annual salary, and shall not be included as compensation\nfor retirement purposes. Teacher excellence fund performance awards\nshall supplement and shall not supplant compensation from sources\nexclusive of this subdivision agreed to as part of a collective\nbargaining agreement.\n  b. For the purpose of this subdivision:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The term "eligible school district" shall mean a common, union\nfree, central, central high school, city, or special act school district\nthat has entered into an agreement with the collective bargaining\nrepresentatives of certified teachers consistent with the provisions of\nthe application submitted by the school district pursuant to paragraph a\nof this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The term "eligible teacher" shall mean a teacher who</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>holds an\ninitial, provisional, transitional, permanent or professional state\nteaching certificate appropriate to the teaching positions, including\nthe subject area if applicable, in which he or she is employed; (ii) is\na classroom teacher subject to the annual professional performance\nreview requirements of section three thousand twelve-c of this chapter;\nand (iii) is rated "highly effective" based on his or her most recent\nannual professional performance review, in accordance with the\nrequirements of section three thousand twelve-c of this chapter and\nregulations of the commissioner.\n  7. Small government assistance. a. In addition to apportionments\notherwise provided by section thirty-six hundred two of this article for\npayable in the two thousand eleven--two thousand twelve school year and\nthereafter the amounts specified in paragraph b of this subdivision\nshall be paid to school districts for small government assistance.\n  b. To school districts that received small government assistance in\nthe state fiscal year two thousand ten--two thousand eleven, such\napportionment in the same amount shall be apportioned to school\ndistricts on or before March thirty-first of the school year upon audit\nand warrant of the comptroller.\n  8. Supplemental educational improvement grants. a. In addition to\napportionments otherwise provided by section thirty-six hundred two of\nthis article, for aid payable in the two thousand seven--two thousand\neight school year and thereafter, the amounts specified in paragraph b\nof this subdivision shall be paid for the purpose of providing\nadditional funding for the costs of educational improvement plans\nrequired as a result of a court-ordered settlement in a school\ndesegregation case to which the state was a party. Grant funds awarded\npursuant to this subdivision shall be used exclusively for services and\nexpenses incurred by the school district to implement such educational\nimprovement plans.\n  b. To the Yonkers c...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>school districts, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nschool districts working in collaboration with institutions of higher\neducation and/or teacher resource and computer resource centers, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nproviders of pre-kindergarten services which are receiving funding\npursuant to section three thousand six hundred two-e of this article,\nfor services and expenses related to targeted instructional staff\ndevelopment grants.\n  b. School districts and providers of pre-kindergarten services seeking\na grant pursuant to this subdivision shall submit a plan for approval of\nthe commissioner that details how the school district will use the grant\nfunds to provide effective and grade-level appropriate staff development\nprograms that are targeted on one or more of the instructional areas\nspecified in paragraph c of this subdivision. Such plan shall be in a\nform prescribed by the commissioner and shall include, but not be\nlimited to, a proposed budget, and a description of:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the program, including, but not limited to, its purpose and target\npopulation;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>how the new program shall be integrated with, and will supplement,\nthe district's existing in-service staff development program;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>when the staff development program shall be offered to teachers\nand the arrangements made by the school district to assure that teachers\nare able to attend, including, but not limited to, arrangements for\nsubstitute teachers;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the local funds, if any, that will be made available to support\nthe new staff development program; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a plan for evaluation of the effectiveness of the program, which\nshall include, but need not be limited to, a survey of all participating\nteachers.\n  c. Staff development programs funded pursuant to this subdivision\nshall be targeted for specialized in-service training in one or more of\nthe following areas:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>understanding and implementing the new higher standards and\nassessments as promulgated by the board of regents and the commissioner;\n  (ii) effective use of technology in instruction;\n  (iii) instruction of children who are participating in\npre-kindergarten programs approved pursuant to section three thousand\nsix hundred two-e of this article;\n  (iv) instruction of children with disabilities within a regular\neducation setting;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>instruction of nondisabled children who demonstrate the need for\nincreased academic attention; and\n  (vi) other areas of need demonstrated by the district that relate\ndirectly to student instruction and are approved by the commissioner.\n  d. Grants shall be awarded on a competitive basis in accordance with\ncriteria established by the commissioner. Grant funds may be used for\nthe approved expenses of the staff development program as defined by the\ncommissioner, provided that such approved expenses shall include, but\nneed not be limited to, reasonable travel costs for instructors,\nreasonable costs for the use of technology to provide staff development\nprograms at a distance, and the actual cost to the district of employing\nsubstitute teachers for teachers participating in the program exclusive\nof any state aid payable for such costs.\n  e. The commissioner shall be authorized to adopt regulations to\nimplement the provisions of this subdivision.\n  f. In the event the appropriation for purposes of this paragraph in\nany year is insufficient to pay all claims received pursuant to this\nparagraph, the commissioner shall pay such claims on a prorated basis\namong all districts filing such claims until the appropriation is\nexhausted. For aid payable in the nineteen hundred\nninety-eight--ninety-nine school year, the aid payable pursuant to this\nparagraph shall not exceed one million five hundred thousand dollars\n($1,500,000); for the nineteen hundred ninety-nine--two thousand school\nyear the aid payable pursuant to this paragraph shall not exceed five\nmillion dollars ($5,000,000); and for the two thousand--two thousand one\nschool year and thereafter the aid payable pursuant to this paragraph\nshall not exceed ten million dollars ($10,000,000).\n  10. Aid for rebuilding schools to uphold education (RESCUE). In\naddition to the apportionments made pursuant to subdivisions six, six-a,\nand six-b and paragraph c of subdivision fourteen of section thirty-six\...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Eligible school construction project", or "eligible project,"\nmeans a project for the design, planning, construction, acquisition,\nreconstruction, rehabilitation or improvement of a public school\nbuilding used primarily for instruction that is an accessibility\nproject, an educational technology project, a health and safety project,\nand/or a physical capacity expansion project, that has been approved by\nthe voters of the school district or approved by the trustees or board\nof education for school districts where voter approval is not required\non or after July first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight or before July\nfirst, two thousand three; that such project is contained in the\ndistrict's five year facilities plan; and such project is a critical and\npriority project as identified by such district's safety rating system\nrequired by sections four hundred nine-d and four hundred nine-e of this\nchapter, or, a construction emergency project.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Eligible minor maintenance and repair project" means a project,\nnot otherwise eligible for an apportionment pursuant to subdivision six\nof section thirty-six hundred two of this article, that is related to\nmaintaining and repairing public school buildings used primarily for\ninstruction, including expenditures for minor repair and improvement\nactivities performed to remedy existing minor maintenance deficiencies\nand expenditures for periodic, scheduled maintenance activities intended\nto mitigate the need for excessive capital renovation and rehabilitation\nin the future as documented by a plan developed by the district and\nsubmitted to the commissioner and which has been approved for funding on\nor after July first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight, or before July\nfirst, two thousand two by the commissioner.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Approved project" means an eligible school construction project\nthat has been reviewed by the department and approved by the\ncommissioner pursuant to this subdivision on or after July first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-eight and before July first, two thousand three\n(except as otherwise provided in subparagraph one of paragraph c of this\nsubdivision) for funding disbursement by an apportionment or\napportionments made hereunder.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For the purposes of the expenditure of the maximum additional\napportionment defined in subparagraph 11, "Approved building aidable\nproject" means an approved project for which approved expenditures are\neligible for an apportionment pursuant to subdivisions six, six-a, six-b\nand/or paragraph c of subdivision fourteen of section thirty-six hundred\ntwo of this article and one or more of the following conditions have\nbeen met:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Projects for which letters of intent are on file with the state\neducation department by August 1, 1999;\n  (ii) Projects approved by the voters by January 15, 2000;\n  (iii) In the case of a school district in a city with a population of\none million or more, projects specifically referenced in the five-year\neducational facilities capital plan pursuant to section 2590-p of the\neducation law on file with the commissioner as of August 1, 1999; and\n  (iv) Projects for which letters of intent are filed with the state\neducation department by July 1, 2000 that are determined to be priority\nprojects necessary to: address the safety or health of students and\nstaff including, but not limited to climate control; or to assure\naccessibility of individuals with disabilities.\n  (4-a) For the purposes of the expenditure of the maximum additional\napportionment defined in subparagraph 11-a, "Approved building aidable\nproject" means an approved eligible school construction project.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Accessibility project" means an eligible school construction\nproject which, as a primary purpose, enhances accessibility to public\nschool buildings used primarily for instruction for individuals with\ndisabilities.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Construction emergency project" means an eligible school\nconstruction project to remediate emergency situations which arise in\npublic school buildings used primarily for instruction as a result of\nsignificant damage caused by an unanticipated and sudden occurrence\nwhich results in the necessity for immediate repair.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Educational technology project" means an eligible school\nconstruction project which, as a primary purpose, enhances the use of\ntechnology in public school buildings used primarily for instruction,\nincluding but not limited to, electrical upgrades, wiring, cabling\ninstallations, fiber optics, conduits, raceways, telecommunication\nsystems and wireless options.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Health and safety project" means an eligible school construction\nproject which, as a primary purpose, addresses the reduction or\nelimination of the risk of personal injury or harm to occupants of\npublic school buildings used primarily for instruction, including but\nnot limited to environmental remediation, the eradication of fire and\nhealth code violations, the provision of adequate ventilation, and the\nrehabilitation and repair of existing facilities.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Physical capacity expansion project" means an eligible school\nconstruction project which, as a primary purpose, expands the\navailability of adequate and appropriate instructional space in a public\nschool building used primarily for instruction, including but not\nlimited to expansions which provide for reduced class size.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"District sharing ratio" means the quotient obtained when the sum\nof the resident public school district enrollment of a school district\nas defined in subparagraph four of paragraph n of subdivision one of\nsection thirty-six hundred two of this article and its resident\nnonpublic school enrollment for such school year as defined in\nsubparagraph five of such paragraph, is divided by the sum of such\nenrollments for all school districts for such school year, with the\nresult expressed as a decimal carried to the sixth place without\nrounding. For any maximum additional apportionment calculated pursuant\nto subparagraph eleven of this paragraph, the resident public school\ndistrict enrollment and its resident nonpublic school enrollment for the\nnineteen hundred ninety-eight--ninety-nine school year shall be used to\ncalculate the district sharing ratio. For any maximum additional\napportionment calculated pursuant to subparagraph eleven-a of this\nparagraph, the resident public schoo...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Maximum additional apportionment" for any appropriation first\nmade in support of this subdivision in the education, labor and family\nassistance budget bill enacted for the nineteen hundred ninety-nine--two\nthousand state fiscal year means the result calculated when one hundred\nforty-five million dollars is multiplied by the district sharing ratio\nfor the school district provided, however, that such maximum additional\napportionment shall not be less than twenty thousand dollars and\nprovided further that in the event that the sum of the apportionments\ncalculated pursuant to this section exceeds one hundred forty-five\nmillion dollars, all such apportionments in excess of twenty thousand\ndollars shall be adjusted downward on a prorated basis as determined by\nthe commissioner, provided further that such adjustment shall not reduce\nany such apportionment below twenty thousand dollars. The commissioner\nshall notify each school district by September fifteenth, nineteen\nhundred n...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nnotwithstanding any other provision of this subdivision, any school\ndistrict eligible for a maximum additional apportionment pursuant to\nthis subdivision in excess of one hundred thousand dollars applying to\nthe commissioner for approval of an eligible project for an\napportionment or apportionments pursuant to this subdivision shall\ndemonstrate:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that any eligible project for which such school\ndistrict is seeking funding is contained within its five year capital\nfacilities plan and is a critical priority project as indicated by the\ndistrict's safety rating system as required by sections four hundred\nnine-d and four hundred nine-e of this chapter, or (ii) that such\nproject is considered a construction emergency as defined in\nsubparagraph six of paragraph a of this subdivision, or (iii) that such\nproject is an approved building aidable project; and</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>notwithstanding\nany other provision of this subdivision, that for any school district\neligible for a maximum additional apportionment pursuant to this\nsubdivision, in an amount less than or equal to one hundred thousand\ndollars, the requirements of clauses</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>- (iii) of subparagraph</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nhereof shall not apply.\n  c. Maximum additional apportionment.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A school district which has\nan approved project or projects shall be entitled to an apportionment or\napportionments for such project or projects in an amount whether in the\naggregate or otherwise, not to exceed the maximum additional\napportionment calculated for such school district. Such maximum\nadditional apportionment shall be available to the school district for\nexpenditure for such approved projects in the school years nineteen\nhundred ninety-nine--two thousand through two thousand two--two thousand\nthree, provided that expenditures for such approved project may be made\nfrom such maximum additional apportionment on or after July first, two\nthousand three and prior to June thirtieth, two thousand four if:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nsuch project is approved by the voters of the school district, or is\napproved by the trustees or board of education for such school district\nwhere voter approval is not required, prior to July first, two thousand\nthree; (ii) application is made to the commissioner for approval of such\neligible project as an approved project by August first, two thousand\nthree; and (iii) the commissioner approves such eligible project as an\napproved project by October first, two thousand three. The maximum\nadditional apportionment may be expended in whole or in part in any of\nsuch school years and beyond June thirtieth, two thousand three as\nspecifically authorized by the immediately preceding sentence. The\namount of such maximum additional apportionment not expended, disbursed\nor encumbered for any such year shall be carried over for expenditure\nand disbursement to the next succeeding school year, provided that for\nthe purposes of this subdivision a carryover shall not be authorized\nbeyond the school year two thousand two--two thousand three except as\notherwise authorized hereinabove in this subparagraph. Such maximum\nadditional apportionment may be used to supplement the apportionments\navailable pursuant to subdivisions six, six-a and six-b and paragraph c\nof subdivision fourteen of section thirty-six hundred two and\nsubdivision twelve of this section for expenditures or disbursements for\napproved building aidable projects, provided that, for any school\ndistrict with an enhanced building aid ratio computed pursuant to clause\n(ii) of subparagraph two of paragraph b of subdivision six of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article that is less than nine-tenths the\ntotal of such apportionments plus the apportionment payable pursuant to\nthis subdivision for the approved project costs of the total\napportionment for any approved building aidable project, as limited by\nthe cost allowances specified in paragraph a of subdivision six of\nsection thirty-six hu...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall report to the governor and to the\nlegislature by February first, two thousand three concerning the amount\nof any maximum additional apportionment available to each school\ndistrict, whether in total or in part, that has not been applied for by\nany such school district by January first, two thousand three. If the\ntotal amount of such maximum additional apportionment has not been\napplied for and approved by the commissioner by July first, two thousand\nthree, or, at the latest, applied for by August first, two thousand\nthree and approved by the commissioner by October first, two thousand\nthree as expressly limited by subparagraph one of this paragraph, the\ncommissioner shall report to the governor and to the legislature and\nnotify all districts by November first, two thousand three the total\nremaining aggregate amount of maximum additional apportionments for all\nschool districts which remain uncommitted by such school districts as of\nsuch date, which su...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>establish an application process for school districts which\nrequest the approval of the commissioner for funding for an\napportionment or apportionments for eligible projects; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>provide that approved projects which receive an apportionment or\napportionments pursuant to this subdivision are designed, constructed\nand maintained in the most cost-effective manner possible, which\nminimizes waste and maximizes efficiency. The board of regents and the\ncommissioner shall impose a mechanism for establishing guidelines for\nmonitoring and documenting this process. The commissioner shall take\nappropriate action to ensure a district's compliance with this\nsubparagraph.\n  f. Maintenance of projects. In order to assure effective discharge of\nstate responsibility with respect to the implementation of this\nsubdivision, the board of regents and the commissioner shall provide\nthat no moneys shall be made available to a school district for an\neligible school construction project, exclusive of a construction\nemergency project unless and until such school district has complied\nwith the requirements of sections four hundred nine-d and four hundred\nnine-e of this chapt...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Submit to the commissioner a five-year educational plan, in a\nmanner prescribed by the commissioner, and such plan shall include\nspecific courses of action that will be taken and details describing how\nadditional state and federal funds will be used to improve educational\noutcomes for students and increase the quality of teachers and\nprincipals. This five-year educational plan will be updated and\nsubmitted to the commissioner by September first of each year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Submit a five-year fiscal stabilization plan in a manner\nprescribed by the commissioner, and aligned with the five-year\neducational plan for approval by the commissioner or his designee by\nSeptember first of each year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide a proposed annual budget to the commissioner by the first\nbusiness day of May of each year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide an annual approved budget to the commissioner by July\nfirst of each year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Provide quarterly budget status reports including compliance with\nthe annual approved budget of the district.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Take any additional actions or submit additional documentation\nidentified by the commissioner deemed necessary to ensure the fiscal\nintegrity of the Roosevelt union free school district.\n  12. Capital outlay transition grants. a. Capital outlay transition\ngrants.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall, upon application therefor, certify\nto the dormitory authority of the state of New York the amounts to be\nawarded as grants to school districts in the two thousand two--two\nthousand three state fiscal year for reimbursement of approved\nexpenditures for capital outlays incurred in the two thousand one--two\nthousand two school year, as calculated pursuant to subdivision six of\nsection thirty-six hundred two of this article and this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>School districts which would have been eligible for an\napportionment for base year approved expenditures for capital outlays\npursuant to subdivision six of section thirty-six hundred two of this\narticle in the two thousand two--two thousand three school year under\nthe provisions of such subdivision six in effect in the two thousand\none--two thousand two school year shall be eligible to apply for a grant\npursuant to this paragraph in lieu of an apportionment of aid for such\napproved expenditures pursuant to subdivision six of section thirty-six\nhundred two of this article. Application for such grant shall be made on\nor before the first business day of September, two thousand two in such\nform as the commissioner shall determine, and shall include\ndocumentation of actual approved expenditures for capital outlays\nincurred in the two thousand one--two thousand two school year.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon approval of such application by the commissioner, the\ndistrict shall be eligible for a grant in an amount equal to the lesser\nof:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the product of the amount of the district's base year approved\nexpenditures for capital outlays for school building purposes determined\npursuant to subdivision six of section thirty-six hundred two of this\narticle from its general fund, capital fund or from a reserve fund,\nbased on data on file with the commissioner on the first business day of\nSeptember, two thousand two, multiplied by the sum of the aid ratio\ncomputed for such expenditures pursuant to the provisions of paragraph c\nof subdivision six of section thirty-six hundred two of this article,\nplus the incentive decimal, if any, calculated pursuant to subparagraph\ntwo of paragraph b of such subdivision six, provided that the amount of\nreimbursement attributable to approved expenditures for capital outlays\nfor joint facilities shall be determined pursuant to subparagraph four\nof this paragraph, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount set forth for such school district\nin the school aid listing for the current year produced by the\ncommissioner in May two thousand two and entitled "SA0203".\n  (ii) In the event that the sum of the grants calculated by the\ncommissioner for school districts pursuant to clause</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubparagraph is less than one hundred forty million dollars the\ndistricts shall be eligible for an additional grant in an amount up to\nthe difference between</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the product of the amount of the district's\nbase year approved expenditures for capital outlays for school building\npurposes determined pursuant to subdivision six of section thirty-six\nhundred two of this article from its general fund, capital fund or from\na reserve fund that was approved by the board of education in a city\nwith a population of more than one hundred twenty-five thousand as of\nMay fifteenth, two thousand two or by the voters in another school\ndistrict prior to July first, two thousand two, based on data on file\nwith the commissioner on the first business day of September, two\nthousand two, multiplied by the sum of the aid ratio computed for such\nexpenditures pursuant to the provisions of paragraph c of subdivision\nsix of section thirty-six hundred two of this article, plus the\nincentive decimal, if any, calculated pursuant to subparagraph two of\nparagraph b of such subdivision six, provided that the amount of\nreimbursement attributable to approved expendi...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount calculated pursuant to clause\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subparagraph. Such additional grants shall be approved in\nthe order of the date of receipt of the district's application by the\ncommissioner, up to the total amount of the appropriation; provided that\nin the even that two or more school districts submit application on the\nsame day and full payment of the amounts so requested exceed such\nappropriation, the commissioner shall adjust the grant amounts to\nconform to such appropriation. In no event shall any grant not be\nawarded due to an inability of the commissioner to make a full award of\nthe amount on the application.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of two or more school districts eligible for operating\naid pursuant to section thirty-six hundred two of this article that have\nentered into an agreement in accordance with section one hundred\nnineteen-o of the general municipal law and subdivision six-b of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article for approved expenditures for the\nconstruction or reconstruction of one or more single site joint\nfacilities where the general contract for the project shall have been\nawarded on or after July first, nineteen hundred ninety-three, and the\nproject and joint agreement shall have been approved by the commissioner\nand, for participating school districts in which the school budget is\nsubject to voter approval, the joint agreement has been approved by the\nvoters of the district, the lead district shall be eligible for the\nproduct of such base year approved expenditures for capital outlays for\nschool building purposes, multiplied by the sum of</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the product for\neach of the participating districts of the district's aid ratio computed\nfor such expenditures pursuant to the provisions of paragraph c of\nsubdivision six of section thirty-six hundred two of this article\nmultiplied by the district's share of the use of the facility, plus (ii)\nthe incentive decimal, if any, calculated pursuant to subparagraph two\nof paragraph b of such subdivision six.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law to the contrary, the\namounts payable pursuant to this paragraph shall be certified by the\ncommissioner in accordance with section sixteen hundred eighty-nine-f of\nthe public authorities law and shall be paid to school districts by the\ndormitory authority of the state of New York, within the amounts\nappropriated for such purpose, from the proceeds of bonds and notes\nissued pursuant to such section sixteen hundred eighty-nine-f. Such\npayment shall fulfill any obligation of the state or the commissioner to\napportion funds pursuant to this paragraph, and whenever a school\ndistrict has been apportioned more money pursuant to this paragraph than\nthat to which it is entitled, the commissioner may deduct such amount\nfrom the next apportionment to be made to such school district.\n  b. Excess capital outlay transition grants.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For aid payable in the\ntwo thousand three--two thousand four school year, the commissioner\nshall, within the amounts appropriated for such purpose, provide grants\nto school districts in the amount of any excess of the product of the\namount of such school district's approved expenditures incurred in the\ntwo thousand one--two thousand two school year for capital outlays for\nschool building purposes determined pursuant to subdivision six of\nsection thirty-six hundred two of this article from its general fund,\ncapital fund or from a reserve fund, multiplied by the sum of the aid\nratio selected for use in the two thousand two--two thousand three\nschool year for such expenditures pursuant to the provisions of\nparagraph c of subdivision six of section thirty-six hundred two of this\narticle, plus the incentive decimal, if any, calculated for the two\nthousand two--two thousand three school year pursuant to subparagraph\ntwo of paragraph b of such subdivision six, provided that the ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A school district which was eligible for a grant pursuant to\nparagraph a of this subdivision and where the product of the amount of\nsuch school district's approved expenditures incurred in the two\nthousand one--two thousand two school year for capital outlays for\nschool building purposes determined pursuant to subdivision six of\nsection thirty-six hundred two of this article from its general fund,\ncapital fund or from a reserve fund, multiplied by the sum of the aid\nratio selected for use in the two thousand two--two thousand three\nschool year for such expenditures pursuant to the provisions of\nparagraph c of subdivision six of section thirty-six hundred two of this\narticle, plus the incentive decimal, if any, calculated for the two\nthousand two--two thousand three school year pursuant to subparagraph\ntwo of paragraph b of such subdivision six, provided that the amount of\nreimbursement attributable to approved expenditures for capital outlays\nfor joint facilities shall be...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, grants\nawarded pursuant to this paragraph shall be payable from funds\nappropriated for such purpose and shall be apportioned in accordance\nwith the payment schedule contained in section thirty-six hundred nine-a\nof this article.\n  c. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary,\napproved expenditures for capital outlays incurred in the two thousand\none--two thousand two school year shall not be eligible for an\napportionment pursuant to subdivision six of section thirty-six hundred\ntwo of this article, provided that nothing in this subdivision shall be\nconstrued to limit the eligibility of a school district for\nreorganization incentive building aid in the two thousand two--two\nthousand three school year based on computations pursuant to subdivision\nsix of section thirty-six hundred two of this article. Expenditures\nincurred for lease or other annual payments under the provisions of\nsection four hund...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section sixty-one of\nthe chapter of the laws of two thousand four which added this\nsubdivision the amounts to be awarded as grants to school districts in\nthe two thousand four--two thousand five state fiscal year for\nreimbursement of approved expenses for transportation capital, debt\nservice and leases for the two thousand three--two thousand four school\nyear, as calculated pursuant to subdivision seven of section thirty-six\nhundred two of this article and this subdivision.\n  b. School districts which would have been eligible for an\napportionment for base year approved expenses for transportation\ncapital, debt service and leases, as defined in subdivision two of\nsection thirty-six hundred twenty-three-a of this article, pursuant to\nsubdivision seven of section thirty-six hundred two of this article in\nthe two thousand four--two thousand five school year under the\nprovisions of such subdivision seven in effect in the two thousand\nthree--two thousand four school year shall be eligible to apply for a\ngrant pursuant to this paragraph in lieu of an apportionment of aid for\nsuch approved expenses pursuant to subdivision seven of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article.  Application for such grant\nshall be made on or before the first business day of November, two\nthousand four in such form as the commissioner shall determine, and\nshall include documentation of actual approved transportation capital,\ndebt service and/or lease expense incurred in the two thousand\nthree--two thousand four school year or that would otherwise have been\neligible for an apportionment in the two thousand four--two thousand\nfive school year pursuant to subdivision seven of section thirty-six\nhundred two of this article as it existed in the two thousand three--two\nthousand four school year.\n  c. Upon approval of such application by the commissioner, the district\nshall be eligible for a grant in an amount equal to the apportionment\ncomputed pursuant to subdivis...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fifty-four of the chapter of the laws of two\nthousand four which added this subdivision from the proceeds of bonds\nand notes issued pursuant to such section thirty-six. Such payment shall\nfulfill any obligation of the state or the commissioner to apportion\nfunds pursuant to this paragraph or subdivision seven of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article for approved expenses for\ntransportation capital, debt service or leases, and whenever a school\ndistrict has been apportioned more money pursuant to this paragraph than\nthat to which it is entitled, the commissioner may deduct such amount\nfrom the next apportionment to be made to such school district.\n  14. Expanding our children's education and learning (EXCEL) a.\nEstablishment of the EXCEL program. There is hereby established the\nexpanding our children's education and learning (EXCEL) program to\nprovide project financing or assistance in the form of grants to\neligible school districts, in addition to, or in lieu of, the\napportionments made pursuant to subdivisions six, six-a, six-b, six-c,\nsix-d, six-e, six-f and paragraph c of subdivision fourteen of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article, and subdivisions ten and twelve\nof this section, for the costs of EXCEL school facility projects. An\napportionment for any such project shall initially be available in the\nstate fiscal year commencing April first, two thousand six.\nNotwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the dormitory\nauthority of the state of New York shall be authorized to issue bonds or\nnotes in an aggregate amount not to exceed two billion six hundred\nmillion dollars for purposes of the EXCEL program.\n  b. Definitions. The following terms, whenever used or referred to in\nthis subdivision, unless the context indicates otherwise, shall have the\nfollowing meanings:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"EXCEL project". An EXCEL project shall include, but not be\nlimited to, the acquisition, design, planning, construction,\nreconstruction, rehabilitation, preservation, development, improvement\nor modernization of an EXCEL school facility, where such project:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for a school district other than the city school district\nof the city of New York, a construction project that has been reviewed\nby the department and approved by the commissioner pursuant to this\nsubdivision, where a certification that a general construction contract\nhad been awarded for such project by or on behalf of the district was\nnot on file with the commissioner as of April first, two thousand six or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the city school district of the city of New York, a project\nwhich is listed and contained in the five year capital plan, which has\nbeen approved and adopted by the city council pursuant to section\ntwenty-five hundred ninety-p of this chapter, for the two thousand five\nthrough two thousand nine fiscal years, and provided that such project\nmust commence, as close as practicable, according to the schedule set\nforth in the five year capital plan as amended and approved by the city\ncouncil as of July, two thousand five, and\n  (ii) falls within one or more of the following categories:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An education technology project which, as a primary purpose,\nenhances the use of technology including but not limited to,\ninstructional content with video streaming, electrical upgrades, wiring,\ncabling installations, internet connections, fiber optics, conduits,\nraceways, telecommunication systems, hardware, electronic commerce and\nwireless options;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A health and safety project which, as a primary purpose, addresses\nthe reduction or elimination of the risk of personal injury or harm to\noccupants of public school buildings used primarily for instruction,\nincluding but not limited to environmental remediation, the eradication\nof fire and health code violations, the provisions of adequate\nventilation including heating, ventilation and air conditioning\nequipment, and the rehabilitation and repair of existing facilities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An accessibility project which, as a primary purpose, enhances\naccessibility to public school buildings used primarily for instruction\nfor individuals with disabilities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A physical capacity expansion project or school construction\nproject which, as a primary purpose, expands the availability of\nadequate and appropriate instructional space in a public school building\nused primarily for instruction, including but not limited to expansions\nwhich provide for reduced class size and science laboratories; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An energy project which, as a primary purpose, reduces energy\ncosts and/or energy consumption.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"EXCEL school facility". An EXCEL school facility shall mean an\nexisting or proposed facility or other property real and personal, and\nother appurtenances thereto to be utilized by a school district for\neducation purposes.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_e__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Eligible project costs". Eligible project costs, for purposes of\nthe EXCEL program shall mean any expenditures for an EXCEL project,\nwhere such project is eligible for an apportionment pursuant to\nsubdivisions six, six-a, six-b, six-f and/or paragraph c of subdivision\nfourteen of section thirty-six hundred two of this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_e__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Eligible school district" means a school district eligible to\nreceive an apportionment in lieu of operating aid in the two thousand\nsix--two thousand seven school year, apportioned pursuant to section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article, or eligible to receive an\napportionment of total foundation aid in the two thousand seven--two\nthousand eight school year and thereafter, pursuant to such section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_e__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Maximum additional apportionment" means the sum of the following\namounts:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For an eligible school district that is eligible for the high-need\nsupplemental building aid ratio pursuant to the provisions of clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subparagraph two of paragraph c of subdivision six of section\nthirty-six hundred two of this article, other than a city school\ndistrict in a city having a population of one million inhabitants or\nmore, an amount equal to the product of seven hundred seventy-eight\ndollars and twenty-two cents ($778.22) multiplied by the public school\ndistrict enrollment of the district in the two thousand five--two\nthousand six school year, as computed pursuant to subparagraph two of\nparagraph n of subdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this\narticle as based on data on file for the school aid computer listing\nproduced by the commissioner in support of the enacted budget for the\ntwo thousand six--two thousand seven school year and entitled "SA060-7".\n  (ii) For any other eligible school district, other than a city school\ndistrict in a city having a population of one million inhabitants or\nmore, an amount equal to the product of three hundred twenty dollars and\nforty-six cents ($320.46) multiplied by the public school district\nenrollment of the district in the two thousand five--two thousand six\nschool year, as computed pursuant to subparagraph two of paragraph n of\nsubdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this article as\nbased on data on file for the school aid computer listing produced by\nthe commissioner of education in support of the enacted budget for the\ntwo thousand six--two thousand seven school year and entitled "SA060-7".\n  (iii) For an eligible city school district in a city having a\npopulation of one million inhabitants or more one billion eight hundred\nmillion dollars.\n  c. EXCEL apportionment.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>EXCEL apportionment for school\nenhancement.  Funds in an aggregate amount not to exceed eight hundred\nmillion dollars shall be available for grants to eligible school\ndistricts other than a city school district in a city having a\npopulation of one million inhabitants or more. Each eligible school\ndistrict which has an EXCEL project or projects shall be entitled to a\ngrant or grants for such project or projects in an amount whether in the\naggregate or otherwise, not to exceed the maximum additional\napportionment calculated for such school district. The amount of such\nmaximum additional apportionment not expended, disbursed or encumbered\nfor any such year shall be carried over for expenditure and disbursement\nto the next succeeding school year. Such maximum additional\napportionment may be used, at the option of the school district, in lieu\nof, or to supplement, the apportionments available pursuant to\nsubdivisions six, six-a, six-b, six-c, six-d, six-e, six-f and paragraph\...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>EXCEL apportionment for city facilities enhancement. Funds in an\naggregate amount not to exceed one billion eight hundred million dollars\nshall be available for grants to a city school district in a city having\na population of one million inhabitants or more. Such school district\nshall be entitled to a grant or grants for each EXCEL project or\nprojects in an amount whether in the aggregate or otherwise, not to\nexceed the maximum additional apportionment calculated for such school\ndistrict. The amount of such maximum additional apportionment not\nexpended, disbursed or encumbered for any such year shall be carried\nover for expenditure and disbursement to the next succeeding school\nyear. Such maximum additional apportionment may be used, at the option\nof the school district, in lieu of, or to supplement, the apportionments\navailable pursuant to subdivisions six, six-a, six-b, six-c, six-d,\nsix-e, six-f and paragraph c of subdivision fourteen of section\nthirty-six hundred two...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall, upon application therefor in such form as\nthe commissioner may require, determine the amounts to be awarded as\ngrants to school districts as calculated pursuant to this subdivision.\nThe amounts determined pursuant to this subdivision shall be certified\nby the commissioner in accordance with subdivision six of section\nsixteen hundred eighty-nine-i of the public authorities law. Upon the\nissuance of bonds by the dormitory authority of the state of New York\npursuant to such section sixteen hundred eighty-nine-i, the amounts of\nmoney so certified shall be paid to school districts by the dormitory\nauthority from the proceeds of such bonds, provided, however, that the\npayment schedule set forth in subdivision one of this section shall not\napply to such payments. Such payment shall fulfill any obligation of the\nstate or the commissioner to apportion funds pursuant to this\nsubdivision, and whenever a school district has been apportioned more\nmoney pursuant...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Bonds" shall mean general obligation bonds issued pursuant to the\n"smart schools bond act of 2014" in accordance with article VII of the\nNew York state constitution and article five of the state finance law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Smart schools investment plan" shall mean a document prepared by\na school district setting forth the smart schools project or projects to\nbe undertaken with such district's smart schools allocation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Smart schools project" shall mean a capital project as set forth\nand defined in subparagraphs four, five, six or seven of this paragraph.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Pre-kindergarten or transportable classroom unit (TCU)\nreplacement project" shall mean a capital project which, as a primary\npurpose, expands the availability of adequate and appropriate\ninstructional space for pre-kindergarten or provides for the expansion\nor construction of adequate and appropriate instructional space to\nreplace TCUs.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Community connectivity project" shall mean a capital project\nwhich, as a primary purpose, expands high-speed broadband or wireless\ninternet connectivity in the local community, including school buildings\nand campuses, for enhanced educational opportunity in the state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Classroom technology project" shall mean a capital project to\nexpand high-speed broadband or wireless internet connectivity solely for\nschool buildings and campuses, or to acquire learning technology\nhardware for schools, classrooms, and student use, including but not\nlimited to whiteboards, computer servers, desktop computers, laptop\ncomputers, and tablet computers.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"School safety and security technology project" shall mean a\ncapital project to install high-tech security features in school\nbuildings and on school campuses, including but not limited to video\nsurveillance, emergency notification systems and physical access\ncontrols, for enhanced educational opportunity in the state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Selected school aid" shall mean the sum of the amounts set forth\nas "FOUNDATION AID", "FULL DAY K CONVERSION", "BOCES", "SPECIAL\nSERVICES", "HIGH COST EXCESS COST", "PRIVATE EXCESS COST", "HARDWARE &amp;\nTECHNOLOGY", "SOFTWARE, LIBRARY, TEXTBOOK", "TRANSPORTATION INCL\nSUMMER", "OPERATING REORG INCENTIVE", "CHARTER SCHOOL TRANSITIONAL",\n"ACADEMIC ENHANCEMENT", "HIGH TAX AID", and "SUPPLEMENTAL PUB EXCESS\nCOST" under the heading "2013-14 BASE YEAR AIDS" in the school aid\ncomputer listing produced by the commissioner in support of the\nexecutive budget proposal for the two thousand fourteen-fifteen school\nyear.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_c__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Smart schools allocation" shall mean, for each school district,\nthe product of</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two billion dollars ($2,000,000,000) multiplied by\n(ii) the quotient of such school district's selected school aid divided\nby the total selected school aid to all school districts.\n  b. Smart schools investment plans.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to the approval of the\ndirector of the budget, the commissioner shall issue guidelines setting\nforth required components and eligibility criteria for smart schools\ninvestment plans to be submitted by school districts. Such guidelines\nshall include but not be limited to:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3641__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a timeline for school district\nsubmission of smart schools investment plans; (ii) any requirements for\nthe use of available state procurement options where applicable; (iii)\nany limitations on the amount of a district's smart schools allocation\nthat may be used for assets with a short probable life; and (iv) the\nloan of smart schools classroom technology pursuant to section seven\nhundred fifty-five of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No school district shall be entitled to a smart schools grant\nuntil such district shall have submitted a smart schools investment plan\nto the department and received the commissioner's approval of such\ninvestment plan. In developing such investment plan, school districts\nshall consult with parents, teachers, students, community members and\nother stakeholders.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall review all smart schools investment plans\nfor compliance with all eligibility criteria and other requirements set\nforth in the guidelines. The commissioner may approve or reject such\nplans, or may return such plans to the school district for\nmodifications; provided that notwithstanding any inconsistent provision\nof law, the commissioner shall approve no such plan first submitted to\nthe department on or after April fifteenth, two thousand seventeen,\nunless such plan calculates the amount of classroom technology to be\nloaned to students attending nonpublic schools pursuant to section seven\nhundred fifty-five of this chapter in a manner that includes the amount\nbudgeted by the school district for servers, wireless access points and\nother portable connectivity devices to be acquired as part of a school\nconnectivity project. Upon approval, the smart schools project or\nprojects described in the investment plan shall be eligible for smart\nschools grants. A...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any amendments or supplements to a smart schools investment plan\nshall be submitted to the department for approval, and shall not take\neffect until such approval is granted.\n  c. Expenditure of money.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Smart schools grants. Each school\ndistrict which has an approved smart schools investment plan including a\nsmart schools project or projects shall be entitled to a grant or grants\nfor the smart schools project or projects included therein in an amount,\nwhether in the aggregate or otherwise, not to exceed the smart schools\nallocation calculated for such school district. The amount of such\nallocation not expended, disbursed or encumbered for any school year\nshall be carried over for expenditure and disbursement to the next\nsucceeding school year. Expenditures from the smart schools allocation\nshall not be eligible for aid under any other provision of this chapter.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The amounts determined pursuant to this subdivision to be paid to\nschool districts shall be certified by the commissioner in accordance\nwith this subdivision. If, upon the option of a school district, a smart\nschools investment plan directs that an amount be transferred or\nsuballocated to a department, agency, or public authority to be spent on\nbehalf of the school district, such amounts shall be transferred or\nsuballocated, consistent with such plan, upon the approval of the\ndirector of the budget. The amounts of money so certified or made\navailable shall be paid by the comptroller in accordance with\nappropriations therefor, provided, however, that the payment schedule\nset forth in subdivision one of this section shall not apply to such\npayments. Such payment shall fulfill any obligation of the state or the\ncommissioner to apportion funds pursuant to this subdivision, and\nwhenever a school district has been apportioned more money pursuant to\nthis subdivision than that to...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>four\nthousand five hundred fifty dollars and twenty-six cents ($4,550.26);\nmultiplied by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the regional cost index calculated in two thousand\neighteen, reflecting an analysis of labor market costs based on median\nsalaries in professional occupations that require similar credentials to\nthose of positions in the education field, but not including those\noccupations in the education field; multiplied by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the modified EN\nindex; and multiplied by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the learning loss wealth factor.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this paragraph, the "learning loss wealth factor"\nshall be equal to the positive difference, if any, of seventy-five\nhundredths (0.75) less half of the combined wealth ratio computed\npursuant to subparagraph one of paragraph c of subdivision three of\nsection thirty-six hundred two of this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this paragraph, the "modified EN index" shall be\nequal to the modified EN percent divided by the statewide average\nmodified EN percent, provided that for the two thousand twenty-one--two\nthousand twenty-two school year, the statewide average modified EN\npercent shall be equal to five thousand five hundred sixty-five\nten-thousandths (0.5565).\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this paragraph, the "modified EN percent" shall be\nequal to the modified EN count divided by public school district\nenrollment for the base year computed pursuant to paragraph n of\nsubdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For purposes of this paragraph, the "modified EN count" shall\nequal the sum of (A) the product of fifty percent (0.5) multiplied by\nthe English language learner count computed pursuant to paragraph o of\nsubdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of this article, plus\n(B) the sparsity count computed pursuant to paragraph r of subdivision\none of section thirty-six hundred two of this article, plus (C) the\nproduct of sixty-five hundredths (0.65) multiplied by the three-year\naverage small area income and poverty estimate rate computed pursuant to\nparagraph mm of subdivision one of section thirty-six hundred two of\nthis article and multiplied further by public school district enrollment\nfor the base year as computed pursuant to paragraph n of subdivision one\nof section thirty-six hundred two of this article, plus (D) the product\nof sixty-five hundredths (0.65) multiplied by the three-year average\neconomically disadvantaged rate defined pursuant to paragraph ll of\nsubdiv...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fourteen\nand two hundred eighty-six thousandths percent (0.14286) of such grants\nfor implementation of evidence-based summer enrichment programs;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nfourteen and two hundred eighty-six thousandths percent (0.14286) for\nimplementation of evidence-based comprehensive afterschool programs; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3641__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the remaining funds for activities to address learning loss by\nsupporting the implementation of evidence-based interventions, such as\nsummer learning or summer enrichment, extended day, comprehensive\nafterschool programs, or extended school year programs. School districts\nshall ensure that such interventions respond to students' academic,\nsocial, and emotional needs and address the disproportionate impact of\nthe coronavirus on low-income students, children with disabilities,\nEnglish learners, migrant students, students experiencing homelessness,\nand children in foster care.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>