<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3650-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3650-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3650_A">
        <num>3650-A</num>
        <heading>State comprehensive school bus driver safety training council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3650-a. State comprehensive school bus driver safety training\ncouncil. 1. There is hereby created and established in the department of\neducation a council, to be known as the state comprehensive school bus\ndriver safety training council.  The council shall advise and assist the\ncommissioner in the development and updating of the school bus driver\nsafety training program and such other related matters as the council\nand commissioner shall deem appropriate.  Such council shall consist of\nthe commissioner of education as chair, the superintendent of state\npolice, the commissioner of transportation and the commissioner of motor\nvehicles and eight other members to be appointed by the governor\nincluding the following:\n  a. Two members to be appointed upon the recommendation of the speaker\nof the assembly.\n  b. Two members to be appointed upon the recommendation of the\ntemporary president of the senate.\n  c. One member to be appointed upon the recommendation of the minority\nleader of the assembly.\n  d. One member to be appointed upon the recommendation of the minority\nleader of the senate.\n  2. The members of the council, other than the ex officio members,\nshall serve for terms of two years. Such terms shall coincide with the\nelection of the members of the state legislature and shall commence on\nthe fifteenth day of January. Vacancies shall be filled for unexpired\nterms in the same manner as the original appointments.\n  3. The council shall meet at least semi-annually at the call of the\nchair. Additional meetings may be called upon at least five days notice\nby the chair or by petition of five members of the council.\n  4. No member of the council shall be disqualified from holding any\nother public office, nor shall employment be forfeited by reason of the\nmember's appointment hereunder, notwithstanding the provisions of any\ngeneral, special or local law, ordinance, county or city charter.\n  5. Each member of the council shall receive reimbursement for actual\nand necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.\n  6. The council shall, during its first year, consider and may make\nrecommendations on the following issues:\n  a. inclement weather procedures;\n  b. emergency school bus evacuation techniques;\n  c. safety equipment training;\n  d. promotion of public safety;\n  e. unauthorized boarding of buses; and\n  f. services for students with disabilities.\n  7. The council shall make, on or before January first of each year, an\nannual report of its activities and such recommendations as it may deem\nappropriate to the board of regents concerning school bus driver safety\ntraining programs.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>