<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3701"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-3701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3701">
        <num>3701</num>
        <heading>Property to be held in trust for public schools</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3701. Property to be held in trust for public schools.  Real and\npersonal estate may be granted, conveyed, devised, bequeathed and given\nin trust and in perpetuity or otherwise, to the state, or to the regents\nor to the commissioner of education for the support or benefit of the\npublic schools, within the state, or within any part or portion of it,\nor of any particular public schools within it; and to any county, or the\ndistrict superintendents of any county, or to any city or any board of\nofficers thereof, or to any supervisory district or its superintendent,\nor to any town, or supervisor of a town, or to any school district or\nits trustees or board of education, for the support and benefit of\npublic schools within such county, city, supervisory district, town or\nschool district, or within any part or portion thereof respectively, or\nfor the support and benefit of any particular public schools therein.\nNo such grant, conveyance, devise or bequest shall be held void for the\nwant of a named or competent trustee or donee, but where no trustee or\ndonee, or an incompetent one is named, the title and trust shall vest in\nthe people of the state, subject to its acceptance by the legislature,\nbut such acceptance shall be presumed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>