<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-379"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-379"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="379"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-379/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-379/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-379/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-379/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_379">
        <num>379</num>
        <heading>Transfer of jurisdiction to state university</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 379. Transfer of jurisdiction to state university. As soon as\npracticable after the completion of work, the fund shall make available\nto the state university trustees for the purposes intended the academic\nbuildings, dormitories and other facilities constructed, acquired,\nreconstructed, rehabilitated or improved under this article.\nResponsibility for the maintenance and routine repair of facilities\nother than dormitories and for the maintenance and upkeep of adjacent\nreal property shall remain in the fund after the completion of work and\nshall be transferred from the fund to the state university trustees\npursuant to agreement between them, and upon such transfer all right,\ntitle and interest of the fund in such facilities shall terminate;\nprovided that in the case of facilities constructed, acquired,\nreconstructed, rehabilitated or improved solely out of appropriations\nand grants or gifts of money, such responsibilities shall be so\ntransferred not later than four months after the completion of work.\nPrior to the transfer of such responsibilities, the state university\ntrustees may act as agent for the fund for the maintenance and routine\nrepair of such facilities and for the maintenance and upkeep of adjacent\nreal property. This section shall not apply when the state university\nconstruction fund acts as agent for a foundation or other not-for-profit\nentity created by or for the state university of New York or when\nproviding facilities or projects authorized by section three hundred\nseventy-two-a of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>