<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-382"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-382"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="382"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-382/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-382/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-382/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-382/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_382">
        <num>382</num>
        <heading>Annual report of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 382. Annual report of trustees.  1. The fund shall submit to the\ngovernor, the regents, the state university trustees, the legislature,\nthe chairs of the senate finance committee and the assembly ways and\nmeans committee, annually on or before January first, a full report of\nits activities and operations through the thirtieth day of the preceding\nSeptember, including details as to state university construction\nprojects in planning, in construction and completed, the performance\nrecord of the fund in completing construction in accordance with the\ndesired completion dates and within the estimated costs recommended by\nthe governor and approved by the legislature, the architects, engineers\nand other private consultants engaged by the fund on a contract basis\nand a statement of the total amount paid and yet to be paid, or\nestimated yet to be paid, under such contract, the letting agency and\nsuccessful bidder for each construction project, the moneys made\navailable for the purposes of the fund, details as to any lease\nagreements executed by the fund and the annual rentals required to be\npaid on account thereof, and such other information related to the\nactivities and operations of the fund as it may consider pertinent. Such\nreport shall also contain details as to all contracts which, pursuant to\nsection three hundred seventy-six of this chapter, have been entered\ninto without public letting where an emergency condition exists,\nincluding the nature of such emergency condition and the state-operated\ninstitution at which the condition occurred.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\non or before November fifteenth of each year, the state university\nconstruction fund shall submit, and thereafter may resubmit, to the\ndirector of the budget, the state comptroller, the chairman of the\nsenate finance committee and the chairman of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee a report setting forth the amounts, if any, of all annual\nrentals and other payments estimated to become due in the succeeding\nstate fiscal year to the dormitory authority from the fund pursuant to\nany leases, subleases or other agreements between the dormitory\nauthority and the fund entered into on or after July first, nineteen\nhundred eighty-eight, to provide state university educational facilities\nfor the state university of New York. Such report shall separately state\nthe amount of income earned on the investment of moneys in the state\nuniversity construction fund educational facilities payment account\nsince the date of the last such report.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>