<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-402-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-402-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="402-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-402-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-402-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-402-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-402-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_402_A">
        <num>402-A</num>
        <heading>Procedures for closing a school building</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The current and projected pupil enrollment, the prospective need\nfor such building, the ramifications of such closing upon the community,\ninitial costs and savings resulting from such closing, the potential\ndisposability of the closed school;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Possible use of such school building for other educational\nprograms or administrative services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The effect of such closing on personnel needs, and on the costs of\ninstruction, administration, transportation and other support services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Type, age and physical condition of such building, outstanding\nindebtedness, maintenance and energy costs, recent or planned\nimprovements for the building, and such building's special features;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Ability of the other schools in the affected district to\naccommodate pupils if such school building closes; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Possible shared utilization of space in such school building\nduring or after regular school hours, as permitted in section four\nhundred fourteen of this chapter.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such educational impact statement shall be filed with the board\nof education or in a city with a population of one million or more, with\nthe city board and/or the appropriate community school board. Such board\nof education shall publish a notice of such proposed closing in at least\none newspaper of general circulation in the community once a week for\ntwo weeks, and shall post a notice conspicuously in the affected school\ndistrict, which shall also be circulated to elected state and local\npublic officials who represent the affected communities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After the statement has been filed and circulated, the board of\neducation, and in a city with a population of one million or more, the\ncity board or, where applicable, the community school board shall hold a\npublic hearing to evaluate the impact of the proposed closing on the\naffected district. Such hearing shall be held within sixty days of the\nissuance of the educational impact statement at times and places\nconvenient and accessible to the public. Notice of such hearing shall be\npublished by such board of education in at least one newspaper of\ngeneral circulation in the community once a week for two weeks, and\nshall be posted conspicuously in the affected school district, and shall\nalso be circulated to elected state and local public officials who\nrepresent the affected communities. At such hearing, factors enumerated\nin subdivision two of this section shall be considered and alternatives\nmay be presented by interested parties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_402_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of education shall render a decision at a regular or\nspecial meeting, the results of which shall be recorded and made\navailable to the public. In a city having a population of one million or\nmore, the community school board shall submit written recommendations\nfor schools within its jurisdiction to the city board. The city board\nshall render a decision for all proposed school building closings at a\nregular or special meeting, the results of which shall be recorded and\nmade available to the public.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>