<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-09-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="409-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-409-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_409_N">
        <num>409-N</num>
        <heading>Maximum temperatures in school buildings and facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 409-n. Maximum temperatures in school buildings and facilities. All\ncommon, union free, central, central high schools, city school districts\nand boards of cooperative educational services shall develop a policy\nfor ensuring the health and safety of students, faculty, and other\nemployees, on extreme heat condition days. For the purpose of this\nsection, extreme heat condition days shall be defined as days when the\noccupiable educational and support services spaces are found to be\neighty-two degrees or greater Fahrenheit. For the purpose of this\nsection, support services spaces shall not include kitchen areas used in\nthe preparation of food for consumption by students. For the purpose of\nthis section, room temperature shall be measured at a shaded location,\nthree feet above the floor near the center of the room. Schools shall be\nrequired to take action to relieve heat-related discomfort when the\noccupied space temperature reaches eighty-two degrees Fahrenheit. These\nactions may include, but are not limited to, turning off the overhead\nlights, pulling down shades or blinds, turning on fans, opening\nclassroom doors and windows to increase circulation, turning off unused\nelectronics that produce heat, and providing water breaks. Such policy\nshall include a plan to remove students and staff from occupied spaces\nwhere practicable when educational and support services spaces reach\neighty-eight degrees Fahrenheit.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>