<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4105"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4105"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4105"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4105">
        <num>4105</num>
        <heading>Required attendance upon instruction</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4105.  Required attendance upon instruction.  1. Every Indian child\nbetween six and sixteen years of age, in proper physical and mental\ncondition to attend school, shall regularly attend upon instruction at a\nschool in which at least the common school branches of reading,\nspelling, writing, arithmetic, English grammar and geography are taught\nin English, or upon equivalent instruction by a competent teacher\nelsewhere than at such school as follows: Every Indian child between\nfourteen and sixteen years of age not regularly and lawfully engaged in\nany useful employment or service, and every such child between six and\nfourteen years of age, shall so attend upon instruction as many days\nannually during the period between the first days of September and the\nfollowing July as a public school of the community or district of the\nreservation, in which such child resides, shall be in session during the\nsame period.\n  2. If any such child shall so attend upon instruction elsewhere than\nat the public school, such instruction shall be at least equivalent to\nthe instruction given to Indian children of like age at a school of the\ncommunity or district in which such child shall reside; and such\nattendance shall be for at least as many hours of each day thereof, as\nare required of children of like age at public schools and no greater\ntotal amount of holidays and vacations shall be deducted from such\nattendance during the period such attendance is required than is allowed\nin public schools for children of like age. Occasional absences from\nsuch attendance not amounting to irregular attendance in a fair meaning\nof the term, shall be allowed upon such excuses only as would be allowed\nin like cases by the general rules and practices of public schools.\n  3. Transportation shall be provided for Indian children who live more\nthan a mile from the elementary and high schools they attend, and the\ncommissioner of education is hereby empowered to make provision for the\ncost of the same as a part of the care and education of Indian children.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>