<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4118"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4118"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4118"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4118/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4118/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4118">
        <num>4118</num>
        <heading>Attendance at post-secondary institutions by Native American students</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4118. Attendance at post-secondary institutions by Native American\nstudents.  1. The education department shall select students for\nattendance at post-secondary institutions from the several Indian tribes\nlocated within this state. In making such selection, due regard shall be\nhad to a just participation in the privileges of this section by each of\nsuch several tribes. If practicable, reference shall also be had to the\npopulation of each of such tribes in determining such selection.\nEligibility for selection shall not be limited to Native Americans\nresiding on reservations.\n  2. No such student may attend a post-secondary institution outside\nthis state, nor one that has not been approved by the New York state\nboard of regents, nor may he be supported or educated at such\ninstitutions for a period exceeding four years unless he is enrolled in\na program normally requiring five years of training.\n  3. Such sum as may be appropriated for the support and education of\nNative American students in such institutions shall be paid from the\ntreasury, upon the audit and warrant of the comptroller, on vouchers\napproved by the education department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>