<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4204-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4204-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4204-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4204-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4204-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4204-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4204-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4204_B">
        <num>4204-B</num>
        <heading>School district contribution and state reimbursement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4204-b. School district contribution and state reimbursement. 1. For\nthe two thousand twelve--two thousand thirteen and prior school years,\nthe school district of which any such child is resident at the time of\nadmission or readmission to any of the institutions or facilities\nsubject to this article shall be required to reimburse the state on\naccount of any expenditure made by the state for any such child\ninitially appointed by the commissioner to such institution or facility\nafter June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-seven in an amount equal\nto the school district basic contribution defined in subdivision eight\nof section forty-four hundred one of this title, except that for the two\nthousand eleven--two thousand twelve and two thousand twelve--two\nthousand thirteen school years, such school district shall be\nresponsible for reimbursing the state in an amount equal to the positive\ndifference of the school district basic contribution minus the tuition\npaid by such school district pursuant to section forty-two hundred four\nor forty-two hundred seven of this article.\n  2. For the two thousand thirteen--two thousand fourteen school year\nand thereafter, the child's current school district of residence shall\nbe required to reimburse the state on account of any expenditure made by\nthe state for any such child in an amount equal to the positive\ndifference of the school district basic contribution minus the tuition\npaid by such school district pursuant to section forty-two hundred four\nor forty-two hundred seven of this article.\n  3. The state comptroller may deduct from any state funds which become\ndue to a school district for each year in which such child was in\nattendance at such institution or facility an amount equal to the\nreimbursement required to be made by such school district in accordance\nwith this section, and the amount so deducted shall not be included in\nthe operating expense of such district for the purposes of computing the\napproved operating expense pursuant to paragraph t of subdivision one of\nsection thirty-six hundred two of this chapter.\n  4. The state shall reimburse the school district of which any such\nchild is resident at the time of admission or readmission to any of the\ninstitutions subject to this article for tuition paid to the institution\nin an amount equal to the positive difference between the amount of such\ntuition and the school district basic contribution. Such state\nreimbursement to the school district shall not be paid prior to April\nfirst of the school year in which such tuition costs are paid by the\nschool district. The tuition incurred through December thirty-first of\nsuch school year shall be payable prior to June thirtieth of such school\nyear, provided that a claim is submitted on or before June first.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>