<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4209"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4209">
        <num>4209</num>
        <heading>Blind and deaf children and blind and cerebral palsied children</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4209. Blind and deaf children and blind and cerebral palsied\nchildren.  1. All children who are both blind and deaf or both blind and\ncerebral palsied shall be admitted as state pupils into one of the\ninstitutions described in this article for the instruction of the deaf\nor blind and under the same conditions of eligibility as are provided\nfor the admission of deaf or blind state pupils.\n  2. In the discretion of the commissioner of education a sum not to\nexceed a sum equal to double the average annual per capita cost for\npupils attending all of the schools which are subject to the provisions\nof section forty-two hundred one of this article  shall be available in\nthe manner provided in section forty-two hundred ten of this article to\naid a blind and deaf pupil in receiving instruction in an institution\nfor the instruction of the deaf or blind located outside the state in\norder to continue the education of such blind and deaf pupil for the\nterm of instruction provided in section forty-two hundred seven of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>