<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4353"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4353"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4353"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4353/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4353/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4353/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4353/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4353">
        <num>4353</num>
        <heading>Advisory board of visitors</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4353. Advisory board of visitors.  1. The regents shall appoint an\nadvisory board of visitors of the New York state school for the deaf\nconsisting of nine members. At least two of the board must be residents\nof the county of Oneida and the majority must be residents within fifty\nmiles of said school. The term of office of members of such board shall\nbe five years, from July first following the date of appointment, except\nthat the first members of such board shall be appointed for such terms\nso that the terms of two members thereof shall expire on July first in\nthe year of nineteen hundred sixty-four, the terms of two members shall\nexpire on July first in the year of nineteen hundred sixty-five, the\nterms of two members shall expire on July first in the year of nineteen\nhundred sixty-six, the terms of two members shall expire on July first\nin the year of nineteen hundred sixty-seven and that the term of one\nmember shall expire on July first in the year of nineteen hundred\nsixty-eight.\n  2. In the event that a vacancy occurs on such board for reason other\nthan the expiration of a term, such vacancy shall be filled by\nappointment by the board of regents for the balance of the unexpired\nterm.\n  3. The members of the board of visitors shall serve without pay but\nthey shall be paid their actual expenses necessarily incurred in the\nofficial discharge of their duties. No member of such board shall be\npecuniarily interested in any contract pertaining to the administration\nof such school.\n  4. The board of visitors shall visit and inspect such school and shall\nhave such other powers and duties as may be required or authorized by\nthe board of regents.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>