<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4410-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4410-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4410-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4410-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4410-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4410-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4410-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4410_B">
        <num>4410-B</num>
        <heading>Use of certain federal funds</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4410_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the school district receives any portion\nof its allocation of funds for the current year pursuant to section six\nhundred nineteen of the individuals with disabilities education act; or\n(ii) the school district receives an application for a sub-allocation by\na public or private agency, or, for the nineteen hundred\nninety-nine--two thousand school year only, the school district receives\nnotice from the commissioner that such an application for a\nsub-allocation has been filed with the commissioner, whichever occurs\nlater.\n  3. Federal flow-through funds. Each school district receiving an\nallocation of funds pursuant to section six hundred eleven of the\nindividuals with disabilities education act for the nineteen hundred\nninety-nine--two thousand school year or any subsequent school year\nshall sub-allocate such funds in accordance with this subdivision to\nother public and private agencies providing special education services\nto students ages three to twenty-one who were placed in such agency by\nthe school district's IEP team. For school years prior to two thousand\nsix--two thousand seven, such sub-allocations shall be made on a per\ncapita basis, based upon the number of students three to twenty-one\nyears of age who were placed in such agency by the school district's IEP\nteam and were served by the public or private agency as of December\nfirst of the base year, as reported to the commissioner; and, for the\nschool year two thousand six--two thousand seven and thereafter, such\nsub-allocations shall be made on a per capita basis, based upon the\nnumber of students three to twenty-one years of age who were placed in\nsuch agency by the school district's IEP team and who were receiving\nspecial education programming and instruction from the public or private\nagency as of December first of the base year, as reported to the\ncommissioner, and according to a formulae based upon the number of\nstudents three to twenty-one years of age who were receiving re...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4410_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe school district receives any portion of its allocation of funds for\nthe current year pursuant to section six hundred eleven of the\nindividuals with disabilities education act; or (ii) the school district\nreceives an application for a sub-allocation by a public or private\nagency, or, for the nineteen hundred ninety-nine--two thousand school\nyear only, the school district receives notice from the commissioner\nthat such an application for a sub-allocation has been filed with the\ncommissioner; whichever occurs later.\n  4. Charter schools. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions two\nand three of this section, any sub-allocation of funds received pursuant\nto sections six hundred eleven and six hundred nineteen of the\nindividuals with disabilities education act shall be made in accordance\nwith section twenty-eight hundred fifty-six of this chapter and the\nregulations of the commissioner implementing such section.\n  5. Carryover funds. In addition to the sub-allocations required\npursuant to subdivisions two and three of this section, each school\ndistrict receiving carryover funds from the nineteen hundred\nninety-eight--ninety-nine allocation pursuant to sections six hundred\neleven and six hundred nineteen of the individuals with disabilities\neducation act shall sub-allocate such carryover funds pursuant to this\nsubdivision to public and private agencies that have their chief\nadministrative offices located within the school district and have\ncarryover funds remaining from such allocation. Such sub-allocations\nshall be made in the amounts determined by the commissioner in\naccordance with procedures established by the commissioner. In the event\nsuch a public or private agency has its chief administrative offices\nlocated outside of the state, such agency may designate any school\ndistrict having resident students attending its programs as the district\nresponsible for sub-allocation of its nineteen hundred\nninety-eight--ninety-nine carryo...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4410_B__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>develop forms to be submitted by school districts that report the\nnumber of students three to twenty-one years of age who are placed in a\npublic or private agency providing special education services and who\nare receiving special education programming and instruction from such\nagency, and the number of such students who are receiving related\nservices only from such agency; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4410_B__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>develop guidelines to assure that funds allocated and\nsub-allocated pursuant to this section are used for purposes consistent\nwith federal laws and regulations governing such funds.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>