<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4501"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4501"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4501"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4501">
        <num>4501</num>
        <heading>Establishment of camps by school districts and appropriations authorized</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4501. Establishment of camps by school districts and appropriations\nauthorized.  1. A school district, acting through its board of\neducation, is hereby authorized to establish camps on lands acquired by\nsuch school district by purchase, gift, grant, devise, rent or lease or\non lands the use of which has otherwise been acquired by such school\ndistrict for camp purposes. Also, two or more school districts may\njointly acquire lands for camp purposes in the same manner and establish\nand operate such school camps thereon as joint projects within the limit\nof funds provided therefor by the respective school districts and in\naccordance with regulations approved by the commissioner of education.\nSuch camps shall be used to furnish education, physical training,\nrecreation and maintenance for all children of school age, whether in\nattendance at a public or non-public school, and shall be under the\njurisdiction of the board of education of such school district. Such\nboard may, however, fix a reasonable fee to cover cost of food and\ninstructional materials. Such board shall provide opportunity for\nchildren to receive instruction in such subjects as such board may deem\nproper. Such board shall prescribe the activities to be carried on and\nshall set up rules and regulations for admission to such camps and the\nconduct and discipline thereof. No child, whether in attendance at a\npublic or non-public school, shall be denied admission to such a camp or\nphysical training, recreation and maintenance at such a camp, because of\ninability to pay any required costs or fees; but no child shall be\nentitled to free education, physical training, recreation and\nmaintenance in any such camp for a period in excess of two weeks during\nany one year, unless the board of education prescribe and direct that\nphysically handicapped or other children be maintained for a longer\nperiod. The board of education of such school district shall make a\nreport at the annual meeting of such school district, of matters\nrelating to carrying out the provisions of this section.\n  2. Any such school district is hereby authorized to appropriate in the\nmanner prescribed by law relating to such school district such sums as\nmay be necessary for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this\nsection. Money shall be paid out of the treasury of such school district\nin the manner provided by law.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the board of\neducation of the city of New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>