<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4601"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4601"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4601"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4601">
        <num>4601</num>
        <heading>Advisory councils</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4601. Advisory councils.  1. The board of education of each school\ndistrict and of each board of cooperative educational services\nmaintaining an approved career education program shall appoint an\nadvisory council for career education consisting of at least ten\nmembers.  The membership shall include, but not be limited to, persons:\n  a. Familiar with the vocational needs and problems of management and\nlabor in the region.\n  b. Familiar with programs of career education at the postsecondary and\nadult levels.\n  c. Familiar with the manpower needs and requirements of the region to\nbe served.\n  d. Familiar with the special educational needs of the physically and\nmentally handicapped.\n  e. Representative of community interests, including persons familiar\nwith the special needs of the population to be served.\n  f. A student who is participating in a career education program at the\nschool district or board of cooperative educational services district\nbeing served by the advisory council.\n  2. It shall be the duty of such advisory council for career education\nto advise the board of education or board of cooperative education on\nthe development of and policy matters arising in the administration of\ncareer education, including the preparation of long-range and annual\nprogram plans submitted to the commissioner of education, and assist\nwith an annual evaluation of career education programs, services and\nactivities provided by the school district or board of cooperative\neducation.\n  3. Advisory councils may appoint consultant committees representative\nof specific occupational fields to assist in the work of the council and\nthe board of education or board of cooperative education with respect to\nthe planning, development and requirements for establishment of new\nprograms or evaluation and revision of existing programs.\n  4. The board of education of any school district or the board of\ncooperative educational services may employ such professional, technical\nand clerical personnel as may be necessary to enable the advisory\ncouncil to carry out its functions specified in this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>