<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4604"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4604">
        <num>4604</num>
        <heading>Continuing education adult schools</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4604. Continuing education adult schools.  1. The board of education\nof each school district may establish and maintain day and evening\nschools for adults, the controlling purpose of which shall be to provide\na general program of continuing education in all its aspects for the\nimprovement of the civic, vocational and general intelligence of adults\nand to enable them to make a wise use of their leisure time. Such\ncontinuing education adult schools may be of the following kinds:\n  a. Citizenship schools providing instruction in English, civics, the\ncommon branches and other subjects which may increase the civic and\ngeneral intelligence of foreign born, illiterate and non-English\nspeaking persons.\n  b. General continuing education adult schools providing instruction in\napproved high school subjects, general cultural subjects, approved\noccupational subjects, music, dramatic arts, fine, applied and practical\narts subjects.\n  c. Recreation and leisure time schools providing instruction in\nphysical education, health education, sports, games, arts and crafts and\nleisure time activities generally.\n  2. The common council, council or board of estimate and apportionment\nof a city, the board of supervisors or other governing elective body of\na county, the board of trustees of an incorporated village and the town\nboard of a town may make appropriations to aid and promote the extension\nof education among illiterate and non-English speaking persons within\nthe jurisdiction of such respective bodies.\n  3. The commissioner is authorized and directed to promulgate rules and\nregulations to provide for the notification of participants in adult\ncontinuing education schools of the emergency procedures to be followed\nin the event of fire.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>