<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4606"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4606"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4606"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4606">
        <num>4606</num>
        <heading>School-to-employment program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4606. School-to-employment program.  1. The commissioner is hereby\nauthorized to make apportionments to school districts in accordance with\nthe provisions of this section, to encourage and assist such districts\nto provide a school-to-employment program to consist of a part-time\nschool and a part-time employment program.\n  2. Any school district planning to establish such a program shall\nsubmit to the commissioner on or before the first day of May of the\nschool year preceding the school year during which the program is to be\nconducted, an application, together with such information as the\ncommissioner shall require, including at least a complete statement of\npurposes of the program, the detailed procedures of operation, a\ndetailed estimate of the cost of such program and a complete description\nof the manner in which the program will operate.\n  In the event that any funds of a school district are to be utilized to\nprovide a stipend for students in the part-time employment program, the\nplan shall indicate the types of employment situations which will be\nfurnished such students. The plan shall indicate that no public funds\nwill be used to pay a student in an employment situation furnished by a\nnon-governmental employer.\n  3. The commissioner shall evaluate such applications and shall\npromulgate a list in accordance with the merit and value of the various\nprograms and where several programs are evaluated, as having equal merit\nand value, the date of receipt of the application.\n  4. The commissioner shall determine the amount of apportionment which\nshall be made to those programs which he deems to have merit within the\namount of the appropriation therefor.\n  5. Notwithstanding any other provision or law to the contrary,\nvocational schools and classes may be organized and conducted in\naccordance with regulations adopted by the commissioner to provide a\nprogram for students fifteen years of age and over who might benefit\nfrom appropriate instruction consisting of a part-time school and a\npart-time employment program.\n  6. Any school district conducting a school-to-employment program is\nhereby authorized and empowered to do and perform any and all acts\nnecessary or convenient to enable it to carry out the provisions of this\narticle and it is authorized to enter into a contract with any person,\nfirm, association, partnership, corporation or governmental agency\nwhereby such person, firm, association, partnership, corporation or\ngovernmental agency will provide part-time employment to students\nenrolled in such program, the consideration of such contract, if it\notherwise meets the provisions of this section, to be a legal charge\nagainst the school district.  Any person, firm, association,\npartnership, corporation or governmental agency participating with a\nschool district in a school-to-employment program is not to be penalized\nfor participating in such program by reason of the fact that such child\nmay be only fifteen years of age or may not have otherwise complied with\nother provisions of the law which would be applicable thereto, and any\npupil obtaining vocational experience in participation with a school\ndistrict in a school-to-employment program is not to be deemed an\nemployee within the meaning of the labor law, provided that the\nschool-to-employment program involved meets the regulations of the\ncommissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>