<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4607"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4607"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4607"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4607/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4607/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4607">
        <num>4607</num>
        <heading>Bridge to employment, work tryout and education program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4607__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>single parent;\n  (ii) dislocated worker;\n  (iii) long-term unemployed;\n  (iv) displaced homemaker;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4607__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>older worker;\n  (vi) economically disadvantaged;\n  (vii) handicapped individuals; or\n  (viii) such other individuals as the commissioner may determine to be\neligible.\n  c. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the work experience\nunder this chapter shall not affect any predetermined eligibility under\nthe Job Training Partnership Act of 1982 or any other appropriate\neducational services program.\n  6. Any agency or organization designated by the commissioner to\nconduct a bridge to employment, work tryout and education program is\nhereby authorized and empowered to do and perform all acts necessary or\nconvenient to enable it to carry out the provisions of this section and\nit is authorized to enter into a contract with any person, firm,\nassociation, partnership or corporation whereby such person, firm,\nassociation, partnership or corporation will provide work tryout\nexperience to participants enrolled in such program, the consideration\nfor such contract, if it otherwise meets the provisions of this section,\nto be a legal charge against the agency or organization. However, no\nplacements will be made with any person, firm, association, partnership\nor corporation where there is an industry/labor controversy, as defined\nin regulations of the commissioner of labor.\n  7. Use of funds. a. Work tryout experiences. Agencies or organizations\nparticipating in the bridge to employment, work tryout and education\nprogram may provide to eligible participants up to one hundred hours of\nfull-time or part-time work tryout experiences with small to\nmedium-sized employers at no cost to those participating employers. No\nsuch experiences may last more than forty hours with any single\nemployer. Employers who elect to retain a participant from the work\ntryout experience may transfer such participants to a bridge to\nemployment placement component of the program and receive full benefit\nof such program. Up to fifty percent of the funds are to be used to\nsuppo...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4607__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Payroll administration and program promotion by the agency or\norganization or sub-contractor for up to two hundred eighty hours but\nnot more than seven weeks for each person placed in employment.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4607__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Appropriate share of wages and fringe benefits for such\nemployment.\n  Employers will be responsible for payment of at least fifty percent of\nthe wages and fringe benefits for such employment. After seven weeks of\nemployment the bridge to employment and education program benefits shall\ncease and the employer must pay all expenses.\n  Employers participating in the program shall not be required to\nparticipate for any specific period of time. Participants may be hired\nby participating employers at any time or may be returned to the bridge\nto employment and education program operator at any time with a\nstatement of circumstances and/or work related deficiencies. Continued\nemployer participation in the program shall be determined by\ndemonstrated transition to unsubsidized employment at levels established\nby the agency or organization and approved by the commissioner. However,\nemployers who have released an excessive number of participants from the\nbridge to employment programs...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>