<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4804"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4804"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4804"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4804">
        <num>4804</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of managers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4804. Powers and duties of managers.  1. The board of managers of\nsuch school shall be responsible for the operation and maintenance of\nthe school; employ a superintendent and such teachers and assistants as\nmay be required for the operation and maintenance of the school; fix\ncompensation of such superintendent, teachers and assistants within the\namount made available therefor by the board of estimate and\napportionment or other similar body or officer of such city; prescribe\nrules and regulations for the management of the school and for the\npurpose of carrying into effect the object thereof; provide for the\ndetention, maintenance and instruction of all children who are admitted\nto the school.  Such board shall on or before the first day of January\neach year furnish to the mayor estimates in writing of the amount of\nexpenditures for the next fiscal year.  All expenses and appropriations\nfor such school shall be subject to the provisions of sections\nseventy-three, seventy-four, seventy-five, seventy-six and seventy-seven\nof second class cities law, and of any and all other provisions of said\nlaw applicable thereto.\n  2. The board of managers shall have full power to discharge or parole\nat any time any child admitted to such school.  A child under sixteen\nyears of age committed to the school by a court and paroled for good\nconduct may be arrested and detained in the school for violation of the\nterms of his parole.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>