<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4901"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4901"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4901"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-4901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4901">
        <num>4901</num>
        <heading>New York nautical school may be established and maintained</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4901. New York nautical school may be established and maintained.\nThe board of education of the city of New York, in its discretion, may\nprovide and maintain a nautical school in such city for the education\nand training of pupils in the science and practice of navigation; may\nfurnish accommodations for such school and make all needful rules and\nregulations therefor, and for the number and compensation of instructors\nand others employed therein; may prescribe the government and discipline\nthereof and the terms and conditions upon which pupils shall be received\nand instructed therein and discharged therefrom and provide in all\nthings for the good management of such nautical school.  Such board\nshall have power to purchase the books, apparatus, stationery and other\nthings necessary or expedient to enable such school to be properly and\nsuccessfully conducted; and may cause such school or the pupils, or part\nof the pupils thereof, to go on board vessels in the harbor of New York\nand take cruises in or from such harbor for the purpose of obtaining a\npractical knowledge in navigation and of the duties of mariners.  Such\nboard is hereby authorized to apply to the United States government for\nthe requisite use of vessels and supplies for the purposes above\nmentioned.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>