<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-497"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-497"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="497"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-497/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-497/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-497/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-497/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_497">
        <num>497</num>
        <heading>Establishment of regional college cooperative services board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 497. Establishment of regional college cooperative services board.\n1. Upon the request of the governing board of at least two or more\nnon-public institutions of higher education, the commissioner of\neducation shall call a joint meeting of the members of such governing\nboards for the purpose of determining whether a regional college\ncooperative services board should be established within the geographic\narea in which such institutions are located. In the event that a\nregional college center with similar purposes is already in existence in\nthe state, the commissioner of education shall extend to such center the\nopportunity to become a regional college cooperative services board.\n  2. If the commissioner determines that such board will strengthen and\nbest develop the educational resources within the area to be served, he\nshall call a meeting to elect a board of trustees of such board. Notice\nof such meeting shall be mailed by the commissioner to each member of\nthe governing board of each institution at his last known address at\nleast five days prior to such meeting.  At such meeting the governing\nboard of each institution shall have one vote.\n  3. Within one month after taking office, the trustees-elect shall\napply to the regents for a charter as a regional college cooperative\nservices board.\n  4. Such board shall elect a president, a secretary and a treasurer.\nBefore entering upon his duties, such treasurer shall execute and file\nwith such board an official undertaking in such sum and with such\nsureties as directed by the board and approved by the commissioner. The\ntreasurer need not be a member of such board.  The funds of such board\nshall be deposited in a bank or banks designated by its board of\ntrustees and shall be expended only under the direction of such board\nupon properly authenticated vouchers.\n  5. The term of office of the trustees of such board shall be five\nyears except that the members of the first board of trustees shall\ndetermine by lot the year in which the term of office of each trustee\nshall expire so that as nearly as possible the terms of one-fifth of the\nmembers of such board will expire annually. Thereafter the successors of\nsuch trustees shall be elected annually at a joint meeting of the member\ninstitutions. Such meeting shall be called by the secretary of the board\nwho shall mail a notice of such meeting to each trustee of each of the\nmember institutions of the board at his last known address, at least ten\ndays prior to such joint meeting. At such joint meeting the board of\ntrustees of each member institution of the board shall have one vote.\nThe board of trustees of any such member institution may, by resolution,\ndesignate one or more members of such board to attend such joint meeting\nand cast the vote of such board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>