<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5002"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5002"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5002"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5002">
        <num>5002</num>
        <heading>Standards for licensed private career schools</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>zero percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination is during\nthe first week of instruction; or\n  (ii) twenty-five percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination\nis during the second week of instruction; or\n  (iii) fifty percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination is\nduring the third week of instruction; or\n  (iv) seventy-five percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination\nis during the fourth week of instruction; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one hundred percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination\noccurs after the fourth week of instruction.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For programs organized by terms of fifteen, sixteen, seventeen or\neighteen weeks apiece, the school shall evenly divide the total tuition\ncharges among the number of terms. After instruction is begun in a\nschool, if a student withdraws or is discontinued, the school may retain\nno more than:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>zero percent of the term's tuition if the termination is during\nthe first week of instruction; or\n  (ii) twenty percent of the term's tuition if the termination is during\nthe second week of instruction; or\n  (iii) thirty-five percent of the term's tuition if the termination is\nduring the third week of instruction; or\n  (iv) fifty percent of the term's tuition if the termination is during\nthe fourth week of instruction; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>seventy percent of the term's tuition if the termination is during\nthe fifth week of instruction; or\n  (vi) one hundred percent of the term's tuition if the termination\noccurs after the completion of the fifth week of instruction.\n  c.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The tuition refund policy for the second term or quarter of any\nprogram at schools licensed pursuant to section five thousand one of\nthis article shall be as follows:\n  (A) For programs which are divided into quarters of up to fourteen\nweeks, the school shall evenly divide the total tuition charges among\nthe number of quarters. After instruction is begun in a school, if a\nstudent withdraws or is discontinued, the school may retain no more\nthan:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>twenty-five percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination is\nduring the first week of instruction; or\n  (ii) fifty percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination is\nduring the second week of instruction; or\n  (iii) seventy-five percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination\nis during the third week of instruction; or\n  (iv) one hundred percent of the quarter's tuition if the termination\noccurs after the third week of instruction.\n  (B) For programs organized by terms of fifteen, sixteen, seventeen or\neighteen weeks apiece, the school shall evenly divide the total tuition\ncharges among the number of terms. After instruction is begun in a\nschool, if a student withdraws or is discontinued, the school may retain\nno more than:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>twenty percent of the term's tuition if the termination is during\nthe first week of instruction; or\n  (ii) thirty-five percent of the term's tuition if the termination is\nduring the second week of instruction; or\n  (iii) fifty percent of the term's tuition if the termination is during\nthe third week of instruction; or\n  (iv) seventy percent of the term's tuition if the termination is\nduring the fourth week of instruction; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one hundred percent of the term's tuition if the termination\noccurs after the completion of the fourth week of instruction.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph one of this\nparagraph, the tuition refund policy set forth in paragraph b of this\nsubdivision shall apply unless the school demonstrates that there are no\nsignificant educational changes in the educational program of the\nstudent, such changes as defined in regulations of the commissioner.\n  d. The tuition refund policy for the third and any subsequent term or\nquarter of any program licensed pursuant to section five thousand one of\nthis article shall be the policy set forth in subparagraph one of\nparagraph c of this subdivision.\n  e. No program shall have a term in excess of eighteen weeks.\n  f. The amount of the refund shall be calculated based on the last day\nof student attendance.\n  g.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any refund due to a student shall be paid by the school within\nforty-five days of the date on which the student withdraws from the\nprogram. For the purposes of this article, such date shall be the\nearliest of</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the date on which the student gives written notice to\nthe school or (ii) the date on which the student is deemed to have\nwithdrawn pursuant to subparagraph two of this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a student has failed to attend classes for a period of thirty\ncalendar days, the school shall send by regular mail a notice to the\nstudent that the student shall be deemed to have withdrawn from the\nprogram if the student does not notify the school to the contrary within\ntwelve days from the date on which the letter is sent. If the student\nfails to respond within such twelve-day period, the student shall be\ndeemed to have withdrawn and the school shall notify the higher\neducation services corporation that the student has withdrawn and the\ndate of the withdrawal.\n  h. Schools shall submit, for approval by the commissioner, the school\ncatalog with a weekly tuition liability chart for each program that\nindicates the amount of refund due the student in the event of\nwithdrawal.\n  i. Upon payment of a refund to a lender, the school shall forthwith\nsend a notice to a person designated by the president of the higher\neducation services corporation upon a form approved by the p...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the entrance requirements demonstrate that students possess\nthe skills, competencies and prerequisite knowledge needed to progress\nin the curriculum;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the content will enable the student to develop those skills\nand competencies required for employment in the occupational area for\nwhich the curriculum was developed;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the school will utilize appropriate instructional methods;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the instructional equipment used within the curriculum is\ncomparable to the equipment currently used by business or industry in\nthe occupational area for which the curriculum was developed; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that a curriculum may include instruction in English as a second\nlanguage at a beginning or basic level, provided such instruction shall\nnot constitute more than fifty percent of such program.\n  c.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the evaluation of a particular course or facility requires\nthe services of an expert not employed by the department, the department\nshall retain such expert at the school's expense in addition to the\napplication fees prescribed in paragraph a of this subdivision.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If, in the interest of expediting the approvals, a school requests\nthe department to employ an outside consultant, the school shall pay the\ncost of such services in addition to the application fees prescribed in\nparagraph a of this subdivision.\n  d. The commissioner shall act on applications for approval of a course\nor curriculum within one hundred twenty days of receipt of a complete\napplication and, in the case of a denial, shall set forth in writing the\nreasons for such denial.\n  e. Notwithstanding paragraphs b, c and d of this subdivision,\ncurriculum certified by a nationally recognized vendor as defined in\ncommissioner's regulations shall be recognized by the department in lieu\nof an expert evaluation when such curriculum is adopted by a school in\nthe original format provided by the vendor as long as the proposed\ncurriculum is a stand alone program and not part of a larger\ncomprehensive course.\n  f. Notwithstanding any other provision of the law, a not-for-profit\nl...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall pre-\nscribe by regulation, standards for reapproval after the first year of\nlicensure, of any curriculum or course based upon factors including but\nnot limited to the following, as appropriate:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5002__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for each curriculum or course, the percentage of students who have\ndropped out;\n  (ii) the acquisition of a specified minimum level of skills by the\nstudents; and\n  (iii) for each curriculum or course, the percentage of students placed\nin occupations related to the instruction, where applicable.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5002__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such standards shall be consistent with those applied to all\nnon-degree career education programs.\n  c. Reapproval contingency. Reapproval of a curriculum or course shall\nbe contingent upon a demonstration by the applicant that the curriculum\nor course has met the curriculum reapproval standards set forth in this\nsubdivision. Except as otherwise provided in paragraph d of this\nsubdivision, no such curriculum or course or substantially similar\ncurriculum or course may be given without reapproval by the\ncommissioner.\n  d. When timely and complete application is made for the reapproval of\na curriculum or course, and no written denial is made thirty days prior\nto the date of expiration of the existing approval, the curriculum or\ncourse shall be deemed to be approved for the period of the curriculum.\nIf the application is denied, the commissioner shall set forth in\nwriting the reasons for such denial.\n  e. The commissioner may provide in regulations for reapproval\nprocedures...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>