<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5006"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5006"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5006"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5006">
        <num>5006</num>
        <heading>Teachout plans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nteachout school must offer courses of study that are substantially\nsimilar to those offered in the school ceasing instruction;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>teachout schools must be located in the geographic area in which\nthe school ceasing instruction was located unless the school ceasing\ninstruction provided distance learning or online training;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all provisions for a teachout plan must be included in the\nenrollment agreement signed by the student; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the teachout school shall agree to fulfill the enrollment\nagreement signed by the student at the school ceasing instruction.\n  3. The licensed school shall provide to the teachout school and to the\ndepartment the following information prior to closure:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Copies of the academic and financial records for all students in\nattendance at the school at the projected time of closure;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A listing of all such students presently in attendance including\ntheir names, addresses, social security numbers, curriculum that each\nstudent is enrolled in and the number of hours the students will have\ncompleted at the time of the school closure.\n  4. The department will provide to the teachout school, immediately\nupon notification of a school closing, a copy of each approved\ncurriculum that the closing school is presently offering.\n  5. The commissioner shall require all teachout schools to address the\nfollowing issues:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Integration of students into a curriculum which may be different\nfrom the curriculum in which they are currently receiving instruction;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Assessments of students' progress so that they may be placed into\nan appropriate course;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provision of remedial instruction to students who are found to be\ndeficient in one or more course areas upon their initial assessment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provision by the teachout school to adhere to the required\nstudent/teacher ratios and room capacities; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5006__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Compliance with statutory and regulatory requirements during the\nteachout.\n  6. The student shall not be subject to any costs beyond the total\ncosts identified in the original enrollment agreement.\n  7. A student may decline to pursue instruction at the teachout school\nand may instead seek a refund pursuant to section five thousand seven of\nthis article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>