<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5009"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5009"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5009"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5009/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5009/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5009/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5009/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5009">
        <num>5009</num>
        <heading>Duties of the commissioner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5009. Duties of the commissioner. In addition to all other duties\nassigned in this article, the duties of the commissioner shall include,\nbut not be limited to:\n  1. ensuring that up-to-date, accurate information is available to the\npublic, via the internet and other appropriate media, regarding every\nduly licensed proprietary school in this state, as well as disciplinary\nactions decided by the state.\n  2. developing and issuing to duly licensed proprietary schools a\nsymbol to indicate such status; provided that such symbol shall be\ndeveloped and made available to such schools no later than September\nthirtieth, nineteen hundred ninety-nine.\n  3. administering a public information campaign aimed at increasing\nawareness about the importance of attending licensed proprietary\nvocational schools. Such campaign shall be targeted to populations at\nrisk of enrolling in unlicensed schools, and shall be conducted using\nmeans including, but not limited to, public service announcements on\ncommercial radio and television stations, public access television, and\nprint media.\n  4. providing for the orderly maintenance of any student records which\nmay be transferred to the department pursuant to any school's plan\ndeveloped pursuant to subdivision eight of section five thousand one of\nthis article; including responding to student requests for transcripts\nand records within twenty days of receiving a request. The commissioner\nis hereby authorized to impose an appropriate fee for such transcripts\npursuant to a schedule approved by the director of the budget.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>