<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5010"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5010"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5010"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5010/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5010/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5010/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5010/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5010">
        <num>5010</num>
        <heading>Advisory council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5010. Advisory council. 1. An advisory council for licensed private\ncareer schools is hereby created for the purpose of advising the board\nof regents and the commissioner as provided herein. The council shall be\ncomposed of eleven members appointed by the governor, two of whom shall\nbe upon the recommendation of the temporary president of the senate, two\nof whom shall be upon the recommendation of the speaker of the assembly,\none of whom shall be upon the recommendation of the minority leader of\nthe senate and one of whom shall be upon the recommendation of the\nminority leader of the assembly. Of the five remaining members, one\nshall be an owner or director of a school regulated pursuant to this\narticle, and one shall be a student advocate. The governor shall\ndesignate a chairperson from such members. The commissioner, the\npresident of the higher education services corporation, the secretary of\nstate, the comptroller, the director of the division of the budget, and\nthe executive director of the job training partnership council, or their\ndesignees, shall serve as ex-officio, non-voting members of the council.\n  2. The council shall meet no less than four times a year. Members of\nthe council shall receive no compensation for their services but shall\nbe reimbursed for reasonable expenses actually and necessarily incurred\nby them in the performance of their duties. Council member terms of\noffice shall be limited to three years, provided that members may be\nreappointed. All appointments to the council to fill vacancies in\nexistence on the effective date of the chapter of the laws of two\nthousand twelve which amended this subdivision shall be made within\nninety days of such effective date.\n  3. The council shall advise the commissioner on such matters as the\ncouncil determines are appropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>