<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-508"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-508"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-11-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="508"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_508">
        <num>508</num>
        <heading>Investment of funds; interest; accounts; reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_508__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The retirement system is authorized to photograph,\nmicrophotograph, film, record, copy, image or otherwise reproduce all or\nany part of its records by any process which accurately reproduces or\nforms a durable medium for reproducing any original document or record.\nWhenever the retirement system shall have so reproduced such records and\nwhenever such reproductions or media have been placed in conveniently\naccessible files and provision has been made for preserving, examining\nand using the same, the retirement system may cause the original record\nwhich has been so reproduced to be disposed of or destroyed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_508__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any reproduction or reproduction from any media authorized\npursuant to this subdivision shall have the same force and effect as the\noriginals thereof would have had and shall be deemed to be an original\nrecord for all purposes, including introduction in evidence in all\ncourts or administrative agencies. Duly certified or authenticated\ncopies of such reproductions shall be admitted in evidence equally with\nthe original reproductions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_508__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A duly authorized representative of the retirement system is\nhereby authorized to certify to the authenticity of any reproduction\nherein authorized and the retirement system shall make such charges\ntherefor as may be authorized by law.\n  17. Any real estate interests acquired by the retirement system\npursuant to this section, or pursuant to any other provision of law,\nshall be conveyed to it directly by name, or may be taken in the name of\na duly authorized nominee. The retirement system shall have the\nauthority to organize corporations for the purpose of carrying out the\nintent of this subdivision, and may make loans to said corporations for\nthe purpose of operating, preserving, or otherwise servicing any\nproperty being held by said corporations.\n  18. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the\nretirement board shall have the power to delegate to one or more\ninvestment managers its authority to invest moneys belonging to the\nretirement system. The term "investment managers" as used in this\nsubdivision shall include but not be limited to independent contractors\nselected by the retirement board.\n  19. Whenever a statute requires that a document must be filed or\nmoneys deposited with the system within a prescribed period of time or\nby a specified date in order for a member to be eligible for service\ncredit or a benefit from the system the document shall be deemed filed\nor the moneys deposited with the system on the date mailed if mailed to\nthe system either through</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_508__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the United States postal service by\nregistered or certified mail or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_508__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such other equivalent postal mail\nservice as the retirement board may specifically permit by rule or\nregulation with a tracking service confirming a date of mailing.\nNotwithstanding the provisions hereof, no such document shall be deemed\nfiled or moneys deposited with the system on the mailing date unless\nactually received by the retirement system as the result of such\nmailing.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>