<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="512-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_512_B">
        <num>512-B</num>
        <heading>Loans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_512_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two percent of\nthe member's contract salary, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_512_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sufficient to pay the interest on\nthe unpaid balances thereof. In the event that a member is on leave of\nabsence without pay or is not regularly employed by an employer subject\nto the provisions of this article, any such outstanding loan shall be\nrepaid in such installments of principal and interest as the retirement\nboard shall determine. In the event of default the retirement board\nshall be authorized to collect such payments due from the employer of\nsuch member through payroll deduction and such member shall forfeit all\nfuture entitlement to borrow from the retirement system until the unpaid\nbalance of the loan outstanding at the time of default is fully paid.\nThe retirement board, at any time, may accept payments on account of any\nloan in addition to the installments fixed for repayment thereof. All\npayments of principal and interest at the minimum rate permitted\npursuant to subdivision three of this section made by the member shall\nbe credited to his accumulated contributions. Any additional interest\npaid by the member shall be credited to the pension accumulation fund.\n  3. Interest. The rate of interest payable upon loans made pursuant to\nthis section shall be set by the retirement board. The retirement board\nshall have power, from time to time and at any time, to decrease such\nrate to not less than that currently being credited on the member's\naccumulated contributions or to increase the same to not more than six\nper centum per annum. Any such decrease or increase shall apply, from\nthe effective date thereof, to unpaid balances of loans outstanding on\nsuch date and to new loans made thereafter.\n  4. Service Charge. A uniform service charge payable upon loans made\npursuant to this section shall be set by the retirement board in an\namount sufficient to cover the cost to the retirement system of\nadministering the loans. Such charge shall be deducted from the member's\naccumulated contributions when the loan is made or in equal annual\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>