<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="512-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-512-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_512_A">
        <num>512-A</num>
        <heading>Deferred retirement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_512_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an\nannuity which shall be the actuarial equivalent of such member's\naccumulated contributions at the time of retirement and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_512_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a pension of\none-one hundred fortieth (1/140) of final average salary multiplied by\nthe total number of years of credited service as of the date of\ndiscontinuing service.\n  3. Any member who discontinues service other than by death or\nretirement on or after June thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy and who\nis credited with at least ten years of full time teaching service\nrendered in the state, at least two of which were rendered since the\ndate he last joined the retirement system and subsequent to June\nthirtieth, nineteen hundred sixty-seven, by written notice duly\nacknowledged and filed with the retirement board at any time before his\nmembership would otherwise terminate pursuant to section five hundred\nthree of this article, may elect, in lieu of the return of his\naccumulated contributions pursuant to section five hundred twelve of\nthis article, to continue membership with the privilege of applying for\nretirement pursuant to this subdivision on or after the date he attains\nage fifty-five. The pension for a member who has made the election\npursuant to this subdivision shall be computed in accordance with the\nprocedures set forth in subdivision four of section five hundred\nthirty-five of this article, unless the member has been credited with at\nleast twenty years of full time New York state service, in which event\nhis pension shall be computed in accordance with subdivisions two and\nthree of the aforementioned section. In no event, however, shall the\npension so computed exceed seventy-five per cent of the member's final\naverage salary. In addition to the pension provided by this subdivision,\nthe member shall receive an annuity which shall be the actuarial\nequivalent of his accumulated contributions at the time of his\nretirement. In the case of persons who last became members on or after\nJuly first, nineteen hundred seventy-three, the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall apply only to those who discontinue service other than\nby death or r...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_512_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the service which\nwould be credited thereunder is credited in any public retirement system\nin the United States, or (ii) a benefit is being received from any\npublic retirement system based upon such credit.\n  12. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section a person who\nhas elected to continue membership pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection may withdraw from membership in the system in accordance with\nthe provisions of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>