<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-513"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-513"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="513"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_513">
        <num>513</num>
        <heading>Optional allowances</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_513__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_513__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section five hundred twelve, except that the amount of his\naccumulated contributions payable under paragraph</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_513__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of said\nsubdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_513__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall be reduced by any annuity payments received by him\nprior to his death and the benefit payable under paragraph</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_513__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of said\nsubdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_513__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall be reduced by any pension payments received by him\nprior to his death. The amounts payable shall be paid to the beneficiary\nor beneficiaries entitled thereto as provided under section five hundred\ntwelve, except that if the member has elected Option 4, as provided\nabove, the beneficiary nominated under such Option 4 shall be\nsubstituted for any beneficiary previously nominated and all amounts\npayable shall be paid to the beneficiary nominated under such Option 4.\n  3. In the case of persons who last became members on or after July\nfirst, nineteen hundred seventy-three, the provisions of subdivision two\nof this section shall apply only to deaths occurring after the date on\nwhich said subdivision two becomes operative and prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-four.\n  4. a. The retirement board may adopt rules and regulations providing\nthat a trustee of an inter vivos or testamentary trust shall be</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_513__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\neligible to be nominated to receive a lump sum benefit under option one\nand</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_513__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>eligible to be nominated to receive any benefit under option\nfour which the retirement board shall deem appropriate.\n  b. Any proceeds received by a trustee under this section shall not be\nsubject to the debts of the member or to transfer or estate taxes to any\ngreater extent than if such proceeds were payable to the beneficiaries\nnamed in the trust and not to the estate of the member.\n  c. A payment made in good faith under this section to either a\ndesignated trustee of an inter vivos trust, a successor trustee of an\ninter vivos trust who provides a copy of his appointment or a trustee or\nsuccessor trustee of a testamentary trust who provides a copy of the\nletters of trusteeship shall be a complete discharge to the system to\nthe extent of the payment.\n  d. If no qualified trustee claims the proceeds within eighteen months\nafter the death of the retired member, or if satisfactory evidence is\nfurnished within such period showing that there is or will be no trustee\nto rece...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>