<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5709"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5709"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5709"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5709/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5709/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5709/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5709/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5709">
        <num>5709</num>
        <heading>Special deputy sheriffs; powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5709. Special deputy sheriffs; powers and duties.  1. For the\nprotection of the grounds, buildings and property of Cornell university\nand of the state institutions and property, or other lands and property\nunder the supervision, administration and control of said university,\nand for the prevention of crime and the enforcement of law and order,\nand for the enforcement of such rules and regulations as the board of\ntrustees of Cornell university shall from time to time make, as\nauthorized in section fifty seven hundred eight of this chapter or\notherwise, the sheriff of a county within which any part of the grounds\nof Cornell university or the grounds of any state institution\nconstituting a part of the educational and research plants, owned or\nunder the supervision, administration or control of said university, are\nlocated, shall appoint and remove at the request of Cornell university\nsuch number of special deputy sheriffs as shall be recommended by the\npresident of Cornell university, such appointments to be made from\npersons nominated by the president of Cornell university, and such\nspecial deputy sheriffs shall act only within the county of the sheriff\nmaking the appointment. Such special deputy sheriffs so appointed shall\nbe employees of the university and subject to its supervision and\ncontrol and shall have the powers of peace officers as set forth in\nsection 2.20 of the criminal procedure law within the said grounds or\npremises owned or administered by Cornell university including any\npublic highway which crosses or adjoins such property. Nothing herein\ncontained shall be construed to prohibit any special deputy sheriff\nappointed as herein provided from holding an appointment in more than\none county at one and the same time.\n  2. Every special deputy sheriff so appointed shall, before entering\nupon the duties of his office, take and subscribe the oath of office\nprescribed by article thirteen of the constitution of the state of New\nYork, which oath shall be filed in the office of the county clerk of the\ncounty in which the grounds, lands and premises in which he is to be\nemployed is situate. Every special deputy sheriff appointed under this\nsection when on regular duty shall wear conspicuously a metallic shield\nwith a designating number and the words "Special Deputy Sheriff Cornell\nUniversity" thereon. The compensation, if any, of such special deputy\nsheriff shall be paid by Cornell university or by the state of New York\nif so provided by law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>