<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5712"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5712"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5712"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5712/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5712/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5712/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5712/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5712">
        <num>5712</num>
        <heading>New York state college of agriculture and life sciences</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5712. New York state college of agriculture and life sciences.  1.\nThe state college of agriculture, established by chapter six hundred\nfifty-five of the laws of nineteen hundred four, shall hereafter be\nknown as the New York state college of agriculture and life sciences at\nCornell university and shall continue to be under the supervision of the\nstate university trustees. The object of said college of agriculture and\nlife sciences shall be to improve the agricultural methods of the state,\nto develop the agricultural resources of the state in the production of\ncrops of all kinds, in the rearing and breeding of livestock, in the\nmanufacture of dairy and other products in determining better methods of\nhandling and marketing such products, and in other ways; and to increase\nintelligence and elevate the standards of living in the rural districts.\nFor the attainment of these objects the college is authorized to give\ninstruction in the sciences, arts and practices relating thereto, in\nsuch courses and in such manner as shall best serve the interests of the\nstate; to conduct extension work in disseminating agricultural knowledge\nthroughout the state by means of experiments and demonstrations on farms\nand gardens, investigations of the economic and social status of\nagriculture, lectures, publication of bulletins and reports, and in such\nother ways as may be deemed advisable in the furtherance of the\naforesaid objects; to make researches in the physical, chemical,\nbiological and other problems of agriculture, the application of such\ninvestigations to the agriculture of New York, and the publication of\nthe results thereof.\n  2. All buildings, furniture, apparatus and other property heretofore\nor hereafter erected or furnished by the state for such college of\nagriculture and life sciences shall be and remain the property of the\nstate.  The Cornell university shall have the custody and control of\nsaid property, and, as the representative of the state university\ntrustees, shall, with whatever state moneys may be received for the\npurpose, administer the said college of agriculture and life sciences as\nto the establishment of courses of study, the creation of departments\nand positions, the determination of the number and salaries of members\nof the faculty and other employees thereof, the appointment and\nemployment thereof, the maintenance of discipline and as to all other\nmatters pertaining to its educational policies, activities and\noperations, including research work.\n  3. The state university trustees shall maintain general supervision\nover the requests for appropriations, budgets, estimates and\nexpenditures of such college. Cornell university shall receive no\nincome, profit or compensation for the exercise and performance of the\npowers and duties conferred and imposed by this section, but all moneys\nreceived from state appropriations for the said college of agriculture\nand life sciences or derived from other sources in the course of the\nadministration thereof, shall be credited by said university to a\nseparate fund, and shall be used exclusively for said New York state\ncollege of agriculture and life sciences. Such moneys as may be\nappropriated to be paid to the Cornell university by the state in any\nyear, to be expended by said university in the administration of said\ncollege of agriculture and life sciences, shall be payable to the\ntreasurer of Cornell university in three equal payments to be made on\nthe first day of October, the first day of January, and the first day of\nApril in such year, and shall be expended upon vouchers approved by the\nchancellor of the state university, as the chief administrative officer\nof the state university, or by such authority or authorities in the\nstate university as shall be designated by the chancellor by a rule or\nwritten direction filed with the comptroller, when and in the manner\nauthorized by the state university trustees.\n  4. The said university shall expend such moneys and use such property\nof the state in administering said college of agriculture and life\nsciences as above provided, and shall submit to the state university\ntrustees during the month of September in each year, a detailed\nstatement of such expenditures and of the general operations of the said\ncollege of agriculture and life sciences.\n  5. The tuition fees charged to students shall be regulated by Cornell\nuniversity after prior consultation with the state university trustees\nand all other fees and charges in said college of agriculture and life\nsciences shall be fixed by Cornell university, and the moneys received\nfrom these sources and from the sales of products shall be credited to a\nseparate fund and shall be used for the current expenses of the said\ncollege of agriculture and life sciences.\n  6. There shall be established in said college of agriculture and life\nsciences courses of instruction in the fundamentals, theory and practice\nof nursery work, including the propagation and growth of nursery stock,\nand in gardening and planting.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>