<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5715"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5715"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5715"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5715/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5715/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5715/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5715/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5715">
        <num>5715</num>
        <heading>New York state school of industrial and labor relations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5715. New York state school of industrial and labor relations.  1.\nFindings.  It is necessary that understanding of industrial and labor\nrelations be advanced; that more effective cooperation among employers\nand employees and more general recognition of their mutual rights,\nobligations and duties under the laws pertaining to industrial and labor\nrelations in New York state be achieved; that means for encouraging the\ngrowth of mutual respect and greater responsibility on the part of both\nemployers and employees be developed; and that industrial efficiency\nthrough the analysis of problems relating to employment be improved.\n  2. Policy. In the interpretation and application of this section, it\nis hereby declared to be the policy of the state to provide facilities\nfor instruction and research in the field of industrial and labor\nrelations through the maintenance of a school of industrial and labor\nrelations.\n  3. School continued. The New York state school of industrial and labor\nrelations, heretofore established by chapter one hundred sixty-two of\nthe laws of nineteen hundred forty-four, is hereby continued in the\nstate university, at Cornell university in the city of Ithaca.\n  4. Object of school. The object of such school shall be to improve\nindustrial and labor conditions in the state through the provision of\ninstruction, the conduct of research, and the dissemination of\ninformation in all aspects of industrial, labor, and public relations,\naffecting employers and employees.\n  5. Property of school. All lands, buildings, furniture, apparatus, and\nother property heretofore or hereafter erected or furnished by the state\nfor the said school of industrial and labor relations shall be and\nremain the property of the state, and shall be in the custody and under\nthe control of Cornell university, as the representative of the state\nuniversity trustees.\n  6. Control and operation. a. Subject to appropriations by the state\ntherefor, Cornell university, as the representative of the state\nuniversity trustees, shall administer the New York state school of\nindustrial and labor relations as to the establishment of courses of\nstudy, the creation of departments and positions, the determination of\nthe number and salaries of members of the faculty and other employees\nthereof, the appointment and employment thereof, the maintenance of\ndiscipline and as to all other matters pertaining to its educational\npolicies, activities and operations, including research work and the\ndissemination of information in all aspects of industrial, labor, and\npublic relations, affecting employers and employees. The state\nuniversity trustees shall maintain general supervision over such school.\n  b. The tuition fees charged to students shall be regulated by Cornell\nuniversity after prior consultation with the state university trustees\nand all other fees and charges in such school shall be fixed by Cornell\nuniversity.\n  c. Cornell university shall receive no income, profit or compensation\nfor the exercise and performance of the powers and duties conferred and\nimposed by this section in connection with such school. All moneys\nreceived by such university in the course of the administration of such\nschool from tuition, fees and other charges shall be used exclusively\nfor such school. Money appropriated by the state for such school shall\nbe payable from the state treasury upon the audit and warrant of the\ncomptroller upon vouchers approved by the chancellor of the state\nuniversity, as the chief administrative officer of the state university,\nor by such authority or authorities in the state university as shall be\ndesignated by the chancellor by a rule or written direction filed with\nthe comptroller, when and in the manner authorized by the state\nuniversity trustees.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>