<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5716"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5716"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5716"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5716/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5716/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5716/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5716/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5716">
        <num>5716</num>
        <heading>Acquisition by the state of land and interests in land of Cornell university upon which buildings have heretofore or may hereafter be ere...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5716. Acquisition by the state of land and interests in land of\nCornell university upon which buildings have heretofore or may hereafter\nbe erected by the state.  Notwithstanding the provisions of section\nfifty-seven hundred and six of this chapter, any lands owned by Cornell\nuniversity upon which buildings have been heretofore or may hereafter be\nerected by the state for the purpose of any college, school or\nexperiment station provided for in this article, together with such\nadditional contiguous lands as may be deemed appropriate or needful to\nthe purposes of any such college, school or experiment station, with\nsuch rights of way, for purposes of ingress and egress thereto and\ntherefrom or for other purposes over other lands of Cornell university,\nas may be deemed necessary, may be conveyed by Cornell university to the\npeople of the state, without consideration, pursuant to such agreement\nor agreements therefor as may be made between Cornell university and,\nwith the approval of the director of the budget, the trustees of the\nstate university of New York, acting for and on behalf of the people of\nthe state.  Any such conveyance may be made upon such terms and\nconditions, including conditions precedent or conditions subsequent with\nprovision of reverter and right of re-entry upon breach thereof, as may\nbe provided for by any such agreement.  All such agreements shall be in\nwriting and shall be approved as to form and manner of execution by the\nattorney-general before they shall become binding on the state.  No\nconveyance authorized herein shall be accepted on behalf of the state\nunless the title to the property conveyed shall be approved by the\nattorney-general and the deed of conveyance approved as to form and\nmanner of execution by him.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>