<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5904"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5904"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5904"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5904/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5904/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5904/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-5904/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5904">
        <num>5904</num>
        <heading>Advisory board; appointment; powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5904. Advisory board; appointment; powers and duties.  1. A\ntemporary advisory board is hereby created to consist of seven members,\ntwo of whom shall be members of the senate to be appointed by the\ntemporary president of the senate, two shall be members of the assembly\nto be appointed by the speaker of the assembly, and three shall be\nappointed by the dean of such graduate school of public affairs.  The\nmembers of the senate and of the assembly so appointed shall serve for\nterms of two years or until the expiration of their term of office as a\nmember of the senate or assembly, respectively, whichever shall first\noccur.  The members appointed by the dean of the graduate school of\npublic affairs shall be appointed for terms of four years. Vacancies\noccurring in the board by reason of expiration of term or for any other\nreason shall be filled by the official authorized to make the original\nappointment.\n  2. The board may choose from among its members a chairman,\nvice-chairman and secretary.\n  3. The members of the board shall serve without compensation, but\nshall be reimbursed their actual and necessary expenses.\n  4. The board shall meet at least four times a year for the purpose of\nadopting rules and regulations governing the operation of the institute\nand the establishment and effectuation of its goals.\n  5. The board after investigation and study shall, on or before January\nfirst, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, prepare plans and submit\nrecommendations to the chancellor and board of trustees of the state\nuniversity and to the legislature for the control, supervision, or\norganization, structure, administration, operation and activities of the\ninstitute.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>