<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6004"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6004"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6004"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6004/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6004/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6004/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6004/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6004">
        <num>6004</num>
        <heading>College board of trustees; powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6004. College board of trustees; powers and duties. The college\nshall continue to be administered and maintained at Syracuse university.\nSubject to the general management and supervision of and in accordance\nwith rules established by the state university trustees, the college\nboard of trustees shall exercise the following powers:\n  a. Recommend regarding the establishment of courses of study, the\ncreation of departments, the general course of instruction, research,\nand experiments to be pursued in the college and the degrees to be\nconferred, number and salaries of faculty, staff and all other\nemployees, their appointment and termination or removal, and the nature\nof their duties.\n  b. To submit for approval all contracts necessary or appropriate for\ncarrying out any of the purposes or objects of the college, including\nsuch as shall involve cooperation with any person, corporation or\nassociation or any department of the government of the state of New York\nor of the United States in laboratory, experimental, investigative or\nresearch work, and the acceptance from such person, corporation,\nassociation or department of the state or federal government of gifts or\ncontributions of money, expert service, labor, materials, apparatus,\nappliances or other property in connection therewith.\n  c. Recommend to the state university trustees candidates for\nappointment by the state university trustees as head of such\ninstitution.\n  d. Review all major plans of the head of such institution for its more\neffective operation and make such recommendations with respect thereto\nas it deems appropriate. Such plans shall be submitted for approval by\nthe state university trustees, together with the recommendations of the\ncollege trustees with respect thereto. The state university trustees\nshall determine what constitutes such major plans, which are hereby\ngenerally defined to include, among others, plans for the appraisal or\nimprovement of the faculty and other personnel, expansion or restriction\nof student admissions, appraisal or improvement of academic programs and\nof standards for the earning of degrees, expansion of institutional\nplants and appraisal or improvement of student activities and housing.\n  e. Make regulations governing the care, custody and management of\nlands, grounds, buildings and equipment.\n  f. Review the proposed budget requests for such institution prepared\nby the head thereof and recommend to the state university trustees a\nbudget for such institution.\n  g. Foster the development of advisory citizens' committees to render\nsuch assistance as the college trustees may request, and to appoint the\nmembers of such citizens' committees. Members of such citizens'\ncommittees shall receive no compensation for their services but shall be\nreimbursed for the expenses actually and necessarily incurred by them in\nthe performance of their duties.\n  h. Name buildings and grounds.\n  i. Make regulations governing the conduct and behavior of students.\n  j. Make an annual report to the state university trustees on or before\nSeptember first of each year, and report to them from time to time on\nany matter it believes requires their attention.\n  k. Perform such other powers and duties as may be authorized or\nrequired by the state university trustees by general rules or special\ndirectives.\n  1. Make and establish, and from time to time alter and amend, such\nregulations pertaining to the affairs of its institution, not\ninconsistent with law or the rules of the state university trustees, as\nmay be necessary or appropriate to carry out effectively the foregoing\npowers and duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>