<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-604"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-604"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="604"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-604/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-604/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_604">
        <num>604</num>
        <heading>General awards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 604. General awards. 1. Tuition assistance program awards are\navailable for all students who are enrolled in approved programs and who\ndemonstrate the ability to complete such courses, in accordance with\nstandards established by the commissioner.\n  2. Regents awards for children of deceased and disabled veterans are\navailable for eligible students in an approved program.\n  3. Regents awards for children of deceased state correction officers\nand state civilian employees of a correctional facility are available\nfor eligible students in an approved program pursuant to section six\nhundred sixty-nine of this chapter.\n  4. Regents awards for children of deceased police officers,\nfirefighters, volunteer firefighters and correction officers are\navailable for eligible students in an approved program pursuant to\nsection six hundred sixty-four of this chapter.\n  5. Veterans tuition awards are available for eligible students\nenrolled in approved undergraduate or graduate programs at degree\ngranting institutions and approved vocational training programs pursuant\nto section six hundred sixty-nine-a of this title.\n  6. Tuition awards for part-time undergraduate students enrolled in\napproved programs in degree-granting institutions.\n  * 7. Tuition benefit for active members of the New York army national\nguard, New York air national guard and naval militia members enrolled in\napproved post-secondary degree programs in degree-granting institutions.\n  * NB Repealed September 1, 2026\n  9. Memorial scholarships for children, spouses and financial\ndependents of deceased firefighters, volunteer firefighters, police\nofficers, peace officers, and emergency medical service workers.\n  10. World trade center memorial scholarships.\n  11. American Airlines flight 587 memorial scholarships pursuant to\nsection six hundred sixty-eight-f of this title.\n  12. Continental Airlines flight 3407 memorial scholarships pursuant to\nsection six hundred sixty-eight-g of this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>