<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-605"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-605"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="605"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-605/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-605/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-605/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-605/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_605">
        <num>605</num>
        <heading>Academic performance awards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the aggregate of the amount of the awards received as\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of months the recipient failed to comply with this\ncondition bears to the number of months he was obligated to comply with\nthis condition, together with interest at seven percent per annum\ncomputed from the date on which he completed his professional training\nand/or active military service. A recipient shall not be required to\ncomply with the provisions of this paragraph unless he shall have\nreceived a medical degree and any obligation to comply with such\nprovisions shall be cancelled upon his death. The regents shall make\nregulations to provide for the waiver or suspension of any financial\nobligation where compliance would involve extreme hardship.\n  c. The requirements of this paragraph shall apply to any recipient who\nreceives his or her first award payment commencing with the nineteen\nhundred eighty-two--nineteen hundred eighty-three academic year or\nsubsequently, and the requirements of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision\nshall not apply to such recipients. Within such time as the commissioner\nshall by regulation provide, a recipient of an award shall have\npracticed medicine in an area designated as having a shortage of\nphysicians pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision for that number\nof months calculated by multiplying by nine the number of annual awards\nreceived by the recipient. If a recipient fails to comply fully with\nsuch condition, the president shall be entitled to recover from such\nrecipient an amount determined by the formula:\n                              A = 2B (t-s)\n                                       t\nin  which "A" is the amount the president is entitled to recover; "B" is\nthe sum of all awards paid to the recipient and  the  interest  on  such\namount which would be payable if at the times such awards were paid they\nwere  loans  bearing interest at the maximum prevailing rate; "t" is the\ntotal number of months in the recipient's period of obligated  services;\nand  "s"  is  the  number  of months of service actually rendered by the\nrecipient. Any amount which the president is entitled to  recover  under\nthis paragraph shall be paid within the one year period beginning on the\ndate  that  the  recipient  failed  to  comply  with  this  condition. A\nrecipient shall not be required to comply with the  provisions  of  this\nparagraph  unless  he  or  she  shall have received a medical degree and\nuntil he or she shall have completed his or her  professional  training,\nor  active military service, or both. Any obligation to comply with such\nprovisions shall be cancelled upon  the  death  of  the  recipient.  The\ncommissioner  shall  make  regulations  to  provide  for  the  waiver or\nsuspension of any financial obligation where  compliance  would  involve\nextreme hardship.\n  d. The regents, after consultation with the commissioner of health,\nshall designate those areas of New York state which have a shortage of\nphysicians for the purposes of this subdivision and, should it be\nnecessary in selecting among the applicants, may establish relative\nrankings of those areas.\n  e. A recipient of an award shall report annually to the New York state\nhigher education services corporat...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have been released from such active duty on conditions not other\nthan honorable, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have a qualifying condition, as defined in\nsection one of the veterans' services law, and have received a discharge\nother than bad conduct or dishonorable from such service, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are\ndischarged LGBT veterans, as defined in section one of the veterans'\nservices law, and have received a discharge other than bad conduct or\ndishonorable from such service. Such scholarships shall be allocated to\neach county in the state in the same ratio that the number of legal\nresidents in such county, as determined by the most recent federal\ncensus, bears to the total number of residents in the state; provided,\nhowever, that no county shall be allocated fewer scholarships than such\ncounty received during the year nineteen hundred\nsixty-eight--sixty-nine.\n  6. Regents scholarships in Cornell University. a. Number. Cornell\nUniversity shall grant, on a competitive basis, tuition reducing\nscholarships, to be known as regents scholarships in Cornell University,\nin the total amount of at least thirty thousand dollars each year for\nnew freshman awards. At least one such scholarship shall be awarded\nannually for each senate district of the state.\n  b. Amount. Each such scholarship shall entitle the recipient to a\ncredit against tuition in any of the tuition paying divisions of Cornell\nUniversity for four years or five years, depending on the number of\nyears required for the baccalaureate. The tuition credit for each such\nscholarship shall be determined by Cornell University on the basis of\nthe financial status of the scholarship holder as related to the cost of\neducation at such university. No such scholarship shall reduce the\ntuition by less than one hundred dollars nor by more than one thousand\ndollars.\n  c. Eligible list. Such scholarships shall be awarded annually by\nCornell University in the order of merit to candidates who meet the\nrequirements for admission to Cornell University and whose names appear\non lists established as the result of competitive examinations prepared\nunder the direction of the commissioner of education. In the award of\nsuch scholarships, preference shall be given, where other qualifications\nare equal, to the ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the aggregate of the amount of the\nawards received as (ii) the number of months the recipient failed to\ncomply with this condition bears to the number of months the recipient\nwas obligated to comply with this condition, together with interest at\nten percent per annum computed from the date on which the recipient\ncompleted professional training. Such recovery may be made over such\nperiod of time as is prescribed by the president. Any obligation to\ncomply with such provisions shall be cancelled upon the recipient's\ndeath. The commissioner shall adopt regulations to provide for the\nwaiver or suspension of any financial obligation in whole or in part\nwhere compliance would involve severe hardship. In determining whether\nto grant such waiver or suspension, the commissioner may consider\nwhether the recipient failed to complete the registered program for the\npreparation of teachers or completed such program under financial\nhardship by reason of the discontinuance of funding for the award of\nscholarships pursuant to this subdivision.\n  7-a. New York state math and science teaching incentive program awards\npursuant to section six hundred sixty-nine-d of this title.\n  8. Empire state challenger fellowships for teachers.  a. Six hundred\nfifty Empire state challenger fellowships shall be awarded annually in\naccordance with paragraphs b, c and d of this subdivision on a\ncompetitive basis as determined by the commissioner to individuals\nenrolled in a registered graduate program in any New York institution of\nhigher education which leads to permanent certification as a teacher of\nmathematics or science or other fields of teacher shortage as identified\nby the commissioner on or after January first, nineteen hundred\neighty-six. The commissioner shall to the extent practicable ensure that\nrecipients of such fellowships include individuals who are unrepresented\nor underrepresented in the respective disciplines.\n  b. A maximum of twenty-five fellowships for...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the aggregate of\nthe amount of the awards received as (ii) the number of months the\nrecipient failed to comply with this condition bears to the number of\nmonths the recipient was obligated to comply with this condition,\ntogether with interest at ten percent per annum computed from the date\non which the recipient completed professional training. Such recovery\nmay be made over such period of time as is prescribed by the president.\nAny obligation to comply with such provisions shall be cancelled upon\nthe recipient's death. The commissioner shall have regulations to\nprovide for the waiver or suspension of any financial obligation in\nwhole or part under this subdivision where compliance would involve\nextreme hardship. In determining whether to grant such waiver or\nsuspension, the commissioner may consider whether the recipient failed\nto complete the registered graduate program leading to permanent\ncertification as a teacher or completed such program under financial\nhardship by reason of the discontinuance of funding for the award of\nfellowships pursuant to this subdivision.\n  9. Regents physician loan forgiveness program. Regents physician loan\nforgiveness awards shall be awarded annually to physicians who agree to\npractice medicine in an area of New York state designated by the regents\nas having a shortage of physicians. Such awards shall be classified and\nallocated in accordance with regents rules.\n  a. Eligibility.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant must be a resident of New York state\nand licensed to practice medicine.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant must have completed a professional residency program\nwithin the five years immediately preceding the period for which the\nfirst award would be granted, or be within two years of completion of an\naccredited residency program in a primary care specialty designated in\nshort supply by the board of regents.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant must agree to practice medicine in an area in New\nYork state designated as having a shortage of physicians. The regents,\nafter consultation with the commissioners of health, corrections and\ncommunity supervision, mental health and developmental disabilities,\nshall designate those regions and facilities of New York state which\nhave a shortage of physicians for the purposes of this section and\nestablish relative rankings thereof.\n  b. Selection. The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner\nof health, shall establish criteria for the selection of participants in\nthe program. An applicant must satisfy at least one of the criteria\nestablished. A priority shall be accorded to any applicant who is\ncompleting the second year of the service requirement and is reapplying\nfor a new award. The criteria shall include but not be limited to the\nfollowing:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reapplication for a new award by a person who is completing the\nsecond year of a service requirement;\n  (ii) receipt of specific training in a primary care specialty or\nobstetrics, determined by the regents to be in short supply;\n  (iii) receipt of specific training or experience in serving a shortage\narea;\n  (iv) receipt of specific training or experience matching a specific\nmedical need existing in a shortage area; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>agreement pursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section to practice\nin an area determined by the regents to have a severe shortage of\nprimary care physician services.\n  c. Notification.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner shall then forward approved\napplications to the president and shall notify unsuccessful applicants;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The president shall verify the approved applicants':\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>eligibility; and\n  (ii) total undergraduate and medical school student expense;\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The president shall notify applicants of their award entitlement.\n  d. Service requirement. Within such time as the commissioner shall by\nregulation provide, a recipient of an award shall have agreed to\npractice medicine in a specific area designated as having a shortage of\nphysicians for a period of twelve months for each annual payment to be\nreceived by the recipient. Physicians in training who receive an award\nshall not receive credit toward their required service for time spent in\na training program. In no case shall the total number of months of\nservice required be less than twenty-four. The president shall, in\nconsultation with the commissioner, develop and secure from each award\nrecipient, a written agreement to:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_605__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>practice medicine in the designated shortage area;\n  (ii) to accept Medicare and Medicaid payments; and\n  (iii) to provide thirty-five hours per week of direct patient care in\nthe designated shortage area being served, or to the designated\npopulation being served.\nIf a recipient fails to comply fully with such conditions, the president\nshall be entitled to receive from such recipient an amount to be\ndetermined by the formula:\n                              A = 2B (t-s)\n                                      ---\n                                       t\nin  which "A" is the amount the president is entitled to recover; "B" is\nthe sum of all payments made to the recipient and the interest  on  such\namount which would be payable if at the times such awards were paid they\nwere  loans  bearing interest at the maximum prevailing rate; "t" is the\ntotal number of months in the recipient's period of obligated  services;\nand  "s"  is  the  number  of months of service actually rendered by the\nrecipient. Any amount which the president is entitled to  recover  under\nthis  paragraph  shall  be paid within the five-year period beginning on\nthe  date  that  the  recipient  failed  to  comply  with  this  service\ncondition.  Nothing  in  the written agreement shall affect the terms of\nemployment of the individual who shall  negotiate,  separate  and  apart\nfrom  the  program, his or her salary and other forms of employment with\nan agency, institution or  a  program  in  which  he  or  she  shall  be\nemployed.\n  Any obligation to comply with such provisions as outlined in this\nsection shall be cancelled upon the death of the recipient. The\ncommissioner shall make regulations to provide for the waiver or\nsuspension of any financial obligation which would involve extreme\nhardship.\n  e. Reporting. A recipient of an award shall report annually to the New\nYork state higher education services corporation, and the department of\nhealth on forms prescribed by the ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>First, to any applicant who is economically disadvantaged as\ndefined by the regents and a minority historically underrepresented in\nthe profession as determined by the regents after consultation with the\ncouncil on professional career opportunity created by section nine\nhundred forty-one of the executive law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Second, to any applicant who is a minority underrepresented in the\nprofession as determined by the regents after consultation with the\ncouncil on professional career opportunity created by section nine\nhundred forty-one of the executive law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Third, to any applicant who is a graduate of the state-sponsored\nopportunity program pursuant to section sixty-four hundred fifty-one or\nsixty-four hundred fifty-two of this chapter.\n  In the event that there are more applicants who have the same priority\nthan there are remaining scholarships, the commissioner shall distribute\nthe remaining number of such scholarships by means of a lottery or other\nform of random selection.\n  b. The commissioner shall then forward approved applications to the\npresident and shall notify unsuccessful applicants.\n  c. The president shall notify applicants of their award entitlement.\n  d. The president shall, in consultation with the commissioner, develop\nand secure from each successful applicant a written agreement to\npractice medicine or dentistry, as appropriate, in a designated shortage\narea. Within such time as the commissioner shall by regulation provide,\na recipient of an award shall have practiced medicine or dentistry in an\narea des...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>First, to any applicant who is economically disadvantaged as\ndefined by the regents and a minority historically underrepresented in\nthe profession or field as determined by the regents after consultation\nwith the council on professional career opportunity created by section\nnine hundred forty-one of the executive law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Second, to any applicant who is a minority underrepresented in the\nprofession or field determined by the regents after consultation with\nthe council on professional career opportunity created by section nine\nhundred forty-one of the executive law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_605__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Third, to any applicant who is enrolled in or is a graduate of the\nstate-sponsored opportunity program pursuant to section sixty-four\nhundred fifty-one or sixty-four hundred fifty-two of this chapter.\n  In the event that there are more applicants who have the same priority\nthan there are remaining scholarships, the commissioner shall distribute\nthe remaining number of such scholarships by means of a lottery or other\nform of random selection.\n  b. The commissioner shall then forward approved applications to the\npresident and shall notify unsuccessful applicants.\n  c. The president shall notify applicants of their award entitlement.\n  d. Within such time as the commissioner shall by regulation provide, a\nrecipient of an award shall have resided and been employed in a\nprofession or field designated by the regents in New York state for that\nnumber of months calculated by multiplying by twelve the number of\nannual awards received by the recipient. If a recipient fails to compl...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>