<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-606"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-606"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="606"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_606">
        <num>606</num>
        <heading>County awards for professional education in nursing, medicine, dentistry, optometry or veterinary medicine</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 606. County awards for professional education in nursing, medicine,\ndentistry, optometry or veterinary medicine.  Each county of the state\noutside New York city is hereby authorized to establish  awards in such\nmanner as the local legislative body of such county may determine, for\nattendance by legal residents of this state, who meet the citizenship\nrequirements established by article fourteen of this chapter for the\nprofessional study of nursing, medicine, dentistry, optometry or\nveterinary medicine, at approved nursing, medical, dental, optometry or\nveterinary medicine schools within the United States, conditioned upon\nthe promise of the scholarship holder to practice nursing, medicine,\ndentistry, optometry or veterinary medicine in such county for such\nperiod as such body may fix, following his licensing as a nurse,\nphysician, dentist, optometrist or veterinarian.  Each such award shall\nentitle the recipient to such sum of money as may be fixed by such body\nwhile in attendance at approved nursing, medical, dental, optometry or\nveterinary medicine schools in the United States during a period of not\nto exceed four years of professional study and for physicians for a\nfurther period of not to exceed two years while engaged in an internship\nor as a resident physician in an accredited hospital in the United\nStates. Such awards may, as an alternative to awards hereinbefore\nauthorized,  be granted by any such county to those already so licensed\nto practice nursing, medicine, dentistry, optometry or veterinary\nmedicine upon the promise of such grantees to practice within the county\nfor a period of time and upon such terms and conditions as the county\nmay fix, provided such recipient did not receive a similar award while a\nstudent.  The county shall appropriate annually such sums of money as\nmay be necessary to defray the costs of such awards and moneys so\nappropriated shall be deemed appropriated for a lawful county purpose\nand shall be raised by the same method as moneys required for other\nlawful county purposes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>