<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-610"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-610"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-06-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="610"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_610">
        <num>610</num>
        <heading>Liberty scholarships</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_610__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\namount of a Pell grant and (ii) the amount of such other state and\nfederal scholarships and grants, other than tuition assistance or\nsupplemental tuition assistance received under this chapter, which do\nnot require repayment, awarded to the recipient for the cost of\nattendance at the institution being attended, as reported to the\npresident; provided, however, that such scholarship shall be reduced one\ndollar for every three dollars of income in excess of eighteen thousand\ndollars of income; or\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_610__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the recipient attends any other degree-granting institution\nwithin New York state and enrolls in a program approved by the\ncommissioner, the annual scholarship award shall be based upon an amount\nequal to the average non-tuition cost of attendance, as determined by\nthe commissioner in consultation with the president and as approved by\nthe director of the budget, for a student at the state university of New\nYork or actual non-tuition cost of attendance at such institution,\nwhichever is less, reduced by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_610__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of a Pell grant the\nrecipient would have been entitled to had the recipient attended the\nstate university of New York and (ii) the amount of such other state and\nfederal scholarships and grants, other than tuition assistance or\nsupplemental tuition assistance received under this chapter, which do\nnot require repayment, awarded to the recipient for the cost of\nattendance at the institution being attended, as reported to the\npresident; provided, however, that such scholarships shall be reduced\none dollar for every three dollars of income in excess of eighteen\nthousand dollars of income.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_610__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Scholarships and grants that reduce the cost of attendance for\npurposes of determining the amount of a scholarship award shall not\ninclude supplemental financial assistance provided on a last dollar\nbasis pursuant to the provisions of section sixty-four hundred fifty-one\nor sixty-four hundred fifty-two of this chapter.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_610__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Non-tuition cost of attendance", as used in this paragraph, shall\nmean:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_610__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the actual amount charged by the institution for room and\nboard and (ii) an allowance for transportation, books and supplies as\ndetermined by the commissioner in consultation with the president and as\napproved by the director of the budget, provided that such determination\nshall be made no later than December first of each year for use in the\nsucceeding academic year. In the event a student does not incur room or\nboard charges at the institution, "non-tuition cost of attendance" shall\nmean an allowance for room and board as determined by the commissioner\nin consultation with the president and approved by the director of the\nbudget. In determining allowances pursuant to this subparagraph, the\ncommissioner may take into consideration the allowances provided for in\nthe Pell grant program.\n  b. For the purposes of determining annual scholarships, the term\n"income" shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of\nsection six hundred sixty-three of this chapter, except that in making\nsuch determination, adjusted gross income, as defined in regulations of\nthe trustees of the corporation, shall be used instead of New York state\nnet taxable income.\n  c. In no event shall the combination of all student financial aid\nreceived by a student exceed the recipient's total cost of attendance at\nthe institution being attended.\n  7. Ineligibility for a tuition assistance, supplemental tuition\nassistance or Pell grant award in a particular academic year shall not\nprevent a recipient from receiving a liberty scholarship award in any\nsubsequent year in which such recipient shall become eligible for a\ntuition assistance, supplemental tuition assistance or Pell grant award,\nprovided, however, the seven-year period referred to in subdivision\nseven of section six hundred sixty-five of this chapter, or an\neight-year period for part-time study, shall not have elapsed.\n  8. Relationship to educational opportunity programs. Liberty\nscholarship recipients who...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>