<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6201"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6201">
        <num>6201</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and intent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6201.  Legislative findings and intent.  1. The legislature finds\nthat in order to meet the state's responsibility to provide\npost-secondary education in New York city beyond the associate degree\nlevel, as it does elsewhere in the state, there should be full state\nfunding of senior college operating and debt service. The governance of\nthe university must reflect increased state responsibility but should\npreserve the city's participation in the governance of the university it\ncreated and developed at city expense.\n  2. The legislature intends that the city university of New York should\nbe maintained as an independent system of higher education governed by\nits own board of trustees responsible for the governance, maintenance\nand development of both senior and community college units of the city\nuniversity. The university must remain responsive to the needs of its\nurban setting and maintain its close articulation between senior and\ncommunity college units. Where possible, governance and operation of\nsenior and community colleges should be jointly conducted or conducted\nby similar procedures to maintain the university as an integrated system\nand to facilitate articulation between units.\n  3. The legislature's intent is that the city university be supported\nas an independent and integrated system of higher education on the\nassumption that the university will continue to maintain and expand its\ncommitment to academic excellence and to the provision of equal access\nand opportunity for students, faculty and staff from all ethnic and\nracial groups and from both sexes.\n  4. The city university is of vital importance as a vehicle for the\nupward mobility of the disadvantaged in the city of New York. The\npioneering efforts of the SEEK and College Discovery programs must not\nbe diminished as a result of greater state financial responsibility for\nthe operation of the city and state of New York.\n  5. Only the strongest commitment to the special needs of an urban\nconstituency justifies the legislature's support of an independent and\nunique structure for the university.  Activities at the city university\ncampuses must be undertaken in a spirit which recognizes and responds to\nthe imperative need for affirmative action and the positive desire to\nhave city university personnel reflect the diverse communities which\ncomprise the people of the city and state of New York. In its urban\nenvironment this commitment should be evident in all the guidelines\nestablished by the board of trustees for the university's operation,\nfrom admissions and hiring to contracting for the provision of goods,\nservices, new construction and facilities rehabilitation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>