<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6204"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6204">
        <num>6204</num>
        <heading>Board of trustees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of trustees shall consist of seventeen trustees. Ten of\nthe trustees shall be appointed by the governor with the advice and\nconsent of the senate. Five of the trustees shall be appointed by the\nmayor of the city of New York with the advice and consent of the senate.\nOne ex-officio trustee shall be the chairperson of the university\nstudent senate. One ex-officio non-voting trustee shall be the\nchairperson of the university faculty senate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The ex-officio trustees shall be afforded the same parliamentary\nprivileges as are conferred upon the appointed trustees. The ex-officio\ntrustees shall be subject to every provision of any general, special or\nlocal law, ordinance, charter, code, rule or regulation applying to the\nappointed trustees of the board with respect to the discharge of their\nduties including, but not limited to, those provisions setting forth\ncodes of ethics, disclosure requirements and prohibiting business and\nprofessional activities. The chair of the university faculty senate\nshall not participate as a voting trustee in any matter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, (ii) and (iii) of this\nparagraph, the term of office of each appointed trustee shall be seven\nyears renewable solely for one additional term of seven years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members of the board of higher education in the city of New\nYork shall be and constitute the members of the board of trustees for\nthe period beginning July first, nineteen hundred seventy-nine and\nending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-nine.\n  (ii) Effective January first, nineteen hundred eighty, the governor\nshall appoint one trustee to a term which expires on June thirtieth,\nnineteen hundred eighty, two trustees to terms which expire on June\nthirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-one, one trustee to a term which\nexpires on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two, two trustees to\nterms which expire on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-three, one\ntrustee to a term which expires on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred\neighty-four, two trustees to terms which expire on June thirtieth,\nnineteen hundred eighty-five, and one trustee to a term which expires on\nJune thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-six. Upon expirations of these\nterms, the governor shall appoint trustees to full seven year terms.\n  (iii) Effective January first, nineteen hundred eighty, the mayor\nshall appoint one trustee to a term which expires on June thirtieth,\nnineteen hundred eighty, one trustee to a term which expires on June\nthirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-two, one trustee to a term which\nexpires on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-three, one trustee to\na term which expires on June thirtieth, nineteen hundred eighty-five,\nand one trustee to a term which expires on June thirtieth, nineteen\nhundred eighty-six.  Upon expiration of the terms the mayor shall\nappoint trustees to full seven year terms.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A chairperson and a vice chairperson of the board of trustees\nshall be appointed by and shall serve at the pleasure of the governor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At least four of the trustees initially appointed by the governor\nand two of the trustees initially appointed by the mayor pursuant to\nthis subdivision shall be selected from among the persons serving on the\nboard of higher education in the city of New York, on and after January\nfirst, nineteen hundred seventy-nine.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The five trustees appointed by the mayor shall include at least\none resident of each of the five boroughs of the city of New York.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The trustees appointed by the governor shall include at least one\nresident of each of the five boroughs of the city of New York.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The trustees appointed by the mayor shall include at least one\nalumnus of an educational unit in the city university. The trustees\nappointed by the governor shall include at least two alumnae of an\neducational unit in the city university including at least one other\nalumnus of a community college.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event of a vacancy occurring in the office of trustee by\ndeath, resignation or otherwise, a successor shall be chosen in the same\nmanner as was the trustee whose office became vacant, to serve for the\nbalance of the term.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any trustee appointed by the governor may be removed by the\ngovernor and any trustee appointed by the mayor may be removed by the\nmayor.  Removal of a trustee by the governor or the mayor shall be upon\nproof of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>official misconduct or neglect of official duties; or (ii)\nmental or physical inability to perform his duties. Before the removal\nof a trustee, the trustee shall receive due and timely written notice of\nthe charges and a copy of the charges. The trustee shall be entitled to\na hearing on the charges pursuant to due and timely notice before the\ngovernor or the mayor, as the case may be, and to the assistance of\ncounsel on such hearing.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Trustees shall receive no compensation for their services but\nshall be reimbursed for their actual and necessary expenses incurred by\nthem in the performance of their duties under this article.\n  3. Meetings of the board of trustees.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The by-laws of the board of\ntrustees shall provide for regular meetings. At least seven days notice\nof every regular meeting and a copy of the agenda for that meeting shall\nbe mailed to the usual address of each trustee. Resolutions for the\nconsideration of the board of trustees must be mailed to the usual\naddress of each trustee no less than seven days prior to a meeting,\nunless the chair shall make available in writing on the day of the\nmeeting the facts which necessitate an immediate vote. The agendas for\nsuch meetings shall be available electronically on the city university\nof New York website three days prior to the meetings unless an executive\ncommittee meeting has been called in which an agenda must be available\ntwenty-four hours in advance, and shall be considered public records. A\nsummary of resolutions and board actions for any such meeting of the\nboard of trustees shall be electronically available on the city\nuniversity of New York website no later than seven days after the\nmeeting and shall be considered public records. The approved minutes,\nattendance, voting record, and either transcripts or video record for\nany such meeting must be posted no later than seven days following their\napproval by the board. Information posted on the city university of New\nYork website regarding board of trustee meetings shall remain on the\nsite as archived data for a minimum of ten years. All meetings shall be\nheld in accordance with article seven of the public officers law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The chairperson, the vice chairperson or any five trustees acting\nby petition, may at any time call a special meeting of the board of\ntrustees and fix the time and place therefor. Each trustee shall receive\ntelephonic or written notice of a special meeting at least twenty-four\nhours prior to the special meeting. An agenda for such meeting,\nincluding meetings of any committees and subcommittees under the purview\nof the board of trustees, shall be available electronically on the city\nuniversity of New York website twenty-four hours prior to the special\nmeeting of the board and shall be considered a public record. A summary\nof resolutions and board actions for any such meeting of the board of\ntrustees shall be electronically available on the city university of New\nYork website no later than seven days after the meeting and shall be\nconsidered a public record. The approved minutes, attendance, voting\nrecord, and either transcripts or video record for any such meeting must\nbe posted no later than seven days following their approval by the\nboard. Information posted on the city university of New York website\nregarding board of trustee meetings shall remain on the site as archived\ndata for a minimum of ten years. Any such meeting of the board of\ntrustees shall be conducted in accordance with article seven of the\npublic officers law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nine trustees attending a meeting shall constitute a quorum for\nthe transaction of business by the board of trustees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6204__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of trustees shall hold at least one public hearing\neach year in each of the five boroughs of the city of New York. The\npurpose of such hearing shall be to receive testimony and statements\nfrom concerned individuals about university issues.\n  (ii) The board of trustees shall fix the time, place, duration and\nformat of each hearing.\n  (iii) At least thirty days notice of the hearing shall be given by the\nchairperson of the board of trustees to all of the trustees, to all\npresidents of educational units, to the chair of faculty-senate bodies\nof educational units, to all student government presidents of\neducational units, to the borough president, the members of the city\ncouncil, the members of the board of estimate, the local community\nboards of the borough where the hearing is to be held and to the media.\nThe notice shall contain the time, place and date of the public hearing.\nSuch information shall be made electronically available on the city\nuniversity of New York website. Any such meeting of the board of\ntrustees shall be conducted in accordance with article seven of the\npublic officers law.\n  (iv) At least three trustees shall attend each hearing.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>