<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6206"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6206"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6206"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6206/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6206/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6206">
        <num>6206</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of trustees shall establish positions, departments,\ndivisions and faculties; appoint and in accordance with the provisions\nof law fix salaries of instructional and non-instructional employees\ntherein; establish and conduct courses and curricula; prescribe\nconditions of student admission, attendance and discharge; and shall\nhave the power to determine in its discretion whether tuition shall be\ncharged and to regulate tuition charges, and other instructional and\nnon-instructional fees and other fees and charges at the educational\nunits of the city university. The trustees shall review any proposed\ncommunity college tuition increase and the justification for such\nincrease. The justification provided by the community college for such\nincrease shall include a detailed analysis of ongoing operating costs,\ncapital, debt service expenditures, and all revenues. The trustees shall\nnot impose a differential tuition charge based upon need or income. All\nstudents enrolled in programs leading to like degrees at the senior\ncolleges shall be charged a uniform rate of tuition, except for\ndifferential tuition rates based on state residency. Notwithstanding any\nother provision of this paragraph, the trustees may authorize the\nsetting of a separate category of tuition rate, that shall be greater\nthan the tuition rate for resident students and less than the tuition\nrate for non-resident students, only for students enrolled in distance\nlearning courses who are not residents of the state; provided, however,\nthat:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Commencing with the two thousand eleven--two thousand twelve\nacademic year and ending in the two thousand fifteen--two thousand\nsixteen academic year, the city university of New York board of trustees\nshall be empowered to increase the resident undergraduate rate of\ntuition by not more than three hundred dollars over the resident\nundergraduate rate of tuition adopted by the board of trustees in the\nprior academic year, provided however that commencing with the two\nthousand eleven--two thousand twelve academic year and ending with the\ntwo thousand sixteen--two thousand seventeen academic year if the annual\nresident undergraduate rate of tuition would exceed five thousand\ndollars, then a tuition credit for each eligible student, as determined\nand calculated by the New York state higher education services\ncorporation pursuant to section six hundred eighty-nine-a of this\nchapter, shall be applied toward the tuition charged for each semester,\nquarter or term of study. Tuition for each semester, quarter or term of\nstudy shall not be due for any student eligible to receive such tuition\ncredit until the tuition credit is calculated and applied against the\ntuition charged for the corresponding semester, quarter or term.\n  (ii) Commencing with the two thousand seventeen--two thousand eighteen\nacademic year and ending in the two thousand twenty--two thousand\ntwenty-one academic year the city university of New York board of\ntrustees shall be empowered to increase the resident undergraduate rate\nof tuition by not more than two hundred dollars over the resident\nundergraduate rate of tuition adopted by the board of trustees in the\nprior academic year, provided however that if the annual resident\nundergraduate rate of tuition would exceed five thousand dollars, then a\ntuition credit for each eligible student, as determined and calculated\nby the New York state higher education services corporation pursuant to\nsection six hundred eighty-nine-a of this titl...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Beginning in state fiscal year two thousand seventeen--two\nthousand eighteen and ending in state fiscal year two thousand\ntwenty--two thousand twenty-one, the state shall appropriate and make\navailable general fund operating support, including fringe benefits, for\nthe city university in an amount not less than the amount appropriated\nand made available in the prior state fiscal year; provided, however,\nthat if the governor declares a fiscal emergency, and communicates such\nemergency to the temporary president of the senate and speaker of the\nassembly, state support for operating expenses at the state university\nand city university may be reduced in a manner proportionate to one\nanother, and the aforementioned provisions shall not apply; provided\nfurther, the state shall appropriate and make available general fund\nsupport to fully fund the tuition credit pursuant to subdivision two of\nsection six hundred sixty-nine-h of this chapter.\n  (vi) Notwithstanding any law, rule, regulation or practice to the\ncontrary, commencing with the two thousand twenty-three--two thousand\ntwenty-four academic year and ending in the two thousand\ntwenty-five--two thousand twenty-six academic year, following the review\nand approval of the chancellor of the city university or his or her\ndesignee, the city university of New York board of trustees shall be\nempowered to annually impose differential tuition rates on non-resident\nundergraduate and graduate rates of tuition for senior colleges,\nprovided that such rates are competitive with the rates of tuition\ncharged by peer institutions and that the board of trustees annually\nprovide the reason and methodology behind any rate increase to the\ngovernor, the temporary president of the senate, and the speaker of the\nassembly prior to the approval of such increases.\n  * NB Effective until July 1, 2027\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of trustees shall establish positions,\ndepartments, divisions and faculties; appoint and in accordance with the\nprovisions of law fix salaries of instructional and non-instructional\nemployees therein; establish and conduct courses and curricula;\nprescribe conditions of student admission, attendance and discharge; and\nshall have the power to determine in its discretion whether tuition\nshall be charged and to regulate tuition charges, and other\ninstructional and non-instructional fees and other fees and charges at\nthe educational units of the city university. The trustees shall review\nany proposed community college tuition increase and the justification\nfor such increase. The justification provided by the community college\nfor such increase shall include a detailed analysis of ongoing operating\ncosts, capital, debt service expenditures, and all revenues. The\ntrustees shall not impose a differential tuition charge based upon need\nor income. All students enrolled in programs leading to like degrees at\nthe senior colleges shall be charged a uniform rate of tuition, except\nfor differential tuition rates based on state residency. Notwithstanding\nany other provision of this paragraph, the trustees may authorize the\nsetting of a separate category of tuition rate, that shall be greater\nthan the tuition rate for resident students and less than the tuition\nrate for non-resident students, only for students enrolled in distance\nlearning courses who are not residents of the state. The trustees shall\nfurther provide that the payment of tuition and fees by any student who\nis not a resident of New York state, other than a non-immigrant\nnoncitizen within the meaning of paragraph</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6206__subsec_i__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of subsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection 1101 of title 8 of the United States Code, shall be paid at a\nrate or charge no greater than that imposed for students who are\nresidents of the state if such student:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6206__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>attended an approved New York high school for two or more years,\ngraduated from an approved New York high school and applied for\nattendance at an institution or educational unit of the city university\nwithin five years of receiving a New York state high school diploma; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6206__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>attended an approved New York state program for general\nequivalency diploma exam preparation, received a general equivalency\ndiploma issued within New York state and applied for attendance at an\ninstitution or educational unit of the city university within five years\nof receiving a general equivalency diploma issued within New York state;\nor\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6206__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>was enrolled in an institution or educational unit of the city\nuniversity in the fall semester or quarter of the two thousand one--two\nthousand two academic year and was authorized by such institution or\neducational unit to pay tuition at the rate or charge imposed for\nstudents who are residents of the state.\n  A student without lawful immigration status shall also be required to\nfile an affidavit with such institution or educational unit stating that\nthe student has filed an application to legalize his or her immigration\nstatus, or will file such an application as soon as he or she is\neligible to do so. The trustees shall not adopt changes in tuition\ncharges prior to the enactment of the annual budget. The board of\ntrustees may accept as partial reimbursement for the education of\nveterans of the armed forces of the United States who are otherwise\nqualified such sums as may be authorized by federal legislation to be\npaid for such education. The board of trustees may condu...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6206__subsec_a__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of\nsubsection</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 1101 of title 8 of the United States Code,\nshall be paid at a rate or charge no greater than that imposed for\nstudents who are residents of the state if such student:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>attended an approved New York high school for two or more years,\ngraduated from an approved New York high school and applied for\nattendance at an institution or educational unit of the city university\nwithin five years of receiving a New York state high school diploma; or\n  (ii) attended an approved New York state program for general\nequivalency diploma exam preparation, received a general equivalency\ndiploma issued within New York state and applied for attendance at an\ninstitution or educational unit of the city university within five years\nof receiving a general equivalency diploma issued within New York state;\nor\n  (iii) was enrolled in an institution or educational unit of the city\nuniversity in the fall semester or quarter of the two thousand one--two\nthousand two academic year and was authorized by such institution or\neducational unit to pay tuition at the rate or charge imposed for\nstudents who are residents of the state.\n  A student without lawful immigration status shall also be required to\nfile an affidavit with such institution or educational unit stating that\nthe student has filed an application to legalize his or her immigration\nstatus, or will file such an application as soon as he or she is\neligible to do so. Except as otherwise authorized in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, the trustees shall not adopt changes in tuition\ncharges prior to the enactment of the annual budget. The board of\ntrustees may accept as partial reimbursement for the education of\nveterans of the armed forces of the United States who are otherwise\nqualified such sums as may be authorized by federal legislation to be\npaid for such education. The board of trustees may conduct on a fee\nbasis extension courses and courses for adult education appropriate to\nthe field of higher education. In all courses and courses of study it\nmay, in its discretion, require students to pay library, laboratory,\nlocker, breakage and other instructional and non-instructional fees and\nmeet the cost of books and consumable supplies. In addition to the\nforegoing fees and charges, the board of trustees may impose and collect\nfees and charges for student government and other student activities and\nreceive and expend them as agent or trustee.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2027\n  (a-2) The trustees shall further provide that the payment of tuition\nand fees by any student who is not a resident of New York state shall be\npaid at a rate or charge no greater than that imposed for students who\nare residents of the state if such student is enrolled in any college or\neducational unit of the city university of New York and is attending\nsuch college or educational unit in accordance with the federal GI bills\nand in compliance with all applicable eligibility requirements thereof.\n  (a-3) The trustees shall further provide that the payment of tuition\nand fees by any student who is not a resident of New York state shall be\npaid at a rate or charge no greater than that imposed for students who\nare residents of the state if such student is enrolled in any college or\neducational unit of the city university of New York and is the spouse or\nthe dependent of a member of the armed forces of the United States on\nfull-time active duty and not stationed in this state immediat...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation, the board of trustees may permit persons\nsixty years of age or over to audit courses given therein without\ntuition, examination, grading or credit therefor upon a space available\nbasis, as determined by the president of each such institution, provided\nthat such audit attendance does not deny course attendance at the city\nuniversity of New York by an individual who is otherwise qualified under\nthis section.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation, the board of trustees shall promulgate\nregulations to permit members of the New York city police department\nemployed in the rank of police officer, who are enrolled in programs\nleading to baccalaureate or higher degrees at a senior college of the\ncity university to attend one course without tuition, provided that such\ncourse is related to their employment as police officers and that such\ntuition-waived attendance does not deny course attendance at a senior\ncollege of the city university by an individual who is otherwise\nqualified under this section.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation, the board of trustees shall promulgate\nregulations to permit firefighters and fire officers employed by the New\nYork city fire department, who are enrolled in programs leading to\nbaccalaureate or higher degrees at a senior college of the city\nuniversity to attend one course without tuition, provided that such\ncourse is related to their employment as firefighters and fire officers\nand that such tuition-waived attendance does not deny course attendance\nat a senior college of the city university by an individual who is\notherwise qualified under this section.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2026\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The trustees shall further provide that any student who is not a\nlegal resident of New York state but is a United States citizen, a\npermanent lawful resident, an individual who is granted U or T\nnon-immigrant status pursuant to the Victims of Trafficking and Violence\nProtection Act of 2000, a person granted temporary protected status\npursuant to the Federal Immigration Act of 1990, an individual of a\nclass of refugees paroled by the attorney general of the United States\nunder his or her parole authority pertaining to the admission of\nnoncitizens to the United States, or an applicant without lawful\nimmigration status may have the payment of tuition and other fees and\ncharges reduced by state-aided programs, scholarships or other financial\nassistance awarded under the provisions of articles thirteen,\nthirteen-A, fourteen and fourteen-A of this chapter, provided that the\nstudent meets the requirements set forth in subparagraph (ii) of\nparagraph a or subparagraph (ii) of paragraph b of subdivision five of\nsection six hundred sixty-one of this chapter, as applicable.\n  * NB There are 2 par</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>'s\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation, the board of trustees shall be authorized\nto set a reduced rate of tuition and/or fees, or to waive tuition and/or\nfees entirely, for students participating in any dual or concurrent\nenrollment program with no reduction in other state, local, or other\nsupport for such students earning college credit that such higher\neducation partner would otherwise be eligible to receive; provided that,\nfor purposes of this provision, a dual or concurrent enrollment program\nshall mean one or more college courses taken by a high school student\nthrough a community college or a senior college of the city university\nwhile such student is still enrolled in high school and for which the\nstudent may receive both high school and college credit.\n  * NB There are 2 par</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>'s\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In state fiscal year two thousand twenty-two--two thousand\ntwenty-three and thereafter, the state shall appropriate and make\navailable general fund operating support in the amount of the tuition\ncredit calculated pursuant to section six hundred eighty-nine-a of this\nchapter annually.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For purposes of this paragraph, "Team USA athlete" means any\nstudent athlete who meets the eligibility standards defined and approved\nby the United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee and by the\nnational governing body for the sport in which the athlete competes.\n  (ii) Notwithstanding the provisions of any other general, special or\nlocal law, rule or regulation and pursuant to an appropriation and\nfunding being made for such purpose, the trustees shall further provide\nthat the payment of tuition and fees by any student who is not a\nresident of New York state shall be paid at a rate or charge no greater\nthan that imposed for students who are residents of this state if such\nstudent is enrolled in an institution or educational unit of the city\nuniversity of New York, is a Team USA athlete, and is training in New\nYork State in an elite level program approved by the United States\nOlympic and Paralympic Committee.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2026\n  8. The board of trustees shall, on the recommendation of its faculty\nor faculties, grant the certificates, diplomas and degrees which were\nannounced in the bulletins of the existing public institutions of higher\nlearning published for the term beginning immediately prior to April\nsixteenth, nineteen hundred twenty-six, and also such other degrees and\nhonors as the regents thereafter specifically authorized or may\nhereafter authorize it to grant.\n  9. When a center is first opened, the board of trustees shall submit\nan initial estimate of the sum needed for its support, maintenance and\noperation, based on an estimated original enrollment of students, for\nthe fiscal year or portion thereof immediately following. Such estimate\nshall be acted upon as hereinbefore prescribed for current annual\nbudgets; and in the event that an initial appropriation be for a part of\nthe fiscal year only, then in making calculation for the succeeding\nannual appropriation, the initial appropriation shall be taken as the\n...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6206__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inform each victim of a sexual offense of their\noptions to notify proper law enforcement authorities, including\non-campus and local police;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6206__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>inform the victim of a sexual offense of\nthe right to report or not to report such offense to local law\nenforcement agencies; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6206__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>offer the option to be assisted by campus\nauthorities in notifying such authorities, if the victim of sexual\nassault so chooses, all in compliance with applicable federal law,\nincluding, but not limited to, the federal Campus Sexual Assault\nVictims' Bill of Rights under Title 20 U.S. Code Section 1092</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n  b. As used in this subdivision, the following terms shall have the\nfollowing meanings:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Local law enforcement agencies" means any agency or agencies\nemploying peace officers or police officers for the enforcement of the\nlaws of the state, and which has or have jurisdiction under provisions\nof the criminal procedure law over offenses occurring at or on the\ngrounds of any institution subject to the provisions of this\nsubdivision.\n  (ii) "Missing student" means any student of an institution subject to\nthe provisions of this subdivision, who resides in a facility owned or\noperated by such institution and who is reported to such institution as\nmissing from his or her residence.\n  (iii) "Violent felony offense" means a violent felony offense as\ndefined in subdivision one of section 70.02 of the penal law.\n  16. The board of trustees shall appoint for the city university campus\nofficers who shall have the powers of peace officers as set forth in the\ncriminal procedure law within the geographical area of the city of New\nYork. A campus officer designated as a peace officer must have\nsatisfactorily completed or complete, within one year of the date of\nsuch designation, a course of law enforcement training prescribed by the\nmunicipal police training council in consultation with the city\nuniversity board of trustees.\n  18. Notwithstanding any law, rule or regulation to the contrary, the\ncity university of New York board of trustees shall pass a resolution by\nJune first, two thousand fifteen, to develop a plan to make available to\nstudents enrolled in an academic program of the city university of New\nYork beginning in the two thousand sixteen--two thousand seventeen\nacademic year, approved experiential or applied learning activities.\nSuch experiential or applied learning activities may include completion\nof activities related to students' program of study, including, but not\nlimited to, service-learning activities completed as part of a course,\npaid or unpaid internships, faculty-supervised undergraduate projects\nand activities leadin...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6206__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision one of section one hundred forty-five of the public\nbuildings law.\n  21. The board of trustees shall adopt a policy requiring that each\ninstitution of the city university of New York collaborate with\nstudents, faculty and staff to encourage campuses to eliminate the use\nof certain plastic items generally recognized by the public as being\ndesigned for single use. Such plastic items may include, but shall not\nbe limited to, tableware, straws, stirrers, cups and food service\ncontainers. In establishing such a policy, the trustees shall consider\nthe following:\n  a. the availability of affordable alternatives;\n  b. the accessibility of alternatives to all students, faculty, and\nstaff;\n  c. an evaluation of the effectiveness of reusable alternatives; and\n  d. benchmarks for assessing progress.\n  22. Notwithstanding any law, rule or regulation to the contrary, the\nboard of trustees shall establish a policy authorizing senior colleges\nand community colleges within the city university of New York to grant\nposthumous degrees to enrolled matriculated students whose death occurs\nprior to graduation. Such policy shall provide that, upon terms set in\nthe policy, any remaining credit requirements shall be waived for any\nstudent who dies and who otherwise would have been eligible for\ngraduation had they been able to complete their academic career.\n  23. Notwithstanding any law, rule or regulation to the contrary, the\ncity university of New York board of trustees shall, by June first, two\nthousand twenty-five, develop a plan to make available to students\nenrolled in an academic program of the city university of New York\nbeginning in the two thousand twenty-five--two thousand twenty-six\nacademic year, approved experiential or applied learning activities, as\ndefined in subdivision eighteen of this section. Such plan shall be\ndeveloped in consultation with university faculty senate, the university\nstudent senate and other stakeholders. Su...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>