<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6207"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6207">
        <num>6207</num>
        <heading>Administration of civil service</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6207. Administration of civil service.  The city university, for the\npurpose of administering the state civil service law, shall be deemed to\nbe a municipal employer, provided, however, that the city university may\nelect to delegate the administration of any or all of the provisions of\nthe civil service law, except article fourteen, to the department of\npersonnel of the city of New York.  In that event, the city department\nof personnel shall enter into a contract with such university for the\nrendition of such services.  The city university of New York shall\ncompensate the city of New York for such services only with respect to\nsuch services rendered for or on behalf of the senior colleges of such\nuniversity.  If the city of New York and city university cannot agree on\nthe amount of such compensation, the state comptroller shall determine\nthe fair and reasonable value of such services and the city university\nshall pay such sum to the city of New York.  Any person on an eligible\nlist for a position with the city university of New York in effect on\nthe effective date of this article shall continue to hold such position\non such list and shall be entitled to the same civil service rights.\nWith respect to all persons employed by the city university on the\neffective date of this article, the city university and the city of New\nYork shall be deemed to be the same public employer only for purposes of\ntransfer of employment under the civil service law.  No civil service\nright of an employee of the city university of New York employed on the\neffective date of this article shall be lost, impaired or affected by\nreason of the enactment of this article into law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>