<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6210"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6210">
        <num>6210</num>
        <heading>Non-Instructional positions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6210. Non-Instructional positions.  1. All persons hereafter\nappointed to serve in non-instructional positions in the city university\nshall be appointed for the probationary period of one year during which\nthe service of a person appointed to any such position may be\ndiscontinued by the board of trustees at any time. All persons employed\nin the non-instructional service of the board of trustees who have\nserved the full probationary period shall hold their respective\npositions during good behavior and efficient and competent service, and\nshall not be removed except for cause after a hearing by the affirmative\nvote of a majority of the board of trustees.\n  The board of trustees shall provide, by appropriate by-laws, for the\npresentation of charges, the reference thereof to a committee of the\nboard of trustees or to others for hearings, the conduct of such\nhearings, and the report thereof on the basis of which the board of\ntrustees shall take such action as it deems necessary or advisable.\n  A person who had acquired tenure in a position with the board of\ntrustees and who is promoted therefrom to a higher position shall be\nfully restored to his lower position and tenure therein in the event his\nservice is discontinued by the board of trustees during his probationary\nperiod in such higher position; upon restoration to such original\nposition the time such person served in the higher position shall be\ncredited for all purposes as if such service had been rendered in the\noriginal position.\n  2. Vacancies in positions included in group II (college office\nassistant B and college secretarial assistant B) and group III\n(administrative assistant) of item number sixteen of section sixty-two\nhundred twenty, shall be filled, as far as practicable, by promotion\nfrom among persons holding positions in the lower grades listed in group\nI (college office assistant A and college secretarial assistant A) and\ngroup II of such item number sixteen of section sixty-two hundred\ntwenty, respectively. Promotions shall be made by the board of trustees\nfrom group I and from group II of the aforesaid item number sixteen so\nthat of the total regularly employed in such three groups, not more than\nforty per centum of the total in the three groups shall be employed in\ngroup I and not less than fifteen per centum of the said total shall be\nemployed in group III.\n  3. The board of trustees shall, by appropriate by-laws, determine from\ntime to time the qualification requirements for all positions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>