<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6215"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6215"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6215"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6215/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6215/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6215/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6215/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6215">
        <num>6215</num>
        <heading>Fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6215. Fees. 1. All instructional and non-instructional fees\nhereafter received from matriculated students by the city university\nshall be accounted for and paid to the city university construction\nfund; subject, however, in the case of any such fees received by\ngraduate institutions, to any prior pledge thereof made by an agreement\nand lease both between the city university of New York and the dormitory\nauthority dated as of January tenth, nineteen hundred sixty-six. The\nfund shall receive, accept, invest, administer, expend and disburse the\ninstructional and non-instructional fees in accordance with the city\nuniversity construction fund act.\n  2. All instructional and non-instructional fees hereafter received\nfrom non-matriculated students by the city university shall be accounted\nfor and paid, as determined by the board of trustees, to the city\nuniversity construction fund; subject, however, in the case of any such\nfees received by graduate institutions, to any prior pledge thereof made\nby an agreement and lease both between the city university and the\ndormitory authority dated as of January tenth, nineteen hundred\nsixty-six. The fund shall receive, accept, invest, administer, expend\nand disburse the instructional and non-instructional fees in accordance\nwith the city university construction fund act.\n  3. For purposes of this article and article one hundred twenty-five-B\nof this chapter, and notwithstanding any other provision thereof, the\ninstructional and non-instructional fees received from matriculated and\nnon-matriculated students at New York city college of technology shall\nbe treated as if they were fees from a community college, and the\ninstructional and non-instructional fees received from matriculated and\nnon-matriculated students at the college of Staten Island shall be\ntreated as if they were senior college fees; provided, however, that\ninstructional and non-instructional fees from students attending that\nportion of the program of the college of Staten Island whose primary\npurpose is providing certificate and associate degree post secondary\nprograms in general and technical educational subjects shall be treated\nas if they were fees from a community college; provided, however, that\ninstructional and non-instructional fees received from all students\nattending the college of Staten Island, New York city college of\ntechnology and Medgar Evers college shall be used to offset the state\nshare of operating expenses.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>