<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6219"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6219"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6219"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6219/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6219/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6219/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6219/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6219">
        <num>6219</num>
        <heading>Conveyance of property</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6219__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>use property so deeded to it with\nimprovements wholly paid for by the state or (ii) sell or otherwise\ndispose of property so deeded to it with improvements wholly paid for by\nthe state, then, within thirty days after the beginning of the city\nfiscal year immediately following such conveyance, the city shall pay to\nthe state an amount equal to the current appraised value of such\nimprovements in such property.\n  e. The commissioner of general services of the state of New York may,\non the request of the city university construction fund for the purposes\nof dormitory authority financing of the portion of the Staten Island\nDevelopmental Center which is to be used by city university for senior\ncollege purposes exclusively, sell, convey, lease or exchange or\notherwise make available to the dormitory authority such state lands,\nsituate within the county of Richmond, the city of New York, upon such\nterms and conditions including consideration as the commissioner may fix\nand determine with the approval of the director of the budget.  However,\nin the event that all or any part of such property should not be\nutilized for senior college purposes exclusively, such property will\nrevert back to the state of New York.\n  2. Real property being used on the effective date of this article or\nto be used by the city university for senior college purposes which is\nencumbered by bonds, mortgages or similar debt instruments and title to\nwhich is held by an agency of the state subject to the provision that\nsuch title shall be conveyed to the city of New York by such state\nagency when such outstanding indebtedness has been satisfied, shall upon\nbeing so conveyed to such city by such agency thereupon be re-conveyed\nby such city to the state of New York.\n  3. Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, the provisions of this\nsection shall apply to Medgar Evers college.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>