<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6222"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6222"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-12-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6222"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6222/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6222/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6222/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6222/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6222">
        <num>6222</num>
        <heading>Admission of non-residents of the city of New York to each community college of the city university</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6222__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The methods and procedures for the admission of such\nnon-resident students to the city university of New York community\ncolleges shall be in accordance with the provisions of section\nsixty-three hundred five of this title. Notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovision of law, any reference contained in such section sixty-three\nhundred five to the state university trustees or to the chancellor of\nthe state university of New York shall, for the purposes of this\nsection, be deemed to mean and refer to the board of trustees and the\nchancellor of the city university of New York, respectively.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6222__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provided, further, in accordance with section six thousand three\nhundred five of this title, the chief fiscal officer of each county, as\ndefined in section 2.00 of the local finance law, shall, upon\napplication and submission to him of satisfactory evidence, issue to any\nperson desiring to enroll in a community college as a non-resident\nstudent, a certificate of residence form showing that said person is a\nresident of said county. If the chief fiscal officer of a county refuses\nto issue such a certificate on the ground that the person applying\ntherefor is not a resident of such county, the person applying may\nappeal to the chancellor of the city university. The chancellor of the\ncity university shall make a determination after a hearing, upon ten\ndays' notice to such chief fiscal officer of the county, and such\ndetermination shall be final and binding on the county. Such person\nshall, upon his registration for each college year, file with the\ncollege such a certificate of residence form issued not earlier than two\nmonths prior thereto, and such certificate of residence form shall be\nvalid for a period of one year from the date of issuance.\n  3. The city university board of trustees shall work in conjunction\nwith the state university board of trustees for the purposes of\nexamining the laws, regulations, and policies regarding community\ncollege charges for non-resident students and submitting a report to the\nlegislature pursuant to subdivision eleven of section sixty-three\nhundred five of this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>