<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6225"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6225"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6225"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6225/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6225/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6225">
        <num>6225</num>
        <heading>Pending actions and proceedings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6225. Pending actions and proceedings.  No action or proceeding\nbased upon a cause of action which arose prior to the effective date of\nthis article or, with respect to Medgar Evers college, prior to July\nfirst, nineteen hundred ninety-four, brought by or against the city of\nNew York, the city university of New York or its board of trustees, or\nthe city university construction fund shall be affected by any provision\nof this article, but the same may be prosecuted or defended by the\ncorporation counsel of the city of New York in the name of the body\ncorporate of the city university of New York created by this article in\nthe same court in which the action is pending.  In all such actions and\nproceedings such body corporate, upon application to the court, shall be\nsubstituted as a party.  Judgments or awards in any such action or\nproceeding shall be paid by the city of New York in the same manner as\nprior to the effective date of this article, provided, however, the\nstate shall reimburse the city to the extent required by law in effect\nat the time the cause of action arose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>