<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6227"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6227"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6227"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6227/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6227/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6227">
        <num>6227</num>
        <heading>Reference in provisions relating to retirement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6227. Reference in provisions relating to retirement.  Whenever the\nterm "board of higher education of the city of New York" or "board of\nhigher education of a city having a population of one million or more"\nis referred to or designated in any charter or administrative code or\nany other general, special or local law relating to pension or\nretirement systems, including but not limited to the New York city\nemployees' retirement system, the New York city teachers' retirement\nsystem, the board of education retirement system or board of higher\neducation optional retirement program, such reference or designation\nshall be deemed to refer to the corporate body of the city university of\nNew York continued by this article.  Whenever the provisions of such law\nrequire the city of New York to make payments to such pension or\nretirement systems or program on behalf of instructional and\nnon-instructional staff of senior colleges of the city university of New\nYork, such payments shall be made, with respect to employment on and\nafter the effective date of this article, by the city university of New\nYork.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>