<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6229"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6229"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6229"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6229/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6229/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6229/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6229/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6229">
        <num>6229</num>
        <heading>City university of New York community college budget process</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6229. City university of New York community college budget process.\n1. For the purposes of this section and section sixty-two hundred\ntwenty-one of this article, the term "approved programs and services"\nshall mean and include all programs and services provided by the\ncommunity colleges, except for campus schools or other elementary or\nsecondary schools which receive state aid under other provisions of law,\nprovided that all such programs have been approved as a part of the\nmaster plan of the city university and as a part of the regents plan for\nhigher education or general revision thereof pursuant to section two\nhundred thirty-seven of this chapter.\n  2. For each city fiscal year, the chancellor of the city university\nshall prepare a proposed operating and capital budget for all approved\nprograms and services. The form and content of such proposed operating\nand capital budget shall be the same as that approved by the state\ndirector of the budget for the community colleges of the state\nuniversity of New York. The proposed operating budget shall be submitted\nin accordance with subdivision one-b of section sixty-three hundred four\nof this chapter and shall also set forth the separate operating budgets\nof each community college.\n  3. Such proposed operating and capital budget, after approval by the\nboard of trustees, shall be submitted to the mayor of the city of New\nYork for his review and approval. Not later than October first of the\ncalendar year preceding the city fiscal year, the mayor shall submit to\nthe state budget director, in the form and content required by\nsubdivision two hereof, the amount of expenditures that he will\nrecommend in his executive budget for the following fiscal year for such\napproved programs and services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>