<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6233"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6233"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6233"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6233/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6233/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6233/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6233/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6233">
        <num>6233</num>
        <heading>Reports of the city university trustees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6233__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a comparison of actual disbursements with the state fiscal year\nexpenditure plan;\n  (ii) the reallocation between campuses of full-time positions and\nfilled full-time positions compared to annual targets;\n  (iii) campus and lump sum transfers and interchanges; and\n  (iv) identification of any revenue shortfalls, deficiencies,\nsurpluses, or budgetary actions by the governor.\n  b. In addition to the items listed in paragraph a of this subdivision,\nthe reports submitted on the fifteenth of October through July of each\nyear will include all receipts of the city university and a comparison\nof actual receipts with the state fiscal year revenue plan.\n  c. In addition to the items listed in paragraphs a and b of this\nsubdivision, the reports submitted on the fifteenth day of November and\nApril of each year will include:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6233__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>comparison of actual enrollment to enrollment targets;\n  (ii) summary of target and actual full-time equivalent positions; and\n  (iii) breakdown by major purpose of target and filled full-time\npositions.\n  3. The trustees of the city university shall submit to the governor,\nthe state comptroller, the legislature and the mayor of the city of New\nYork, within one hundred twenty days after the close of each city\nuniversity fiscal year, an annual financial statement for the senior\ncolleges which has been audited by an independent certified public\naccountant and prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting\nprinciples as prescribed by the state comptroller.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>