<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6250"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6250"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6250"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6250/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6250/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6250/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6250/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6250">
        <num>6250</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6250.  Definitions. Wherever used in this article:\n  1. The term "city university" means the city university of New York\nunder the jurisdiction of the board of higher education of the city of\nNew York.\n  2. The term "board" means the board of higher education of the city of\nNew York.\n  3. The term "eligible employees" means members of the instructional\nstaffs of the colleges administered by the board of higher education in\nthe city of New York pursuant to the provisions of article one hundred\ntwenty-five of the education law, who are employed in the following\ntitles: president, dean, director, professor, associate professor,\nassistant professor, instructor, tutor, fellow, lecturer, librarian,\nassociate librarian, assistant librarian, library assistant, registrar,\nassistant registrar, registrar's assistant, principal, first assistant,\nsupervisor, assistant teacher, critic teacher, teacher, college science\nassistant, college science technician, college engineering technician,\nand any other members of the instructional staffs of such colleges as\ndefined in section sixty-two hundred six, subdivision 1b of the\neducation law, and such other titles as the board in its discretion may\nadd thereto, by reason of their close relationship to the educational\npurposes required to carry on the functions of the city university. No\nperson receiving a benefit by reason of his retirement from any\nretirement or pension system of New York state or any political\nsubdivision thereof shall be eligible to elect the optional retirement\nprogram.\n  4. The term "optional retirement program" means the retirement program\nestablished pursuant to this article.\n  5. The term "electing employee" shall mean any eligible employee who\nexercises his election pursuant to this article to come under the\noptional retirement program.\n  6. The term "salary" means all amounts paid by or for the city of New\nYork as compensation for services rendered by an eligible employee.\n  7. The term "insurer" shall mean a life insurance corporation, or\nother corporation subject to supervision by the department of financial\nservices of the state of New York.\n  8. The term "city" shall mean the city of New York.\n  9. The term "comptroller" shall mean the comptroller of the city of\nNew York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>