<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6277"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6277"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6277"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6277/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6277/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6277/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6277/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6277">
        <num>6277</num>
        <heading>Authority of city to convey real property and grant consents to dormitory authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6277__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any\ngeneral, special or local law, charter or ordinance to the contrary, on\nrequest of the fund and with the approval of the city board of estimate,\nthe city of New York may sell, convey, lease, exchange or otherwise make\navailable to the dormitory authority, for a nominal consideration, any\ninterest in real property of the city designated by the board of higher\neducation as suitable for a facility.  Such sale, conveyance, lease,\nexchange, or other disposition may be made at nominal cost and without\nthe requirement of public auction or sealed bids, or restriction as to\nthe term of any such lease or arrangement, and the provisions of\nsubdivision b of section three hundred eighty-four of the New York city\ncharter shall not apply in such cases. Conveyances made pursuant to this\nsection shall include but shall not be limited to real property on which\nare situated facilities of, or are under the jurisdiction of, or\nassigned to, the board of higher education.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6277__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local\nlaw, charter or ordinance to the contrary, on request of the fund, the\ncity board of estimate in behalf of the City of New York may grant\nrevocable or irrevocable consents or rights of any kind or nature\nwhatsoever, providing for or involving or relating to the occupation or\nuse of any of the streets of the city, whether on, under or over the\nsurface thereof, to the dormitory authority, on such terms and\nconditions and for such period of time or duration as may be determined\nby the board of estimate to be in the public interest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>