<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6311"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6311">
        <num>6311</num>
        <heading>New York opportunity promise scholarship</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is at least twenty-five years of age or older, but in no case more\nthan fifty-five years of age, as of January first of the calendar year\nfor the semester for which the applicant makes initial application;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has applied for a New York state tuition assistance program award\npursuant to section six hundred sixty-seven of this chapter, a federal\nPell grant pursuant to section 1070 of title 20 of the United States\ncode, et. seq., and any other applicable financial aid;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is matriculated at a community college of the state university of\nNew York or the city university of New York, as defined in subdivision\ntwo of section sixty-three hundred one of this article or subdivision\nfour of section sixty-two hundred two of this title, respectively, in an\napproved program directly leading to an associate's degree in a\nhigh-demand field; provided that for the two thousand twenty-five -- two\nthousand twenty-six academic year, such fields shall include but not be\nlimited to advanced manufacturing, technology, cybersecurity,\nengineering, artificial intelligence, nursing and allied health\nprofessions, green and renewable energy, and pathways to teaching in\nshortage areas, provided further that such fields may be updated\nannually thereafter by the department of labor no later than one hundred\neighty days prior to the first start date of the fall term of such\ncommunity colleges, and provided further that the eligibility of such\napproved program established in the semester for which the applicant\nmakes initial application shall continue;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is eligible for the payment of tuition and fees at a rate no\ngreater than that imposed for resident students in community colleges;\nand\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has not already obtained any postsecondary degree, provided that\nnothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit the eligibility\nof a student who is already enrolled in an eligible associate degree\nprogram on the effective date of this section and who meets all the\nother eligibility requirements of this subdivision.\n  2. Amount. Within amounts appropriated therefor, and subject to\navailability of funds, awards shall be granted for the two thousand\ntwenty-five -- two thousand twenty-six academic year and thereafter to\napplicants who are determined to be eligible to receive such awards.\nSuch awards shall be calculated on a per term basis prior to the start\nof each term the applicant is successfully enrolled and shall not exceed\nthe positive difference, if any, of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the sum of actual tuition, fees,\nbooks, and applicable supplies charged to the applicant and approved by\nthe applicable community college, less</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the sum of all payments\nreceived by the applicant from all sources of financial aid received by\nthe applicant with the exception of aid received pursuant to federal\nwork-study programs authorized under sections 1087-51 through 1087-58 of\ntitle 20 of the United States code and educational loans taken by the\napplicant or guardian.\n  3. Additional provisions. An eligible recipient shall complete at\nleast six credits per semester, for a total of at least twelve credits\nper academic year, in an approved program of study. An eligible\nrecipient shall be continuously enrolled without a gap of more than one\nacademic year, provided that such duration may be extended for an\nallowable interruption of study including, but not limited to, death of\na family member, medical leave, military service, and parental leave.\nNotwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this section, if an\napplicant fails to meet the eligibility criteria of this section at any\npoint, no further awards shall be made to the applicant.\n  4. Conditions.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An eligible recipient shall continue to make\nsatisfactory academic progress in order to maintain continued\neligibility for an award pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each campus that enrolls students pursuant to this section shall\ntake steps consistent with established policy to maximize the award of\ncredit for prior learning for participating students.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No student shall receive an award pursuant to this section for\ngreater than ten semesters.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A student who earns college credit pursuant to this section shall\nbe entitled to transfer such credit to another state university of New\nYork or city university of New York campus consistent with transfer\npolicies established by the state university of New York or city\nuniversity of New York.\n  5. Reporting. By September first, two thousand twenty-six, and by\nSeptember first of each year thereafter, the chancellor of the state\nuniversity of New York and the chancellor of the city university of New\nYork shall each submit a report to the governor, the speaker of the\nassembly, and the temporary president of the senate, including but not\nlimited to the following information:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>enrollment data by full and part-time status;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>retention and completion rates by full and part-time status;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>barriers to student participation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>demographic data related to the program;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>average prior learning and transfer credit awarded;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the total amount of funds awarded and the average award per\nstudent; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6311__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>post-completion outcomes including transfer, employment, and\nwages, as applicable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>