<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6430"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6430"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6430"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6430/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6430/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6430/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6430/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6430">
        <num>6430</num>
        <heading>General provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6430. General provisions. 1. The trustees or other governing board\nof every college chartered by the regents or incorporated by special act\nof the legislature and which maintains a campus, unless otherwise\nprovided, shall adopt written rules for implementing all policies\nrequired pursuant to this article and for the maintenance of public\norder on college campuses and other college property used for\neducational purposes and provide a program for the enforcement thereof.\nSuch rules shall prohibit, among other things, any action or situation\nwhich recklessly or intentionally endangers mental or physical health or\ninvolves the forced consumption of liquor or drugs for the purpose of\ninitiation into or affiliation with any organization. Such rules shall\ngovern the conduct of students, faculty and other staff as well as\nvisitors and other licensees and invitees on such campuses and property.\nThe penalties for violations of such rules shall be clearly set forth\ntherein and shall include provisions for the ejection of a violator from\nsuch campus and property, in the case of a student or faculty violator\nhis or her suspension, expulsion, or other appropriate disciplinary\naction, and in the case of an organization which authorizes such\nconduct, recision of permission for that organization to operate on\ncampus property. Such penalties shall be in addition to any penalty\npursuant to the penal law or any other law to which a violator or\norganization may be subject.\n  2. A copy of such rules shall be given to all students enrolled in\nsaid college and shall be deemed to be part of the by-laws of all\norganizations operating on said campus which shall review annually such\nby-laws with individuals affiliated with such organizations.\n  3. Each college shall annually file with the department on or before\nthe first day of July a certificate of compliance with the provisions of\nthis article.\n  4. If a college fails to file a certificate of compliance pursuant to\nsubdivision three of this section within sixty days of the time\nrequired, such college shall not be eligible to receive any state aid or\nassistance until such certificate of compliance is duly filed.\n  5. Each college shall file a copy of all written rules adopted as\nrequired in this article with the department on or before the first day\nof July, two thousand four, and once every ten years thereafter.\n  6. Nothing contained in this article shall:\n  a. be construed to limit or restrict the freedom of speech and\npeaceful assembly; or\n  b. prevent or limit a college from setting forth additional standards\nof conduct for students.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>