<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6431"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6431"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-10-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6431"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6431/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6431/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6431/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6431/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6431">
        <num>6431</num>
        <heading>Advisory committee on campus security</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6431. Advisory committee on campus security. 1. The president or\nchief administrative officer of each college, except those independent\ncolleges ineligible to receive state aid under section sixty-four\nhundred one of this title, shall appoint an advisory committee on campus\nsecurity.\n  2. Such committee shall consist of a minimum of six members, at least\nhalf of whom shall be female; one-third of the committee shall be\nappointed from a list of students that contains at least twice the\nnumber to be appointed which is provided by the largest student\ngovernance organization on such campus, one-third thereof shall be\nappointed from a list of faculty members that contains twice the number\nto be appointed which is provided by the largest faculty organization on\nsuch campus, and one-third of whom shall be selected by the president or\nchief administrative officer.\n  3. The committee shall review current campus security policies and\nprocedures and make recommendations for their improvement. It shall\nspecifically review current policies and procedures for:\n  a. educating the campus community, including security personnel and\nthose persons who advise or supervise students, about sexual assault,\ndomestic violence and stalking offenses pursuant to section sixty-four\nhundred thirty-two of this article, and bias related and hate crimes\npursuant to section sixty-four hundred thirty-six of this article;\n  b. educating the campus community about personal safety and crime\nprevention;\n  c. reporting sexual assaults, domestic violence, stalking incidents\nand hate crimes and assisting victims during investigations;\n  d. referring complaints to appropriate authorities;\n  e. counseling victims; and\n  f. responding to inquiries from concerned persons.\n  4. The committee shall report, in writing, to the college president or\nchief administrative officer on its findings and recommendations at\nleast once each academic year, and such report shall be available upon\nrequest.\n  5. Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter, amend, modify\nor affect existing standards for civil liability.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>