<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6436-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6436-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6436_A">
        <num>6436-A</num>
        <heading>Designation of a Title VI coordinator and duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6436_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To ensure students are\nprotected from illegal discrimination based on characteristics, as\nfurther described in applicable state and federal law, institutions\nshall engage in proper coordination of these efforts through a\ncentralized process and with a centralized point of contact for all\ncompliance, similar to the role of the Title IX coordinator and their\nrole in the implementation of applicable federal laws, rules and\nregulations, and state law, including article one hundred twenty-nine-B\nof this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6436_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within ninety days of the effective date of this section, an\ninstitution, defined as a college or university chartered by the regents\nor incorporated by special act of the legislature that maintains a\ncampus in New York state shall designate a Title VI coordinator to\nensure compliance with Title VI of the federal civil rights act of 1964,\ncodified at 42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq., 34 C.F.R. Part 100, and any other\nrelated applicable laws, rules or regulations.\n  2. Responsibilities of the Title VI coordinator when receiving reports\nof discrimination or harassment. If the Title VI coordinator receives a\nreport, the Title VI coordinator shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6436_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>offer supportive measures for the student or students making a\ncomplaint;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6436_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>notify any students who report conduct that may reasonably\nconstitute discrimination or harassment under this section and Title VI\nof the federal civil rights act of 1964, of the institution's policies\nand/or procedures; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6436_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ensure there is a process for investigation and resolution of\ncomplaints consistent with obligations under federal and state law.\n  3. Developing training to promote equal access and participation. The\ndivision of human rights, in coordination with institutions of public\nand private higher education located within the state, shall develop\nmodel training for students and employees to ensure institutional\ncompliance. Such training or institutionally developed equivalents shall\nbe delivered annually to all students and employees commencing with the\nfirst full academic year after this section shall take effect, and each\nacademic year thereafter.\n  4. Notification of policies and procedures. The Title VI coordinator\nshall notify all students and employees each academic year of the\ninstitution's policies and procedures for reporting discrimination and\nharassment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6436_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Form of notification. The Title VI coordinator shall ensure that\nthe annual notification includes:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6436_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the institution's nondiscrimination policy statement;\n  (ii) website links to all policies and procedures for reporting\ndiscrimination and harassment to the institution;\n  (iii) the contact information of the Title VI coordinator; and\n  (iv) any other information the Title VI coordinator and the\ninstitution deem necessary.\n  5. Designees. The Title VI coordinator may have a designee or\ndesignees to assist in carrying out the functions set forth in this\nsection, and may work with other employees to carry out the functions\nset forth in this section, provided, however, the Title VI coordinator\nshall be ultimately responsible for coordinating and overseeing the\ninstitution's compliance with this section and with Title VI of the\nfederal civil rights act of 1964.\n  6. Training for Title VI coordinator and designee or designees. All\nTitle VI coordinators and their designees shall be trained in their\nduties and responsibilities set forth in this section and Title VI of\nthe federal civil rights act of 1964.\n  7. Recordkeeping.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6436_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Title VI coordinator shall be responsible\nfor appropriate recordkeeping related to any reports and complaints of\ndiscrimination and harassment, in accordance with applicable state and\nfederal law, including all records related to assessments of reports,\nrecords documenting actions the institution took to meet its\nobligations, and any records of training attendance and materials.\n  8. Other duties. The Title VI coordinator may perform other relevant\nduties as established by the institution.\n  * NB Effective August 26, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>