<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6446"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6446"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6446"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6446/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6446/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6446/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6446/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6446">
        <num>6446</num>
        <heading>Options for confidential disclosure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6446__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, in an\nanonymized manner that identifies neither the specifics of the crime nor\nthe identity of the reporting individual; that the institution is\nobligated to issue timely warnings of crimes enumerated in the Clery Act\noccurring within relevant geography that represent a serious or\ncontinuing threat to students and employees, except in those\ncircumstances where issuing such a warning may compromise current law\nenforcement efforts or when the warning itself could potentially\nidentify the reporting individual; that a reporting individual shall not\nbe identified in a timely warning; that the Family Educational Rights\nand Privacy Act, 20 U.S.C. 1232g, allows institutions to share\ninformation with parents when i. there is a health or safety emergency,\nor ii. when the student is a dependent on either parent's prior year\nfederal income tax return; and that generally, the institution shall not\nshare information about a report of domestic violence, dating violence,\nstalking, or sexual assault with parents without the permission of the\nreporting individual.\n  2. The institution may take proactive steps, such as training or\nawareness efforts, to combat domestic violence, dating violence,\nstalking or sexual assault in a general way that does not identify those\nwho disclose or the information disclosed.\n  3. If the institution determines that an investigation is required, it\nshall notify the reporting individuals and take immediate action as\nnecessary to protect and assist them.\n  4. The institution should seek consent from reporting individuals\nprior to conducting an investigation. Declining to consent to an\ninvestigation shall be honored unless the institution determines in good\nfaith that failure to investigate does not adequately mitigate a\npotential risk of harm to the reporting individual or other members of\nthe community.  Honoring such a request may limit the institution's\nability to meaningfully investigate and pursue conduct action agains...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>