<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6447"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6447"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6447"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6447/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6447/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6447/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6447/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6447">
        <num>6447</num>
        <heading>Student onboarding and ongoing education</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6447__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n  2. Included in this campaign shall be a requirement that all new\nfirst-year and transfer students shall, during the course of their\nonboarding to their respective institution, receive training on the\nfollowing topics, using a method and manner appropriate to the\ninstitutional culture of each institution:\n  a. The institution prohibits sexual and interpersonal violence and\nwill offer resources to any victims and survivors of such violence while\ntaking administrative and conduct action regarding any accused\nindividual within the jurisdiction of the institution;\n  b. Relevant definitions including, but not limited to, the definitions\nof sexual assault, domestic violence, dating violence, stalking,\nconfidentiality, privacy, and consent;\n  c. Policies apply equally to all students regardless of sexual\norientation, gender identity, or gender expression;\n  d. The role of the Title IX Coordinator, university police or campus\nsecurity, and other relevant offices that address domestic violence,\ndating violence, stalking, and sexual assault prevention and response;\n  e. Awareness of violence, its impact on victims and survivors and\ntheir friends and family, and its long-term impact;\n  f. Bystander intervention and the importance of taking action to\nprevent violence when one can safely do so;\n  g. Risk assessment and reduction including, but not limited to, steps\nthat potential victims, perpetrators, and bystanders can take to lower\nthe incidence of violations, which may contain information about the\ndangers of drug and alcohol use, including underage drinking and binge\ndrinking, involuntary consumption of incapacitating drugs and the danger\nof mislabeled drugs and alcohol, the importance of communication with\ntrusted friends and family whether on campus or off campus, and the\navailability of institution officials who can answer general or specific\nquestions about risk reduction; and\n  h. Consequences and sanctions for individuals who commit t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6447__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, to educate the student\npopulation. They shall, as appropriate, provide or expand specific\ntraining to include groups such as international students, students that\nare also employees, leaders and officers of registered or recognized\nstudent organizations, and online and distance education students. They\nshall also provide specific training to members of groups that the\ninstitution identifies as high-risk populations.\n  6. Every institution shall require that each student leader and\nofficer of student organizations recognized by or registered with the\ninstitution, as well as those seeking recognition by the institution,\ncomplete training on domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or\nsexual assault prevention prior to receiving recognition or\nregistration, and each institution shall require that each\nstudent-athlete complete training on domestic violence, dating violence,\nstalking, or sexual assault prevention prior to participating in\nintercollegiate athletic competition.\n  7. Every institution must regularly assess programs and policies\nestablished pursuant to this article to determine effectiveness and\nrelevance for students.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>