<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6451"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6451"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-07-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6451"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6451/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6451/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6451/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6451/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6451">
        <num>6451</num>
        <heading>Arthur O</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6451. Arthur O. Eve opportunity for higher education; non-public\ninstitutions. 1. To advance the cause of educational opportunity in\nhigher education, the commissioner may contract with non-public\ninstitutions of higher education for the support of special programs for\nthe screening, testing, counseling, tutoring of, and, assistance to,\nresidents of the state who are, (1) graduates of an approved high school\nor individuals who have attained a New York state high school\nequivalency diploma or its equivalent, as determined by the\ncommissioner, (2) who have potential for the successful completion of a\npost secondary program, and (3) are economically and educationally\ndisadvantaged, as defined by the regents.\n  2. To qualify for state assistance through such contracts, an\ninstitution of higher education must be a college or university\nincorporated by the regents or by the legislature, or a school of\nmedicine, dentistry or osteopathy authorized by the regents to confer\nthe degree of doctor of medicine, doctor of medical science, doctor of\ndental surgery or doctor of osteopathy and must maintain one or more\nearned degree programs culminating in an associate or higher degree.\n  3. Moneys made available to institutions through contracts shall be\nspent only for the following purposes:\n  a. Special testing, counseling and guidance services in the course of\nscreening potential enrollees;\n  b. Remedial courses, developmental or compensatory courses and summer\nclasses for such students;\n  c. Special tutoring, counseling and guidance services for such\nenrolled students;\n  d. Any necessary supplemental financial assistance, which may include\nthe cost of books and necessary maintenance for such enrolled students,\nincluding students without lawful immigration status provided that the\nstudent meets the requirements set forth in subparagraph (ii) of\nparagraph a or subparagraph (ii) of paragraph b of subdivision five of\nsection six hundred sixty-one of this chapter, as applicable; provided,\nhowever, that such supplemental financial assistance shall be furnished\npursuant to criteria promulgated by the commissioner with the approval\nof the director of the budget;\n  e. Partial reimbursement for tuition for regular academic courses\npursuant to criteria promulgated by the commissioner;\n  f. Student travel for academic activities or conferences;\n  g. Expenses related to helping students apply for and prepare for\ngraduate or professional school; and\n  h. The hiring of enrolled students participating in an Arthur O. Eve\nopportunity for higher education work-study program.\n  4. The commissioner shall promulgate regulations requiring the\nsubmission to him by any institution intending to contract with the\nstate for assistance pursuant to this section of reports in such form\nand containing such information as he shall require, concerning, but not\nlimited to, such matters as a description of the proposed program,\nestimated costs, objectives, the extent of the institution's support of\nsuch program and similar programs and the progress of students in such\nprograms, and the commissioner shall take such factors into account in\ndetermining whether to enter into a contract with such institution and\nthe terms and conditions thereof.\n  5. Contracts made pursuant to this section shall be subject to the\napproval of the director of the budget.\n  6. The commissioner shall prepare an annual report of the activities\nof the institutions which received state funds pursuant to this section\nin the preceding fiscal year, concerning, but not limited to, the\neffectiveness of each of the programs contracted for, the costs of the\nprograms and the future plans thereof and shall transmit such report to\nthe Governor and the legislature on or before the December first next\nfollowing the close of such fiscal year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>