<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6502-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6502-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6502_A">
        <num>6502-A</num>
        <heading>Renewal of professional license, certification, or registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6502-a. Renewal of professional license, certification, or\nregistration. 1. This section shall apply to healthcare professionals\nlicensed, certified, registered or authorized pursuant to this title\nother than those licensed or registered pursuant to article one hundred\nthirty-one of this title.\n  2. In conjunction with and as a condition of each registration\nrenewal, the professionals described in subdivision one of this section\nshall provide to the department, and the department shall collect, such\ninformation and documentation required by the department, in\nconsultation with the department of health, as is necessary to enable\nthe department of health to evaluate access to needed services in this\nstate, including, but not limited to, the location and type of setting\nin which the professional practices and other relevant information. The\ndepartment of health, in consultation with the department, shall make\nsuch data available in aggregate, de-identified form on a publicly\naccessible website.\n  3. The dates by which the professionals described in subdivision one\nof this section must comply with the requirements of subdivision two of\nthis section shall be determined by the department and may vary by\nprofession, to allow the development and refinement of necessary program\nfeatures and to allow sufficient advanced notice to be provided to\naffected professionals. The provisions of this section shall be\neffective only if and for so long as an appropriation is made for the\npurposes of its implementation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>