<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-06-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6505-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6505-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6505_E">
        <num>6505-E</num>
        <heading>Provision of information related to coursework and training in nutrition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6505-e. Provision of information related to coursework and training\nin nutrition. 1. The department, in consultation with the department of\nhealth, shall compile a list of continuing medical education courses and\ntraining opportunities regarding nutrition, which may include but not be\nlimited to plant-based nutrition, clinically proven methods for the\nprevention, reversal, and treatment of diet-related illnesses, and\ninformational resources regarding racial disparities in outcomes for\ndiet-related diseases, that are publicly available, and shall distribute\nsuch compilation to physicians who are licensed to practice medicine in\nthe state.\n  2. The compiled list shall be made publicly available on the\ndepartment's website and on the department of health's website, and\nshall be updated and redistributed no less frequently than every two\nyears via email.\n  3. In compiling such resources, the department shall consult with\norganizations representative of professions, and institutions of higher\neducation, and the department of health shall consult with those with\nexpertise in nutrition and the prevention, reversal, and treatment of\ndiet-related illnesses.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>