<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6508"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6508"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6508"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6508/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6508/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6508">
        <num>6508</num>
        <heading>Assistance by state boards for the professions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6508__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the\nmembership of each professional licensing board shall be increased by\none member, and each such board shall have at least one public\nrepresentative who shall be selected by the board of regents from the\ngeneral public.\n  a. The membership of the professional licensing boards created under\nsections sixty-five hundred twenty-three, sixty-eight hundred four,\nsixty-nine hundred three, and seventy-four hundred three of this chapter\nshall be increased by two members, and each such board shall have at\nleast two public representatives, who shall be selected by the board of\nregents from the general public.\n  b. For the purposes of this title, a "public representative" shall be\na person who is a consumer of services provided by those licensed or\notherwise supervised or regulated by the boards created hereunder, and\nshall not be, nor within five years immediately preceding appointment\nhave been:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6508__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a licensee or person otherwise subject to the supervision or\nregulation of the board to which appointed; or\n  (ii) a person maintaining a contractual relationship with a licensee\nof such board, which would constitute more than two percentum of the\npractice or business of any such licensee, or an officer, director, or\nrepresentative of such person or group of persons.\n  2. Each board, or its committee on licensing, shall select or prepare\nexaminations, may conduct oral and practical examinations and\nreexaminations, shall fix passing grades, and assist the department in\nother licensing matters as prescribed by the board of regents.\n  3. Each board shall conduct disciplinary proceedings as prescribed in\nthis article and shall assist in other professional conduct matters as\nprescribed by the board of regents.\n  4. Members of each board shall be appointed by the board of regents\nfor five-year terms except that the terms of those first appointed shall\nbe arranged so that as nearly as possible an equal number shall\nterminate annually. A vacancy occurring during a term shall be filled by\nan appointment by the board of regents for the unexpired term. Each\nstate professional association or society may nominate one or more\ncandidates for each appointment to be made to the board for its\nprofession, but the board of regents shall not be required to appoint\ncandidates so nominated. Former members of a board may be re-appointed\nby the board of regents, on the recommendation of the commissioner, to\nserve as members of the board solely for the purposes of disciplinary\nproceedings, proceedings relating to the moral character of an applicant\nfor licensure, and proceedings relating to applications for the\nrestoration of a professional license. In addition, each board shall\nestablish a roster of auxiliary members from candidates nominated by\nprofessional associations or societies for appointment by the board of\nregents, on the recommendation of the commissio...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>