<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-02-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6509-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6509_E">
        <num>6509-E</num>
        <heading>Additional definition of professional misconduct; mental health professionals</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6509_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>means any practice by a\nmental health professional that seeks to change an individual's sexual\norientation, including, but not limited to, efforts to change behaviors,\ngender identity, or gender expressions, or to eliminate or reduce sexual\nor romantic attractions or feelings towards individuals of the same sex\nand (ii) shall not include counseling for a person seeking to transition\nfrom one gender to another, or psychotherapies that: (A) provide\nacceptance, support and understanding of patients or the facilitation of\npatients' coping, social support and identity exploration and\ndevelopment, including sexual orientation-neutral interventions to\nprevent or address unlawful conduct or unsafe sexual practices; and (B)\ndo not seek to change sexual orientation.\n  2. It shall be professional misconduct for a mental health\nprofessional to engage in sexual orientation change efforts upon any\npatient under the age of eighteen years, and any mental health\nprofessional found guilty of such misconduct under the procedures\nprescribed in section sixty-five hundred ten of this subarticle shall be\nsubject to the penalties prescribed in section sixty-five hundred eleven\nof this subarticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>