<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6509-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6509-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6509_C">
        <num>6509-C</num>
        <heading>Additional definition of professional misconduct; failure to comply in paternity or child support proceedings; limited application</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6509-c.  Additional definition of professional misconduct; failure\nto comply in paternity or child support proceedings; limited\napplication.  1.  The provisions of this section shall apply in all\ncases of licensee or registrant failure after receiving appropriate\nnotice, to comply with a summons, subpoena or warrant relating to a\npaternity or child support proceeding referred to the board of regents\nby a court pursuant to the requirements of section two hundred\nforty-four-c of the domestic relations law or pursuant to section four\nhundred fifty-eight-b or five hundred forty-eight-b of the family court\nact.\n  2.  Upon receipt of an order from the court pursuant to one of the\nforegoing provisions of law, the board of regents, if it finds such\nperson to be so licensed or registered, shall within thirty days of\nreceipt of such order from the court, provide notice to the licensee or\nregistrant that his or her license or registration shall be suspended in\nsixty days unless the conditions as set forth in subdivision three of\nthis section are met.\n  3.  Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this article or of\nany other provision of law to the contrary, the license or registration\nof a person subject to the provisions of this title and/or subject to\nthe provisions of title two-A of article two of the public health law\nshall be suspended unless the court terminates its order to commence\nsuspension proceedings.  Such suspension shall not be lifted unless the\ncourt issues an order to the board of regents terminating its order to\ncommence suspension proceedings.\n  4.  The board of regents shall inform the court of all actions taken\nhereunder as required by law.\n  5.  This section applies to paternity or child support proceedings\ncommenced under, and support obligations paid pursuant to any order of\nchild support or child and spousal support issued under provisions of\nsection two hundred thirty-six or two hundred forty of the domestic\nrelations law, or article four, five, five-A or five-B of the family\ncourt act.\n  6.  Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this article or of\nany other provision of law to the contrary, the provisions of this\nsection shall apply to the exclusion of any other requirements of this\narticle and to the exclusion of any other requirement of law to the\ncontrary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>