<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6510"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6510/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6510">
        <num>6510</num>
        <heading>Proceedings in cases of professional misconduct</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6510__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by mailing by\ncertified mail, return receipt requested, to the person to be served at\nhis or her last known residence, or (ii) by mailing by certified mail,\nreturn receipt requested, to the person to be served at his or her last\naddress on file with the division of licensing services of the\ndepartment in an envelope bearing the legend "personal and\nconfidential," provided that, in either case: such delivery and mailing\nshall be effected within twenty days of each other; service pursuant to\nthis subparagraph shall be complete ten days after either the delivery,\nor the mailing, whichever is later; and proof of service shall, among\nother things, identify such person of suitable age and discretion and\nstate the date, time and place of such service; or\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>where service under subparagraphs one and two of this paragraph\ncannot be made with due diligence, a copy of the charges and the notice\nof hearing shall be served by certified mail, return receipt requested,\nto the person's last known address on file with the division of\nlicensing services of the department or by affixing the changes and the\nnotice of hearing to the door of either the actual place of business,\ndwelling place or usual place of abode of the person to be served;\nprovided that: service pursuant to this subparagraph shall be complete\nten days after such mailing, and proof of service shall set forth the\ndepartment's efforts of due diligence.\n  g. Service of charges and notice of hearing outside of the state. A\nnatural person subject to the jurisdiction of the department may be\nserved with a copy of the charges and the notice of hearing outside of\nthe state in the same manner as service is made within the state, by any\nperson authorized to make service within th...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the time and place of the hearing,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the\nlicensee may file a written answer to the charges prior to the hearing,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the licensee may appear personally at the hearing and may be\nrepresented by counsel,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the licensee shall have the right to\nproduce witnesses and evidence in his behalf, to cross-examine witnesses\nand examine evidence produced against him, and to issue subpoenas in\naccordance with the provisions of the civil practice law and rules,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nthat a stenographic record of the hearing will be made, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such\nother information as may be considered appropriate by the department.\n  b. Hearing panel. The hearing shall be conducted by a panel of three\nor more members, at least two of whom shall be members of the applicable\nstate board for the profession, and at least one of whom shall be a\npublic representative who is a member of the applicable state board or\nof the state board for another profession licensed pursuant to this\ntitle. The executive secretary for the applicable state board shall\nappoint the panel and shall designate its chairperson. After the\ncommencement of a hearing, no panel member shall be replaced. A\ndetermination by the administrative officer of a need to disqualify or\nremove any panel member will result in the disqualification or removal\nof the panel and cause a new panel to be appointed. In addition to said\npanel members, the department shall designate an administrative officer,\nadmitted to practice as an attorney in the state of New York, who shall\nhav...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>findings of fact,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a determination of guilty\nor not guilty on each charge, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in the event of a determination of\nguilty, a recommendation of the penalty to be imposed. For the panel to\nmake a determination of guilty, a minimum of two of the voting members\nof the panel must vote for such a determination. A copy of the report of\nthe hearing panel shall be transmitted to the licensee.\n  4. Regents decision procedures.\n  a. Regents review committee. The transcript and report of the hearing\npanel shall be reviewed at a meeting by a regents review committee\nappointed by the board of regents. The regents review committee shall\nconsist of three members, at least one of whom shall be a regent.\n  b. Regents review committee meetings. The review shall be based on the\ntranscript and the report of the hearing panel. The licensee may appear\nat the meeting, and the regents review committee may require the\nlicensee to appear. The licensee may be represented by counsel. The\ndepartment shall notify the licensee at least seven days before the\nmeeting</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the time and place of the meeting,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of his right to\nappear,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of his right to be represented by counsel,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>whether or\nnot he is required to appear, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of such other information as may\nbe considered appropriate. After the meeting, the regents review\ncommittee shall transmit a written report of its review to the board of\nregents. In cases referred directly to the regents review committee\npursuant to paragraph d of subdivision two of this section, the review\nshall be based upon the charges, the documentary evidence submitted by\nthe department, any answer, affidavits or brief the licensee may wish to\nsubmit, and any evidence or sworn testimony presented by the licensee or\nthe department at the hearing, pursuant to the procedures described by\nparagraph d of subdivision two of this section.\n  c. Regents decision and order. The board of regents</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>shall consider\nthe transcript, the report of the hearing panel, and the report of the\nregents review committee,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>shall decide whether the licensee is\nguilty or not guilty on each charge,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>shall decide what penalties, if\nany, to impose as prescribed in section sixty-five hundred eleven of\nthis article, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6510__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>shall issue an order to carry out its decisions.\nSuch decisions shall require the affirmative vote of a majority of the\nmembers of the board of regents. If the board of regents disagrees with\nthe hearing panel's determination of not guilty, it shall remand the\nmatter to the original panel for reconsideration or to a new panel for a\nnew hearing. The panel's determination of not guilty on reconsideration\nor a new hearing shall be final. The order shall be served upon the\nlicensee personally or by certified mail to the licensee's last known\naddress and such service shall be effective as of the date of the\npersonal service or five days after mailing by certified mail. The\nlicensee shall deliver to the department the license and registration\ncertificate which has been revoked, annulled, suspended, or surrendered\nwithin five days after the effective date of the service of the order.\nIf the license or registration certificate is lost, misplaced or its\nwhereabouts is otherwise un...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6510__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of section 130.05 of the penal law has been committed\nby the licensee against a client or patient during a treatment session,\nconsultation, interview, or examination, the professional conduct\nofficer or the office of professional discipline shall notify the\nappropriate law enforcement official or authority.\n  6. The provisions of subdivisions one through four of this section\nshall not be applicable to proceedings in cases of professional\nmisconduct involving the medical profession, except as provided in\nparagraph m of subdivision ten of section two hundred thirty of the\npublic health law.\n  7. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, persons who assist the\ndepartment as consultants or expert witnesses in the investigation or\nprosecution of alleged professional misconduct, licensure matters,\nrestoration proceedings, or criminal prosecutions for unauthorized\npractice, shall not be liable for damages in any civil action or\nproceeding as a result of such assistance, except upon proof of actual\nmalice. The attorney general shall defend such persons in any such\naction or proceeding, in accordance with section seventeen of the public\nofficers law.\n  8. The files of the department relating to the investigation of\npossible instances of professional misconduct, or the unlawful practice\nof any profession licensed by the board of regents, or the unlawful use\nof a professional title or the moral fitness of an applicant for a\nprofessional license or permit, shall be confidential and not subject to\ndisclosure at the request of any person, except upon the order of a\ncourt in a pending action or proceeding. The provisions of this\nsubdivision shall not apply to documents introduced in evidence at a\nhearing held pursuant to this chapter and shall not prevent the\ndepartment from sharing information concerning investigations with other\nduly authorized public agencies responsible for professional regulation\nor criminal prosecution.\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>