<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6512"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6512"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6512"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6512/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6512/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6512/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6512/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6512">
        <num>6512</num>
        <heading>Unauthorized practice a crime</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6512. Unauthorized practice a crime. 1. Anyone not authorized to\npractice under this title who practices or offers to practice or holds\nhimself out as being able to practice in any profession in which a\nlicense is a prerequisite to the practice of the acts, or who practices\nany profession as an exempt person during the time when his professional\nlicense is suspended, revoked or annulled, or who aids or abets an\nunlicensed person to practice a profession, or who fraudulently sells,\nfiles, furnishes, obtains, or who attempts fraudulently to sell, file,\nfurnish or obtain any diploma, license, record or permit purporting to\nauthorize the practice of a profession, shall be guilty of a class E\nfelony.\n  2. Anyone who knowingly aids or abets three or more unlicensed persons\nto practice a profession or employs or holds such unlicensed persons out\nas being able to practice in any profession in which a license is a\nprerequisite to the practice of the acts, or who knowingly aids or abets\nthree or more persons to practice any profession as exempt persons\nduring the time when the professional licenses of such persons are\nsuspended, revoked or annulled, shall be guilty of a class E felony.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>