<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6527"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6527"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6527"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6527/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6527/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6527/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6527/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6527">
        <num>6527</num>
        <heading>Special provisions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a committee established\nto administer a utilization review plan of a hospital, including a\nhospital as defined in article twenty-eight of the public health law or\na hospital as defined in subdivision ten of section 1.03 of the mental\nhygiene law, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a committee having the responsibility of the\ninvestigation of an incident reported pursuant to section 29.29 of the\nmental hygiene law or the evaluation and improvement of the quality of\ncare rendered in a hospital as defined in article twenty-eight of the\npublic health law or a hospital as defined in subdivision ten of section\n1.03 of the mental hygiene law, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any medical review committee or\nsubcommittee thereof of a local, county or state medical, dental,\npodiatry or optometrical society, any such society itself, a\nprofessional standards review organization or an individual when such\ncommittee, subcommittee, society, organization or individual is\nperforming any medical or quality assurance review function including\nthe investigation of an incident reported pursuant to section 29.29 of\nthe mental hygiene law, either described in clauses</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, required by law, or involving any controversy or dispute\nbetween</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a physician, dentist, podiatrist or optometrist or hospital\nadministrator and a patient concerning the diagnosis, treatment or care\nof such patient or the fees or charges therefor or (ii) a physician,\ndentist, podiatrist or optometrist or hospital administrator and a\nprovider of medical, dental, podiatric or optometrical services\nconcerning any medical or health charges or fees of such physician,\ndentist, podiatrist or optometrist, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a committee appointed\npursuant to section twenty-eight hundred five-j of the public health law\nto participate in the medical and dental malpractice prevention program,\nor</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any individual who participated in the preparation of incident\nreports required by the department of health pursuant to section\ntwenty-eight hundred five-l of the public health law, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a committee\nestablished to administer a utilization review plan, or a committee\nhaving the responsibility of evaluation and improvement of the quality\nof care rendered, in a health maintenance organization organized under\narticle forty-four of the public health law or article forty-three of\nthe insurance law, including a committee of an individual practice\nassociation or medical group acting pursuant to a contract with such a\nhealth maintenance organization, shall be liable in damages to any\nperson for any action taken or recommendations made, by him within the\nscope of his function in such capacity provided that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such individual\nhas taken action or made recommendations within the scope of his\nfunction and without malice, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the reasonable belief after\nreasonable investigation that the act or recommendation was warranted,\nbased upon the facts disclosed.\n  Neither the proceedings nor the records relating to performance of a\nmedical or a quality assurance review function or participation in a\nmedical and dental malpractice prevention program nor any report\nrequired by the department of health pursuant to section twenty-eight\nhundred five-l of the public health law described herein, including the\ninvestigation of an incident reported pursuant to section 29.29 of the\nmental hygiene law, shall be subject to disclosure under article\nthirty-one of the civil practice law and rules except as hereinafter\nprovided or as provided by any other provision of law. No person in\nattendance at a meeting when a medical or a quality assurance review or\na medical and dental malpractice prevention program or an incident\nreporting function described herein was performed, including the\ninvestigation of an incident reported pursuant to section 29.29 of the\nmental hygiene law, shall be required to testify as to what transpired\nthereat. The prohibition relating to discovery of testimony shall not\napply to the statements made by any person in attendance at such a\nmeeting who is a party to an action or proceeding the subject matter of\nwhich was reviewed at such meeting.\n  4. This article shall not be construed to affect or prevent the\nfollowing:\n  a. The furnishing of medical assistance in an emergency;\n  b. The practice of the religious tenets of any church;\n  c. A physician from refusing to perform an act constituting the\npractice of medicine to which he is conscientiously opposed by reason of\nreligious training and belief.\n  d. The organization of a medical corporation under article forty-four\nof the public health law, the organization of a university faculty\npractice corporation under section fourteen hundred twelve of the\nnot-for-profit corporation law or the organization of a ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering immunizations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the emergency treatment of anaphylaxis.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering purified protein derivative (PPD) tests or other\ntests to detect or screen for tuberculosis infections.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering tests to determine the presence of the human\nimmunodeficiency virus.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering tests to determine the presence of the hepatitis C\nvirus.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the urgent or emergency treatment of opioid related overdose or\nsuspected opioid related overdose.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>screening of persons at increased risk of syphilis, gonorrhea and\nchlamydia.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering tests to determine the presence of COVID-19 or its\nantibodies or influenza virus.\n  * NB Repealed July 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering electrocardiogram tests to detect signs and symptoms\nof acute coronary syndrome.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering point-of-care blood glucose tests to evaluate acute\nmental status changes in persons with suspected hypoglycemia.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering tests and intravenous lines to persons that meet\nsevere sepsis and septic shock criteria.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering tests to determine pregnancy.\n  7. A licensed physician may prescribe and order a patient specific\norder or non-patient specific regimen to a licensed pharmacist, pursuant\nto regulations promulgated by the commissioner, and consistent with the\npublic health law, for:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering immunizations to prevent\ninfluenza to patients two years of age or older; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering\nimmunizations to prevent pneumococcal, acute herpes zoster, hepatitis A,\nhepatitis B, human papillomavirus, measles, mumps, rubella, varicella,\nCOVID-19, meningococcal, tetanus, diphtheria or pertussis disease and\nmedications required for emergency treatment of anaphylaxis to patients\neighteen years of age or older; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>administering other\nimmunizations recommended by the advisory committee on immunization\npractices of the centers for disease control and prevention for patients\neighteen years of age or older if the commissioner of health in\nconsultation with the commissioner determines that an immunization:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\n(A) may be safely administered by a licensed pharmacist within their\nlawful scope of practice; and (B) is needed to prevent the transmission\nof a reportable communicable disease that is prevalent in New York\nstate; or (ii) is a recommended immunization for such patients who: (A)\nmeet age requirements, (B) lack documentation of such immunization, (C)\nlack evidence of past infection, or (D) have an additional risk factor\nor another indication as recommended by the advisory committee on\nimmunization practices of the centers for disease control and\nprevention. Nothing in this subdivision shall authorize unlicensed\npersons to administer immunizations, vaccines or other drugs.\n  7-a. A licensed physician may prescribe and order a patient specific\norder or non-patient specific order to a licensed pharmacist, pursuant\nto regulations promulgated by the commissioner in consultation with the\ncommissioner of health, and consistent with the public health law, for\ndispensing up to a seven day starter pack of HIV post-exposure\nprophylaxis for the purpose of preventing human immunodeficiency virus\ninfection following a potential human immunodeficiency virus exposure.\n  8. Nothing in this article shall prohibit the provision of\npsychotherapy as defined in subdivision two of section eighty-four\nhundred one of this title to the extent permissible within the scope of\npractice of medicine, by any not-for-profit corporation or education\ncorporation providing services within the state of New York and\noperating under a waiver pursuant to section sixty-five hundred three-a\nof this title, provided that such entities offering such psychotherapy\nservices shall only provide such services through an individual\nappropriately licensed or otherwise authorized to provide such services\nor a professional entity authorized by law to provide such services.\n  9.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this article shall be construed to affect or prevent\na person in training or trained and deemed qualified by a supervising\nlicensed physician, to assist the licensed physician in the care of a\npatient for the purpose of instilling mydriatic or cycloplegic eye drops\nand anesthetic eye drops in conjunction with such dilating drops to the\nsurface of the eye of a patient, provided that the person instilling\nsuch eye drops is:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>under the on-site supervision of a supervising licensed physician;\n  (ii) at least eighteen years of age; and\n  (iii) complies with standards issued by the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The supervising licensed physician shall submit a form prescribed\nby the department detailing the identity of each person instilling\nmydriatic or cycloplegic eye drops and anesthetic eye drops in\nconjunction with such dilating drops to the surface of the eye of a\npatient, under his or her supervision, attesting to compliance with the\nabove requirements.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6527__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The supervising licensed physician's use of any such person\npursuant to the terms of this subdivision shall be undertaken with\nprofessional judgment in order to ensure the safety and well-being of\nthe patient.  Such use shall subject the licensed physician to the full\ndisciplinary and regulatory authority of the office of professional\nmedical conduct and the board of regents. The licensed physician must\nnotify the patient or the patient's designated health care surrogate\nthat the licensed physician may utilize the services of an individual to\nadminister certain eye drops and must provide the patient or the\npatient's designated health care surrogate the opportunity to refuse the\nlicensed physician's plan to utilize such person.\n  10. A licensed physician may prescribe and order a\nnon-patient-specific regimen to a licensed pharmacist, for insulin and\nrelated supplies pursuant to section sixty-eight hundred one of this\ntitle.\n  11. A licensed physician may prescribe and order a non-patient\nspecific order to a pharmacist licensed and located in the state,\npursuant to regulations promulgated by the commissioner, and consistent\nwith section sixty-eight hundred one of this title, for dispensing\nself-administered hormonal contraceptives as defined in section\nsixty-eight hundred two of this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>