<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6548"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6548"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6548"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6548/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6548/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6548/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6548/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6548">
        <num>6548</num>
        <heading>Registration</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6548__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at the time of application is at least twenty-one years of age;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6548__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is of good moral character;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6548__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has successfully completed a four-year course of study in a\nsecondary school approved by the board of regents or has passed an\nequivalency test; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6548__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has satisfactorily completed an approved program for the training\nof specialist assistants.\n  2. The department shall furnish to each person applying for\nregistration hereunder an application form calling for such information\nas the department deems necessary and shall issue to each applicant who\nsatisfies the requirements of subdivision one of this section a\ncertificate of registration as specialist assistant in a particular\nmedical specialty for the period expiring December thirty-first of the\nfirst odd-numbered year terminating subsequent to such registration.\n  3. Every registrant shall apply to the department for a certificate of\nregistration. The department shall mail to every registered specialist\nassistant an application form for registration, addressed to the\nregistrant's post office address on file with the department. Upon\nreceipt of such application properly executed, together with evidence of\nsatisfactory completion of such continuing education requirements as may\nbe established by the commissioner of health pursuant to section\nthirty-seven hundred eleven of the public health law, the department\nshall issue a certificate of registration. Registration periods shall be\ntriennial and the registration fee shall be forty-five dollars.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>