<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-655"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-655"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="655"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-655/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-655/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-655/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-655/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_655">
        <num>655</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the president</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_655__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>those required by the federal student aid programs;\n  (ii) periodic reports on the status of student borrowers at the\nparticular college;\n  (iii) interviews or other appropriate communications with student\nborrowers at the time an application for a loan is certified or as soon\nthereafter as feasible emphasizing the importance of the loan\nobligation;\n  (iv) interviews or other appropriate communications with student\nborrowers who are graduating or are known to be terminating their\nenrollment emphasizing the importance of the loan obligation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_655__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>providing the corporation, upon request, with the last known\naddresses of borrowers who have graduated or otherwise left the college\nand who are in default, including any change of address known to the\ncollege after such request;\n  (vi) certification of student loans as frequently as is advisable and\nfeasible, and as lenders will process them (on an annual, semester,\nquarterly or other academic period basis), with such certification\nlimited to those educational expenses approved under the federal student\naid programs;\n  (vii) cooperation in whatever way is feasible and appropriate under\ninstitutional regulations in advising defaulting borrowers of their loan\nobligations.\n  5.  To establish, revise from time to time, charge and collect fees as\nthe corporation shall determine, consistent with the applicable\nprovisions of the New York state and federal student aid programs.\n  6.  To prepare and make available explanatory pamphlets concerning\nstate aid and loan programs.\n  7.  To establish a comprehensive collection of information and\nmaterials relative to public and private sources of higher education\nfinancial assistance available to students and to the characteristics of\nthe students who are the recipients of such assistance.\n  8.  To conduct financial aid program reviews of a post-secondary\ninstitution's procedures and records with respect to:  certification to\nthe corporation of eligible students for purposes of tuition assistance\nprogram and New York state sponsored student aid programs; compliance of\nfinancial aid programs with the provisions of this article and the\nrelevant portion of the regulations of the commissioner; disbursement of\ntuition assistance program and other awards;  and the capacity of\ninstitutions to administer New York state and federal financial aid\nprograms.\n  9. To request and receive from any department, division, board,\nbureau, commission or agency of the state or any subdivision thereof\nsuch assistance and ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>