<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6604-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6604-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6604_A">
        <num>6604-A</num>
        <heading>Mandatory continuing education for dentists</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6604_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each\ndentist, licensed pursuant to this article, required to register\ntriennially with the department to practice in this state shall comply\nwith the provisions of the mandatory continuing education requirements,\nexcept as set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6604_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6604_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\nDentists who do not satisfy the mandatory continuing education\nrequirements shall not practice until they have met such requirements\nand have been issued a registration or conditional registration\ncertificate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6604_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Dentists shall be exempt from the mandatory continuing education\nrequirement for the triennial registration period during which they are\nfirst licensed. In accordance with the intent of this section,\nadjustments to the mandatory continuing education requirement may be\ngranted by the department for reasons of health, certified by a\nphysician, for extended active duty with the armed forces of the United\nStates, or for other good cause acceptable to the department which may\nprevent compliance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6604_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A licensed dentist not engaged in public practice as an individual\npractitioner, a partner of a partnership, a shareholder of a\nprofessional service corporation, or an employee of such practice units,\nshall be exempt from the mandatory continuing education requirement upon\nthe filing of a statement with the department declaring such status. Any\nlicensee who returns to the public practice of dentistry during the\ntriennial registration period shall notify the department prior to\nreentering the profession and shall meet such mandatory continuing\neducation requirements as shall be prescribed by regulation of the\ncommissioner.\n  2. During each triennial registration period an applicant for\nregistration shall complete a minimum of sixty hours of acceptable\nformal continuing education, a maximum of eighteen hours of which may be\nself-instructional coursework as approved by the department. Beginning\nwith the first registration renewal period for any dentist occurring on\nor after January first, two thousand two, and before the occurrence of\nthe second registration renewal period following that date, a dentist\nshall have completed on a one-time basis, as part of the sixty hours of\nacceptable formal continuing education required by this section, no\nfewer than two hours of coursework and training regarding the chemical\nand related effects and usage of tobacco and tobacco products and the\nrecognition, diagnosis, and treatment of the oral health effects,\nincluding but not limited to cancers and other diseases, caused by\ntobacco and tobacco products, provided that any dentist who provides\nwritten proof satisfactory to the department that the dentist has\ncompleted, at any time subsequent to the effective date of this section,\nan approved mandatory continuing education course of not less than two\nhours in the same or substantially similar subject matter shall be\ndeemed to have met this requirement, and further provided that dentists\nwho are exempt from t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>