<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6605-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6605-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6605_A">
        <num>6605-A</num>
        <heading>Dental anesthesia certificate</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6605-a. Dental anesthesia certificate. 1. A licensed dentist shall\nnot employ conscious sedation, deep sedation or general anesthesia in\nthe practice of dentistry, at any location other than a general\nhospital, without a dental anesthesia certificate issued by the\ndepartment.\n  2. The commissioner shall promulgate regulations, establishing\nstandards and procedures for the issuance of certificates. Such\nstandards shall require completion of an educational program and/or\ncourse of training or experience sufficient to ensure that a dentist is\nspecifically trained in the use and administration of conscious\nsedation, deep sedation or general anesthesia and in the possible\neffects of such use, and in the recognition of and response to possible\nemergency situations.  Such regulations may also establish standards and\nsafeguards for the use of conscious sedation, deep sedation or general\nanesthesia.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall limit a dentist's use of local\nanesthesia, a dentist's use of nitrous oxide, or a dentist's use of any\nother substance or agent for a purpose other than achieving deep\nsedation, conscious sedation, or general anesthesia.\n  4. The fee for a dental anesthesia certificate shall be one hundred\ndollars and shall be paid on a triennial basis upon renewal of such\ncertificate. A certificate may be suspended or revoked in the same\nmanner as a license to practice dentistry.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>