<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6610"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6610"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6610"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6610">
        <num>6610</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6610.  Exempt persons.  Nothing in this article shall be construed\nto affect or prevent:\n  1. An unlicensed person from performing solely mechanical work upon\ninert matter in a dental office or on a dental laboratory prescription\nof a dentist holding a license or limited permit;\n  2. A student from engaging in clinical practice as part of a\nregistered program operated by a school of dentistry under supervision\nof a dentist holding a license or limited permit for instructing in\ndentistry in a school of dentistry:\n  3. A student from engaging in any procedure authorized under section\nsixty-six hundred six of this article in clinical practice as part of a\nregistered program in dental hygiene under supervision of a dentist\nholding a license or a limited permit for instructing in dentistry in a\nschool of dental hygiene;\n  4. An employee of a federal agency from using the title of and\npracticing as a dentist or dental hygienist insofar as such activities\nare required by his salaried position;\n  5. A dentist or a dental hygienist licensed in some other state or\ncountry from making a teaching clinical demonstration before a regularly\norganized dental or medical society or group, or from meeting licensed\ndentists in this state for consultation, provided such activities are\nlimited to such demonstration or consultation.\n  6. A dentist licensed in another state or country who is employed on a\nfull-time basis by a registered dental school as a faculty member with\nthe rank of assistant professor or higher from conducting research and\nclinical demonstrations as a part of such employment, under the\nsupervision of a licensed dentist and on the premises of the school. No\nfee may be charged for the practice of dentistry authorized by this\nsubdivision.\n  7. A dentist licensed in another state or country who is visiting an\napproved dental school or any other entity operating a residency program\nthat has been accredited by a national accrediting body approved by the\ndepartment to receive dental instruction for a period not to exceed\nninety days from engaging in clinical practice, provided such practice\nis limited to such instruction and is under the direct supervision of a\nlicensed dentist.\n  8. Any student matriculated in an accredited dental school located\noutside New York state from engaging in appropriately supervised\nclinical practice as part of the school's dental program in a teaching\nhospital which has a teaching affiliation agreement with the student's\ndental school.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>