<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6612"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6612"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6612"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6612/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6612/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6612/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6612/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6612">
        <num>6612</num>
        <heading>Identification of removable full or partial prosthetic devices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6612. Identification of removable full or partial prosthetic\ndevices.  1. Except as provided herein, every dentist licensed in this\nstate making or directing to be made a removable prosthetic denture,\nbridge, appliance or other structure to be used and worn as a substitute\nfor natural teeth, shall offer to the patient for whom the prosthesis is\nintended the opportunity to have such prosthesis marked with the\npatient's name or initials. Such markings shall be accomplished at the\ntime the prosthesis is made and the location and methods used to apply\nor implant them shall be determined by the dentist or the person acting\non behalf of the dentist. Such marking shall be permanent, legible and\ncosmetically acceptable.\n  2. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if in the judgment of the dentist or\nthe person making the prosthesis, such identification is not practicable\nor clinically safe, the identification marks may be omitted entirely.\n  3. The commissioner shall adopt rules and regulations and provide\nstandards necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>