<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-662"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-662"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="662"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-662/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-662/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-662/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-662/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_662">
        <num>662</num>
        <heading>Revocations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 662. Revocations.  1. If at any time the president determines that\nthe recipient of an academic performance award has failed to comply with\nthe regulations of the commissioner in respect to the use of such award,\nor to observe the rules, regulations or conditions prescribed or imposed\nby the institution attended, or that an award was made through error, or\ncontrary to law, he may suspend or revoke such award. In the event of a\nviolation of law he shall take such action as shall be required by such\nlaw.\n  2. Disposition of relinquished or revoked awards. An academic\nperformance award relinquished by the holder or revoked by the president\nshall be issued to the next alternate in the year in which such academic\nperformance award was issued. However, an academic performance award\nrelinquished by the holder or revoked after the holder was matriculated\nshall not be reawarded, nor shall any academic performance award be\nawarded or reawarded after the first semester, quarter or term of\nattendance following the effective date of the academic performance\naward series.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>