<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-663"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-663"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="663"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-663/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-663/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-663/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-663/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_663">
        <num>663</num>
        <heading>Income, a determinant of amount of awards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_663__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nsix hundred twelve of the tax law, as reported in New York state income\ntax returns for the calendar year coinciding with the tax year\nestablished by the U.S. department of education to qualify applicants\nfor federal student financial aid programs authorized by title IV of the\nHigher Education Act of 1965, as amended, for the school year in which\napplication for assistance is made, except that any amount received by\nan applicant as a scholarship at an educational institution or as a\nfellowship grant, including the value of contributed services and\naccommodations, shall not be included within the definition of "income"\nfor the purposes of this article. The term "parent" shall include birth\nparents, stepparents, adoptive parents and the spouse of an adoptive\nparent. Income, if not a whole dollar amount, shall be assumed to be\nequal to the next lowest whole dollar amount. Any change in the status\nof an applicant with regard to the persons responsible for the\napplicant's support occurring after the beginning of any semester shall\nnot be considered to change the applicant's award for that semester.\n  2. Separation of parents. If the parents of an applicant are living\napart, the income of the applicant shall be based upon the income of\nthat parent with whom the applicant is living; or who exercises custody\nif the applicant is a minor, or would exercise custody if the applicant\nwere a minor, and any appropriate payments for the support of the\napplicant from the other parent.\n  3. Exclusion of parental income in the determination of the amount of\nan award. a. In determining the amount of an award for students, the\nincome of the parents shall be excluded if the student has been\nemancipated from his parents.\n  b. A student shall be considered emancipated if:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_663__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant is a student who was married on or before December\nthirty-first of the calendar year prior to the beginning of the academic\nyear for which application is made or is an undergraduate student who\nhas reached the age of twenty-two on or before June thirtieth prior to\nthe academic year for which application is made and who, during the\ncalendar year next preceding the semester, quarter or term of attendance\nfor which application is made and at all times subsequent thereto up to\nand including the entire period for which application is made:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_663__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has not resided and will not reside with his or her parents for\nmore than six weeks; and\n  (ii) has not and will not receive financial assistance or support\nvalued in excess of seven hundred fifty dollars from his or her parents;\nand\n  (iii) has not and will not be claimed as a dependent by either parent\nfor purposes of either federal or state income tax; or\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_663__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant has reached the age of thirty-five on or before June\nthirtieth prior to the academic year for which application is made; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_663__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The applicant was enlisted in full time active military service in\nthe armed forces of the United States and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_663__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has been honorably\ndischarged from such service, or (ii) has a qualifying condition, as\ndefined in section one of the veterans' services law, and has received a\ndischarge other than bad conduct or dishonorable from such service, or\n(iii) is a discharged LGBT veteran, as defined in section one of the\nveterans' services law, and has received a discharge other than bad\nconduct or dishonorable from such service, and, provided, however, that\nthe applicant has not and will not be claimed as a dependent by either\nparent for purposes of either federal or state income tax.\n  c. In making a determination of where a student resides for the\npurposes of item</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_663__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subparagraph one hereof, the president may\nconsider such criteria as he deems appropriate. Residence by the student\nin an apartment, building, or other premises owned by a parent shall be\nconsidered residence with that parent, for the purposes of this section,\neven if the student makes payment therefor in the form of rent or other\nconsiderations.\n  d. Any undergraduate student who was allowed to exclude parental\nincome pursuant to the provisions of subdivision three of section six\nhundred three of this chapter as they existed prior to July first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-four may continue to exclude such income for so\nlong as he continues to comply with such provisions.\n  e. In making a determination of whether a student has been claimed by\na parent as a dependent for purpose of either federal or state income\ntax, the president may require the student to submit a copy of that\nportion of the parents' federal income tax return which includes the\nparents' signature and the list of claimed dependents.\n  4. Relinquishing of parental control. In determining the amount of an\naward, the president may, in cases of unusual and exceptional family\ncircumstances warranting such action, recognize an existing condition\nwherein parental control has in effect been relinquished by the parents\nor others responsible for the applicant, and notwithstanding the\nprovisions of subdivision three of this section, the applicant has in\neffect been emancipated. Provided, however, that students who have\nqualified as an orphan, foster child, or ward of the court for the\npurposes of federal student financial aid programs authorized by Title\nIV of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended, shall not be\nconsidered emancipated for the purposes of determining an award pursuant\nto section six hundred sixty-seven of this article. The criteria used in\ndetermining these cases of unusual and exceptional family circumstances\nshall be established by the president with the ap...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>