<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6636"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6636"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6636"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6636/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6636/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6636/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6636/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6636">
        <num>6636</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6636. Exempt persons. This article shall not prohibit:\n  1. The practice of perfusion by any student who is engaged in clinical\ntraining in a general hospital licensed pursuant to article twenty-eight\nof the public health law or during the transport of patients or organs\nsupported by extracorporeal or intracorporeal equipment and who is\nenrolled in a perfusion program approved by the department, provided\nsuch practice is limited to such clinical training which shall be\ncarried out under the direct supervision of a licensed perfusionist and\npursuant to the order and direction of a physician; or\n  2. The performance of any of the tasks or responsibilities included in\nthe definition of perfusion by any other person licensed under this\ntitle, provided that such tasks or responsibilities are authorized by\nthe article governing the profession pursuant to which said person is\nlicensed; or\n  3. The practice of perfusion by any legally qualified perfusionist of\nany other state or territory who is serving in the armed forces or the\npublic health service of the United States or who is employed by the\nveterans administration, while engaged in the performance of his or her\nduties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>