<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-04-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="667-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-667-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_667_D">
        <num>667-D</num>
        <heading>Enhanced tuition awards</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_667_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if enrolled in (A) a private degree granting institution of higher\neducation prior to application, has completed at least thirty combined\ncredits per year following the student's start date, or its equivalent,\napplicable to his or her program or programs of study or (B) a public\ndegree granting institution of higher education prior to application,\nhas completed at least thirty combined credits per year following the\nstudent's start date, or its equivalent, applicable to his or her\nprogram or programs of study and which were accepted upon transfer to a\nprivate degree granting institution of higher education; (ii) enrolls in\nat least twelve credits per semester and completes at least thirty\ncombined credits per year following the student's start date, or its\nequivalent, applicable to his or her program or programs of study except\nin limited circumstances as prescribed by the corporation in regulation.\nNotwithstanding, in the student's last semester, the student may take at\nleast one course needed to meet his or her graduation requirements and\nenroll in and complete at least twelve credit hours or its equivalent.\nFor students who are disabled as defined by the Americans With\nDisabilities Act of 1990, 42 USC 12101, the corporation shall prescribe\nrules and regulations that allow applicants who are disabled to be\neligible for an award pursuant to this section based on modified\ncriteria.\n  e. Notwithstanding paragraph d of this subdivision, a student who\notherwise satisfies all of the requirements under this section but fails\nto complete at least thirty combined credits, or its equivalent,\napplicable to his or her program or programs of study in any year shall\nbe eligible to receive an award payment for the first semester of such\nyear, provided however, the student shall be ineligible for any further\npayments under this section.\n  f. Additional requirements. A recipient shall agree to reside\nexclusively in New York state, and shall not be empl...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to complete undergraduate study; or (ii) to attend\ngraduate school on at least a half-time basis. Any obligation to comply\nwith such provisions as outlined in this paragraph may be cancelled upon\nthe death of the recipient. Notwithstanding any provisions of this\nparagraph to the contrary, the corporation is authorized to promulgate\nrules and regulations to provide for the waiver or suspension of any\nfinancial obligation which would involve extreme hardship.\n  g. Failure to meet the conditions of the award shall not otherwise\ndisqualify a student's eligibility to receive an award under section six\nhundred sixty-seven of this subpart.\n  2. Duration. No undergraduate shall be eligible for more than four\nacademic years of study, or five academic years if the program of study\nnormally requires five years. An undergraduate student enrolled in an\neligible two-year program approved by the commissioner shall be eligible\nfor no more than two academic years. Under no circumstances shall a\nstudent receive an award for a two-year program for more than two\nconsecutive years of academic study or four consecutive semesters of\nacademic study; or at a four or five-year program, for more than four\nconsecutive years or eight consecutive semesters of academic study or\nfive consecutive years, or ten consecutive semesters of study if the\nprogram normally requires five years. Notwithstanding, such duration may\nbe extended for an allowable interruption of study including, but not\nlimited to, death of a family member, medical leave, military service,\nand parental leave, as established by the corporation in regulation.\n  3. Income. An award shall be made to an applicant who has an adjusted\ngross income for the qualifying year, as such terms are defined in this\nsubdivision, equal to or less than:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_667_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>one hundred thousand dollars for\nrecipients receiving an award in the two thousand seventeen--two\nthousand eighteen academic year; (ii) one hundred ten thousand dollars\nfor recipients receiving an award in the two thousand eighteen--two\nthousand nineteen academic year; and (iii) one hundred twenty-five\nthousand dollars for recipients receiving an award in the two thousand\nnineteen--two thousand twenty academic year and thereafter. Adjusted\ngross income shall be the total of the combined adjusted gross income of\nthe applicant and the applicant's parents or the applicant and the\napplicant's spouse, if married. Qualifying year shall be the adjusted\ngross income as reported on the federal income tax return, or as\notherwise obtained by the corporation, for the calendar year coinciding\nwith the tax year established by the U.S. department of education to\nqualify applicants for federal student financial aid programs authorized\nby Title IV of the Higher Education Act of nineteen hundred sixty-five,\nas amended, for the school year in which application for assistance is\nmade. Provided, however, if an applicant demonstrates to the corporation\nthat there has been a change in such applicant's adjusted gross income\nin the year or years subsequent to the qualifying year which would\nqualify such applicant for an award, the corporation shall review and\nmake a determination as to whether such applicant meets the requirement\nset forth in this subdivision based on such year. Provided, further that\nsuch change was caused by the death, permanent and total physical or\nmental disability, divorce, or separation by judicial decree or pursuant\nto an agreement of separation which is filed with a court of competent\njurisdiction of any person whose income was required to be used to\ncompute the applicant's total adjusted gross income.\n  4. Amount. Within the amounts appropriated therefor and based on\navailability of funds, awards shall be granted beginning with the two\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>