<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="668-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_668_B">
        <num>668-B</num>
        <heading>Memorial scholarships for children, spouses and financial dependents of deceased firefighters, volunteer firefighters, police officers, p...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 668-b. Memorial scholarships for children, spouses and financial\ndependents of deceased firefighters, volunteer firefighters, police\nofficers, peace officers, and emergency medical service workers. 1.\nNotwithstanding subdivision five of section six hundred sixty-one of\nthis article, children, spouses or the financial dependents of\nfirefighters, volunteer firefighters, police officers, peace officers,\nand emergency medical service workers who have died as a result of an\ninjury sustained in the line of duty, in service to the state of New\nYork shall be eligible to receive an annual amount determined pursuant\nto subdivision two of section six hundred sixty-eight-d of this article.\nAny award pursuant to this section shall be inclusive of any amount the\nstudent would otherwise be eligible for pursuant to section six hundred\nsixty-eight-a or six hundred sixty-eight-d of this article.\n  2. Awards under this section shall be payable for each of not more\nthan four academic years of undergraduate study or five academic years\nif a program normally requires five years, as defined by the\ncommissioner pursuant to article thirteen of this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>