<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="668-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-668-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_668_A">
        <num>668-A</num>
        <heading>Regents awards for children of deceased police officers, peace officers, firefighters and volunteer firefighters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 668-a. Regents awards for children of deceased police officers,\npeace officers, firefighters and volunteer firefighters. 1. Eligible\nstudents.  Awards shall be made to resident children of police officers\nand peace officers as defined in the criminal procedure law,\nfirefighters and volunteer firefighters and correction officers of the\nstate or any political subdivision thereof, or volunteer firefighters of\nfire departments or companies under contract to provide fire protection\nto a municipality or fire district who have died as a result of an\ninjury sustained in the line of duty.\n  2. Amount and duration. Every recipient shall receive an annual award\nof four hundred fifty dollars for each of not more than four academic\nyears of undergraduate study or five academic years if a program\nnormally requires five years, as defined by the commissioner pursuant to\narticle thirteen of this chapter.\n  3. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this chapter, no\nchild of a correction officer of the state who is receiving an award\nunder the provisions of section six hundred sixty-nine of this article\nshall receive an award under the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>