<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="669-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-669-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_669_G">
        <num>669-G</num>
        <heading>The New York state achievement and investment in merit scholarship (NY-AIMS)</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_669_G__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>first, to applicants who have received payment of an award\npursuant to this section in a prior year and remain in good academic\nstanding; and\n  (ii) second, to applicants in descending order based on the unmet need\nto reach the full cost of attendance as indicated on the financial aid\naward letter.\n  However, in the program's first year, first priority shall be in\naccordance with subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph.\n  b. In the event that there are more applicants who have the same\npriority than there are remaining scholarships, the president shall\ndistribute the remaining number of such scholarships by means of a\nlottery or other form of random selection.\n  c. In each year, the awards made shall be proportionate to the total\napplications received for students accepted for undergraduate study at\npublic and private not-for-profit degree granting institutions.\n  4. Awards. Within amounts appropriated therefor, the president shall\ngrant an annual award to eligible applicants on a competitive basis\npursuant to subdivisions two and three of this section in the amount of\nfive hundred dollars for not more than four academic years of\nundergraduate study, or five academic years, if the program of study\nnormally requires five years as defined by the commissioner pursuant to\narticle thirteen of this chapter. Up to five thousand awards may be\ngranted to new recipients annually.\n  5. Offset. Such awards may be used to offset the applicant's total\ncost of attendance determined for federal Title IV student financial aid\npurposes.\n  6. Rules. The corporation is authorized to promulgate rules and\nregulations, and may promulgate emergency regulations, necessary for the\nimplementation of the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>