<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6705"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6705"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6705"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6705">
        <num>6705</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nassisting in diagnosis and surgery be under the immediate personal\nsupervision of such veterinarian;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>assisting in treatment be under\nthe direct supervision of such veterinarian; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>only one such\nstudent shall be supervised, as specified in clauses</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, by one such veterinarian.\n  10. Any employee of a not-for-profit pound, shelter, duly incorporated\nsociety for the prevention of cruelty to animals, humane society or dog\nor cat protective association may insert a microchip for the purposes of\nidentification of any animal being held for adoption by such\norganization.\n  11. A veterinary graduate of an approved program engaging in clinical\npractice under the supervision, but not necessarily direct personal\nsupervision, of a licensed veterinarian, provided the graduate has\npassed the required state licensing examination and applied and paid a\nfee for the licensing. This exemption shall not extend beyond sixty days\nafter graduation.\n  12. A physician duly licensed to practice medicine in this state, who\nis board certified in an area of human medicine equivalent to the\nrequired veterinary specialty in cases in which a veterinary specialist\nin the area of medicine required for such animal's care does not exist,\nis not available, or cannot be procured in a timely fashion, who\nprovides medical care to a gibbon or siamang (Hylobatidae, Hylobates\nsp.), orangutan (Hominidae Pongindae, Pongo sp.), chimpanzee (Hominidae,\nHomininae Pan. sp.), gorilla (Hominidae, Homininae, Gorilla sp.),\nmacaque (Cercopithecidea, Cercopithecinae, Macaca sp.), baboon\n(Cercopithecidae, Cercopithecinae, Papio sp., Theropithecus sp.,\nMandrillus sp.), langur (Cercopithecidae, Colobinac, Presbytis sp.,\nTrachypithecus sp.), colobus monkey (Cercopithecidae, Colobinae, Colobus\nsp.) or guenon (Cercopithecidae, Cercopithecinae, Cercopithecus sp.)\nheld by a facility accredited by the American Zoo and Aquarium\nAssociation at the request of and under the immediate personal\nsupervision of a licensed veterinarian who has personally diagnosed the\ncondition to be treated or who has specifically delegated such duties to\nthe physician and who evaluates the services provided by such physician.\n  13. Any person certif...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an official invitation has\nbeen extended to the veterinarian for a specified period of time by the\nlaw enforcement authority with jurisdiction over the investigation; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such law enforcement authority determines that the veterinarian\npossesses skills, training, or experience necessary and relevant to such\ninvestigation of alleged incidents of animal fighting or animal cruelty.\nSuch exemption shall not extend beyond the time period specified by the\nlaw enforcement authority with jurisdiction over such investigation. The\nlaw enforcement authority shall notify the state veterinarian of any\ninvestigation conducted pursuant to this subdivision for the purposes of\nfacilitating appropriate animal disease control measures, if necessary,\npursuant to articles five and twenty-six of the agriculture and markets\nlaw. Any person practicing as a veterinarian in New York state pursuant\nto this subdivision shall be subject to the personal and subject matter\njurisdiction and disciplinary and regulatory authority of the board of\nregents as if he or she is a licensee and as if the exemption pursuant\nto this subdivision is a license. Such individual shall comply with\napplicable provisions of the rules of the board of regents, and the\nregulations of the commissioner, relating to professional misconduct,\ndisciplinary proceedings and penalties for professional misconduct.\n  15. A veterinarian who is licensed in another state, and who is in\ngood standing in such state, providing services during an emergency or\nnatural disaster within the scope and location of assigned veterinary\nmedical duties of the response efforts if:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an official declaration\nof the disaster or emergency has been made by the governor or the\ndelegated state official; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6705__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an official invitation has been\nextended to the veterinarian for a specified time by the authority that\nhas jurisdiction for coordinating the animal/agricultural issues in the\nstate during emergencies either within or outside the emergency\nmanagement assistance compact (EMAC). Any person practicing as a\nveterinarian in New York state pursuant to this subdivision shall be\nsubject to the personal and subject matter jurisdiction and disciplinary\nand regulatory authority of the board of regents as if he or she is a\nlicensee and as if the exemption pursuant to this subdivision is a\nlicense. Such individual shall comply with applicable provisions of the\nrules of the board of regents, and the regulations of the commissioner,\nrelating to professional misconduct, disciplinary proceedings and\npenalties for professional misconduct.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>