<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6711-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6711-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6711_A">
        <num>6711-A</num>
        <heading>Limited permits to engage in the practice of veterinary technology</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6711-a. Limited permits to engage in the practice of veterinary\ntechnology.  Permits limited as to eligibility, practice, and duration,\nshall be issued by the department to eligible applicants as follows:\n  1. Eligibility. Persons shall be eligible for a limited permit who\nfulfill all requirements for a license as a veterinary technician except\nthose relating to the examination and citizenship or permanent residence\nin the United States.\n  2. Duration. A limited permit issued pursuant to subdivision one of\nthis section shall be valid for one year or until the individual has had\nthe opportunity to take the state veterinary technician licensing\nexamination and receive the results of this examination, whichever shall\noccur first. It may be renewed once at the discretion of the department\nif the permit holder has not had a reasonable opportunity to take the\nstate veterinary technician licensing examination during the period for\nwhich such limited permit was originally issued.\n  3. Fees. The fee for each limited permit and for each renewal shall be\nfifty dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>