<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-674"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-674"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="674"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-674/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-674/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-674/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-674/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_674">
        <num>674</num>
        <heading>Regents veterans with war service scholarships</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 674. Regents veterans with war service scholarships.  1. Number and\ncertification.  Six hundred regents veterans with war service\nscholarships shall be awarded for study beginning with the college year\nnineteen hundred seventy-five--nineteen hundred seventy-six, to eligible\nstudents certified to the president by the commissioner.\n  2. Residence. Notwithstanding any provision of this article to the\ncontrary, for such scholarship the only residence requirement for\neligibility is that an applicant must have been a legal resident of New\nYork state at the time of entry into the armed forces and must currently\nbe a legal resident.\n  3. Duration. Each such scholarship shall entitle the recipient thereto\nto an annual award for each of four academic years of full-time or\npart-time study, as defined by the commissioner pursuant to article\nthirteen, at a college or at a business, professional, vocational,\ntechnical or trade school licensed or approved by the regents. If all of\na scholarship holder's attendance is less than full-time, as so defined,\npayments may be made for a total period not to exceed five academic\nyears.\n  4. Amount. Notwithstanding any provisions of this article to the\ncontrary, the president shall make academic year awards in the amounts\nprovided in this subdivision. The recipient shall be entitled to a\nmaximum award of three hundred fifty dollars for each semester or term\nof full-time or part-time study, but not to exceed the cost of tuition\nand educational fees for such study.  However, the aggregate award for a\nsingle academic year shall not exceed three hundred fifty dollars, or\nfive hundred twenty-five dollars if the recipient is in continuous\nattendance during the entire academic year, including the summer term,\nand the total aggregate payment under this subdivision shall in no case\nexceed one thousand four hundred dollars.\n  5. Leave of absence. Notwithstanding any provision of the article to\nthe contrary, if an award is paid the recipient under this subdivision\nfor any semester, quarter or term of attendance during an academic year,\nthen a leave of absence shall not be required for non-attendance during\nany part of the balance of such academic year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>