<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6742"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6742/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6742">
        <num>6742</num>
        <heading>Special provision</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6742. Special provision.  1. Any person who is employed as a\nphysical therapist assistant in a facility satisfactory to the state\nboard for a period of not less than two years prior to the effective\ndate of this article and who does not qualify for certification under\nsubdivision b of section sixty-seven hundred forty of this article may\nbe certified as a physical therapist assistant upon successful\ncompletion of an examination approved by the state board of physical\ntherapy in accordance with the commissioner's regulations.\n  2. Application for examination for certification pursuant to this\nsection must be submitted not later than January first, nineteen hundred\neighty-five. The department shall provide a total of three such\nexaminations. The third examination shall be given not later than April\nfirst, nineteen hundred eighty-five.  The fee for examination or\nreexamination shall be twenty-five dollars for each examination. Any\nperson who qualifies for admission to an examination pursuant to this\nsection may practice as a physical therapist assistant in the course of\nhis or her employment in a facility satisfactory to the state board\nuntil thirty days after notification of failure to qualify pursuant to\nthis section.\n  3. Any person who was employed as a physical therapist assistant for\nat least two years prior to April first, nineteen hundred eighty-one,\nand who had attained permanent civil service status as a physical\ntherapist assistant prior to that date, shall be issued written\nauthorization from the department to continue working in that capacity\nwithout examination. This authorization shall remain in effect until the\nperson leaves the position in which the civil service status had been\ngranted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>