<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="679-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_679_I">
        <num>679-I</num>
        <heading>New York state child welfare worker loan forgiveness incentive program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 679-i. New York state child welfare worker loan forgiveness\nincentive program. 1. Purpose. the president shall grant student loan\nforgiveness awards for the purpose of attracting workers to be employed\nin voluntary not-for-profit child welfare agencies in New York state\nlicensed by the office of children and family services as a child\nwelfare worker. Such awards shall be made on a competitive basis, in\naccordance with rules and regulations promulgated by the corporation for\nsuch purposes, to applicants who meet the eligibility criteria.\n  2. Eligibility. To be eligible for an award pursuant to this section,\napplicants shall:\n  a. have graduated and obtained an undergraduate or graduate degree\nfrom a college or university located in New York state;\n  b. have outstanding student loan debt from obtaining such degree;\n  c. agree to work in a voluntary not-for-profit child welfare agency in\nNew York state licensed by the office of children and family services as\na child welfare worker, on a full time basis for a period of no less\nthan five years;\n  d. apply for this program within two years of college graduation; and\n  e. comply with subdivisions three and five of section six hundred\nsixty-one of this part.\n  3. Awards. Awards shall be granted to qualified applicants in the\namount of up to ten thousand dollars per year, per applicant, not to\nexceed a duration of five years and not to exceed the total amount of\nsuch applicant's student loan debt. The corporation shall grant such\nawards within amounts appropriated for such purposes and based on the\navailability of funds. No one applicant shall receive more than a total\nof fifty thousand dollars upon the end of a five-year period.\n  4. Priority. First priority shall be given to applicants who have\nreceived payment of an award pursuant to this section in a prior year\nand remain eligible. Second priority shall be given to applicants who\nare completing the second, third, fourth or fifth year of full-time\nemployment at a voluntary not-for-profit child welfare agency in New\nYork state licensed by the office of children and family services. Third\npriority shall be given to an applicant who can demonstrate economic\nneed but did not receive an award during the first year of this\nprogram's operation. If larger numbers of applicants are eligible\npursuant to this subdivision than funds available, applicants shall be\nchosen pursuant to rules and regulations promulgated by the corporation;\nprovided, however, that each applicant chosen shall receive an award of\nup to ten thousand dollars in each year such applicant is accepted into\nthe program.\n  5. Rules and regulations. The corporation is authorized to promulgate\nrules and regulations, and may promulgate emergency regulations,\nnecessary for the implementation of the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>