<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="679-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_679_D">
        <num>679-D</num>
        <heading>New York state nursing faculty loan forgiveness incentive program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be licensed as a registered professional nurse;\n(ii) have an outstanding student loan debt from a nursing degree program\nacquired on or after January first, two thousand one; (iii) have a\nmaster's degree in nursing or doctoral degree that qualified them as\nnursing faculty or adjunct clinical faculty; (iv) be employed as a\nfaculty member at a nursing school located in New York state; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_D__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ncomply with subdivisions three and five of section six hundred sixty-one\nof this part.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_679_D__subsec_v__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An award of eight thousand dollars shall be made annually to\nrecipients who have provided classroom or clinical instruction of not\nless than twelve academic credit hours, or its equivalent, as nursing\nfaculty or in clinical teaching service in the academic year preceding\nthe granting of the award, provided that no recipient shall receive\ncumulative awards, pursuant to this section, in excess of forty thousand\ndollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_679_D__subsec_v__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Other awards. Award recipients shall be eligible to apply for\nother awards.\n  b. Duration. Loan forgiveness awards shall be made annually to\napplicants whom the corporation has certified are eligible to receive\nsuch awards and have provided nursing faculty or clinical nurse faculty\nservices required pursuant to this article; provided that no award shall\nbe granted for more than five years.\n  c. Amount. The corporation shall grant such awards within the amounts\nappropriated for such purpose and based on availability of funds in an\namount not to exceed the total cost of the student loan debt.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>