<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="679-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_679_H">
        <num>679-H</num>
        <heading>New York state child welfare worker incentive scholarship program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_H__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nrecipient fails to complete their degree program within a reasonable\ntime as determined by the corporation; or (ii) one year after the\ncompletion of the degree program it is found that a recipient did not\nbegin full-time employment at a voluntary not-for-profit child welfare\nagency in New York state licensed by the office of children and family\nservices as a child welfare worker; or (iii) the recipient fails to\ncomplete five continuous years of full-time employment at a voluntary\nnot-for-profit child welfare agency in the state licensed by the office\nof children and family services as a child welfare worker or maintain\nresidency in New York state for such period of employment; or (iv) the\nrecipient fails to respond to requests by the corporation for the status\nof his or her academic or professional progress. The terms and\nconditions of this subdivision shall be deferred for any interruption in\nan undergraduate or graduate study or employment as established by the\nrules and regulations of the corporation. Any obligation to comply with\nsuch provisions as outlined in this section shall be cancelled upon the\ndeath of the recipient. Notwithstanding any provisions of this\nsubdivision to the contrary, the corporation is authorized to promulgate\nrules and regulations necessary for the waiver of suspension of any\nfinancial obligation which would involve extreme hardship.\n  8. Recipient selection. The president may establish:\n  a. an application deadline; and\n  b. a method of selecting recipients if in any given year there are\ninsufficient funds to cover the needs of all applicants and returning\nrecipients.\n  9. Rules and regulations. The corporation is authorized to promulgate\nrules and regulations, and may promulgate emergency regulations,\nnecessary for the implementation of the provisions of this section\nincluding, but not limited to, the criteria to distributing the awards,\nwhich may include a lottery or other form of random selection, an...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>