<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="679-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_679_C">
        <num>679-C</num>
        <heading>Senator Patricia K</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 679-c. Senator Patricia K. McGee nursing faculty scholarship\nprogram. 1. Purpose:\n  a. The president shall grant scholarship awards for the purpose of\nincreasing the number of educators and adjunct clinical faculty teaching\nin the field of nursing education in New York state. Such awards shall\nbe made on a competitive basis, as promulgated by the corporation\nthrough rules and regulations to applicants who are registered\nprofessional nurses and are enrolling in an approved program to obtain a\nmaster's degree in nursing or a doctoral degree that will qualify them\nas nursing faculty or adjunct clinical faculty.\n  b. To be eligible for an award pursuant to this subdivision,\napplicants shall (1) be a licensed registered nurse in New York state;\n(2) enroll in a master's degree program in nursing or doctoral degree\nprogram that will qualify them as nursing faculty or adjunct clinical\nfaculty in New York state; (3) agree to practice in New York state as\nnursing faculty upon completion of such degree program; and (4) comply\nwith subdivisions three and five of section six hundred sixty-one of\nthis part.\n  2. Award conditions and requirements. Scholarships shall be awarded on\na competitive basis as promulgated by the corporation through rules and\nregulations to applicants whom the corporation has certified are\neligible to receive such awards; and who agree to provide not less than\ntwelve academic credit hours or its equivalent as nursing faculty or\nclinical teaching service for the duration of at least four years upon\ncompletion of the degree program.\n  3. Amount. The corporation shall grant such awards within the amounts\nappropriated for such purpose and based on availability of funds\naccording to a schedule to be determined by the corporation in an\namount:\n  a. equal to the tuition charged to state resident students attending a\nmaster's degree program in nursing or doctoral degree program that will\nqualify them as nursing faculty or adjunct clinical faculty at the state\nuniversity of New York; the average mandatory fees charged at the state\nuniversity of New York, or the actual tuition and fees charged to the\nrecipient, whichever is less; and the average non-tuition cost of\nattendance, as determined by the corporation and as approved by the\ndirector of the budget, for a student at the state university of New\nYork or actual non-tuition cost of attendance at such institution,\nwhichever is less, provided that the scholarship shall not exceed an\namount that is equal to the total cost of attendance determined for\nfederal Title IV student financial aid purposes, less all other\nscholarships and grants provided by New York state, other states, the\nfederal government, or other governments, and the amount of educational\nbenefits paid under any program that would duplicate the purposes of\nthis program, provided that any scholarships or grants provided to a\nrecipient by the institution which are intended to fund any portion of\nthe difference between the annual state award and the actual costs of\nattendance at any such institution shall not be considered to duplicate\nthe purposes of this program.\n  b. No annual award shall exceed twenty thousand dollars.\n  4. Other awards. Award recipients shall be eligible to apply for other\nawards.\n  5. Penalties for noncompliance. a. The corporation shall convert to a\nstudent loan the full amount of the award given pursuant to this\nsection, plus interest, according to a schedule to be determined by the\ncorporation if: (1) three years after the completion of the degree\nprogram it is found that an applicant did not begin to provide nursing\nfaculty or clinical nurse faculty services; (2) if such applicant does\nnot provide nursing faculty or clinical nursing faculty services for\nfour years within seven years of the completion of the master's degree\nprogram in nursing or doctoral degree; or (3) the student fails to\nreceive a master's degree in nursing or doctoral degree that will\nqualify them as nursing faculty or adjunct clinical faculty within the\nthree years of receiving the award. The terms and conditions of this\nsubdivision shall be deferred for any interruption in graduate or\ndoctoral study or employment as established by the rules and regulations\nof the corporation. Any obligation to comply with such provisions as\noutlined in this section shall be cancelled upon the death of the\nrecipient. Notwithstanding any provisions of this subdivision to the\ncontrary, the corporation is authorized to promulgate rules and\nregulations to provide for the waiver or suspension of any financial\nobligation which would involve extreme hardship.\n  b. The rate of interest charged for repayment of the student loan\nshall be determined pursuant to rules and regulations promulgated by the\ncorporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>