<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="679-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-679-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_679_A">
        <num>679-A</num>
        <heading>New York state licensed social worker loan forgiveness program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be licensed as a social worker\npursuant to article one hundred fifty-four of this chapter;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>comply\nwith subdivisions three and five of section six hundred sixty-one of\nthis part; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have an outstanding student loan debt.\n  3. Priority. Such awards shall be made annually to applicants in the\nfollowing priority:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>First priority shall be given to applicants who have received\npayment of an award pursuant to this section in a prior year and who, in\nthe year prior to application, have provided social work services in</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\na critical human service area, or (ii) a previously designated critical\nhuman service area;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Second priority shall be given to applicants who have not received\npayment of an award pursuant to this section in a prior year and who\nhave provided social work services in a critical human service area in\nthe year prior to such application; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_679_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Third priority shall be given to applicants who are economically\ndisadvantaged as defined by the corporation.\n  4. Awards. The corporation shall grant awards in the value of six\nthousand five hundred dollars to individuals who have provided full-time\nsocial work services in a critical human service area in the year prior\nto such application, provided that no recipient shall receive an award\nthat exceeds the total remaining balance of the student loan debt and\nthat no recipient shall receive cumulative awards, pursuant to this\nsection, in excess of twenty-six thousand dollars. Awards shall be\nwithin the amounts appropriated for such purpose and based on\navailability of funds.\n  5. Rules and regulations. The corporation is authorized to promulgate\nrules and regulations necessary for the implementation of the provisions\nof this section. In the event that there are more applicants who have\nthe same priority, as provided in subdivision three of this section,\nthan there are remaining awards, the corporation shall provide in\nregulation the method of distributing the remaining number of such\nawards, which may include a lottery or other form of random selection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>