<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6802"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6802"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6802"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6802">
        <num>6802</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6802__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>(A) may be safely administered by a licensed pharmacist\nwithin their lawful scope of practice; and (B) is needed to prevent the\ntransmission of a reportable communicable disease that is prevalent in\nNew York state; or (ii) is a recommended immunization for such patients\nwho: (A) meet age requirements, (B) lack documentation of such\nimmunization, (C) lack evidence of past infection, or (D) have an\nadditional risk factor or another indication as recommended by the\nadvisory committee on immunization practices of the centers for disease\ncontrol and prevention. If the commissioner of health determines that\nthere is an outbreak of disease, or that there is the imminent threat of\nan outbreak of disease, then the commissioner of health may issue a\nnon-patient specific regimen applicable statewide.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6802__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the direct application of an immunizing agent to children between\nthe ages of two and eighteen years of age, whether by injection,\ningestion, inhalation or any other means, pursuant to a patient specific\norder or non-patient specific regimen prescribed or ordered by a\nphysician or certified nurse practitioner, for immunization to prevent\ninfluenza and medications required for emergency treatment of\nanaphylaxis resulting from such immunization. If the commissioner of\nhealth determines that there is an outbreak of influenza, or that there\nis the imminent threat of an outbreak of influenza, then the\ncommissioner of health may issue a non-patient specific regimen\napplicable statewide.\n  b. The injection of medications for the treatment of mental health and\nsubstance use disorder, as prescribed or ordered by a licensed\nprescriber, acting within the scope of their practice in this state and\nin accordance with regulations promulgated by the commissioner, in\nconsultation with th...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6802__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such administration is conducted pursuant to a valid\npatient-specific prescription or patient-specific order that authorizes\na pharmacist to administer medications approved by the U.S. Food and\nDrug Administration for the treatment of mental health and substance use\ndisorder. The pharmacist shall notify the licensed prescriber that the\nadministration is complete within five days and shall convey such\ninformation to the prescriber by making an entry into an interoperable\nelectronic medical records system, an electronic prescribing technology\nor a pharmacy record, or by using facsimile, electronic transmission or\nother electronic means. If an electronic means described in this\nsubparagraph is not available to the pharmacist at the time of\ncommunication, the pharmacist or pharmacist's designee may communicate\nthe information by telephone. Notification shall also be required if a\npatient does not receive an administration or if the patient experiences\nany side effects or adve...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6802__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such prescription may be subject to reassessment at appropriate\nintervals, as determined by the licensed prescriber.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6802__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Such activity is conducted in accordance with regulations,\npromulgated or adopted by the commissioner, in consultation with the\ndepartment of health and any other state agencies, as necessary, which\nshall include requirements for the following:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6802__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Maintaining continued competency regarding the populations served\nand medications administered.\n  (ii) Pre-administration patient consent and education regarding common\nside effects, drug interactions, injection site reactions and other\ninformation routinely provided to patients upon dispensing. If a patient\nis unable to provide consent, the pharmacist must obtain consent from a\nperson legally responsible when the recipient is incapable of\nconsenting.\n  (iii) When administering an injection in a pharmacy, the pharmacist\nshall provide an area for the injection that provides for the patient's\nprivacy.\n  (iv) Ensuring that only U.S. Food and Drug Administration approved\nmedications are administered.\n  23. "Electronic prescription" means a prescription created, recorded,\nor stored by electronic means; issued with an electronic signature; and\ntransmitted by electronic means, in accordance with regulations of the\ncommissioner and applicable regulations of the commissioner of health\nand federal regulations; provided, however, that an original hard copy\nprescription that is created electronically or otherwise may be\ntransmitted from the prescriber to the pharmacist by facsimile and must\nbe manually signed. "Electronic" means of or relating to technology\nhaving electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical,\nelectromagnetic, or similar capabilities. "Electronic signature" means\nan electronic sound, symbol, or process, attached to or logically\nassociated with an electronic prescription and executed or adopted by a\nperson with the intent to sign the prescription, in accordance with\nregulations of the commissioner and applicable regulations of the\ncommissioner of health and federal regulations.\n  24. "Compounding" means the combining, admixing, mixing, diluting,\npooling, reconstituting, or otherwise altering of a drug or bulk drug\nsubstance to create a drug with respect to an outsourcing facility under\nsection 503B of the Federal Food, Drug and ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6802__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is engaged in the compounding of sterile drugs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6802__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is currently registered as an outsourcing facility with the\nSecretary of Health and Human Services; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6802__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>complies with all applicable requirements of federal and state\nlaw, including the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act.\n  26. "Sterile drug" means a drug that is intended for parenteral\nadministration, an ophthalmic or oral inhalation drug in aqueous format,\nor a drug that is required to be sterile under federal or state law.\n  27. "Biological product" means a biological product as defined in\nsubsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6802__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act, 42\nU.S.C. Section 262</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6802__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n  28. "Interchangeable biological product" means a biological product\nlicensed by the United States Food and Drug Administration pursuant to\n42 U.S.C. Section 262</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6802__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6802__subsec_k__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>as set forth in the latest edition or\nsupplement of the United States Food and Drug Administration Lists of\nLicensed Biological Products with Reference Product Exclusivity and\nBiosimilarity or Interchangeability Evaluations, sometimes referred to\nas the "Purple Book," or a biological product determined by the United\nStates Food and Drug Administration to be therapeutically equivalent as\nset forth in the latest edition or supplement of the United States Food\nand Drug Administration Approved Drug Products with Therapeutic\nEquivalence Evaluations, sometimes referred to as the "Orange Book."\n  29. "Self-administered hormonal contraceptives", for the purpose of\nsection sixty-eight hundred one of this article, means self-administered\ncontraceptive medications or devices approved by the federal Food and\nDrug Administration to prevent pregnancy by using hormones to regulate\nor prevent ovulation, and includes oral hormonal contraceptives,\nhormonal contraceptive vaginal rings and h...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_6802__subsec_k__subsec_30">
            <num>(30)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Shared pharmacy services" means a system that allows a\nregistered pharmacist or a registered pharmacy, pursuant to a request\nfrom another registered pharmacist or pharmacy, to process or fill a\nprescription or order, pursuant to regulations promulgated by the\ncommissioner.\n  * NB Effective May 22, 2026\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>