<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6804"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6804"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6804"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6804/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6804/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6804">
        <num>6804</num>
        <heading>State board of pharmacy</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6804. State board of pharmacy. A state board of pharmacy shall be\nappointed by the regents on recommendation of the commissioner for the\npurpose of assisting the regents and the department on matters of\nprofessional licensing and professional conduct in accordance with\nsection sixty-five hundred eight of this title. The board shall be\ncomposed of not less than nine pharmacists licensed in this state for at\nleast five years and two registered pharmacy technicians. The initial\nregistered pharmacy technician members of the state board of pharmacy\nneed not be licensed prior to their appointment but shall have met all\nother requirements of licensure pursuant to section sixty-eight hundred\nforty-two of this title except for filing an application and paying a\nfee. An executive secretary to the board shall be appointed by the\nregents on recommendation of the commissioner and shall be a pharmacist\nlicensed in this state for at least five years. The board shall provide\nassistance to the department:\n  a. To regulate the practice of pharmacy, registered pharmacy\ntechnicians and the employment of interns and employees in pharmacies,\n  b. To regulate and control the sale, distribution, character and\nstandard of drugs, poisons, cosmetics, devices and new drugs,\n  c. To prevent the sale or distribution of such drugs, poisons,\ncosmetics, devices and new drugs as do not conform to the provisions of\nthis article or of the public health law,\n  d. To investigate alleged violations of the provisions of this\narticle, and\n  e. To issue limited permits or registrations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>