<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6805"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6805"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6805"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6805/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6805/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6805/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6805/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6805">
        <num>6805</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a professional license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6805. Requirements for a professional license. 1. To qualify for a\npharmacist's license, an applicant shall fulfill the following\nrequirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education, including a bachelor's or\nequivalent degree in pharmacy, in accordance with the commissioner's\nregulations;\n  (3) Experience: have experience satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (5) Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship or immigration status: be a United States citizen or a\nnoncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United\nStates;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of one hundred seventy-five dollars to the\ndepartment for admission to a department conducted examination and for\nan initial license, a fee of eighty-five dollars for each\nre-examination, a fee of one hundred fifteen dollars for an initial\nlicense for persons not requiring admission to a department conducted\nexamination, and a fee of one hundred fifty-five dollars for each\ntriennial registration period.\n  2. On or before April first, nineteen hundred seventy-two, any person\nwho holds a valid license as "druggist" in this state shall make\napplication and on the payment of fees specified in this title be\nlicensed by the department as a pharmacist. Such person shall have all\nof the rights, privileges, duties and responsibilities of a pharmacist.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>