<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6806"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6806"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-12-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6806"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6806/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6806/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6806/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6806/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6806">
        <num>6806</num>
        <heading>Limited permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6806. Limited permits. 1. The department may issue a limited permit\nfor employment as a "pharmacy intern" to:\n  a. A student enrolled in the last two years of a registered program in\npharmacy, or\n  b. A graduate of a program in pharmacy which meets standards\nestablished by the commissioner's regulations who is engaged in meeting\nthe experience requirements or whose application for initial licensure\nis pending with the department.\n  2. A pharmacy intern may, as determined by the commissioner's\nregulations, practice as a pharmacist under the immediate personal\nsupervision of a licensed pharmacist. A pharmacy intern may also receive\na certificate of administration if he or she provides satisfactory\nevidence to the commissioner that he or she meets the requirements of\nsubdivision three of this section.\n  3. No pharmacy intern shall administer immunizing agents without\nreceiving training satisfactory to the commissioner and the commissioner\nof health, as prescribed in regulations of the commissioner, which shall\ninclude, but not be limited to: techniques for screening individuals and\nobtaining informed consent; techniques of administration; indications,\nprecautions and contraindications in the use of an agent or agents;\nrecordkeeping of immunization and information; and handling emergencies,\nincluding anaphylaxis and needlestick injuries. To receive a\ncertification to administer immunizations, the pharmacy intern shall\nprovide documentation, on a form prescribed by the department, from the\ndean or other appropriate official of the registered program that the\nintern has completed the required training, pursuant to regulations of\nthe commissioner.\n  4. A limited permit issued to a pharmacy intern shall have an\nexpiration date of five years from the date of issue. Limited permits\nmay be renewed once for a period not to exceed two years.\n  5. Fees. The fee for each limited permit issued to a pharmacy intern\nshall be seventy dollars.\n  6. In the case of a pharmacy intern, certified to administer\nimmunizations, administration must be conducted under the immediate\npersonal supervision of a licensed pharmacist certified to administer\nvaccines. A person receiving a vaccine must be informed that a pharmacy\nintern, certified to administer immunizations, will be administering the\nvaccine and of the option to receive the vaccination from a certified\npharmacist.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>