<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6814"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6814"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6814"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6814/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6814/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6814/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6814/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6814">
        <num>6814</num>
        <heading>Records of shipment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6814. Records of shipment.  For the purpose of enforcing provisions\nof this article, carriers engaged in commerce, and persons receiving\ndrugs, devices or cosmetics in commerce or holding such articles so\nreceived, shall, upon the request of an officer duly assigned by the\nsecretary, permit such officer, at reasonable times, to have access to\nand to copy all records showing the movement in commerce of any drug,\ndevice or cosmetic, or the holding thereof during or after such\nmovement, and the quantity, shipper, and consignee thereof: and it shall\nbe unlawful for any such carrier or person to fail to permit such access\nto and copying of any such record so requested when such request is\naccompanied by a statement in writing specifying the nature or kind of\ndrug, device or cosmetic to which such request relates: Provided, that\nevidence obtained under this section shall not be used in a criminal\nprosecution of the person from whom obtained:  Provided further, that\ncarriers shall not be subject to the other provisions of this article by\nreason of their receipt, carriage, holding or delivery of drugs, devices\nor cosmetics in the usual course of business as carriers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>