<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6826"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6826"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6826"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6826/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6826/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6826/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6826/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6826">
        <num>6826</num>
        <heading>Drug retail price lists</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6826__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nconcerning discounts from its listed retail prices that may be available\nto consumers and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6826__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any limitations that the pharmacy may have as to\nwhat group or groups of customers it serves.\n  3. The pharmacy's corresponding retail price means the actual price to\nbe paid by a retail purchaser to the pharmacy for any listed drug at the\nlisted dosage. However, upon implementation of the prescription drug\nretail price list database by the department of health under section two\nhundred seventy-six-a of the public health law, the pharmacy's\ncorresponding retail price shall mean the price sent to it by the\ndepartment of health under that section.\n  4. Pharmacies shall have a sign notifying people of the availability\nof the drug retail price list and the availability of the department of\nhealth prescription drug retail price list database and the web address\nof that database, conspicuously posted at or adjacent to the place in\nthe pharmacy where prescriptions are presented for compounding and\ndispensing, in the waiting area for customers, or in the area where\nprescribed drugs are delivered.\n  5. Nothing contained herein shall prevent a pharmacy from changing and\ncharging the current retail price at any time, provided that the listed\nprice is updated at least weekly to reflect the new retail price.\n  6. The commissioner shall make regulations necessary to implement this\nsection, including how this section is applied to mail-order and\ninternet pharmacies.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>