<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6827"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6827"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6827"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6827/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6827/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6827/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6827/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6827">
        <num>6827</num>
        <heading>Mandatory continuing education</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6827__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each licensed\npharmacist required under article one hundred thirty of this chapter to\nregister triennially with the department to practice in the state shall\ncomply with provisions of the mandatory continuing education\nrequirements prescribed in subdivision two of this section except as set\nforth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6827__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6827__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. Pharmacists who do\nnot satisfy the mandatory continuing education requirements shall not\npractice until they have met such requirements, and they have been\nissued a registration certificate, except that a pharmacist may practice\nwithout having met such requirements if he or she is issued a\nconditional registration certificate pursuant to subdivision three of\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6827__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In accord with the intent of this section, adjustment to the\nmandatory continuing education requirement may be granted by the\ndepartment for reasons of health certified by an appropriate health care\nprofessional, for extended active duty with the armed forces of the\nUnited States, or for other good cause acceptable to the department\nwhich may prevent compliance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6827__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A licensed pharmacist not engaged in practice as determined by the\ndepartment, shall be exempt from the mandatory continuing education\nrequirement upon the filing of a statement with the department declaring\nsuch status. Any licensee who returns to the practice of pharmacy during\nthe triennial registration period shall notify the department prior to\nreentering the profession and shall meet such mandatory education\nrequirements as shall be prescribed by regulations of the commissioner.\n  * 2. During each triennial registration period an applicant for\nregistration shall complete a minimum of forty-five hours of acceptable\nformal continuing education, as specified in subdivision four of this\nsection, provided that no more than twenty-two hours of such continuing\neducation shall consist of self-study courses. Any pharmacist\nparticipating in collaborative drug therapy management pursuant to\nsection six thousand eight hundred one-a of this article shall complete\nat least five hours of acceptable formal continuing education in the\narea or areas of practice generally related to any collaborative drug\ntherapy management protocols to which the pharmacist may be subject. Any\npharmacist whose first registration date following the effective date of\nthis section occurs less than three years from such effective date, but\non or after January first, nineteen hundred ninety-eight, shall complete\ncontinuing education hours on a prorated basis at the rate of one and\none-quarter hours per month for the period beginning January first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-seven up to the first registration date\nthereafter. A licensee who has not satisfied the mandatory continuing\neducation requirements shall not be issued a triennial registration\ncertificate by the department and shall not practice unless and until a\nconditional registration certificate is issued as provided for in\nsubdivision three of this section. Continuing education hours taken\nduring one triennium may ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>