<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6907"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6907"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6907"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-6907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6907">
        <num>6907</num>
        <heading>Limited permits</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6907__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>graduates of schools of nursing registered by the\ndepartment, (ii) graduates of schools of nursing approved in another\nstate, province, or country or (iii) applicants for a license in\npractical nursing whose preparation is determined by the department to\nbe the equivalent of that required in this state.\n  2. Such limited permit shall expire one year from the date of issuance\nor upon notice to the applicant by the department that the application\nfor license has been denied, or ten days after notification to the\napplicant of failure on the professional licensing examination,\nwhichever shall first occur.  Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions\nof this subdivision, if the applicant is waiting the result of a\nlicensing examination at the time such limited permit expires, such\npermit shall continue to be valid until ten days after notification to\nthe applicant of the results of such examination.\n  3. A limited permit shall entitle the holder to practice nursing only\nunder the supervision of a nurse currently registered in this state and\nwith the endorsement of the employing agency.\n  4. Fees. The fee for each limited permit shall be thirty-five dollars.\n  5. Graduates of schools of nursing registered by the department may be\nemployed to practice nursing under supervision of a professional nurse\ncurrently registered in this state and with the endorsement of the\nemploying agency for ninety days immediately following graduation from a\nprogram in nursing and pending receipt of a limited permit for which an\napplication has been filed as provided in this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>