<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7008"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7008"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-08-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7008"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7008/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7008/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7008/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7008/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7008">
        <num>7008</num>
        <heading>Limited residency permits and limited fellowship permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7008. Limited residency permits and limited fellowship permits. 1.\nLimited residency permits and limited fellowship permits may be issued\nby the department to graduates of a program of professional education in\npodiatry registered by the department or accredited by an accrediting\nagency acceptable to the department.\n  2. Such permits shall allow a resident or fellow in podiatric medicine\nparticipating in an approved post-graduate residency or fellowship\nprogram to perform such duties, tasks and functions that are required\nfor successful completion of such program under the administrative\nsupervision of a licensed podiatrist serving as the residency or\nfellowship director, as applicable, in a hospital or health care\nfacility licensed pursuant to article twenty-eight of the public health\nlaw. At any time during the residency or fellowship, a licensed\nphysician or a licensed podiatrist may provide direct personal\nsupervision of activities which he or she is authorized and competent to\nprovide in the approved facility; provided, however, when the resident's\nor fellow's training involves practice beyond that authorized in section\nseven thousand one of this article, a licensed physician shall provide\ndirect personal supervision. For the purposes of this section, direct\npersonal supervision means supervision of procedures based on\ninstructions given directly by a licensed physician or licensed\npodiatrist, as applicable, who remains in the immediate area where the\nprocedures are being performed, authorizes the procedures and evaluates\nthe procedures performed by the podiatric resident or fellow.\n  3. Such permit shall be issued for three years and may be renewed at\nthe discretion of the department for additional one-year periods when\nnecessary to permit the completion of an approved post-graduate\nresidency or fellowship in podiatric medicine.\n  4. The fee for a limited residency permit or a limited fellowship\npermit shall be one hundred five dollars and the fee for a renewal shall\nbe fifty dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>