<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="701"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_701">
        <num>701</num>
        <heading>Power to designate text-books; purchase and loan of text-books; purchase of supplies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_701__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any\nbook, or a book substitute, which shall include hard covered or\npaperback books, work books, or manuals and (ii) for expenses incurred\nafter July first, nineteen hundred ninety-nine, any courseware or other\ncontent-based instructional materials in an electronic format, as such\nterms are defined in the regulations of the commissioner, which a pupil\nis required to use as a text, or a text-substitute, in a particular\nclass or program in the school he or she legally attends. For expenses\nincurred on or after July first, two thousand eleven, a text-book shall\nalso mean items of expenditure that are eligible for an apportionment\npursuant to sections seven hundred eleven, seven hundred fifty-one\nand/or seven hundred fifty-three of this title, where such items are\ndesignated by the school district as eligible for aid pursuant to this\nsection, provided, however, that if aided pursuant to this section, such\nexpenses shall not be aidable pursuant to any other section of law.\nExpenditures aided pursuant to this section shall not be eligible for\naid pursuant to any other section of law. Courseware or other\ncontent-based instructional materials in an electronic format included\nin the definition of textbook pursuant to this subdivision shall be\nsubject to the same limitations on content as apply to books or book\nsubstitutes aided pursuant to this section.\n  3. In the several cities and school districts of the state, boards of\neducation, trustees or such body or officers as perform the function of\nsuch boards shall have the power and duty to purchase and to loan upon\nindividual request, textbooks, to all children residing in such district\nwho are enrolled in a public school including children attending the\npublic schools of the district for whom the district is eligible to\nreceive reimbursement pursuant to paragraph a of subdivision eight of\nsection thirty-two hundred two of this chapter, provided, however, that\nsuch children shall not be counted by...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>