<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-704"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-704"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="704"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_704">
        <num>704</num>
        <heading>Text-books containing seditious or disloyal matter</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 704. Text-books containing seditious or disloyal matter.  No\ntext-book in any subject used in the public schools in this state shall\ncontain any matter or statements of any kind which are seditious in\ncharacter, disloyal to the United States or favorable to the cause of\nany foreign country with which the United States may be at war.  The\ncommission, consisting of the commissioner of education and of two\npersons to be designated by the regents, whose duty it shall be on\ncomplaint to examine text-books used in the public schools of the state,\nin the subjects of civics, economics, English, history, language and\nliterature, for the purpose of determining whether such text-books\ncontain any matter or statements of any kind which are seditious in\ncharacter, disloyal to the United States or favorable to the cause of\nany foreign country with which the United States may be at war, is\nhereby continued.  Any person may present a written complaint to such\ncommission that a text-book in any of the aforesaid subjects for use in\nthe public schools of this state or offered for sale for use in the\npublic schools of this state contains matter or statements in violation\nof this section, specifying such matter or statements in detail. If the\ncommission determine that the text-book against which complaint is made\ncontains any such matter or statements, it shall issue a certificate\ndisapproving the use of such text-book in the public schools of this\nstate, together with a statement of the reasons for its disapproval,\nspecifying the matter found unlawful.  Such certificate of disapproval\nof a text-book, with a detailed statement of the reasons for its\ndisapproval, shall be duly forwarded to the boards of education or other\nboards or authorities having jurisdiction of the public schools of the\nschool districts of this state, and after the receipt of such\ncertificate the use of a text-book so disapproved shall be discontinued\nin such school district.\n  Any contract hereafter made by any such board of education or other\nschool authorities for the purchase of a text-book in any of such\nsubjects, which has been so disapproved, shall be void.  Any school\nofficer or teacher who permits a text-book in any of such subjects,\nwhich has been so disapproved, to be used in the public schools of the\nstate, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>