<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7101"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7101">
        <num>7101</num>
        <heading>Definition of the practice of optometry</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7101. Definition of the practice of optometry. The practice of the\nprofession of optometry is defined as diagnosing and treating optical\ndeficiency, optical deformity, visual anomaly, muscular anomaly or\ndisease of the human eye and adjacent tissue by prescribing, providing,\nadapting or fitting lenses or by prescribing, providing, adapting or\nfitting non-corrective contact lenses, or by prescribing or providing\northoptics or vision training, or by prescribing and using drugs. The\npractice of optometry shall not include any injection or invasive\nmodality. For purposes of this section invasive modality means any\nprocedure in which human tissue is cut, altered, or otherwise\ninfiltrated by mechanical or other means. Invasive modality includes\nsurgery, lasers, ionizing radiation, therapeutic ultrasound and the\nremoval of foreign bodies from within the tissue of the eye. Nothing in\nthis section or section seventy-one hundred one-a of this article shall\nbe construed to limit the scope of optometric practice as authorized\nprior to January first, nineteen hundred ninety-five. The use of drugs\nby optometrists is authorized only in accordance with the provisions of\nthis article and regulations promulgated by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>