<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-712"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-712"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="712"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-712/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-712/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-712/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-712/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_712">
        <num>712</num>
        <heading>Loan of school library materials</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 712. Loan of school library materials.  1. In the several cities and\nschool districts of the state, boards of education, trustees or such\nbody or officers as perform the function of such boards shall have the\npower and duty to loan upon request of an individual or a group of\nindividual pupils, to all pupils defined in subdivision three of section\nseven hundred eleven of this article, school library materials. School\nlibrary materials loaned to such pupils attending private schools shall\nbe school library materials which are designated for use in any public\nelementary or secondary schools of the state or are approved by any\nboard of education, trustees or other school authorities. Such school\nlibrary materials are to be loaned free to such children subject to such\nrules and regulations as are or may be prescribed by the board of\nregents and such boards of education, trustees or other school\nauthorities.\n  2. No school district shall be required to loan school library\nmaterials in excess of the school library materials owned or acquired by\nsuch district pursuant to section seven hundred eleven of this article.\nSuch school library materials shall be loaned on an equitable basis to\nchildren defined in subdivision three of section seven hundred eleven of\nthis article attending in the current year. The payment of tuition under\narticle eighty-nine of this chapter is deemed to be an equitable loan to\nchildren for whom such tuition is paid.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>