<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7206-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7206-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7206_A">
        <num>7206-A</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a license as a professional land surveyor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7206-a. Requirements for a license as a professional land surveyor.\n1. To qualify for a license as a professional land surveyor, an\napplicant shall fulfill the following requirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education, including a bachelor's or\nhigher degree based on a program in land surveying, in accordance with\nthe commissioner's regulations;\n  (3) Experience: Have practical experience satisfactory to the\ndepartment and in accordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (5) Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship or immigration status: be a United States citizen or a\nnoncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United\nStates;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of one hundred thirty-five dollars to the\ndepartment for an initial license, and a fee of two hundred ten dollars\nfor each triennial registration period.\n  2. In lieu of the degree requirements specified in paragraph (2) of\nsubdivision one of this section, an associate's degree in land\nsurveying, or an associate's degree or higher in engineering, math, or\nrelated science with credits in land surveying acceptable to the\ndepartment.\n  2-a. For admittance to the fundamentals of surveying examination, the\napplicant shall fulfill the education, experience, and examination\nrequirements in accordance with the commissioner's regulations. Upon the\nsuccessful completion of the examination, an identification card as an\n"intern land surveyor" shall be issued by the department. The fee for\nexamination qualification and identification card as an "intern land\nsurveyor" shall be seventy dollars.\n  * 2-b. In lieu of the degree and experience requirements specified in\nparagraphs two and three of subdivision one of this section, eight years\nof practical experience in work satisfactory to the department may be\naccepted, provided that each full year of college study in engineering\nor land surveying satisfactory to the department may at the discretion\nof the department be accepted in lieu of one year of the required eight\nyears of experience.\n  * NB Repealed April 3, 2029\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>