<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7207"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7207">
        <num>7207</num>
        <heading>Limited permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7207. Limited permits. 1. On recommendation of the board, the\ndepartment may issue a limited permit to practice engineering to an\nengineer not a resident of this state and having no established place of\npractice in this state who is legally qualified to practice as such in\nhis own country or state and who submits satisfactory evidence of\nestablished and recognized professional standing in his own country or\nstate and who submits satisfactory certifications as to character and\nqualifications from at least two licensed professional engineers, one of\nwhom shall be a resident of this state. Such limited permit shall be\nissued solely in connection with the specific project for which such\nlimited permit is granted.\n  2. A limited permit to practice as a professional engineer, land\nsurveyor or professional geologist in this state may be issued by the\ndepartment to a person not a resident in this state and having no\nestablished place of practice in this state, when such practice does not\naggregate more than thirty days in any calendar year, provided that such\nperson is legally qualified to practice in his own state or country. The\nlimited permit authorizing such right to practice in this state shall\nspecify the dates within the calendar year when such right may be\nexercised.\n  3. On recommendation of the board, the department may issue a limited\npermit to practice geology to a geologist not a resident of this state\nand having no established place of practice in this state who is legally\nqualified to practice as such in his or her own country or state with\nstandards equivalent to those enumerated in this article and who submits\nevidence satisfactory to the board established and recognized\nprofessional standing in his or her own country or state and who submits\nsatisfactory certification as to character and qualifications from at\nleast two professional geologists, one of whom shall be a resident of\nthis state. Such limited permit shall be issued solely in connection\nwith the specific project for which such limited permit is granted.\n  4. Fees. The fee for each limited permit shall be one hundred five\ndollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>