<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-03-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7210"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7210">
        <num>7210</num>
        <heading>Certificates of authorization</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7210. Certificates of authorization. 1. Domestic or foreign\nprofessional service corporations, design professional service\ncorporations, professional service limited liability companies, foreign\nprofessional service limited liability companies, registered limited\nliability partnerships, New York registered foreign limited liability\npartnerships, partnerships and joint enterprises specified in\nsubdivision four of section seventy-two hundred nine of this article,\nprovided each of the foregoing entities is authorized to provide\nprofessional engineering, land surveying or professional geology\nservices and general business corporations authorized to provide\nprofessional engineering or land surveying services pursuant to\nsubdivision six of section seventy-two hundred nine of this article may\noffer to provide or provide professional engineering, land surveying or\nprofessional geology services only after obtaining a certificate of\nauthorization from the department. Except as otherwise authorized by\nstatute, rule or regulation, other business entities are not authorized\nto offer or provide professional engineering, land surveying or\nprofessional geology services and may not obtain certificates of\nauthorization provided that nothing contained herein shall prohibit an\nindividual who is licensed to practice professional engineering, land\nsurveying or professional geology under this article from obtaining a\ncertificate of authorization upon application and payment of the\nappropriate fees provided for under this section.\n  2. Upon application a certificate of authorization shall be issued by\nthe department to all individuals, corporations, limited liability\ncompanies, limited liability partnerships, partnerships and joint\nenterprises specified in subdivision one of this section and which are\nauthorized to provide professional engineering or land surveying\nservices and pay the appropriate fee.\n  3. A "certificate of authorization" shall authorize such individual,\ncorporation, limited liability company, limited liability partnership,\npartnership or joint enterprise to provide professional engineering or\nland surveying services for three years from the date of issuance\nsubject to, as otherwise prescribed by law, the supervision of the\nregents of the university of the state of New York including the power\nto discipline and impose penalties in the same manner and to the same\nextent as is provided with respect to individuals and their licenses and\nregistration pursuant to this title.\n  4. An application, triennial renewal, delinquent or replacement\ncertificate fee must accompany the "certificate of authorization"\nrequest in the amount shown below. A business entity that fails to renew\nits certificate of authorization before the expiration date shall be\nrequired to pay the additional delinquent fee for late filing of ten\ndollars for each full month it has practiced after the expiration of its\ncertificate of authorization.\n  Application fee and first triennial certificate of authorization -\n  $125.00;\n  Triennial renewal fee - $75.00;\n  Delinquent fee - $10.00 per month of practice without a certificate of\n  authorization;\n  Replacement certificate fee - $10.00.\n  All checks shall be made payable to the state department of education,\nstate of New York and submitted to the department. If a business\nenterprise is not eligible to receive a "certificate of authorization",\nthe fee will be retained to cover the costs of processing. Triennial\nrenewal fees for all "certificates of authorization" are due and payable\non or before the filing date of each triennial registration period.\n  5. The department shall compile a registry of the holders of all\ncertificates of authorization. Such registry shall include the name and\naddress of all registrants, state whether a certificate of authorization\nhas been issued, denied, suspended, or revoked, and disclose whether the\ncertificate is current or expired. Access to the registry shall be made\navailable electronically without cost. A record search of the registry\nmay be obtained in person or by mail provided that a fee of ten dollars\nshall be paid for each putative registrant.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>