<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7326"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7326"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7326"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7326/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7326/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7326/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7326/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7326">
        <num>7326</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7326. Exempt persons.  This article shall not be construed to affect\nor prevent:\n  a. The preparation of details and shop drawings by persons, other than\nlandscape architects, for use in connection with the execution of their\nwork;\n  b. Employees of those lawfully practicing as landscape architects\nunder the provisions of this article from acting under the instruction,\ncontrol or supervision of their employers;\n  c. Supervision by builders, or superintendents employed by such\nbuilders, of the installation of landscape projects; or\n  d. Business conducted in this state by any agriculturist,\nhorticulturist, tree expert, arborist, forester, nurseryman or landscape\nnurseryman, gardener, landscape gardener, landscape contractor, garden\nor lawn caretaker or grader or cultivator of land, as these terms are\ngenerally used, except that no such person shall use the designation\nlandscape architect, landscape architectural or landscape architecture\nunless licensed under this article.\n  e. Employment of any person as a junior or assistant landscape\narchitect by the City of New York in a position the title of which was\napproved and in use as of July first, nineteen hundred seventy-one,\nprovided such person acts under the general supervision of a licensed\nlandscape architect.\n  f. The practice of architecture by an architect licensed in this\nstate, or the practice of engineering or land surveying by an engineer\nor land surveyor licensed in this state, provided that no such\narchitect, engineer or land surveyor shall use the designation\n"landscape architect," "landscape architectural" or "landscape\narchitecture" unless licensed as a landscape architect in this state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>