<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7405"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7405"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7405"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7405">
        <num>7405</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a license as a public accountant</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7405. Requirements for a license as a public accountant.  To qualify\nfor a license as a public accountant, an applicant shall fulfill the\nfollowing requirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Declaration of intention: a. Have filed a declaration of intention\nto practice as a public accountant with the department on or before\nOctober first, nineteen hundred fifty-nine, on the basis of evidence\nthat the applicant was engaged for a total of six years during the ten\nyears immediately preceding April twenty-third, nineteen hundred\nfifty-nine, in the practice of public accountancy as an individual\npractitioner or as a partner of a partnership or as an employee of such\nan individual practitioner or partnership engaged in the practice of\npublic accountancy or as an employee of a department, agency or\ninstrumentality of the United States, the state, or a political\nsubdivision of the state in which employment his duties entailed the\nperformance of all or some of the services which would constitute the\npractice of public accountancy, or a combination of the foregoing\nduties, or in the opinion of the board the equivalent thereof;\n  b. Establish by evidence satisfactory to the board that at the date of\nthe filing of said declaration of intention, the applicant had complied\nwith the conditions established by law on April twenty-third, nineteen\nhundred fifty-nine, has not violated the provisions relating to practice\nin public accountancy, and is about to engage in the practice of public\naccountancy as his principal occupation as an individual practitioner or\nas a partner of a partnership;\n  (3) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (4) Fees: pay a fee to the department for an initial license of two\nhundred twenty dollars, and a fee of two hundred ten dollars for each\ntriennial registration period.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>