<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7504"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7504"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7504"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7504/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7504/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7504/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7504/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7504">
        <num>7504</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a professional license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7504. Requirements for a professional license. 1. To qualify for a\nlicense as a certified shorthand reporter, an applicant shall fulfill\nthe following requirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education, including high school\ngraduation and completion of a program in shorthand reporting, in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (3) Experience: have experience satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (5) Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship or immigration status: be a United States citizen or a\nnoncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United\nStates;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of one hundred fifteen dollars to the department\nfor admission to a department conducted examination and for an initial\nlicense, a fee of forty-five dollars for each reexamination, a fee of\nfifty dollars for an initial license for persons not requiring admission\nto a department conducted examination, and a fee of fifty dollars for\neach triennial registration period.\n  2. In lieu of professional qualifications specified in subparagraphs\n(2) and (3) of subdivision one of this section, five years of experience\nin shorthand reporting satisfactory to the board may be accepted by the\ndepartment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>