<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7603"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7603"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7603"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7603/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7603/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7603/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-7603/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7603">
        <num>7603</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a professional license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7603. Requirements for a professional license. To qualify for a\nlicense as a psychologist, an applicant shall fulfill the following\nrequirements:\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: have received an education, including a doctoral degree\nin psychology, granted on the basis of completion of a program of\npsychology registered with the department or the substantial equivalent\nthereof, in accordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (3) Experience: have two years of supervised employment or engagement\nin appropriate psychology activities satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations. Satisfactory experience\nobtained in an entity operating pursuant to a waiver issued by the\ndepartment pursuant to section sixty-five hundred three-a of this title\nmay be accepted by the department, notwithstanding that such experience\nmay have been obtained prior to the effective date of such section\nsixty-five hundred three-a and/or prior to the entity having obtained a\nwaiver. The department may, for good cause shown, accept satisfactory\nexperience that was obtained in a setting that would have been eligible\nfor a waiver but which has not obtained a waiver with the department or\nexperience that was obtained in good faith by the applicant under the\nbelief that appropriate authorization had been obtained for the\nexperience, provided that such experience meets all other requirements\nfor acceptable experience;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations;\n  (5) Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  (6) Citizenship: meet no requirement as to United States citizenship;\n  (7) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment; and\n  (8) Fees: pay a fee of one hundred seventy dollars to the department\nfor admission to a department conducted examination and for an initial\nlicense, a fee of eighty-five dollars for each reexamination, a fee of\none hundred fifteen dollars for an initial license for persons not\nrequiring admission to a department conducted examination, and a fee of\none hundred fifty-five dollars for each triennial registration period.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>