<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8003"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8003"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8003"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8003/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8003/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8003">
        <num>8003</num>
        <heading>State board for dietetics and nutrition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8003. State board for dietetics and nutrition.  A state board for\ndietetics and nutrition shall be appointed by the board of regents, on\nrecommendation of the commissioner, for the purpose of assisting the\nboard of regents and the department on matters of certification and\nprofessional conduct in accordance with section sixty-five hundred eight\nof this chapter.\n  The board shall consist of not less than thirteen members, ten of whom\nshall be certified dietitians or certified nutritionists, except that\nthe members of the first board need not be certified  but shall be\npersons who are eligible for certification under the provisions of this\narticle prior to their appointment to the board.  The first board, with\nrespect to members representing the profession, shall consist of five\nmembers registered by a national dietetic association having\nregistration standards acceptable to the department and five members who\nare members of or registered by a national nutritional association\nhaving membership and/or registration standards acceptable to the\ndepartment. Thereafter, members of the profession appointed to such\nboard shall be certified pursuant to this article.  To the extent\nreasonable, the board of regents should insure the state board is\nbroadly representative of various professional interests within the\ndietetic and nutritional community.  Three members shall be\nrepresentatives of the general public. An executive secretary to the\nboard shall be appointed by the board of regents on the recommendation\nof the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>