<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-801-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-801-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="801-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-801-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-801-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-801-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-801-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_801_A">
        <num>801-A</num>
        <heading>Instruction in civility, citizenship and character education</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 801-a. Instruction in civility, citizenship and character education.\nThe regents shall ensure that the course of instruction in grades\nkindergarten through twelve includes a component on civility,\ncitizenship and character education. Such component shall instruct\nstudents on the principles of honesty, tolerance, personal\nresponsibility, respect for others, with an emphasis on discouraging\nacts of harassment, bullying, discrimination, observance of laws and\nrules, courtesy, dignity and other traits which will enhance the quality\nof their experiences in, and contributions to, the community. Such\ncomponent shall include instruction of safe, responsible use of the\ninternet and electronic communications. The regents shall determine how\nto incorporate such component in existing curricula and the commissioner\nshall promulgate any regulations needed to carry out such determination\nof the regents. For the purposes of this section, "tolerance," "respect\nfor others" and "dignity" shall include awareness and sensitivity to\nharassment, bullying, discrimination and civility in the relations of\npeople of different races, weights, national origins, ethnic groups,\nreligions, religious practices, mental or physical abilities, sexual\norientations, genders, and sexes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>