<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="803-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-803-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_803_A">
        <num>803-A</num>
        <heading>Courses of study in prevention of child abduction</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 803-a. Courses of study in prevention of child abduction.  1. All\npupils in grades K-8 in all public schools in the state shall receive\ninstruction designed to prevent the abduction of children. Such\ninstruction shall be provided by or under the direct supervision of\nregular classroom teachers, provided, however, that such instruction may\nbe provided by any other agency, public or private.\n  2. The commissioner, shall provide technical assistance to assist in\nthe development of curricula for such courses of study which shall be\nage appropriate and developed according to the needs and abilities of\npupils at successive grade levels in order to provide awareness skills,\ninformation, self-confidence and support to aid in the prevention of\nchild abduction.\n  3. For purposes of developing such courses of study, the board of\neducation or trustees of every school district may establish local\nadvisory councils or utilize the school-based shared decision making and\nplanning committee established pursuant to regulations of the\ncommissioner to make recommendations concerning the content and\nimplementation of such courses. School districts may alternatively\nutilize courses of instruction developed by consortia of school\ndistrict, boards of cooperative educational services, other school\ndistricts or any other agency, public or private. Such advisory councils\nshall consist of, but not be limited to, parents, school trustees and\nboard members, appropriate school personnel, business and community\nrepresentatives, and law enforcement personnel having experience in the\nprevention of child abduction.\n  4. The board of education or trustees of every school district shall\nprovide appropriate training and curriculum materials for the regular\nteachers who provide such instruction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>