<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="804-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-804-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_804_B">
        <num>804-B</num>
        <heading>Education regarding child development</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 804-b. Education regarding child development. 1. All schools shall\nbe authorized to include, as an integral part of home economics or\nhealth education, instruction regarding child development and parental\nskills and responsibility.\n  2. Instruction regarding child development and parental skills and\nresponsibility may be included in the home economics or health education\nprovided for all secondary school pupils and shall be taught by teachers\ncertified to teach home economics or health education. Related courses\nin the secondary school curriculum may be taught in a manner supportive\nof home economics education or health education regarding child\ndevelopment and parental skills and responsibility.\n  3. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations to\nestablish a curriculum for instruction regarding child development and\nparental skills and responsibility for the welfare of pupils and the\ncommunity to be available in school districts. The contents may be\nvaried to meet the needs of particular school districts, or portions\nthereof, and need not be uniform throughout the state; such curriculum\nmay include instruction relating to the consequences and prevention of\nshaken baby syndrome, which may include the viewing of a video\npresentation for students in secondary schools.\n  4. School authorities shall be authorized to provide the needed\nfacilities, time, and place for the instruction set forth herein and to\nprovide learning aids and curriculum resource materials which contribute\nto effective teaching methods and learning in home economics education\nor health education regarding child development and parental skills and\nresponsibility.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>