<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-810"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-810"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="810"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-810/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-810/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-810/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-810/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_810">
        <num>810</num>
        <heading>Conservation day</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 810. Conservation day.  1. The last Friday in April each year is\nhereby made and declared to be known as Conservation day, and observed\nin accordance with the provisions of this chapter, except that for the\nyear nineteen hundred seventy-eight, Conservation day shall be May\nthird.\n  2. It shall be the duty of the authorities of every public school in\nthis state to assemble the pupils in their charge on that day in the\nschool building, or elsewhere, as they may deem proper, and to provide\nfor and conduct (1) such exercises as shall tend to encourage the\nplanting, protection and preservation of trees and shrubs, and an\nacquaintance with the best methods to be adopted to accomplish such\nresults, and (2) such lectures, pictures or tours, as shall tend to\nincrease the interest and knowledge of such pupils in the fish and wild\nlife, soil and water of the state.\n  3. The commissioner of education may prescribe from time to time a\ncourse of exercises and instruction in the subjects hereinbefore\nmentioned, which shall be adopted and observed by the public school\nauthorities on Conservation day. Upon receipt of copies of such course\nsufficient in number to supply all the schools under their supervision,\nthe school authorities aforesaid shall promptly provide each of the\nschools under their charge with a copy, and cause it to be observed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>