<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-816"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-816"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="816"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-816/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-816/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-816/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-816/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_816">
        <num>816</num>
        <heading>Local library and school partnerships</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 816. Local library and school partnerships. 1. Legislative intent.\nIn order to promote and encourage children to read and learn outside the\nclassroom, this law seeks to encourage local libraries and schools to\nwork together to promote the availability of library services and\nresources.\n  2. Definitions. For the purposes of this section, the following terms\nshall be defined as follows:\n  a. "School district" shall mean any public school district in the\nstate of New York that contains one or more schools with any combination\nof grades from and including kindergarten through grade twelve.\n  b. "Public library" shall mean any public or association library as\ndefined in section two hundred fifty-three of this title.\n  3. Upon the request of a public library that is located within the\nboundaries of a school district, the district shall disseminate\ninformational materials provided by the library regarding the public\nlibrary and applications for public library cards to students enrolled\nin the school district. Such materials shall be distributed to any or\nall of the following, as requested by the public library:\n  a. annually to every student of such school district upon his or her\nentry into kindergarten, grade six and grade nine, except that a library\nand school may agree to alternate or additional grades;\n  b. to every student upon his or her enrollment as a new student; and\n  c. available at all times in the school library in each school within\nthe school district for students and parents who wish to obtain such\nmaterials.\n  4. The director of each participating public library shall consult\nannually with the school district in order to coordinate the provision\nof materials containing information regarding the library, instructions\non how students may obtain a library card and an application for a\nlibrary card.\n  5. Each public library that is located in the school district shall\nprovide sufficient copies of such materials to the school district for\ndistribution as described in subdivision three of this section so that\neach school may satisfy the requirements of this section.\n  6. In the event there is no public library located within the\nboundaries of a school district, such school district shall not be\nrequired to comply with this section.\n  7. The commissioner shall have the authority to establish rules and\nregulations to implement the provisions of this section.\n  8. Nothing in this act shall require a school district to expend\nadditional funds in order to comply with the provisions of this section.\n  9. This section shall not apply to a school district or a library in a\ncity of one million or more where such district or library are subject\nto a local law which was adopted prior to the enactment of this section\nand which provides for the distribution of library materials in public\nschools.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>