<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-817"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-817"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="817"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-817/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-817/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-817/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-817/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_817">
        <num>817</num>
        <heading>Expanding access to advanced courses to improve educational equity</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 817. Expanding access to advanced courses to improve educational\nequity. 1. Each school district and charter school shall annually\nprovide notification to parents and students of the benefits and the\nopportunities within the district or charter school of participating in\nadvanced courses.\n  2. Such notification shall include:\n  a. the benefits of participating in advanced courses;\n  b. a description of the advanced courses offered by the school\ndistrict or charter school in middle and high school and how to prepare\nfor and enroll in them;\n  c. a description of the advanced courses to be offered by the school\ndistrict or charter school in the following school year; and\n  d. a description of the academic and non-academic support the school\ndistrict or charter school provides to help students succeed in advanced\ncourses, as well as any financial assistance available to reduce or\neliminate any costs associated with participation in advanced courses,\nincluding but not limited to related fees, supplies, and assessments.\n  3. Notification shall be provided electronically or by mail and be\nposted on the website of the school district or charter school.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 817's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>