<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-818"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-818"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="818"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-818/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-818/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-818/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-818/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_818">
        <num>818</num>
        <heading>Evidence-based and scientifically based reading instruction</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_818__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before January first, two thousand twenty-five, the\ncommissioner shall provide school districts with the instructional best\npractices for the teaching of reading to students in prekindergarten\nthrough grade three. Instructional best practices for the teaching of\nreading shall be evidence-based and scientifically based, focusing on\nreading competency in the areas of phonemic awareness, phonics,\nvocabulary development, reading fluency, comprehension, including\nbackground knowledge, oral language and writing, oral skill development,\nand align with the department's culturally responsive-sustaining\nframework. Such instructional best practices shall be periodically\nupdated by the commissioner where appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_818__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every school district shall annually review their curriculum and\ninstructional practices in the subject of reading for students in\nprekindergarten through grade three to ensure that they align with the\nreading instructional best practices provided by the commissioner, and\nthat all early reading instructional practices and interventions are\npart of an aligned plan designed to improve student reading outcomes in\nprekindergarten through grade three.\n  2. For the purpose of this section, "evidence-based and scientifically\nbased", "phonemic awareness", "comprehension", "reading fluency",\n"vocabulary development", "culturally responsive-sustaining framework",\nand such other terms necessary to implement this section shall be as\ndefined by the commissioner in regulations.\n  3. On or before September first, two thousand twenty-five, every\nschool district shall verify to the commissioner that their curriculum\nand instructional practices in the subject of reading in prekindergarten\nthrough grade three align with all of the elements of the instructional\nbest practices provided by the commissioner pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>