<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8211"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8211">
        <num>8211</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8211__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Profession of acupuncture" is the treating, by means of\nmechanical, thermal or electrical stimulation effected by the insertion\nof needles or by the application of heat, pressure or electrical\nstimulation at a point or combination of points on the surface of the\nbody predetermined on the basis of the theory of the physiological\ninterrelationship of body organs with an associated point or combination\nof points for diseases, disorders and dysfunctions of the body for the\npurpose of achieving a therapeutic or prophylactic effect. The\nprofession of acupuncture includes recommendation of dietary supplements\nand natural products including, but not limited to, the recommendation\nof diet, herbs and other natural products, and their preparation in\naccordance with traditional and modern practices of East Asian (Chinese,\nKorean or Japanese) medical theory.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8211__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each acupuncturist licensed pursuant to this article, shall advise\neach patient as to the importance of consulting with a licensed\nphysician regarding the patient's condition and shall keep on file with\nthe patient's records, a form attesting to the patient's notice of such\nadvice. Such form shall be in duplicate, one copy to be retained by the\npatient, signed and dated by both the acupuncturist and the patient and\nshall be prescribed in the following manner:\n  WE, THE UNDERSIGNED, DO AFFIRM THAT               (THE PATIENT) HAS\nBEEN ADVISED BY                , (A LICENSED ACUPUNCTURIST), TO CONSULT\nA PHYSICIAN REGARDING THE CONDITION OR CONDITIONS FOR WHICH SUCH PATIENT\nSEEKS ACUPUNCTURE TREATMENT.\n___________________________          ________________________\n        (Signature)                            Date\n___________________________          ________________________\n        (Signature)                            Date\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8211__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit an individual who is\nnot subject to regulation in this state as a licensed acupuncturist from\nengaging in the recommendation of traditional remedies and supplements\nas defined herein, nor shall this section be construed to authorize an\nindividual to practice pharmacy under article one hundred thirty-seven\nof this title.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_8211__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Board" is the state board for acupuncture as created by section\neighty-two hundred thirteen of this article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>