<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8214"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8214"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8214"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8214">
        <num>8214</num>
        <heading>Requirements for a professional license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8214. Requirements for a professional license.  To qualify for a\nlicense as a licensed acupuncturist an applicant shall fulfill the\nfollowing requirements.\n  (1) Application: file an application with the department;\n  (2) Education: provide evidence of satisfactory completion of a course\nof formal study or its substantial equivalent in accordance with the\ncommissioner's regulations;\n  (3) Experience: have experience in accordance with the commissioner's\nregulations;\n  (4) Examination: pass an examination satisfactory to the board and in\naccordance with the commissioner's regulations. Such examination shall\nbe given at least once within twelve months of the effective date of\nthis article, and at least once annually thereafter, and shall consist\nof both written and practical parts. Either part may be given at the\ndiscretion of the department in English and/or Chinese or other\nlanguage. Nothing in this subdivision is to be construed to require the\ndepartment to issue an exam in a language other than English. The\npractical part of the exam must be directly administered by an\nacupuncturist acceptable to the department, who may also be a member of\nthe board. The cost of the initial examination or reexamination shall be\nborne by the applicant in accordance with a schedule established by the\ndepartment and approved by the director of the budget;\n  (5) Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  (6) Character: be of good moral character as determined by the\ndepartment;\n  (7) Fees: pay a fee of five hundred dollars to the department for\ninitial licensure, and a fee of two hundred fifty dollars for each\ntriennial registration;\n  (8) Registration: if a license is granted, register triennially with\nthe department, including present home and business address and such\nother pertinent information as the department requires.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>