<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8351"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8351"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8351"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8351/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8351/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8351/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8351/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8351">
        <num>8351</num>
        <heading>Definition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8351. Definition. 1. As used in this article "athletic trainer"\nmeans any person who is duly licensed in accordance with this article to\nperform athletic training under the supervision of a physician and\nlimits his or her practice to secondary schools, institutions of\npostsecondary education, professional athletic organizations, amateur\nathletic organizations, non-profit athletic organizations, dance\norganizations, military academies and facilities of the United States,\nfire training programs or academies, and police training schools and\nacademies. An athletic trainer may also, under the supervision of a\nphysician in a health care organization or a physician's private\npractice, carry out comparable functions on orthopedic athletic\ninjuries.\n  2. Supervision of an athletic trainer by a physician shall be\ncontinuous but shall not be construed as requiring the physical presence\nof the supervising physician at the time and place where such services\nare performed, provided however, that such supervision shall include a\nsigned written agreement or protocol created collaboratively between the\nsupervising physician and licensed athletic trainer. The written\nagreement or protocol shall address and describe the nature and scope of\nathletic training services to be performed by such licensed athletic\ntrainer, in accordance with this title. Such written agreement or\nprotocol shall be reviewed at least once a year by the supervising\nphysician and athletic trainer and revised if necessary. No physician\nshall supervise more than four athletic trainers, except that such\nlimitation shall not apply for athletic trainers practicing in secondary\nschools, and institutions of postsecondary education, who are practicing\nunder the supervision of a physician who serves as the medical director\nfor such school or institution.\n  3. An athletic trainer shall make a written or oral referral to a\nphysician of any individual being treated for an orthopedic athletic\ninjury whose symptoms have not improved for a period of four days from\nthe day of onset. An individual treated for an orthopedic athletic\ninjury by an athletic trainer in a healthcare organization or a\nphysician's private practice shall receive a medical evaluation or\nreevaluation if treatment by the athletic trainer exceeds two weeks.\n  4. The scope of work described in this section shall not be construed\nas authorizing the management and treatment of acute, subacute, or\nchronic neurological pathologies and comorbidities or neurological\ndisease processes. Athletic trainers may, however, perform an initial\nevaluation and triage of emergent neurological conditions such as\npotential concussions, spinal cord injuries or nerve injuries that\nresult from engagement in athletic activity, and following the\nindividual's clearance by the supervising physician, the athletic\ntrainer may work with the individual pursuant to the signed written\nagreement or protocol to manage, monitor and treat concussions and\nperipheral nerve injuries in such settings as part of the rehabilitation\nto return to athletic activity subject to the limitations of subdivision\none of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>