<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8354"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8354"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8354"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8354/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8354/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8354">
        <num>8354</num>
        <heading>State committee for athletic trainers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8354. State committee for athletic trainers. A state committee for\nathletic trainers shall be appointed by the board of regents, upon the\nrecommendation of the commissioner and shall assist on matters of\nprofessional licensing and professional conduct in accordance with\nsection six thousand five hundred eight of this title. The committee\nshall consist of seven members, five of whom are athletic trainers\nlicensed in this state, one physician who is licensed in the state and\ncertified by a physician specialty certification organization acceptable\nto the department in the specialties of orthopedic surgery, primary\ncare, family practice, sports medicine, or neurology, and one public\nmember that is a consumer of the profession. The committee shall assist\nthe state board for medicine in athletic training matters. Nominations\nand terms of office of the members of the state committee for athletic\ntrainers shall conform to the corresponding provisions relating thereto\nfor state boards under article one hundred thirty of title eight of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>