<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8356"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8356"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8356"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8356/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8356/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8356/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8356/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8356">
        <num>8356</num>
        <heading>Exempt persons</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8356__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who is licensed or title-protected as an athletic\ntrainer, or as an athletic therapist credentialed by a foreign\ngovernment and in good standing in another state, territory, or country,\nand who has a written agreement to provide athletic training services to\nathletes and team personnel of a United States sports team recognized by\nthe United States Olympic and Paralympic Committees or an out-of-state\nsecondary school, an institution of postsecondary education, a\nprofessional or amateur athletic organization sports team, or a\nperforming arts troupe, may provide athletic training services to such\nathletes and team personnel at a discrete sanctioned team sporting event\nor performance at a secondary school, institution of postsecondary\neducation, professional athletic organization, amateur athletic\norganization, non-profit athletic organization, dance organization,\nmilitary academy or facility of the United States, fire training program\nor academy, or police training school or academy in this state, provided\nsuch services are provided only to such athletes and team personnel at\nsuch discrete sanctioned team sporting event or performance. Any such\nathletic training services shall be provided only five days before\nthrough three days after each such discrete sanctioned team sporting\nevent or traveling performance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8356__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person practicing as an athletic trainer in this state\npursuant to this subdivision shall be subject to the personal and\nsubject matter jurisdiction and disciplinary and regulatory authority of\nthe board of regents as if such person is a licensee and as if the\nexemption pursuant to this subdivision is a license. Such individual\nshall comply with applicable provisions of the rules of the board of\nregents, and the regulations of the commissioner, relating to\nprofessional misconduct, disciplinary proceedings and penalties for\nprofessional misconduct.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>