<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8506"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8506"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8506"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8506">
        <num>8506</num>
        <heading>Limited permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8506. Limited permits. Permits limited as to eligibility, practice\nand duration shall be issued by the department to eligible applicants as\nfollows:\n  1. Eligibility. A person who fulfills all requirements for\nregistration as a respiratory therapist except that relating to the\nexamination shall be eligible for a limited permit.\n  2. Limit of practice. All practice under a limited permit shall be\nunder the direct supervision of a licensed respiratory therapist\nphysician specializing in pulmonary medicine, an anesthesiologist or an\notherwise legally authorized physician.\n  3. Duration. A limited permit shall expire one year from the date of\nissuance or upon notice to the permittee by the department that the\napplication for licensure has been denied, or ten days after\nnotification to the permittee of failure on the professional licensing\nexamination, whichever first occurs; provided, however, that if the\npermittee is awaiting the results of a licensing examination at the time\nsuch limited permit expires, such permit shall continue to be valid\nuntil ten days after notification to the permittee of the result of such\nexamination.\n  4. Fees. The fee for each limited permit shall be seventy dollars.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>