<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8705"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8705"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8705"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8705">
        <num>8705</num>
        <heading>Requirements and procedures for professional licensure</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8705. Requirements and procedures for professional licensure. To\nqualify for a license as a professional medical physicist, an applicant\nshall fulfill the following requirements:\n  1. Application: file an application with the department;\n  2. Education: have received an education including a master's or\ndoctoral degree from an accredited college or university in accordance\nwith the commissioner's regulations. Such person shall have completed\nsuch courses of instruction as are deemed necessary by the commissioner\nto practice in the medical physics specialty in which the applicant has\napplied for a license;\n  3. Experience: have experience in his or her medical physics specialty\nsatisfactory to the board and in accordance with the commissioner's\nregulations;\n  4. Examination: pass an examination in his or her medical specialty\nsatisfactory to the board and in accordance with the commissioner's\nregulations. The examination requirement may be waived by the board on\nrecommendation of the commissioner for certain applicants with extensive\nexperience as a medical physicist;\n  5. Age: be at least twenty-one years of age;\n  6. Fee: pay a fee of three hundred dollars to the department for\nadmission to a department conducted examination for licensure, a fee of\none hundred fifty dollars for licensure with special competency in the\nfirst specialty and twenty-five dollars for each additional specialty,\nand a fee of three hundred dollars for each biennial registration\nperiod.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>