<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8856"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8856"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-12-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8856"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8856/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8856/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8856/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-8856/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8856">
        <num>8856</num>
        <heading>Exemptions and exempt persons</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 8856. Exemptions and exempt persons. This article shall not\nprohibit:\n  1. The performance of any tasks or responsibilities by any student\nengaged in clinical training in a general hospital licensed pursuant to\narticle twenty-eight of the public health law, provided such practice is\nlimited to clinical training that shall be carried out under the direct\nsupervision of a licensed physician who practices anatomic pathology; or\n  2. The performance of any tasks or responsibilities by any person\nlicensed under this title, provided such tasks or responsibilities are\npermitted by the article governing the profession pursuant to which such\nperson is licensed; or\n  3. The performance of any tasks or responsibilities by any legally\nqualified pathologists' assistants of any other state or territory who\nis serving in the armed forces or the public health service of the\nUnited States or who is employed by the veterans administration, while\nengaged in the performance of his or her duties; or\n  4. The performance of any tasks and responsibilities by any individual\nlegally carrying out the examinations and tests enumerated in\nsubdivision two of section five hundred seventy-nine of the public\nhealth law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>