<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-902-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-902-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="902-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-902-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-902-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-902-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-902-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_902_A">
        <num>902-A</num>
        <heading>Treatment of students diagnosed with diabetes by school personnel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 902-a. Treatment of students diagnosed with diabetes by school\npersonnel. 1. Licensed nurses, nurse practitioners, physician\nassistants, or physicians employed by school districts or boards of\ncooperative educational services are authorized to calculate prescribed\ninsulin dosages, administer prescribed insulin, program the prescribed\ninsulin pump, refill the reservoir in the insulin pump, change the\ninfusion site, inject prescribed glucagon, teach an unlicensed person to\nadminister glucagon to an individual, and perform other authorized\nservices pursuant to the scope of practice of the licensed individual\nunder title VIII of this chapter, to pupils who have received written\npermission by a physician or other licensed health care provider, and\nwritten parental consent to carry and use insulin and glucagon pursuant\nto section nine hundred sixteen-b of this article, during the school day\non school property and at any school function as such terms are defined,\nrespectively, by subdivisions one and two of section eleven of this\nchapter. Nothing in this section shall authorize unlicensed persons to\nperform these services except as otherwise permitted by section nine\nhundred twenty-one of this article.\n  2. A school district, board of cooperative educational services and/or\ntheir agents or employees shall incur no legal or financial liability as\na result of any harm or injury sustained by a pupil or other person\ncaused by reasonable and good faith compliance with this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>