<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-919"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-919"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="919"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_919">
        <num>919</num>
        <heading>On-site nebulizers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 919. On-site nebulizers. 1. The board of education or trustees of\nthe school district responsible for providing health services in a\nschool, or the board of cooperative educational services in the case of\nprograms under its jurisdiction, shall make a nebulizer available\non-site in every public and private school building in which full or\npart time nurse services are provided. Nebulizers in such school\nbuildings shall be made available to allow reasonable access to all\npublic and private school students with a patient specific order, who\nrequire inhaled medications administered by a nebulizer, provided,\nhowever, that nebulizers shall be administered by a school nurse or\nphysician pursuant to the student's patient specific order. Every\nnebulizer shall be maintained in working order by the school district or\nboard of cooperative educational services that provides school health\nservices to the school building where the nebulizer is located.\n  2. The commissioner shall be authorized to promulgate regulations for\nthe implementation of this section.\n  * NB Not effective pursuant to confirmation from DOB stating no\nfunding has been provided for nebulizers (see ch. 672/2007).\nConfirmation received 1/24/2012.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>