<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EDN">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-920"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-920"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="920"/>
          <FRBRname value="EDN"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-920/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-920/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-920/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/edn/section-920/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_920">
        <num>920</num>
        <heading>Public schools; infestation of bedbugs (Cimex lectularius)</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 920. Public schools; infestation of bedbugs (Cimex lectularius). 1.\nIn a city school district having a population of one million or more\ninhabitants, the principal of each public school shall provide immediate\nnotification to parents, persons in parental relation or guardians of\npotentially affected students attending the school, disclosing a finding\nrelating to the infestation of bedbugs (Cimex lectularius) in such\nschool; provided, however, that if pursuant to regulations of the\ncommissioner it is determined that any infestation is contained within a\ndiscrete area, the principal may limit such notification to parents,\npersons in parental relationship or guardians of all potentially\naffected students within such area, and shall advise the parents'\nassociation of the scope of such notification.\n  2. Along with the notification required pursuant to subdivision one of\nthis section, the principal of such public school shall also include\ninformation regarding proper procedures to prevent further infestations\nat the school and to prevent the transfer of bedbugs from the school to\nthe residences of students. Such information shall be developed by the\nboard of education in consultation with other city agencies and shall be\navailable in various languages as deemed necessary.\n  3. The principal shall ensure that the bedbug infestation at the\nschool is properly addressed in the most effective and safe manner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>