<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EPT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-1.9"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-1.9"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1.9"/>
          <FRBRname value="EPT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-1.9/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-1.9/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-1.9/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-1.9/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1_9">
        <num>11-1.9</num>
        <heading>Power of Fiduciary or Custodian to Deposit Securities in a</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_1_9__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any fiduciary (as\ndefined in section 1-2.7) holding securities in its fiduciary capacity,\nany bank, trust company or private banker holding securities as a\ncustodian or managing agent, and any bank, trust company or private\nbanker holding securities as custodian for a fiduciary pursuant to\nsection 11-1.1</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_1_9__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_1_9__subsec_b__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, is authorized to deposit or arrange through a\nsubcustodian or otherwise for the deposit of such securities in a\nclearing corporation (as defined in article eight of the Uniform\nCommercial Code). When such securities are so deposited, certificates\nrepresenting securities of the same class of the same issuer may be\nmerged and held in bulk in the name of the nominee of such clearing\ncorporation with any other such securities deposited in such clearing\ncorporation by any person regardless of the ownership of such\nsecurities, and certificates of small denomination may be merged into\none or more certificates of larger denomination. The records of such\nfiduciary and the records of such bank, trust company or private banker\nacting as custodian, as managing agent or as custodian for a fiduciary\nshall at all times show the name of the party for whose account the\nsecurities are so deposited. Ownership of, and other interests in, such\nsecurities may be transferred by bookkeeping en...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_1_9__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This section shall apply to any fiduciary holding securities in\nits fiduciary capacity, and to any bank, trust company or private banker\nholding securities as a custodian, managing agent or custodian for a\nfiduciary, acting on the effective date of this section or who\nthereafter may act regardless of the date of the agreement, instrument\nor court order by which it is appointed and regardless of whether or not\nsuch fiduciary, custodian, managing agent or custodian for a fiduciary\nowns capital stock of such clearing corporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>