<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EPT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-A-2.2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-A-2.2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-A-2.2"/>
          <FRBRname value="EPT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-A-2.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-A-2.2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-A-2.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-11-A-2.2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_A_2_2">
        <num>11-A-2.2</num>
        <heading>Distribution to residuary and remainder beneficiaries</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each beneficiary described in paragraph 11-A-2.1</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is entitled\nto receive a portion of the net income equal to the beneficiary's\nfractional interest in undistributed principal assets, using values as\nof the distribution date, provided, however, that any amount allowed as\na tax deduction to the estate for income payable to a charitable\norganization shall be paid, without diminution for taxes, to the\ncharitable organization entitled to receive such income. If a fiduciary\nmakes more than one distribution of assets to beneficiaries to whom this\nsection applies, each beneficiary, including one who does not receive\npart of the distribution, is entitled, as of each distribution date, to\nthe net income the fiduciary has received after the date of death or\nterminating event or earlier distribution date but has not distributed\nas of the current distribution date.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In determining a beneficiary's share of net income, the following\nrules apply:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The beneficiary is entitled to receive a portion of the net income\nequal to the beneficiary's fractional interest in the undistributed\nprincipal assets immediately before the distribution date, including\nassets that later may be sold to meet principal obligations.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The beneficiary's fractional interest in the undistributed\nprincipal assets must be calculated without regard to property\nspecifically given to a beneficiary and property required to pay\npecuniary amounts not in trust.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The beneficiary's fractional interest in the undistributed\nprincipal assets must be calculated on the basis of the aggregate value\nof those assets as of the distribution date without reducing the value\nby any unpaid principal obligation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The distribution date for purposes of this section may be the date\nas of which the fiduciary calculates the value of the assets if that\ndate is reasonably near the date on which assets are actually\ndistributed.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a fiduciary does not distribute all of the collected but\nundistributed net income to each person as of a distribution date, the\nfiduciary shall maintain appropriate records showing the interest of\neach beneficiary in that net income.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A fiduciary may apply the rules in this section, to the extent\nthat the fiduciary considers it appropriate, to net gain or loss\nrealized after the date of death or terminating event or earlier\ndistribution date from the disposition of a principal asset if this\nsection applies to the income from the asset.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The portion of a beneficiary determined under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is\nsubject to the fiduciary's further power of adjustment under\nsubparagraph 11-2.3</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_A_2_2__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, which adjustment if made shall be made to or\nfrom the principal of such beneficiary's share. The fiduciary shall\nmaintain appropriate records showing the principal interest of each\nbeneficiary, as adjusted.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>