<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EPT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-12-2.3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-12-2.3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-2.3"/>
          <FRBRname value="EPT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-12-2.3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-12-2.3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-12-2.3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-12-2.3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12_2_3">
        <num>12-2.3</num>
        <heading>Effect of application to surrogate to sell real property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 12-2.3 Effect of application to surrogate to sell real property\n  If, during the pendency of an action to enforce a liability created by\nthis article against a distributee or devisee of real property, a\nproceeding is pending or is subsequently commenced for the judicial\nsettlement of the account of the personal representative, the action\ninsofar as it affects any real property of the decedent shall be stayed\nuntil the accounting proceeding is concluded without an application for\nan order, under SCPA article 19, to dispose of real property of the\ndecedent for the payment of debts, funeral or administration expenses\nhaving been made or, if made, without such an order having been granted.\nIf such an order is granted, the action shall be dismissed as to the\nreal property ordered to be disposed of and the plaintiff remitted to\nthe enforcement of his rights against the proceeds of the real property\nheld by the personal representative.  Nothing contained herein precludes\na person from asserting any right he may have under this article with\nrespect to any other property of the decedent.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>