<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EPT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-5.1"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-5.1"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-5.1"/>
          <FRBRname value="EPT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-5.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-5.1/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-5.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-5.1/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_5_1">
        <num>3-5.1</num>
        <heading>Formal validity, intrinsic validity, effect, interpretation,</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this section:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Real property" means land or any estate in land, including\nleaseholds, fixtures and mortgages or other liens thereon.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Personal property" means any property other than real property,\nincluding tangible and intangible things.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Formal validity" relates to the formalities prescribed by the law\nof a jurisdiction for the execution and attestation of a will.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Intrinsic validity" relates to the rules of substantive law by\nwhich a jurisdiction determines the legality of a testamentary\ndisposition, including the general capacity of the testator.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Effect" relates to the legal consequences attributed under the\nlaw of a jurisdiction to a valid testamentary disposition.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Interpretation" relates to the procedure of applying the law of a\njurisdiction to determine the meaning of language employed by the\ntestator where his intention is not otherwise ascertainable.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Local law" means the law which the courts of a jurisdiction apply\nin adjudicating legal questions that have no relation to another\njurisdiction.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the other provisions of this section:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The formal validity, intrinsic validity, effect, interpretation,\nrevocation or alteration of a testamentary disposition of real property,\nand the manner in which such property descends when not disposed of by\nwill, are determined by the law of the jurisdiction in which the land is\nsituated.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The intrinsic validity, effect, revocation or alteration of a\ntestamentary disposition of personal property, and the manner in which\nsuch property devolves when not disposed of by will, are determined by\nthe law of the jurisdiction in which the decedent was domiciled at\ndeath.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A will disposing of personal property, wherever situated, or real\nproperty situated in this state, made within or without this state by a\ndomiciliary or non-domiciliary thereof, is formally valid and admissible\nto probate in this state, if it is in writing and signed by the\ntestator, and otherwise executed and attested in accordance with the\nlocal law of:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>This state;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The jurisdiction in which the will was executed, at the time of\nexecution; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The jurisdiction in which the testator was domiciled, either at\nthe time of execution or of death.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A testamentary disposition of personal property intrinsically\nvalid under the law of the jurisdiction in which the testator was\ndomiciled at the time the will was executed shall not be affected by a\nsubsequent change in the domicile of the testator to a jurisdiction by\nthe law of which the disposition is intrinsically invalid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Interpretation of a testamentary disposition of personal property\nshall be made in accordance with the local law of the jurisdiction in\nwhich the testator was domiciled at the time the will was executed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether a testamentary disposition of personal property is\neffectively revoked or altered by the provisions of a subsequent\ntestamentary instrument or by a physical act to or upon the will by\nwhich the testamentary disposition was made is determined by the law of\nthe jurisdiction in which the testator was domiciled at the time the\nsubsequent instrument was executed or the physical act performed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, the intrinsic validity,\neffect, revocation or alteration of a testamentary disposition by which\na power of appointment over personal property is exercised, and the\nquestion of whether such power has been exercised at all, are determined\nby:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_f__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of a presently exercisable general power of\nappointment, the law of the jurisdiction in which the donee of such\npower was domiciled at the time of death.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_f__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In the case of a general power of appointment exercisable by will\nalone or a special power of appointment:\n  (A) If such power was created by will, the law of the jurisdiction in\nwhich the donor of the power was domiciled at the time of death.\n  (B) If such power was created by inter vivos disposition, the law of\nthe jurisdiction which the donor of the power intended to govern such\ndisposition.\n  (C) If the donor is himself the donee of a general power of\nappointment exercisable by will alone, the law of the jurisdiction in\nwhich the donor of the power was domiciled at the time of death.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_f__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The formal validity of a will by which any power of appointment\nover personal property is exercised is determined in accordance with\nparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>on the basis that the testator referred to therein is the\ndonee of such power.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a testator, not domiciled in this state at the time of\ndeath, provides in his will that he elects to have the disposition of\nhis property situated in this state governed by the laws of this state,\nthe intrinsic validity, including the testator's general capacity,\neffect, interpretation, revocation or alteration of any such disposition\nis determined by the local law of this state. The formal validity of the\nwill, in such case, is determined in accordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the definition of "real property" in subparagraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>, whether an estate in, leasehold of, fixture, mortgage or other\nlien on land is real property governed by subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or\npersonal property governed by subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_3_5_1__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is determined by the\nlocal law of the jurisdiction in which the land is situated.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>