<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EPT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-6.5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-6.5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-6.5"/>
          <FRBRname value="EPT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-6.5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-6.5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-6.5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-3-6.5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_6_5">
        <num>3-6.5</num>
        <heading>Caution to the testator</heading>
        <content>
          <p>* ยง 3-6.5 Caution to the testator\n  An electronic will shall include a disclosure substantially similar to\nthe following in twelve-point font or larger, boldface, double-spaced\ntype:\n  CAUTION TO THE TESTATOR: YOUR WILL IS AN IMPORTANT DOCUMENT. AS\nTESTATOR, YOUR WILL SHOULD REFLECT YOUR FINAL WISHES. TO BE VALID, IT\nMUST BE SIGNED BY YOU OR ANOTHER INDIVIDUAL AUTHORIZED BY YOU AND WHO IS\nIN YOUR PHYSICAL PRESENCE AT THE TIME OF SIGNING. IT MUST ALSO BE SIGNED\nIN YOUR PHYSICAL OR ELECTRONIC PRESENCE BY AT LEAST TWO INDIVIDUALS,\nEACH OF WHOM IS A DOMICILIARY OF A STATE, AND EACH OF WHOM SIGNS THE\nWILL WITHIN A THIRTY DAY PERIOD AFTER WITNESSING YOU SIGN THE WILL OR\nACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU SIGNED IT.\n  WITHIN THIRTY DAYS AFTER THE ELECTRONIC WILL IS EXECUTED, IT MUST BE\nELECTRONICALLY FILED WITH THE NEW YORK STATE UNIFIED COURT SYSTEM.\n  YOU MAY REVOKE YOUR ELECTRONIC WILL AT ANY TIME. YOU MAY DO SO BY\nEXECUTING A SUBSEQUENT WILL OR SEPARATE WRITING CLEARLY INDICATING YOUR\nINTENT TO REVOKE ALL OR PART OF YOUR ELECTRONIC WILL, OR BY REQUESTING\nITS REMOVAL FROM THE NEW YORK STATE UNIFIED COURT SYSTEM. ONCE YOU HAVE\nREMOVED YOUR ELECTRONIC WILL FROM THE NEW YORK STATE UNIFIED COURT\nSYSTEM, IT IS REVOKED.\n  * NB Effective June 10, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>