<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="EPT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-7-1.9"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-7-1.9"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-1.9"/>
          <FRBRname value="EPT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-7-1.9/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-7-1.9/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-7-1.9/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/ept/section-7-1.9/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_1_9">
        <num>7-1.9</num>
        <heading>Revocation of trusts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_1_9__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the written consent, acknowledged or proved in the manner\nrequired by the laws of this state for the recording of a conveyance of\nreal property, of all the persons beneficially interested in a trust of\nproperty, heretofore or hereafter created, the creater of such trust may\nrevoke or amend the whole or any part thereof by an instrument in\nwriting acknowledged or proved in like manner, and thereupon the estate\nof the trustees ceases with respect to any part of such trust property,\nthe disposition of which has been revoked. If the conveyance or other\ninstrument creating a trust of property was recorded in the office of\nthe clerk or register of any county of this state, the instrument\nrevoking or amending such trust, together with the consents thereto,\nshall be recorded in the same office of every county in which the\nconveyance or other instrument creating such trust was recorded.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_1_9__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this section, a disposition, contained in a\ntrust created on or after September first, nineteen hundred fifty-one,\nin favor of a class of persons described only as the heirs, next of kin\nor distributees (or by any term of like import) of the creator of the\ntrust does not create a beneficial interest in such persons.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_1_9__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A testamentary or lifetime trust wholly benefitting one or more\ncharitable beneficiaries may be terminated as provided for by\nsubparagraph two of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_1_9__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 8-1.1 of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>