<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_C">
        <num>10-C</num>
        <heading>Consolidated local highway assistance payments</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>First, 41.40 percent of moneys so appropriated or authorized by\nthe legislature for distribution pursuant to this subdivision in any\nfiscal year shall be distributed to New York city and to the counties\noutside of New York city, fifty percent on the basis of their relative\nshares of motor vehicle registration and fifty percent on the basis of\nthe relative shares of center line highway mileage, except interstate\nand state highways, under the maintenance jurisdiction of the city of\nNew York and the several counties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Second, the balance of the moneys so appropriated or authorized by\nthe legislature for distribution pursuant to this subdivision in any\nfiscal year shall be distributed among four jurisdictional systems based\non relative vehicle miles of travel as follows:\n  JURISDICTIONAL                                             PERCENT OF\n  SYSTEM                                         VEHICLE MILES OF TRAVEL\n  Cities                                                        42.7\n  Counties                                                      18.5\n  Villages                                                      10.7\n  Towns                                                         28.1\n                                                               -----\n    Total                                                      100.0\n  Within each jurisdictional system, the distribution made to each\nmunicipality shall be based on the ratio of the number of lane miles\nunder the maintenance jurisdiction, except interstate and state\nhighways, of each municipality that is devoted to the movement of\ntraffic, excluding lanes devoted to the parking of vehicles, to the\ntotal number of such lane miles under the operational jurisdiction,\nexcept interstate and state highways, of all municipalities in the state\nwithin each jurisdictional system.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Third, the amounts distributed to each municipality in accordance\nwith paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall be adjusted so\nthat such amounts will not be less than the "funding level" as defined\nin subdivision five of this section for each such municipality. In order\nto achieve the objectives of this paragraph, to the extent necessary the\namounts in excess of the funding levels to be distributed to each\nmunicipality under paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof shall be reduced in\nequal proportion.\n  4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each fiscal year commencing on and after April first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-two and prior to April first, nineteen hundred\neighty-seven, amounts shall be distributed pursuant to an annual\nappropriation from the local assistance account of the general fund of\nthirty-four million dollars in accordance with the percentums\nestablished in subdivision five of section two hundred thirty-two of the\ntransportation law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each fiscal year set out in the schedule hereinbelow amounts\nshall be distributed pursuant to an annual appropriation from the local\nassistance account of the general fund in an amount set out in such\nschedule for the corresponding state fiscal year. Each fiscal year\ndistribution shall be made in accordance with the per centums\nestablished in subdivision five of section two hundred thirty-two of the\ntransportation law:\n    State Fiscal Year                                  Appropriation\n        1987-88                                         $65,000,000\n        1988-89                                         $70,000,000\n        1989-90                                         $75,000,000\n        1990-91                                         $80,000,000\n        1991-92                                         $85,000,000\n        1992-93                                         $87,000,000\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sub-allocations within each percentum shall be made in accordance\nwith the allocations established by the commissioner pursuant to chapter\nthree hundred sixty-nine of the laws of nineteen hundred seventy-nine.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amounts distributed pursuant to this subdivision shall be paid\nin four equal payments on or before the twenty-fifth day of April, June,\nSeptember and November.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Funds allocated for local street or highway projects under this\nsubdivision shall be used to undertake work on a project either with the\nmunicipality's own forces or by contract, provided however, that\nwhenever the estimate for the construction contract work exceeds one\nhundred thousand dollars but does not exceed three hundred fifty\nthousand dollars such work must be performed either with the\nmunicipality's own forces or by contract let by competitive bid in\naccordance with the provisions of section one hundred three of the\ngeneral municipal law and provided further, however, that whenever the\nestimate for the construction contract work exceeds three hundred fifty\nthousand dollars such work must be performed by contract let by\ncompetitive bid in accordance with the provisions of section one hundred\nthree of the general municipal law.\n  5. For amounts to be distributed pursuant to this section above the\nfunding level, as defined in this subdivision, received by any\nmunicipality, such municipality shall use at least seventy-five percent\nof such apportioned moneys for the construction, reconstruction or\nimprovement of local highways, bridges and/or highway-railroad\ncrossings, including right of way acquisition, preliminary engineering,\nand construction supervision and inspection, where the service life of\nthe project is at least ten years. Such moneys made available may be\nused to match other state and federal funds made available for such\nprojects under federal-aid highway acts. The remainder of the\napportionment, may be used for any highway purposes, except debt\nservice, including but not limited to, the acquisition of materials and\nequipment devoted to operation and maintenance of local highways,\nbridges and/or highway-railroad crossings and the payment of any costs\ndirectly attributable to operation and maintenance of local highways,\nbridges and/or highway-railroad crossings. At the discretion of the\ncommissioner, the requirement speci...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each fiscal year set out in the schedule hereinbelow\namounts shall be distributed pursuant to annual appropriation from the\nlocal assistance account of the general fund in an amount set out in\nsuch schedule for the corresponding state fiscal year:\n    State Fiscal Year                                  Appropriation\n        1993-94                                         $72,652,000\n        1994-95                                         $72,652,000\n        1995-96                                         $72,652,000\n        1996-97                                         $72,652,000\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For each fiscal year set out in the schedule hereinbelow amounts\nshall be distributed pursuant to annual appropriation from the dedicated\nhighway and bridge trust fund or by authorization by the legislature for\ncapital projects in an amount set out in such schedule for the\ncorresponding state fiscal year:\n    State Fiscal Year                                  Appropriation\n        1993-94                                         $170,000,000\n        1994-95                                         $175,000,000\n        1995-96                                         $180,000,000\n        1996-97                                         $185,000,000\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The moneys appropriated or authorized in each fiscal year pursuant\nto the schedules in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall be\ndistributed in accordance with the procedures contained in subdivisions\nthree and four of this section. The total of funds distributed in\naccordance with the procedures in subdivision three of this section\nshall equal one hundred forty-five million dollars in each fiscal year.\nThe balance of funds shall be distributed in accordance with the\nprocedures in subdivision four of this section. For purposes of\ncalculating distributions in accordance with subdivision three of this\nsection, the "funding level" shall be proportioned between amounts\ndistributed pursuant to paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>