<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-10-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_E">
        <num>10-E</num>
        <heading>Additional special powers of the commissioner of transportation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>description and\nlocation of each activity;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the projected dates of commencement and\ncompletion;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the estimated total cost, including the amount of\nfederal aid available therefor. Nothing in such agreement shall provide\nfor the transfer of any interests in buildings or personal property,\nincluding equipment, materials and facilities used or useful in\nconnection with activities authorized in this section.\n  3. In addition to the requirements of subdivision two of this section,\neach such dedicated highway and bridge trust fund agreement or\nagreements shall provide that:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any real property interest transfer\npursuant to subdivision eight of this section shall be maintained and\noperated under the supervision of the department of transportation\nwithout cost to the New York State thruway authority;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>simultaneously\nwith the conveyance of any real property interest by the department by\nquitclaim deed or otherwise pursuant to subdivision eight of this\nsection the New York state thruway authority shall issue a use permit or\nlease to the department of transportation for such real property\ninterest on a toll free basis; and,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_10_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no such activity shall require\ndedicated highway and bridge trust fund cooperative agreement payments\nfor a term in excess of thirty years and, at the expiration of such term\nas the commissioner and the authority may agree, pursuant to subdivision\neight of this section all rights and interest of the New York state\nthruway authority in each such activity shall without any additional\npayment by the state to such authority revert to and be vested in the\npeople of the state of New York. In no event shall any property\ntransferred to the thruway authority pursuant to this section be deemed\npart of the thruway for the purposes of any provision of the tax law.\n  4. The commissioner of transportation is hereby authorized to\nundertake any of the authorized activities pursuant to section\neighty-nine-b of the state finance law, in any case where the expense\nthereof is paid in whole or in part by the state, as financed by the New\nYork state thruway authority of disbursements made by the state; and,\nprovided that all such activities shall be performed in accordance with\nthe provisions of this chapter and other applicable laws.\n  5. The commissioner of transportation is hereby authorized and\nempowered to provide, in each dedicated highway and bridge trust fund\ncooperative agreement or agreements during the term or terms of each\nsuch agreement or agreements, against loss or damage to any project\ncaused by storm, flood, fire, explosion or other catastrophe, whether by\ninsurance or otherwise.\n  Each dedicated highway and bridge trust fund cooperative agreement or\nagreements pursuant to this section shall contain a clause that such\nagreement or agreements of the state thereunder are not a debt of the\nstate and that such agreement or agreements shall be deemed executory\nonly to the extent of the monies available to the state and no liability\non account thereof shall be incurred by the state beyond the monies\navailable for the purpose thereof.\n  6. The comp...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>