<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-115"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-115"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="115"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_115">
        <num>115</num>
        <heading>Preparation of map showing proposed county road system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 115. Preparation of map showing proposed county road system. The\ncounty superintendent of highways of each county shall prepare a map\nshowing a proposed county road system for such county to be constructed\nwith moneys from the county road fund, such system not to include a\nstate highway, except that a designated state highway not under state\nmaintenance may be included in such system and be improved by a county.\nThis map must be approved by the board of supervisors of such county\nbefore it becomes effective; and when so approved it shall be filed in\nthe office of the county clerk and county superintendent. An existing\nmap of a county road system, however, may be approved by the board of\nsupervisors and, when approved by such superintendent, such action shall\nbe deemed a compliance with this article, when the map is filed as above\nprovided.  Thereafter, except as otherwise provided by section one\nhundred fourteen of this chapter, no road shall be constructed,\nreconstructed or maintained with any such county road fund moneys except\nthe road set forth on such map, excepting, however, and notwithstanding\nany of the provisions of this article, any highway enumerated in section\nthree hundred forty-one of this chapter that has been constructed or\nimproved under section one hundred and ninety-four or one hundred and\nninety-five, or under the general or special law governing the\nconstruction or improvement of highways, that has been constructed or\nimproved as a state highway, may be maintained from such county road\nfund moneys.  Amendments to such map may from time to time be made by\nsuch county superintendent and if approved by such board of supervisors\nshall be filed in the office of the county clerk and county\nsuperintendent.  Construction in accordance with such map shall, subject\nto the provisions of this chapter, proceed in such manner that any money\nin the county road fund used in any one year shall be used so far as is\npracticable to build or finish complete road units or projects as shown\non such map within such year and not to construct parts of units or\nprojects divided from each other.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>