<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-116"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-116"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="116"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-116/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-116/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_116">
        <num>116</num>
        <heading>Statement and approval of proposed work</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 116. Statement and approval of proposed work. Before any county road\nfund moneys are spent or obligated in any one year under article six,\nexcept as otherwise provided in this section, the county superintendent\nof highways shall prepare a statement of the roads on such map proposed\nto be constructed or reconstructed during such year. This statement must\nbe approved by the board of supervisors of such county and shall show\nthe location of the proposed road, the total mileage thereof and the\nmileage of the portion to be constructed or reconstructed in such year,\nthe estimated cost of such construction or reconstruction, width,\nthickness and type.  Such statement shall be made in triplicate and\nafter final approval as hereinbefore specified one copy thereof shall be\nfiled in the office of the board of supervisors of the county, one in\nthe office of the county superintendent of highways and one in the\noffice of the county treasurer.  Upon recommendation of the county\nsuperintendent, the board of supervisors may authorize by resolution\nthat a specific amount of said county road fund moneys may be used by\nthe county superintendent for preliminary engineering and surveys to\nacquire necessary data for the preparation of said statement of the\nroads on such map proposed to be constructed or reconstructed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>