<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-12"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-12"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-12/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-12/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-12/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-12/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12">
        <num>12</num>
        <heading>Commissioner to provide for maintenance, repair, and for control of snow and ice; roads and driveways on state lands</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that\nit requests, with the approval of the commissioner, that the term of the\nagreement be extended for a specified term of up to five years or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it\nintends not to extend the agreement and such agreement shall expire at\nthe end of the term. If the municipality fails to notify the\ncommissioner as herein provided, it shall be deemed that the\nmunicipality intends not to extend the agreement. Such agreement may be\nterminated during the specified term provided the municipality shall\nnotify the commissioner eighteen months prior to such termination. If\nany such agreement expires, a new agreement between the commissioner and\na municipality may be entered into for a term of up to five years, with\nextended term or terms upon notification as above provided. Whenever the\ncommissioner shall deem the work of control of snow and ice by any\nmunicipality to be inadequate or unsatisfactory according to the terms\nof any such agreement, he or she may, by official order to be filed in\nthe department, and by filing a certified copy thereof in the office of\nthe department of state, cancel said agreement, and the payments\nthereunder provided by the state shall cease; whereupon the commissioner\nmay carry out the work of control of snow and ice. The official order\nprovided in this subdivision shall become effective at the expiration of\nfive days after the commissioner shall mail a certified copy thereof to\nthe clerk or other official who performs related duties in such\nmunicipality. The governing board or body of any such municipality is\nauthorized to appropriate such sum as it deems necessary to enable such\nmunicipality to perform the terms of such agreement. The work of such\ncontrol of snow and ice may be done by any of the methods provided in\nsubdivision one of this section for the work of maintenance and repair,\nor by a combination of such methods. Any county is hereby authorized to\nenter into a contract with another municipality located within the same\ncounty for the performance of the work of such control of snow and ice\nas a subcontractor under any agreement with the commissioner as such\nagreement ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided hereafter the state shall indemnify and\nhold harmless such municipalities for any and all liability for damages\nfor personal injury, injury to property or wrongful death for losses\narising from or occasioned by the manner of performance of the functions\nunder any agreement with a municipality for the control of snow and ice\npursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In no event shall the state be obligated to defend or indemnify\nsuch municipality, in any action, proceeding, claim or demand arising\nout of the actual operation of an insured vehicle or vehicle subject to\nself-insurance while engaged in the operation of snow and ice control\nfunctions under such agreement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The municipality shall be entitled to representation by the\nattorney general in any claim described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, provided, however, that the municipality shall be entitled\nto itself defend any such action, proceeding, claim or demand whenever\nthe attorney general determines, based upon his investigation and review\nof the facts and circumstances of the case that representation by the\nattorney general would be inappropriate, or whenever a court of\ncompetent jurisdiction determines that a conflict of interest exists and\nthat the municipality is entitled to be separately represented. Whenever\nthe municipality is entitled to defend the action itself, the state\nshall reimburse the municipality for any and all costs and expenses,\nincluding, but not limited to, counsel fees and disbursements.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The state shall indemnify and save harmless such municipality in\nthe amount of any judgment obtained against such municipality in any\nstate or federal court on any claim described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, or in the amount of any settlement of such claim, or shall\npay such judgment or settlement; provided, however, that the act or\nomission from which such judgment or settlement arose occurred while the\nmunicipality was acting within the scope of its functions for control of\nsnow and ice; provided, further, that no stipulation of settlement of\nany such action, proceeding, claim or demand shall be made or executed\nwithout approval of the attorney general and of the commissioner or his\ndesignee. Payment of any claim made pursuant to settlement shall not\nexceed the sum of fifty thousand dollars. Nothing herein shall authorize\nthe state to indemnify or save harmless with respect to punitive or\nexemplary damages.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The duty to defend or indemnify and save harmless prescribed by\nthis subdivision shall be conditioned upon</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>delivery to the attorney\ngeneral or an assistant attorney general at the office of the department\nof law located in Albany or New York city and by delivery to the\ncommissioner or his designee a copy of any claim, summons, complaint,\nprocess, notice, demand or other pleading within ten days after such\nmunicipality is served with such document and (ii) the full cooperation\nof the municipality in the defense of such action, proceeding, claim or\ndemand and in the defense of any action, proceeding, claim or demand\nagainst the state based upon the same act or omission, and in the\nprosecution of any appeal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The benefits of this subdivision shall inure only to such\nmunicipalities and shall not enlarge or diminish the rights of any other\nparty nor shall any provision of this subdivision be construed to\neffect, alter or repeal any provision of the workers' compensation law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This subdivision shall not in any way affect the obligation of any\nclaimant to give notice to the state under section ten of the court of\nclaims act or any other provision of law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this subdivision shall not be construed to\nimpair, alter, limit or modify the rights and obligations of any insurer\nunder any insurance agreement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise specifically provided in this subdivision, the\nprovisions of this subdivision shall not be construed in any way to\nimpair, alter, limit, modify, abrogate or restrict any immunity\navailable to or conferred upon any unit, entity, officer or employee of\nthe state or municipality or any other level of government, or any right\nto defense and indemnification provided for any governmental officer or\nemployee by, in accordance with, or by reason of, any other provision of\nstate or federal statutory or common law.\n  3. The commissioner shall have the power to purchase</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>materials for\nsuch maintenance and repair, except where such work is done by contract,\nand to contract for the delivery thereof at convenient intervals along\nsuch highways, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>equipment and appliances that he may deem\nnecessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Any municipality,\nacting by and through its authorized official, is hereby empowered to\nrent its machinery, tools, equipment, and storage space, to the state,\nacting by and through the commissioner, for the purpose of such control\nof snow and ice upon such terms and at such rate as may be agreed\nbetween the municipality and the commissioner. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of any general, special or local law or of any charter, the\ngoverning board or body of any such municipality is hereby authorized to\nsell such machinery, tools and equipment to the state, acting by and\nthrough the commissioner, for the purposes of this section and without\ncompetitive bidding or other limitation or restriction provided in any\ngeneral, special or local law or of any charter, and the commissioner,\nmay, upon approval by the state comptroller and the state commissioner\nof general services, purchase such machinery, tools and equipment from\nany such municipality as herein provided.\n  4. Whenever funds therefor are made available, the commissioner shall\nhave power to acquire for the state, by purchase, or by appropriation\nthrough the procedure described in section thirty of this chapter,\nproperty for the purpose of storing, maintaining or processing\nconstruction and maintenance supplies, material or equipment and for the\npurpose of providing, erecting and maintaining offices for department\npersonnel and structures for storing, maintaining or processing\nconstruction and maintenance materials or equipment.\n  5. Whenever a state highway has been constructed at a greater width\nthan that provided in the original plans, upon petition of a village, as\nprovided in sections forty-six and forty-seven of this chapter, or upon\npetition of a town or county, as provided in sections forty-eight,\nforty-nine, or fifty-nine of this chapter, or whenever such highway has\nbeen widened b...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state department having\njurisdiction or control over such lands, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the department of audit\nand control. Thereupon any such road and driveway shall be maintained\nand repaired under the direct supervision and control of the\ncommissioner in the same manner as is provided in this section for the\nmaintenance and repair of improved state highways in towns and in\nincorporated villages.\n  7. Whenever the head of any state department, agency, institution or\npublic benefit corporation having jurisdiction or control over the lands\nowned and occupied by the state or such department, agency, institution\nor public benefit corporation requests the commissioner to construct,\nreconstruct, and/or maintain any loop or peripheral roadway which is or\nis to be located on, around, over, or across such lands, notwithstanding\nthe provisions of any general, special or local law, the commissioner is\nauthorized to grant such request and undertake such construction,\nreconstruction and/or maintenance. Before undertaking the work of\nconstruction, reconstruction and/or maintenance of such roadways, the\ncommissioner and the head of the state department, agency, institution\nor public benefit corporation shall enter into a written agreement,\nsubject to the approval of the director of the budget, providing the\nfunds therefor, or reimbursement by such state department, agency,\ninstitution or public benefit corporation of the funds therefor,\nincluding all costs incurred by the department in connection with such\nconstruction, reconstruction and/or maintenance. Where such loop or\nperipheral roadway is to be constructed, reconstructed and/or maintained\non lands occupied by either the state university of New York or the\nstate university construction fund, both the state university of New\nYork and the state university construction fund shall be parties to such\nagreement. Such roadway shall be constructed, or reconstructed, to\nmutually agreeable standards, in the same manner as state highways are\nconstructed or reconstructed pursuant to this chap...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>