<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-125"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-125"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="125"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_125">
        <num>125</num>
        <heading>Land may be sold or leased; disposition of proceeds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 125. Land may be sold or leased; disposition of proceeds. Any lands\nacquired by purchase or condemnation, for the purpose of obtaining\ngravel, stone or other materials, for the construction or maintenance of\nhighways improved or constructed as provided in this article, or\nrequired for spoil banks, may be sold in accordance with the eminent\ndomain procedure law or leased by the governing body of any county, when\nno longer needed for any of such purposes. The proceeds thereof shall be\npaid into and become a part of the county road fund. The governing body\nmay, where it has acquired land by purchase or condemnation as a\nright-of-way for a county road, sell, convey, grant or lease to the\nowner or owners of property adjoining the same, so much thereof as may\nbe unnecessary for such highway purposes, provided the strip of land\nretained for such highway purposes is not less than sixty feet in width,\nand provided such sale, conveyance, grant or lease will give said\nadjoining owner or owners of land a frontage immediately in front of\ntheir respective premises upon the new highway and right-of-way when\ncompleted. The governing body may make such sale, conveyance, grant or\nlease to such owner or owners of real property for the purpose of\ncompensating such owner or owners for damages sustained by reason of the\nchange of the location of such highway and in full settlement thereof.\n  In the county of Wayne, however, if any such owner or owners of\nproperty adjoining lands heretofore acquired by said county from the R.\n&amp; S. Liquidating Corporation and being formerly lands of the Rochester &amp;\nSyracuse Trolley Company, for purposes of a right-of-way for a state\nhighway, do not purchase such lands or any part thereof as may be\nunnecessary for highway purposes as provided by this section, within\nsixty days from the receipt by such owner or owners of the offer of the\ngoverning body of such county to sell such lands or any part thereof,\nthen such board may sell and convey such lands or any part thereof, on\nthe same terms and conditions as those of such offer or offers, to any\nother person or persons, and the proceeds thereof shall be used in the\nmanner provided by this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>