<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_E">
        <num>131-E</num>
        <heading>Bridges over county lines</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131-e. Bridges over county lines. The board shall provide for the\ncare, maintenance, preservation and repair of any draw or other bridge\nintersecting the boundary line of counties or towns, which bridge is by\nlaw a joint charge on such counties or towns, or on the towns in which\nit is situated; and to severally apportion, as it may deem equitable,\nthe expenses thereof on the towns respectively liable therefor, or on\nthe respective counties when liable; but when such bridge shall span any\nportion of the navigable tide-waters of this state, forming, at the\npoint of crossing, the boundary line between two counties, such expense\nshall be a joint and equal charge upon the two counties in which the\nbridge is situated, and the board of supervisors in each of such\ncounties shall apportion such expense among the several towns and cities\nin their respective counties, or upon any or either of such towns and\ncities, as in their judgment may seem proper; and if there be in either\nof said counties, a city, the boundaries of which are the same as the\nboundaries of the county, then it shall be the duty of the common\ncouncil of such city, to perform the duty hereby imposed upon the boards\nof supervisors; but no town or city not immediately adjacent to such\nwaters at the points spanned by said bridge shall be liable for a larger\nproportion of such expense than the taxable property of such town or\ncity bears to the whole amount of taxable property of such county. The\nboard of supervisors of such counties or, in any city embracing the\nentire county and having no board of supervisors, the common council,\nshall have full control of such bridges. No such bridge shall be\nconstructed unless the board of supervisors in each of such counties,\nand the common council of the city whose boundaries are the same as the\nboundary of the other county adjacent to such waters, shall first by\nresolution determine that such bridge is necessary for public\nconvenience. Whenever any bridge now spanning any such navigable\ntide-waters or hereafter erected across any such navigable tide-waters,\nshall be condemned by the United States authorities as an obstruction to\nnavigation, and shall be ordered removed, the county and city\nauthorities having charge of such bridge, if they shall determine that\nsuch bridge shall be rebuilt, shall, as soon as practicable after such\ndetermination, cause plans to be prepared for the erection of the new\nbridge and the removal of any bridge so condemned as aforesaid, and\nwithin a reasonable time after the approval of any such plans by the\nUnited States authorities, the proper officers shall proceed with the\nconstruction of said new bridge.  In case of any unreasonable delay on\nthe part of the officer or officers charged with the duty of\nconstruction of such new bridge, such duty may be enforced by mandamus\nupon the application of any citizen interested in its performance.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>