<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_B">
        <num>131-B</num>
        <heading>County highways and bridges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131-b. County highways and bridges. 1. A board of supervisors may,\nwhen satisfied that it is for the interest of the county, lay out,\nconstruct, open, alter or discontinue a county highway therein, or cause\nthe same to be done, and construct, repair or abandon a county bridge\ntherein, or cause the same to be done when the board shall deem that the\ninterest of the county will be promoted thereby. All expenses so\nincurred shall be a county charge, and may be financed pursuant to the\nlocal finance law.\n  2. Whenever the board of supervisors of a county shall determine to\nconstruct a bridge in accordance with the foregoing provisions of this\nsection, such board, on behalf of the county, and the town board of a\ntown or in case of a city the board of aldermen or any similar board\nexercising the functions of aldermen, on behalf of such town or city,\nmay enter into an agreement with the county, to the effect that such\ntown or city will operate and maintain such bridge, in case the bridge\nis located wholly in a town or city. In case the bridge is constructed\nover a stream forming the boundary line between two towns or two cities\nor between a town and city, then they may agree with the county to\noperate and maintain such bridge jointly, in proportion to the assessed\nvaluation of such town or city. The sum which the town or towns, city or\ncities are obliged to pay under such an agreement is a charge upon such\ntowns or cities and shall be paid as other town or city charges are\npaid.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>