<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-11-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="131-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-131-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_131_G">
        <num>131-G</num>
        <heading>Regulation of toll rates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 131-g. Regulation of toll rates. 1. Such boards shall have power by\na vote of two-thirds of all the members elected to authorize an\nalteration, reduction or change of the rates of toll charged or received\nby any turnpike, plank or gravel road, or other toll road within such\ncounty, or by any bridge company or ferry within such county, or, if\nwithin more than one county, then by joint action with the supervisors\nof such counties, provided such alteration shall be asked for by the\ndirectors, trustees or owners of such road, bridge or ferry; but that no\nincrease of toll shall be so authorized unless notice of such proposed\nincrease shall have been published once each week for three successive\nweeks in a newspaper having general circulation in each town in which\nsuch road or bridge is located or in which such ferry is operated,\ncommencing at least thirty days prior to the date of such authorization;\nand any alteration in rates of toll authorized by any board of\nsupervisors may be changed or modified by any subsequent board, on their\nown motion, by a like vote of two-thirds of all the members elected to\nsuch board; but nothing in this section contained shall affect or\nabridge the powers of any city.\n  2. In the case of rates of toll for a ferry, such boards shall be\nauthorized to adopt a local law to provide that a ferry shall carry\nwithout charge or fee of any kind for transportation between points\nwholly within the state of New York any member of the United States\narmed forces in uniform during their term of enlistment in the service\nof the United States. Provided, however, that the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall not apply to a ferry owned or operated by a\nmunicipality that is subject to the provisions of section one hundred\nfour of the transportation law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>