<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-133"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-133"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="133"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-133/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-133/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_133">
        <num>133</num>
        <heading>Machinery, tools, equipment, implements, materials and supplies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such amounts as the board of\nsupervisors by resolution may, from time to time, appropriate thereto\nfrom the general fund,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all rentals received from any source for the\nuse of county owned machinery, equipment, tools and implements,\nincluding amounts payable pursuant to section one hundred seventeen of\nthis chapter,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all amounts payable thereto under the provisions of\nsubdivision three of this section, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all other moneys received for\nsuch fund from any other source pursuant to law.\n  2. The board of supervisors may, at any regular or special meeting,\nappropriate available moneys in such fund for</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the purchase and\nrepair of machinery, tools, implements and equipment to be used for\nhighway, snow removal or bridge purposes,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the operation of such\nmachinery, tools, implements and equipment and supplies therefor,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe operation of necessary shops or garages under the jurisdiction of\nthe county superintendent,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the acquisition, construction,\nreconstruction or repair of buildings, under the direction and\nsupervision of the county superintendent, for the housing or repair of\nsuch machinery, tools, implements and equipment, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_133__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the purchase of\nmaterials and supplies adequate to provide a central stock-pile, on an\nannual basis for highway, snow removal and bridge purposes. Should such\nfund at any time become larger than necessary for the annual\nrequirements, any excess amount may, upon recommendation of the county\nsuperintendent, be transferred to the general fund by resolution of the\nboard of supervisors.\n  3. Whenever materials and supplies from a central stock-pile,\nestablished pursuant to subdivision two of this section, are used for\nany highway, snow removal or bridge purpose, the cost of such materials\nand supplies shall be considered as an expense of such purpose. On or\nbefore the tenth day of each month, the county superintendent shall\nprepare itemized vouchers, properly certified by him, covering the cost\nof such materials and supplies used during the preceding month and\nsubmit the same for audit. Payments therefor shall be made to the county\nroad machinery fund from appropriations provided for the purposes for\nwhich the materials and supplies were used.\n  4. The county superintendent shall make all purchases chargeable to\nthe county road machinery fund. The superintendent may, with the\napproval of the board of supervisors or of a duly authorized committee\nthereof, sell any machinery, equipment, tools and implements used for\nhighway, snow removal or bridge purposes no longer needed by the county,\nor which shall have become worn out or obsolete, or may exchange the\nsame or surrender it to the vendor as part payment for new machinery,\nequipment, tools and implements. If sold, the proceeds shall be credited\nto the receipts of such funds and become a part thereof. Any purchase of\nnew machinery, of a value in excess of ten thousand dollars, in order to\nbecome effective, shall have the approval of the board of supervisors,\nor a committee of the board duly authorized and designated by the board\nfor such purpose.\n  5. No claim chargeable to the county road mac...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>