<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-135-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-135-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="135-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-135-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-135-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-135-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-135-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_135_A">
        <num>135-A</num>
        <heading>Control of snow and ice conditions on county roads</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_135_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By such city, town or village renting its highway tools or\nequipment to the county for such purposes at such terms as may be agreed\nupon;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_135_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By removal of snow from county roads by a city, town or village;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_135_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By sanding and otherwise treating of county roads for the purpose\nof removing the danger of ice and snow by a city, town or village;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_135_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By removal of snow and sanding and control of ice and snow on\ncounty roads by a city, town or village;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_135_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By any combination of a, b, c and d.\n  A county may in like manner contract with a city, town or village for\nthe erection of county owned snow fence along a county road upon such\nterms and conditions as may be agreed upon. The erection of snow fence\nshall not be deemed to be a part of the contract entered into as\ndescribed in b, c, d or e above, unless expressly so provided in\nwriting.\n  Such contract or contracts shall be in writing for not longer than a\nperiod of ten years. Money received by a town pursuant to the provisions\nof this section shall be credited to the respective funds which were\ncharged with the objects of expense. Money so received by a city or\nvillage shall be placed in the city or village general fund,\nrespectively, and may be used for any lawful city or village highway\npurpose.\n  Any county shall annually appropriate and expend such sum as it deems\nproper for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>