<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="142-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142_C">
        <num>142-C</num>
        <heading>Removal of snow and ice from streets and repair of sidewalks in villages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 142-c. Removal of snow and ice from streets and repair of sidewalks\nin villages. The town board may authorize the town superintendent to (1)\nremove snow and ice from streets and sidewalks in any village or portion\nthereof within the town.\n  (2) Repair streets and sidewalks within any village or portion thereof\nwithin the town.\n  (3) Permit the use of town highway machinery, snow and ice removal\nequipment, tools and equipment in or by any village located wholly or\npartly within the town.\n  (4) The work authorized by this section shall be performed upon such\nterms and conditions as may be agreed upon by the town board of the town\nand board of trustees of the village.\n  (5) Moneys received by a town pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection shall be first applied to the credit of the fund authorized by\nsubdivision four of section one hundred forty-one of this chapter to the\nextent that any expense incurred was originally charged thereto, and the\nbalance of such moneys, if any, shall be credited to the fund authorized\nby subdivision three of section one hundred forty-one of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>