<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="142-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-142-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142_B">
        <num>142-B</num>
        <heading>Removal of snow and ice, making of repairs, and rental of town highway machinery; school and other districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 142-b. Removal of snow and ice, making of repairs, and rental of\ntown highway machinery; school and other districts. The town board of\nany town may authorize the town superintendent to (1) remove snow and\nice from any property within the town belonging to a school district,\nupon such terms as may be agreed upon by the town board and governing\nboard of any such school district.\n  (2) Repair roads and sidewalks within the town belonging to a school\ndistrict, upon such terms as may be agreed upon by the town board and\nthe governing board of any such school district.\n  (3) Permit the use of town highway machinery, tools and equipment\nwithin the town by any fire district, special improvement district or\nschool district, located in whole or in part in any such town, upon such\nterms and conditions as may be agreed upon by the town board and the\ngoverning board or governing body of any such district.\n  (4) Except as otherwise provided in section one hundred forty-two-c of\nthis chapter with respect to the use of town highway machinery, snow and\nice removal equipment, tools and equipment by a village located wholly\nor partly within the town, permit the use of town highway machinery,\nsnow and ice removal equipment, tools and equipment during an emergency\nby any city, village, town, county, fire district, special improvement\ndistrict or school district, upon such terms and conditions as may be\nagreed upon by the town board and the governing board or governing body\nof any such district.\n  (5) Moneys received by a town pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection shall be first applied to the credit of the fund authorized by\nsubdivision four of section one hundred forty-one of this chapter to the\nextent that any expense incurred was originally charged thereto, and the\nbalance of such moneys, if any, shall be credited to the fund authorized\nby subdivision three of section one hundred forty-one of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>