<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-147"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-147"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="147"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-147/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-147/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-147/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-147/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_147">
        <num>147</num>
        <heading>Entry upon lands by town superintendent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 147. Entry upon lands by town superintendent. The town\nsuperintendent may, when directed by the county superintendent, and when\nauthorized by the town board, enter\n  1. Upon any lands adjacent to any of the highways in the town, for the\npurpose of opening an existing ditch or drain, or for digging a new\nditch or drain for the free passage of water for the drainage of such\nhighways.\n  2. Upon the lands of any person adjoining rivers, streams or creeks,\nto drive spiles, throw up embankments and perform such other labor as\nmay be necessary to keep such rivers, streams or creeks within their\nproper channels, and to prevent their encroachment upon highways or\nabutments of bridges.\n  3. Upon the lands adjoining a highway which, during the spring\nfreshets or at a time of high water are subject to overflow from such\nrivers, streams or creeks, to remove or change the position of a fence\nor other obstruction preventing the free flow of water under or through\na highway, bridge or culvert, whenever the same may be necessary for the\nprotection of such highway or bridge.\n  4. Upon any lands adjacent to highways to remove any fence or other\nobstruction which causes snow to drift in and upon such highways, and\nerect snow fences or other devices upon such lands to prevent the\ndrifting of snow in or upon such highways.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>