<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-196"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-196"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="196"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-196/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-196/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-196/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-196/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_196">
        <num>196</num>
        <heading>County aid for connecting highway through villages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 196. County aid for connecting highway through villages. The board\nof supervisors of a county may, upon the petition of the board of\ntrustees of an incorporated village, provide for the construction or\nimprovement of a highway or section thereof, through such village, at\nthe joint expense of the county and village. The board of supervisors\nshall determine the portion of the cost of the construction and\nimprovement of such highway to be borne by the county and the portion to\nbe borne by the village. The portion, if any, to be borne by the village\nshall be a village charge and the residue shall be a county charge. The\namount to be borne by the county shall be provided by tax, to be levied\nupon the taxable property of the county and collected in the same manner\nas other county charges and shall be paid into the county treasury and\nsuch tax shall not be reported as a basis for state aid as provided by\narticle six of this chapter or the county may finance all or part of its\nshare pursuant to the local finance law. The board of supervisors may,\nin its discretion, appropriate and make immediately available from\ncounty funds, the portion of the moneys to be borne by the county.\n  The board of supervisors may designate the highway to be improved\nunder the provisions of this section and in such case, the cost shall be\nborne by the county. No such highway shall be so constructed and\nimproved through a village, except to connect a highway improved\npursuant to the provisions of sections one hundred and ninety-four, one\nhundred and ninety-five, or article six of this chapter with a state\nhighway, or a county road, or to connect with another town highway\nimproved pursuant to the provisions of sections one hundred and\nninety-four, one hundred and ninety-five, or article six of this\nchapter, or to connect a city street with a highway improved by the\ncounty or state. Such construction shall not be commenced until the\nportion, if any, to be borne by the village, as determined by the board\nof supervisors, has been deposited in the county treasurer's office of\nsuch county. The construction or improvement of a highway, as herein\nprovided, shall be done under the supervision and direction of the\ncounty superintendent of highways or of a committee known as the highway\nofficials of the county, to consist of the county superintendent, three\nmembers of the board to be appointed by the chairman, and the supervisor\nof the town in which road is being improved. Payments therefor shall be\nmade from time to time by the county treasurer upon the certificate of\nthe county superintendent, approved by the chairman of the board of\nsupervisors.\n  A highway within a village constructed or improved as herein provided,\nshall be of the same width and type of construction as such town\nhighways so improved by the aid of the county outside the village,\nunless a greater width or different type of construction is desired by\nthe village. The additional expense caused by the increased width or\ndifferent type or both, shall be borne wholly by the village. Any such\nhighway, when completed, shall thereafter be repaired and maintained by\nthe village wherein such highway is located in the same manner as all\nother village highways. The board of supervisors may determine that such\nhighways be thereafter repaired and maintained under the supervision and\ndirection of the county superintendent of highways and thereafter the\namount, if any, to be borne by the village shall be paid by the village\ninto the county treasury and the whole of such money including the share\nof the county and of the village, if any, shall be paid out by the\ncounty treasurer for the repair and maintenance of such highways on\norders signed by the county superintendent of highways and countersigned\nby the chairman of the board of supervisors.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>