<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-205-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-205-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-04-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="205-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-205-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-205-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-205-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-205-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_205_C">
        <num>205-C</num>
        <heading>Minimum maintenance roads</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_205_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the volume and type of motor vehicle traffic on such road;\n  (ii) a determination that the property owners of land abutting the\nroad shall continue to have access to their property;\n  (iii) a determination that the users of the road traveling at a\nreasonable and prudent speed, under the circumstances, shall not be\nplaced in a hazardous situation;\n  (iv) a determination that such road, or portion thereof, does not\nconstitute a farm access road as defined in this section; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_205_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the effect of such designation on any farm operations dependent\nupon the road, and that such designation does not restrict farm\noperations in agricultural districts.\n  A copy of the town board's findings shall be made available for public\ninspection in the town clerk's office and posted to the town website if\navailable.\n  A copy of the findings shall be sent to the school board of the school\ndistrict in which each road is located and to the town planning board.\nSuch school board and planning board may review the findings of the town\nboard and within forty-five days file with the town clerk their\nrecommendation and findings. In the event the school or planning board\ntakes no action within the forty-five day review period the town board\nmay proceed without said board's recommendation and findings. School or\nplanning board review may be waived, shortened or extended upon mutual\nconsent of said board and the town board. The town board of the town\nmay, by resolution, accept, accept in part, or reject the\nrecommendations of either the school or planning board prior to any vote\nupon the proposed local law.\n  A copy of the findings shall also be sent to the department of\nenvironmental conservation or any other relevant state agency that has\njurisdiction over the land that the road proposed to be designated as\nminimum maintenance passes over or provides access to.\n  c. At least thirty days prior to the public hearing on such local law,\nwritten notice of such hearing, including a summary of the findings,\nshall be served by certified mail upon every owner of real property, as\ndetermined by the latest completed assessment roll, abutting such road\nor portion thereof.\n  d. The town clerk shall give notice of such hearing by the publication\nof a notice in at least one newspaper of general circulation in the\ntown, and post such notice on the town website if available, specifying\nthe time when and the place where such hearing will be held, and in\ngener...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>