<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-211-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-211-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="211-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-211-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-211-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-211-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-211-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_211_B">
        <num>211-B</num>
        <heading>Abandonment of certain town highways in school districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 211-b. Abandonment of certain town highways in school districts.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, and upon the\nrequest of either the county superintendent of highways or the town\nsuperintendent of highways, any town board may, by resolution duly\nadopted, declare any town highway or portion thereof in the town running\nthrough school district lands not necessary for ingress to or egress\nfrom any privately or publicly owned lands, and not necessary to connect\nexisting town, county or state highways, to be abandoned and\ndiscontinued for public purposes. Such town shall at least thirty days\nprior to such abandonment cause to be filed and recorded in the office\nof the town clerk a written description of such highway or portion to be\nabandoned with a written statement attached thereto that such highway or\nportion thereof so described is proposed to be abandoned, and shall\ncause notices to be posted in at least three conspicuous places in such\ntown of the time and place when such declaration of abandonment will be\nmade, for the purpose of permitting any interested person to appear for\nor against the adoption of such resolution.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>