<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220">
        <num>220</num>
        <heading>Improvement of town highways; submission of plan</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>With the board of supervisors, or other legislative body, of the\ncounty in which such town is located, together with the written\nrecommendations of the county superintendent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>With the commissioner, together with a copy of the resolution of\napproval of such county board of supervisors or legislative body.\n  2. The commissioner, after investigation, may approve such plan or the\nplan of any separate project thereof for execution as appropriations\ntherefor may be available or may disapprove any such plan and shall\nimmediately notify the town board of such approval or disapproval. If\nany such plan be disapproved, the commissioner shall immediately return\nsuch plan to the town board with his reasons for disapproval and\nsuggestion for modification of the plan and shall notify the board of\nsupervisors and county superintendent of such action.  Modification of a\ndisapproved plan shall be made and filed in like manner.\n  3. A copy of such plan, when prepared and approved as herein provided,\ntogether with copies of the approval of the commissioner and the board\nof supervisors, shall be filed in the office of the clerk of the town in\nwhich such highway is located, in the office of the county clerk and\ncounty superintendent of the county in which such town is located. The\ncopy transmitted to the commissioner shall be retained by him.\n  4. The statement of necessity required as a part of the plan for a\nproject shall set forth the reasons why such improvement, repair or\nreconstruction is necessary adequately to serve permanent agricultural,\nresidential, commercial or industrial development and to sustain the\nvehicular load imposed or likely to be imposed on such town highway.\n  5. Modification of any plan approved as herein provided may be made by\nthe town board of the town affected thereby and must be filed and\napproved in the manner hereinbefore provided for the filing and approval\nof an original plan, except that the approval of the county board of\nsupervisors, or other legislative body, of the county in which such town\nis located shall not be required. The commissioner may refuse to approve\nthe modification of the plan o...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>