<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-228"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-228"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="228"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-228/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-228/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-228/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-228/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_228">
        <num>228</num>
        <heading>Payment of state aid</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 228. Payment of state aid. 1. The county superintendent shall notify\nthe commissioner when work has been commenced on an approved project. As\nwork progresses on a project according to approved plans and\nspecifications, a town may request the state aid in relation thereto to\nbe paid in installments or it may request such aid to be paid after a\nproject has been completed.\n  2. Claims for such aid shall be made on forms prepared and furnished\nby the commissioner. They shall be executed in the name of the town by\nthe town superintendent or, where such work is done pursuant to a\ncontract with the county or with an independent contractor, the town\nboard may authorize the town supervisor to execute such claims instead\nof the town superintendent. Such claims, when approved by the county\nsuperintendent, shall be filed with the commissioner.  The commissioner\nshall examine such claims and shall certify to the state comptroller\nwithin thirty days of the receipt of such claims the amounts which the\nstate should pay thereon to the supervisor of the town. If any such\nclaim or any portion thereof be disapproved, the commissioner shall\nimmediately notify the town board, the board of supervisors and county\nsuperintendent of such action. Any such claim must be filed with the\ncommissioner in the year for which the project was approved or not later\nthan the thirty-first day of January in the calendar year succeeding\nthat for which the project was approved except where work has been\ndeferred with the approval of the commissioner for completion during the\nfollowing construction season. The commissioner shall not otherwise\ncertify payment of the final installment of state aid for any project\nunless the work thereon has been completed according to approved plans\nbut all other installments may be paid with the final installment\nallocated to stabilization and surfacing materials deferred until so\ncompleted.\n  3. In the final adjustment of any claim, if it is determined that a\ntown has been paid an amount in excess of that permitted under this\narticle, the state comptroller shall withhold an equivalent amount from\nany state aid payable to the town pursuant to sections two hundred\nseventy-nine and two hundred eighty of the highway law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>