<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-229-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-229-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="229-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-229-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-229-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-229-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-229-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_229_A">
        <num>229-A</num>
        <heading>Federal aid</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 229-a. Federal aid. 1. If the federal government, through any\nfederal law, makes an allotment of moneys or otherwise provides\nfinancial aid and assistance for approved projects, the commissioner is\nhereby authorized to accept such federal moneys, aid and assistance, to\nsign all necessary agreements therefor, and to do and perform all\nnecessary acts in connection therewith. The commissioner shall not enter\ninto any agreement or agreements which will require a total state\ncontribution in excess of the amounts available for the state's share of\nthe cost of such projects.\n  2. The execution by the state of any such agreement or agreements\nshall not operate or be construed to relieve the state or any town from\nits or their obligations under the provisions of this article, except as\nhereinafter provided in this section.\n  3. The department of taxation and finance may accept and receive as\ncustodian any and all grants and money awarded for assistance for\napproved projects in this state under or pursuant to any such federal\nlaw. All moneys so received shall be deposited by the department of\ntaxation and finance in a special fund or funds and shall be used\nexclusively for the purposes of any such federal law. Such moneys shall\nbe paid from such fund or funds on audit of the state comptroller upon\nvouchers certified or approved by the commissioner for carrying out the\npurposes of such federal law.\n  4. Federal aid in relation to any approved project shall be allocated\nto reduce the amount of state aid for the project and the town's share\nof the cost of the project in the same proportion as each is required to\ncontribute to or pay for the portion of the cost of the project in\nrelation to which state aid may be paid under section two hundred\ntwenty-seven of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>