<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-230"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-230"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="230"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-230/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-230/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-230/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-230/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_230">
        <num>230</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 230. Definitions. As used in this article the following terms shall\nhave the following meanings:\n  1. "Bridge" means a structure including supports erected over a\ndepression or an obstruction such as water, highway, or railway, having\na track or passageway for carrying traffic or other moving loads and\nhaving an opening measured along the center of the track or roadway of\nmore than twenty feet between under croppings of abutments or spring\nlines or arches, or extreme ends of openings for multiple boxes and may\ninclude multiple pipes where the clear distance between openings is less\nthan half of the smaller contiguous opening. The term bridge, as defined\nin this section, shall also include the approaches.\n  2. "Culvert" means a structure whether of single or multiple span\nconstruction within an interior width of twenty feet or less when\nmeasurement is made horizontally along the center line of roadway from\nface to face of abutments or sidewalls immediately below the copings or\nfillets; or, if there are no copings or fillets at points six inches\nbelow the bridge seats or immediately under the top slab in the case of\nframe structures. In the case of arches, the span shall be measured from\nspring line to spring line.  All measurements shall include the widths\nof intervening piers or division walls as well as the width of copings\nor fillets. The term culvert, as defined in this section, shall also\ninclude the approaches.\n  3. "Publicly-owned, operated or maintained" means a bridge that is\nowned, operated or maintained by any department, board, bureau,\ncommission or agency of the state or its political subdivisions, public\nbenefit corporation or by any public authority including the port\nauthority of New York and New Jersey.\n  4. "Public entity" means any department, board, bureau, commission or\nagency of the state or its political subdivisions, public benefit\ncorporation or any public authority including the port authority of New\nYork and New Jersey.\n  5. "Substantial structural alteration" means any work that modifies\nthe load capacity, loan distribution or load paths or structural\nbehavior of the bridge.\n  6. "Railroad bridge" means a structure including supports erected over\na depression or an obstruction such as water, highway, or railway,\nhaving a track or tracks for carrying freight or passengers or other\nmoving loads and having an opening measured along the center of the\ntrack or roadway of more than twenty feet between under croppings of\nabutments or spring lines or arches, or extreme ends of openings for\nmultiple boxes and may include multiple pipes where the clear distance\nbetween openings is less than half of the smaller contiguous opening\nwhether privately or publicly owned. The term railroad bridge, as\ndefined in this section, shall also include the approaches.\n  7. "Railroad" means a private or public railroad operating in the\nstate of New York carrying either freight, passengers or freight and\npassengers including, but not limited to, those operated by the\nmetropolitan transportation authority and its subsidiaries, the Long\nIsland Rail Road, the metro-north railroad, the Staten Island rapid\ntransit operating authority, the New York city transit authority or any\nother public authority or local government and shall include tourist\nexcursion operations and railrides on standard gauge tracks.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>