<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-234"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-234"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="234"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_234">
        <num>234</num>
        <heading>Public authority, public benefit corporation, commission, county, town, city or village bridges</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_234__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the recommendation of the county superintendent that any\nbridge having a span of twenty-five feet or over, which is on a county\nroad or a town highway, has become useless and not necessary for the\npublic convenience and welfare, the board of supervisors, to promote the\ninterests of the county, upon a resolution adopted by a majority of the\nmembers of such board, may authorize, empower and direct the county\nsuperintendent acting for and in behalf of such board, to make an order\nabandoning any such bridge, provided, however, that such order shall\nbecome effective if and when he shall have obtained a written release\nfrom all damages from the owners of the land adjacent to the section of\nthe highway upon which such bridge is located between lateral\nintersecting highways affected thereby. Such release shall contain a\nprovision that it shall forever be binding upon and in full force and\neffect against the owner, his lessees, grantees, assigns, successors,\nheirs and devisees and such release shall, when recorded and indexed as\nhereinafter prescribed, be so binding. Said release shall be duly\nacknowledged in the manner to entitle a conveyance transferring any\nestate in real property to be recorded and it shall be recorded and\nindexed in the county clerk's office in which the lands described in a\nrelease are located as a conveyance under the real property law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_234__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The county superintendent, with the approval of the chairman of\nthe board of supervisors and the county judge, may agree with such owner\nor owners upon the amount of consideration for such releases in a gross\nsum not to exceed five thousand dollars. An order of the county\nsuperintendent as herein provided shall be final. The amount agreed upon\nto be paid to such owners for such releases and the cost of the removal\nof such useless bridge and/or the cost for the erection of obstructions\nor barricades shall be a county charge and may by resolution of the\nboard of supervisors be paid from any funds of the county that may be\nlegally used for such purpose or may be raised, in whole or in part,\npursuant to the local finance law. Whenever the money to be paid for\nsuch releases is available the county treasurer shall pay to the said\nowners executing said releases the amounts agreed upon to be paid to\nthem for said releases upon the requisition of the county\nsuperintendent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_234__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the duty of the county superintendent upon the making\nof an order of abandonment to file the same in the office of the clerk\nof the board of supervisors and to file copies thereof certified by the\nclerk of the board of supervisors in the town clerk's office of the town\nor towns in which such useless bridge or part thereof is situated, and\nhe shall send two such certified copies of said order to the department\nof transportation. Upon the filing of said order it shall be the duty of\nthe county superintendent to erect at and across each end of such\nuseless bridge a suitable substantial barricade or obstruction to close\nsuch bridge and for the prevention of further use thereof and passage\nthereon or thereto and there shall be installed suitable signs, the type\nand manner of placement of which shall conform to the New York State\nmanual of uniform traffic control devices. If such bridge is taken down,\nthe county superintendent shall place like obstructions or barricades at\nthe ends of the portions of the highway at the places where the highway\njoined such bridge. The county superintendent shall also erect suitable\nsigns at lateral intersecting highways which in his judgment afford most\nconvenient detours to another bridge or bridges to be used by the\ntraveling public instead of such abandoned bridge. The cost of such\nsigns, their erection and maintenance shall be paid for in the manner\nprovided for the payment of the barricades and obstructions as\naforesaid.\n  12. Upon the written recommendation of the county superintendent that\nany bridge having a span of twenty-five feet or over, which is on a\ncounty road or town highway, has become useless and not necessary for\nthe public convenience and welfare, the board of supervisors, upon a\nfinding by resolution of the town board as to any such bridge on a town\nhighway, or upon a finding by resolution of such board of supervisors as\nto any such bridge on a county road, to promote the interes...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>