<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-248"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-248"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="248"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-248/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-248/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-248/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-248/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_248">
        <num>248</num>
        <heading>Resolution of board of supervisors for abolition of toll bridges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 248. Resolution of board of supervisors for abolition of toll\nbridges. The board of supervisors of any county may, and upon the\npresentation of a petition signed by fifty per centum of the owners of\nreal property and representing a majority of the assessed valuation of\nthe town or city in which a toll bridge is wholly or partly situated\nmust, except where such bridge extends between the state of New York and\na foreign country, pass a resolution that public interest demands the\nabolition of such toll bridge situate wholly or partly within said\ncounty. In case of a toll bridge situated in two counties such\nresolution shall be a concurrent resolution passed by the boards of\nsupervisors of the counties wherein said bridge is situated. Within ten\ndays after the passage of such resolution the clerk or clerks of the\nboard or boards of supervisors shall transmit certified copies thereof\nto the department of transportation. Before transmitting such certified\ncopy or copies to the department of transportation, the board or boards\nof supervisors shall investigate as to the value of such toll bridge and\nshall prepare an estimate of the probable cost of acquiring the same,\nand the clerk or clerks shall transmit such estimate, together with any\ndata in relation to the value of such toll bridge which the board or\nboards of supervisors may secure, to the department of transportation\nwith the certified copy or copies of such resolution.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>