<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-249"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-249"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="249"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-249/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-249/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-249/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-249/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_249">
        <num>249</num>
        <heading>Investigation by the department of transportation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 249. Investigation by the department of transportation. The\ndepartment of transportation shall upon the receipt of such resolution\nor concurrent resolution, investigate and determine whether the bridge\nso sought to be abolished is of sufficient public importance to come\nwithin the provisions of this article, taking into account the use,\nlocation and value of such toll bridge for the purpose of common traffic\nand travel and shall also investigate as to the value of such toll\nbridge and from the estimate and data transmitted by the board or boards\nof supervisors, or from such other information as the department of\ntransportation may secure, prepare an estimate of the probable cost of\nacquiring such toll bridge. After such investigation such department of\ntransportation shall certify its approval or disapproval of such\nresolution. If it shall disapprove such resolution, it shall certify its\nreasons therefor to such board or boards of supervisors. If it shall\napprove such resolution it shall certify its approval thereof to the\nattorney general, and shall transmit to him the estimate made by the\ndepartment of transportation of the probable cost of acquiring such toll\nbridge, together with any data the department of transportation may have\nin its possession in relation to the value thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>