<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-266"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-266"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="266"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-266/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-266/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-266/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-266/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_266">
        <num>266</num>
        <heading>Payment for machinery, tools, equipment and implements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 266. Payment for machinery, tools, equipment and implements. After\nthe authorization of the purchase of machinery or equipment as\nprescribed in section one hundred forty-two, the town board may direct\nand authorize the supervisor to complete the purchase of such machinery\nor equipment. If bonds or notes are issued for the purchase of such\nmachinery, willful failure of the town superintendent to include the\namount of such a maturing bond or note and interest thereon in his\nhighway estimate shall be reason for removal from office. The amount of\nsuch bond or note and the interest thereon shall be included in the\nestimate of the town superintendent required by section one hundred\nforty-one of this chapter to be prepared and filed by him in the year\nimmediately preceding the due date of such obligation. The estimate or\nestimates of the town superintendent, including the amount or amounts\nrequired to pay such bonds or notes, shall not exceed the limitation\nprescribed in section two hundred seventy-one of this chapter.\n  Provided, however, that the town board at the meeting thereof at which\nthe annual estimate is adopted, may appropriate from the unexpended\nbalance of money raised or received for the repair or improvement of\ntown highways, or from any other funds based on the estimate of the town\nsuperintendent, a sum sufficient to pay a part or all of any bonds or\nnotes and interest thereon, not exceeding the amount earned by such\nmachine, machines or equipment, for the total number of hours actually\nused upon the highways at the hourly rate fixed by the state\ncommissioner of transportation, provided, that no more than half the\namount of such bonds or notes may be paid from the moneys raised or\nreceived for the repair or improvement of highways, and the amount\nappropriated by the town board shall be deducted from the amount\nincluded in the estimate of the town superintendent.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>