<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-269"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-269"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="269"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-269/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-269/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-269/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-269/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_269">
        <num>269</num>
        <heading>Extraordinary repairs of highways and bridges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 269. Extraordinary repairs of highways and bridges. If any highway\nor bridge or the board walk on any highway less than two rods in width,\nor a walk built to replace the same under section one hundred and\nfifty-one, shall at any time be damaged or destroyed by the elements or\notherwise, or become unsafe for public use and travel, or if any bridge\nor the board walk on any highway less than two rods in width, or any\nsuch walk built to replace the same, be condemned by the department of\ntransportation, as provided in this chapter, the town superintendent\nshall cause the same to be immediately repaired or rebuilt, with the\napproval of the town board. Such highway or bridge or walk shall be so\nrepaired or rebuilt in accordance with the directions or the plans and\nspecifications prepared or approved by the county superintendent; except\nif the bridge or walk to be repaired or rebuilt is one which has been\ncondemned by the department of transportation, as provided in this\nchapter, the same shall be repaired or rebuilt in accordance with plans\nand specifications to be prepared or approved by the department of\ntransportation. The town clerk shall prepare a statement showing the\nprobable cost of improving, repairing or rebuilding such highway or\nbridge or walk, which statement shall be signed in duplicate by a\nmajority of the members of the town board, one of which duplicates shall\nbe filed with the town clerk and one be delivered to the supervisor.\nThe town clerk shall make a copy of such statement and transmit the same\nto the department of transportation. The supervisor shall present such\nstatement to the board of supervisors, who shall cause the amount\ncontained in such statement to be assessed, levied and collected in the\nsame manner as amounts levied and collected for other highway and bridge\npurposes, as provided by law. The amount so raised shall be paid to the\nsupervisor to be expended for the purposes specified in such statement.\nNothing herein contained shall be construed to prevent the financing of\nsuch repairing or rebuilding, in whole or in part, pursuant to the local\nfinance law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>