<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-271"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-271"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-11-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="271"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-271/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-271/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-271/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-271/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_271">
        <num>271</num>
        <heading>Limitations of amounts to be raised</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 271. Limitations of amounts to be raised. The amounts to be raised\nby tax upon the vote of a town board, as provided in this article, shall\nbe subject to the following limitations: 1. The amount to be levied and\ncollected in each year for the repair and improvement of highways,\nincluding sluices, culverts and bridges having a span of less than five\nfeet and board walks or renewals thereof, on highways less than two rods\nin width, shall not be less than the amount prescribed under subdivision\none of section one hundred and forty-one.\n  3. a. Unless duly authorized by vote at a special or biennial town\nelection, there shall not be levied and collected in any one year in any\ntown, for the purchase of stone crushers, power rollers, motor trucks,\nscarifiers, concrete mixers, traction engines or road machines for\ngrading and scraping, equipment, tools and other implements, an amount\ngreater than as hereinafter specified, to wit:\n  (1) Two hundred thousand dollars in the towns of Colonie, Bethlehem\nand Guilderland in Albany county, in the town of Carmel in Putnam\ncounty, in the town of Greenburgh in Westchester county, in the towns of\nHaverstraw, Clarkstown, and Stony Point in Rockland county, in the towns\nof Riverhead, Southold and Southampton in Suffolk county, in the towns\nof Camillus, Cicero, DeWitt, Manlius, Onondaga and Salina in Onondaga\ncounty, in the town of Poughkeepsie, Dutchess county, or in any town of\nthe first class in Erie county.\n  (1-a) Four hundred thousand dollars in the towns of Babylon and Islip\nin Suffolk county.\n  (1-b) One hundred fifty thousand dollars in the town of Cortlandville,\nCortland county.\n  (1-c) Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph one of this\nparagraph, four hundred thousand dollars in the town of Amherst in Erie\ncounty.\n  * (1-d) One million dollars in the town of Brookhaven in Suffolk\ncounty for replacement of equipment or replacement for comparable use.\n  * NB There are 2 subpar (1-d)'s\n  * (1-d) Eight hundred thousand dollars in any town in Nassau county.\n  * NB There are 2 subpar (1-d)'s\n  (1-e) One million two hundred thousand dollars in the town of\nSmithtown in Suffolk county.\n  (1-f) Four hundred thousand dollars in the town of Ramapo in Rockland\ncounty to be used only for replacement of equipment or replacement for\ncomparable use.\n  (1-g) Six hundred fifty thousand dollars in the town of Orangetown in\nRockland county to be used only for replacement or repair of equipment\nor replacement for comparable use.\n  (1-h) One million dollars in the town of Huntington in Suffolk county.\n  (2) One hundred thousand dollars in the towns of Geddes and Clay in\nOnondaga county, in the towns of East Hampton and Shelter Island in\nSuffolk county or in any town in Westchester county, except the town of\nGreenburgh.\n  (2-a) Two hundred thousand dollars in any town of the first class in\nMonroe county.\n  (2-b) One hundred thousand dollars for the town of Shawangunk in\nUlster County.\n  (2-c) One hundred twenty-five thousand dollars in the town of Maine in\nthe county of Broome.\n  (2-d) One hundred twenty-five thousand dollars in the town of\nColesville in the county of Broome.\n  (3) Seventy-five thousand dollars in any town in Orange county or in\nSullivan county.\n  (4) Sixty thousand dollars in any other town.\n  b. If duly authorized at a special or biennial town election the\nincrease of the amount of any limitation provided in paragraph a of this\nsubdivision shall continue in effect for succeeding fiscal years until\nchanged by a vote of a special or biennial town election.\n  c. The limitations contained in this subdivision shall not be\nconstrued as limitations upon the amount of money which may be spent in\nany fiscal year for any object or purpose described in this subdivision.\n  4. Not more than three thousand dollars shall be levied and collected\nin any one year in any town for the repair or construction of any\nhighway or bridge which has been damaged or destroyed as provided in\nsection two hundred and sixty-nine or which has been condemned by the\ndepartment of transportation as provided in this chapter, unless by\nunanimous consent of the town board, but in no case shall more than six\nthousand dollars be levied and collected unless duly authorized by the\nvote of a town meeting, except that in any town in the county of\nWestchester by the unanimous consent of the town board, the sum of not\nmore than twelve thousand dollars may be levied and collected unless\nduly authorized by the vote of a town meeting.\n  5. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section, if any\nsuch town is located wholly or partly within the Adirondack park and has\nwithin its boundaries state lands subject to taxation assessed at more\nthan thirty per centum of the total taxable assessed valuation of the\ntown as determined from the assessment rolls of the town, as completed\nfrom time to time, it shall be necessary to obtain the consent of the\nstate comptroller, on behalf of the state, in addition to the unanimous\nconsent of the town board in order to exceed the limitations of\nsubdivisions two and four of this section, and in addition to the vote\nof a special or biennial town election in order to exceed the\nlimitations of subdivision three of this section as fixed by such\nsubdivision three or as fixed prior to May first, nineteen hundred\nforty-eight, by a special or biennial town election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>