<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-29"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-29"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-09-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-29/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-29/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-29/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-29/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29">
        <num>29</num>
        <heading>Property for highways, bridges and other highway uses and purposes to be acquired by acquisition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 29. Property for highways, bridges and other highway uses and\npurposes to be acquired by acquisition. 1. Notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provisions of this chapter, or any other laws, general or\nspecial, the commissioner of transportation shall, whenever the federal\ngovernment shall agree to grant or contribute to the state not less than\ntwenty-five per centum of the cost thereof, acquire pursuant to the\nprovisions of the eminent domain procedure law any and all property\nnecessary for the construction and reconstruction of highway projects\nlocated on the "strategic network of highways," as defined in the\nfederal defense highway act of nineteen hundred forty-one and as revised\nto May fifteenth, nineteen hundred forty-one and approved by the\nsecretary of war, or on such network as hereafter revised and approved,\nand also any and all property necessary for any other highway project,\nexclusive of parkways, when certified by the army or navy as important\nfor the purposes of national defense, and a like grant or contribution\nis to be made by the federal government. A highway indicated under this\nsection for construction or improvement, or any portion of such highway,\nmay be constructed or improved, or reconstructed, as a controlled access\nhighway, upon the adoption of a resolution by a majority vote of the\nboard of supervisors of the county in which the highway is to be\nconstructed. The resolution of the board of supervisors herein referred\nto shall not be required in relation to highways to be projected as\nthrough trunk routes and principally on new location. The costs of all\nsuch property as may be acquired under this section shall be paid in the\nfirst instance from any funds available for the construction,\nreconstruction and improvement of state highways and bridges.\n  2. The commissioner of transportation shall cause to be prepared an\naccurate acquisition map of any property which he may deem necessary for\npurposes connected with such highway projects or of any property in and\nto which he may deem the acquisition or exercise of an easement,\ninterest or right to be necessary for such purposes indicating and\ndescribing in each case the particular easement, interest or right. On\nthe approval of such acquisition map by the commissioner of\ntransportation, he shall acquire such property, easements, interests or\nrights pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law.\n  3. If the commissioner shall determine, prior to the filing of a copy\nof a map of acquisition, as provided in section four hundred two of the\neminent domain procedure law, in the office of the county clerk as\naforesaid, that changes, alterations or modifications of such map as\nfiled in the main office of the department should be made, he or she\nshall, subject to the provisions of article two of the eminent domain\nprocedure law, if applicable, direct the preparation of an amended map,\neither by preparing a new map or by making changes on the original\ntracing of such map, with a notation indicating such changes. On the\napproval of such amended map by the commissioner, it shall be filed in\nthe main office of the department in the same manner as the original map\nwas filed and the amended map shall thereupon in all respects and for\nall purposes supersede the map previously filed.\n  4. If the commissioner shall determine, prior to the filing of such\ncopy of the acquisition map in the office of the county clerk as\nprovided in section four hundred two of the eminent domain procedure\nlaw, that such map should be withdrawn, he or she shall file a\ncertificate of withdrawal in the offices of the department and\ndepartment of law. Upon the filing of such certificate of withdrawal,\nthe map to which it refers shall be cancelled and all rights thereunder\nshall cease and determine.\n  5. If, at or after the vesting of title to such property in the people\nof the state of New York in the manner provided for in the eminent\ndomain procedure law, the commissioner of transportation shall deem it\nnecessary to cause the removal of an owner or other occupant from such\nproperty, he may cause such owner or other occupant to be removed\ntherefrom by proceeding in accordance with section four hundred five of\nsuch law. The proceeding shall be brought in the name of the\ncommissioner of transportation as agent of the state. If any person\nproceeded against shall contest the petition by an answer, the attorney\ngeneral shall be notified, and he thereafter shall represent the\npetitioner in the proceedings. No execution shall issue for costs, if\nany, awarded against the state or the commissioner of transportation,\nbut they shall be part of the costs of the acquisition and be paid in\nlike manner. Proceedings may be brought separately against one or more\nof the owners or other occupants of a property, or one proceeding may be\nbrought against all or several of the owners or other occupants of any\nor all property within the territorial jurisdiction of the same justice\nor judge; judgment shall effect or be made for immediate removal of\npersons defaulting in appearance or in answering, or withdrawing their\nanswers, if any, without awaiting the trial or decision of issues raised\nby contestants, if any.\n  6. The commissioner of transportation upon making any agreement\nprovided for in section three hundred four of the eminent domain\nprocedure law shall deliver to the comptroller such agreement and a\ncertificate stating the amount due such owner or owners thereunder on\naccount of such appropriation of his or their property and the amount so\nfixed shall be paid out of the state treasury, after audit by the\ncomptroller, from moneys appropriated for purposes connected with such\nhighway projects, but not until there shall have been filed with the\ncomptroller a certificate of the attorney general showing the person or\npersons claiming the amount so agreed upon to be legally entitled\nthereto.\n  7. Application for reimbursement of incidental expenses as provided in\nsection seven hundred two of the eminent domain procedure law shall be\nmade to the commissioner upon forms prescribed by him and shall be\naccompanied by such information and evidence as the commissioner may\nrequire. Upon approval of such application, the commissioner shall\ndeliver a copy thereof to the comptroller together with a certificate\nstating the amount due thereof, and the amount so fixed shall be paid\nout of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from monies\nappropriated for the acquisition of property under this section.\n  8. The commissioner of transportation, with the approval of the\ndirector of the budget, shall establish and may from time to time amend\nrules and regulations authorizing the payment of actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses of occupants of property acquired pursuant to\nthis section; of actual direct losses of tangible personal property as a\nresult of moving or discontinuing a business or farm operation, but not\nexceeding an amount equal to the reasonable expenses that would have\nbeen required to relocate such property, as determined by the\ncommissioner; and actual reasonable expenses in searching for a\nreplacement business or farm; or in hardship cases for the advance\npayment of such expenses and losses. For the purposes of making payment\nof such expenses and losses only, the term "business" means any lawful\nactivity conducted primarily for assisting in the purchase, sale,\nresale, manufacture, processing or marketing of products, commodities,\npersonal property or services by the erection and maintenance of an\noutdoor advertising display or displays, whether or not such display or\ndisplays are located on the premises on which any of the above\nactivities are conducted.\n  Such rules and regulations may further define the terms used in this\nsubdivision. In lieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses, any such displaced owner or tenant of residential property may\nelect to accept a moving expense allowance, plus a dislocation\nallowance, determined in accordance with a schedule prepared by the\ncommissioner and made a part of such rules and regulations. In lieu of\nsuch actual reasonable and necessary moving expenses, any such displaced\nowner or tenant of commercial property who relocates or discontinues his\nbusiness or farm operation may elect to accept a fixed relocation\npayment in an amount equal to the average annual net earnings of the\nbusiness or farm operation, except that such payment shall be not less\nthan two thousand five hundred dollars nor more than ten thousand\ndollars. In the case of a business, no such fixed relocation payment\nshall be made unless the commissioner finds and determines that the\nbusiness cannot be relocated without a substantial loss of its existing\npatronage, and that the business is not part of a commercial enterprise\nhaving at least one other establishment, which is not being acquired by\nthe state or the United States, which is engaged in the same or similar\nbusiness. In the case of a business which is to be discontinued but for\nwhich the findings and determinations set forth above cannot be made,\nthe commissioner may prepare an estimate of what the actual reasonable\nand necessary moving expenses, exclusive of any storage charges, would\nbe if the business were to be relocated, and enter into an agreed\nsettlement with the owner of such business for an amount not to exceed\nsuch estimate in lieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses. Application for payment under this subdivision shall be made\nto the commissioner upon forms prescribed by him and shall be\naccompanied by such information and evidence as the commissioner may\nrequire. Upon approval of such application, the commissioner shall\ndeliver a copy thereof to the comptroller together with a certificate\nstating the amount due thereunder, and the am</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>