<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-327"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-327"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="327"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-327/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-327/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-327/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-327/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_327">
        <num>327</num>
        <heading>Lighting roads, highways and bridges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 327. Lighting roads, highways and bridges. The town board of any\ntown may from time to time provide for lighting dangerous portions of\nany road or highway defined by section three of this chapter or\nconstructed or improved under the provisions of section one hundred and\nninety-four of this chapter, and of bridges located thereon. The initial\naction of the board shall be in the form of a proposal. The roads and\nportions thereof to be lighted, and the manner of lighting, shall be set\nforth in such proposal. Such proposal shall be embodied in a resolution.\nThe lighting of one or more such roads, highways or bridges, or either,\nmay be proposed in a single resolution. The board may provide for such\nlighting, if its proposal is so approved. The expense of installing,\nmaintaining and caring for such lights shall be a town charge, and the\nmoneys therefor shall be provided and appropriated in the same manner as\nfor other town expenses. The furnishing of light under this section may\nbe provided for by contract or otherwise; but nothing herein contained\nshall be deemed to authorize the town board to acquire, construct or\nestablish a gas or electric lighting plant for the above purposes. The\ninstallation of lights, fixtures and connections shall be done under the\nsupervision of the county superintendent of highways. The town board may\nprovide for the care of such lights in such manner as it may deem\nproper. The board may, in its discretion, at any time discontinue the\nlighting of any road, highway or bridge, or portion thereof, provided\nfor under this section. Any installation of lighting pursuant to this\nsection on a state highway shall be subject to the approval of the\ncommissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>