<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-328"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-328"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="328"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_328">
        <num>328</num>
        <heading>Lighting of public highways or bridges</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 328. Lighting of public highways or bridges. The board of\nsupervisors of any county may from time to time provide for lighting\npublic highways, or portions thereof, or bridges, located in such county\noutside of cities and villages. The initial action of the board shall be\nin the form of a proposal. The highways, or portions thereof, or bridges\nto be lighted, and the manner of lighting, shall be set forth in such\nproposal. Such proposal shall be embodied in a resolution. The lighting\nof one or more of such highways, or portions thereof, or bridges may be\nproposed in a single resolution. The board may provide for such lighting\nif its proposal be so approved. The expense of installing, maintaining\nand caring for such lights shall be a county charge, and the moneys\ntherefor shall be provided and appropriated in the same manner as for\nother county expenses. The furnishing of light under this section may be\nprovided for by contract or otherwise, but nothing herein shall be\ndeemed to authorize the board to acquire, construct or establish a\nlighting plant for such purposes. The installation of lights, fixtures\nand connections shall be done under the supervision of the county\nsuperintendent of highways. The board may provide for the care of such\nlights in such manner as it may deem proper. The board may, in its\ndiscretion, at any time discontinue the lighting of any highway, or\nportion thereof, or bridge provided for under this section.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of this section, the county of Monroe may\nfrom time to time provide for lighting public highways, streets, or\nportions thereof, or bridges located in the city of Rochester, subject\nto the approval of the city council of the city of Rochester. Any\ninstallation of lighting pursuant to this section on a state highway\nshall be subject to the approval of the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>