<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="340-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_340_B">
        <num>340-B</num>
        <heading>Construction, improvement and maintenance of state interstate highways</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_340_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the construction and reconstruction of\ninterstate highways designated and described in section three hundred\nforty-a of this chapter,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_340_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the construction, reconstruction,\nalteration or repair, pursuant to the provisions of section two hundred\nthirty of this chapter, of bridges and culverts on the interstate\nhighway system, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_340_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the preparation of preliminary surveys, plans,\nspecifications and estimates of costs in connection with any of the\nforegoing, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_340_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the acquisition of rights of way necessary for such\ninterstate highways. The commissioner of transportation may perform such\nwork with respect to any interstate project which he may, in his\ndiscretion, select. The proportion of the total cost of work performed\non any interstate project, in addition to such elements thereof as are\nnot subject to federal aid, which shall be borne by the state of New\nYork shall be the difference between the funds contributed for such work\nby the federal government and the actual cost thereof. No city shall be\nrequired to participate in the costs of an interstate highway project,\nwhether or not the alignment coincides with the alignment of a\npreviously approved arterial route, except for those costs which are\nincurred under any special cooperative agreement between a city and the\nstate.\n  5. a. Any property in the city of New York which is deemed by the\ncommissioner of transportation to be necessary for the construction,\nreconstruction and maintenance of interstate highways shall be acquired\nand may be disposed of by him pursuant to applicable provisions of\nsection thirty of this chapter.\n  b. In any case in which property is to be acquired or disposed of\npursuant to the provisions of this subdivision and in any case where\nproperty is created by landfill adjoining such property, the\ncommissioner of transportation shall, prior to any proposed acquisition,\ndisposition or new or different utilization, development or improvement\nthereof, notify the city planning commission and the community board in\neach community district in which the property is located of such\nproposal. Such notice shall be given so as to afford the city planning\ncommission and the community board reasonable opportunity to:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_340_B__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>notify\nthe public of the proposal;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_340_B__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>conduct a public hearing thereon; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_340_B__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>prepare and submit any written recommendations thereon to the\ncommissioner of transportation not later than sixty days after notice of\nthe contents of the proposal.\n  Within a reasonable time after receipt of any recommendations of the\ncity planning commission or community board or the expiration of the\ntime within which any such recommendation could have been made, the\ncommissioner shall notify the commission and respective board of the\ncontents of his resulting proposal.  If any of the items contained in\nthe resulting proposal were not available for consideration by the\ncommission or board within the time provided for the making of\nrecommendations thereon the resulting proposal shall constitute a\ndifferent proposal and as such shall be subject to the foregoing\nprovisions.\n  The provisions of this paragraph b shall only be applicable to a\nproposal by the commissioner of transportation which if proposed by a\ncity agency or instrumentality would be subject to the provisio...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_340_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not more than\neighty-five cents per square yard of the pavement area that is included\nin the state highway system according to the provisions of this section,\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_340_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an additional ten cents per square yard of such pavement area\nwhere such pavement area is located on any elevated bridge.\n  The maintenance and repair, as provided in this section, shall be done\neither by the forces of such city and with its equipment, or by its\ncontractor, or by a combination of these two methods.\n  Such agreement for maintenance and repair as authorized by this\nsection, shall include the procedure and method for regulation of street\nopenings, and appropriate provisions for the care, protection and\npatching of the pavement or pavements, and curbs, the care and\nprotection of drainage facilities and structures, the maintenance of\nadjacent roadside and landscaped areas to include the care of trees,\nshrubs and groundcovers and the cutting of grass at specified locations\nand to the extent as shall be deemed by such commissioner of\ntransportation to be for the best interest of the public, control of\nsnow and ice on any such state interstate highway or portion thereof\nincluded in such agreement, the performance of repairs and alterations,\nand the operation and care of traffic lights, directional guides and\ncontrols, and parking controls.  Such maintenance and repair, whether\ndone by the city pursuant to an agreement therefor as authorized by this\nsection, or by the state because of the absence of such agreement, as\nthe case may be, shall not include</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_340_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>services of lighting, cleaning,\nsweeping and sprinkling of any such state interstate highway or portion\nthereof, all of which services are deemed to be the normal maintenance\nof streets by the city, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_340_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any work on or in connection with\nsubsurface installations and structures that are owned and operated by\nthe city, including sanitary sewers, gas mains, water lines and conduits\nand appurtenances thereto.\n  6. All the provisions of this chapter relating to state highways and\nstate arterial highways and not inconsistent with the provisions of this\nsection or with the provisions of the federal-aid highway act of\nnineteen hundred fifty-six, shall apply to the construction or\nimprovement and the control of maintenance of interstate highways in the\nsame manner as though they were designated as state highways or arterial\nhighways.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>