<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-09-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="340-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_340_A">
        <num>340-A</num>
        <heading>Designation of state interstate routes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 340-a. Designation of state interstate routes. State interstate\nroutes are hereby set forth and generally described as follows:\n  Interstate Route 501. Beginning at the New York City-Westchester\ncounty line north of Pelham Bay park, thence generally northeasterly\nthrough or in the vicinity of Mt. Vernon, New Rochelle and Rye, to the\nNew York-Connecticut border in the vicinity of Port Chester, the\nforegoing route being a portion of the New York state thruway.\n  Interstate Route 502. Beginning on the New York City-Westchester\ncounty line at the Major Deegan expressway, thence in a general\nnortherly direction through Yonkers to interstate route connection 520\nin the vicinity of Elmsford, the foregoing route being a portion of the\nNew York state thruway, thence from interstate route connection 520 in\nthe vicinity of White Plains in a general northerly direction to\ninterstate route 503 in the vicinity of Brewster, excluding a short\nsection through the western tip of Fairfield county, Connecticut, thence\nfrom interstate route 503 in the vicinity of Newburgh, continuing\ngenerally northerly passing through or in the vicinity of Kingston and\nAlbany, intersecting interstate route 504 in the vicinity of Albany, the\nforegoing route between Newburgh and Albany being a portion of the New\nYork state thruway, thence continuing in a general northerly direction\ncrossing the Mohawk river on a new bridge to be constructed as part of\nthis route, such bridge shall be designated and shall be known as the\n"Thaddeus Kosciuszko bridge", and passing through or in the vicinity of\nSaratoga Springs, Glens Falls and Plattsburgh to the United\nStates-Canada border in the vicinity of Champlain. In order to provide a\ncontinuous and uninterrupted interstate route section from the vicinity\nof White Plains to the vicinity of Brewster as aforesaid, the\ncommissioner of transportation is authorized and empowered to enter into\nan agreement or agreements with the duly authorized representatives of\nthe state of Connecticut in order to provide for the construction and\nmaintenance of necessary connections between said interstate route 502\nand an interstate route to be constructed through the said excluded\nsection of interstate route 502 running through the western tip of\nFairfield county, Connecticut.\n  Interstate Route 503. Beginning at the Pennsylvania-New York border in\nthe vicinity of Port Jervis, thence generally easterly, crossing the\nHudson River in the vicinity of Newburgh and Beacon, to the New\nYork-Connecticut border in the vicinity of Brewster.\n  Interstate Route 504. Beginning on the Pennsylvania-New York border in\nthe vicinity of Lake Erie, thence in a general northeasterly direction\npassing in the vicinity of Dunkirk, to the vicinity of Big Tree and\ngenerally northerly to the town of Cheektowaga, and continuing northerly\nto the vicinity of Williamsville and generally easterly through or in\nthe vicinity of Batavia and Syracuse, intersecting interstate route 505\nin the vicinity of Syracuse, continuing generally easterly passing\nthrough or in the vicinity of Oneida, Utica, Little Falls, Amsterdam and\nSchenectady to an intersection with interstate route 502 in the vicinity\nof Albany the foregoing route being a portion of the New York state\nthruway; thence in a general easterly direction through the city of\nAlbany to an intersection with interstate route connection 540 in the\nvicinity of Lower Patroon Island, thence in a general southeasterly\ndirection to a point on the Berkshire section of the New York state\nthruway in the vicinity of state highway five thousand eighty-four, as\ndetermined by the commissioner of transportation and the chairman of the\nNew York state thruway authority, thence continuing along the New York\nstate thruway to the New York-Massachusetts border, such interstate\nroute to be designated, in addition to any other name or designation, as\nthe "AMVETS Memorial Highway".\n  Interstate Route 505. Beginning at the Pennsylvania-New York border in\nthe vicinity of Corbettsville, thence generally northerly through or in\nthe vicinity of Binghamton, Cortland and Syracuse, intersecting\ninterstate route 504 in the vicinity of Syracuse, continuing generally\nnortherly through or in the vicinity of Watertown to the United\nStates-Canada border in the vicinity of Grass Point Park, also\ncontinuing from a point on interstate route 505 north of Watertown and\nin a northeasterly direction to or in the vicinity of Massena, thence\neasterly and southeasterly passing in the vicinity of Malone, to a\nconnection with interstate route 502 in the vicinity of Plattsburgh.\n  Interstate Route 506. Beginning at interstate route 504 in the town of\nCheektowaga, thence generally westerly and northwesterly through\nBuffalo, across Grand Island, the foregoing route being a portion of the\nNew York state thruway, and thence generally westerly to the United\nStates-Canada border in the vicinity of Lewiston; also including a\nconnection beginning at the Peace bridge toll plaza, as determined by\nthe commissioner of transportation, thence generally southwesterly and\nsoutherly to a point on the southbound lane of the Niagara section of\nthe New York state thruway in the vicinity of Porter avenue, as\ndetermined by the commissioner of transportation and the chairman of the\nNew York state thruway authority.\n  Interstate Route 507. Beginning at the New Jersey-New York border in\nthe vicinity of Suffern, Rockland county, thence in a general\nnorthwesterly direction to Delaware county, thence in a general westerly\ndirection to the Pennsylvania line in the county of Chautauqua, along\nthe southern section of New York State, following substantially what is\nnow touring route 17.\n  Interstate Route 508. Beginning at interstate route 505 in or near the\ncity of Binghamton thence generally northeasterly within the Susquehanna\nriver valley and through or near the city of Oneonta, thence continuing\nnortheasterly through or in the vicinity of the city of Schenectady, to\na connection with interstate route 502 in the vicinity of Latham.\n  Interstate Route 509. Beginning at a point on the Southern Tier\nexpressway in the vicinity of Avoca, thence generally northwesterly to\nthe vicinity of Dansville and continuing generally northerly to\ninterstate route connection 580 in the city of Rochester.\n  New York City Routes and Connections.\n  Interstate Route Connection 511. Cross Bronx expressway from George\nWashington bridge approach to Bruckner expressway. Bruckner expressway\nfrom Cross Bronx expressway to New England thruway, New England thruway\nfrom Bruckner expressway to Westchester county line.\n  Interstate Route Connection 512. Staten Island expressway from\nGoethals bridge approach to Verrazzano-Narrows bridge approach,\nBrooklyn-Queens expressway from Verrazzano-Narrows bridge approach to\nGrand Central parkway, Grand Central parkway from Brooklyn-Queens\nexpressway to Robert F. Kennedy bridge approach, Major Deegan expressway\nfrom Robert F.  Kennedy bridge approach to the Westchester county line\nconnecting with interstate route 502.\n  Interstate Route Connection 513. Nassau expressway from Van Wyck\nboulevard to 150th street, Clearview expressway from Hillside avenue to\nThrogs Neck bridge approach, Throgs Neck expressway from Throgs Neck\nbridge approach to Bruckner expressway including Cross Bronx expressway\nfrom Throgs Neck expressway to Bruckner expressway.\n  Interstate Route Connection 514. Queens-Midtown expressway from\nBrooklyn-Queens expressway to Queens boulevard, Horace Harding\nexpressway from Queens boulevard to Clearview expressway.\n  Interstate Route Connection 515. From Brooklyn-Queens expressway\neasterly to Northern boulevard in the vicinity of Grand Central parkway;\nNorthern boulevard and Whitestone parkway from Grand Central parkway to\nBronx-Whitestone bridge approach, including Van Wyck expressway from\nHorace Harding expressway northerly to Whitestone parkway, Hutchinson\nRiver expressway from Bronx-Whitestone bridge approach to Bruckner\nexpressway.\n  Interstate Route Connection 516. Bruckner expressway from Robert F.\nKennedy bridge approach to Cross-Bronx expressway.\n  Interstate Route Connection 517. Arthur V. Sheridan expressway from\nBruckner expressway to Cross-Bronx expressway.\n  Interstate Route Connection 518. West Side highway from\nBrooklyn-Queens expressway via Hugh L. Carey tunnel to the Lincoln\ntunnel, including a connection from the Lincoln tunnel to West\nSeventy-second street. In no event shall traffic by any type of motor\nvehicle used for commercial purposes, such as the transportation of\ngoods, wares and merchandise including trailers and semi-trailers, and\ntractors when used in combination with trailers and semi-trailers, and\nmotor coaches carrying passengers except taxicabs be permitted on this\nroute north of Fifty-ninth street, and such commercial traffic shall\nexit from or enter on this route no further north than the connections\nor ramps to this route at Fifty-seventh street.\n  Up State Connections.\n  Interstate Route Connection 520. From interstate route 502 in the\nvicinity of Elmsford, generally easterly passing through or northerly of\nWhite Plains to a connection with interstate route 501 in the vicinity\nof Rye, including an interchange with interstate route 501, which\ninterchange is to be maintained and constructed jointly by the\ndepartment of transportation and the New York State thruway authority in\na manner determined by the commissioner of transportation and the New\nYork State thruway authority. The county of Westchester is hereby\nauthorized to convey to the state of New York all the right, title,\ninterest and option rights of the people of Westchester county in and to\nsuch parts of the lands, buildings and other real property and rights\nthereto acquired and held by it, as deemed necessary by the commissioner\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>