<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="340-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-340-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_340_C">
        <num>340-C</num>
        <heading>Designation of state expressways</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 340-c. Designation of state expressways. State expressway routes are\nhereby set forth and generally described as follows:\n  Southern tier expressway. Beginning at a point on the Broome-Tioga\ncounty line in the vicinity of state highway four hundred twenty, as\ndetermined by the commissioner of transportation, thence in a general\nwesterly direction on new location through or in the vicinity of\nWaverly, thence continuing generally northwesterly through or in the\nvicinity of Hornell, thence generally southwesterly through or in the\nvicinity of Olean, thence generally westerly through or in the vicinity\nof Jamestown, thence generally westerly to a point on the New\nYork-Pennsylvania state line as determined by the commissioner of\ntransportation.\n  Babylon-Northport expressway. Beginning at a point, to be determined\nby the commissioner of transportation, on Sunrise highway in the\nvicinity of Higbie Lane, thence generally northerly on new location to a\npoint on State highway eight thousand one hundred fifty-eight as\ndetermined by the commissioner of transportation.\n  South Mall expressway. Beginning at the interchange of interstate\nroute connection 540 and the Mall Arterial in the city of Albany, thence\ngenerally easterly crossing the Hudson river on new location and through\nthe city of Rensselaer to a point on the easterly city line of\nRensselaer, to be determined by the commissioner of transportation.\n  LaSalle expressway. Beginning on the easterly Niagara Falls city line\nconnecting with the LaSalle arterial route, thence in a generally\neasterly direction on new location to a point at or near the northerly\nNorth Tonawanda city line, thence continuing generally southerly through\nor in the vicinity of the cities of North Tonawanda and Tonawanda to a\npoint on interstate route connection five hundred ninety, as determined\nby the commissioner of transportation.\n  Genesee expressway. Beginning at a point, to be determined by the\ncommissioner of transportation on state highway six hundred forty-eight\nin the vicinity of state highway one thousand three hundred\nninety-three-A, thence in a generally southerly direction on new\nlocation through or in the vicinity of Geneseo, thence continuing\ngenerally southeasterly through or in the vicinity of Dansville, thence\nto a point on the Southern Tier expressway in the vicinity of Bath, as\ndetermined by the commissioner of transportation.\n  Lockport expressway. Beginning at a point, to be determined by the\ncommissioner of transportation, on interstate route connection five\nhundred ninety in the vicinity of Millersport highway, thence in a\ngenerally northeasterly direction, passing in the vicinity of the barge\ncanal, and through or in the vicinity of the city of Lockport to a point\non state highway eight thousand four hundred fifty-one as determined by\nthe commissioner of transportation, including a connection to the State\nUniversity of New York at Buffalo, Amherst campus internal loop road\nsystem, as determined by the commissioner.\n  Belt expressway. Beginning at a point, to be determined by the\ncommissioner of transportation on the Mile Strip road extension in the\nvicinity of state highway nine thousand two hundred sixty-nine, thence\nin a generally easterly and northeasterly direction to a point in the\nvicinity of Transit road, as determined by the commissioner of\ntransportation, thence continuing generally northerly and northwesterly\nto a connection with the LaSalle expressway at or near the northerly\nNorth Tonawanda city line, as determined by the commissioner of\ntransportation.\n  Susquehanna expressway. Beginning from a point on a state highway in\nor near the city of Binghamton, as determined by the commissioner,\nthence generally northeasterly within the Susquehanna river valley and\nthrough or near the city of Oneonta, thence continuing northeasterly\ngenerally in the vicinity of New York touring route seven to an\ninterchange with interstate route connection 550 in the vicinity of the\nAlbany-Schenectady county line.\n  Delaware-Saint Lawrence expressway. Beginning from a point on New York\ntouring route seventeen, as determined by the commissioner, thence\ngenerally northerly through the Rome-Utica area and continuing northerly\nto a connection or connections with existing state highways at or near\nthe Saint Lawrence river in Saint Lawrence county, as determined by the\ncommissioner.\n  University expressway. Beginning at a point, to be determined by the\ncommissioner, on interstate route connection five hundred ninety, thence\nin a generally southwesterly direction, continuing generally southerly\nalong or in the vicinity of the Erie Lackawanna railway right of way to\nthe extent feasible, as determined by the commissioner to a connection\nwith the Kensington arterial highway, as determined by the commissioner.\n  Baldwinsville expressway. Beginning at interstate route connection\nfive hundred four in the vicinity of Lakeside, thence generally\nnorthwesterly and northerly along New York touring route six hundred\nninety to a connection with New York touring route forty-eight northwest\nof Baldwinsville.\n  Camillus expressway. Beginning at the intersection of New York touring\nroutes five and one hundred seventy-four, west of the village of\nCamillus, thence generally northerly and easterly along New York touring\nroute five in the vicinity of Fairmount, thence continuing southeasterly\nand southerly along New York touring route five to the intersection of\nWest Genesee street in Westvale.\n  Fulton expressway. Beginning at interstate route connection five\nhundred five in the vicinity of North Syracuse, thence generally\nnorthwesterly along New York touring route four hundred eighty-one to\nthe intersection of New York touring route fifty-seven and the Fulton\ncity line.\n  Geddes expressway. Beginning at a point on state highway five thousand\nsixteen north of Fairmount, thence generally northerly to a point on\ninterstate route connection five hundred seventy in the vicinity of the\nState Fairgrounds.\n  Ithaca expressway. Beginning at the intersection of New York touring\nroute thirteen and Dey street in the city of Ithaca, thence generally\nnortherly and easterly along New York touring route thirteen to the\nintersection of Warren road in the village of Lansing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>