<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-341-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-341-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="341-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-341-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-341-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-341-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-341-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_341_A">
        <num>341-A</num>
        <heading>Repayment to state of moneys advanced to counties for the construction of county highways</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 341-a. Repayment to state of moneys advanced to counties for the\nconstruction of county highways. Wherever a county highway has been\nconstructed at the joint expense of the state and county and the state\nhas paid the entire cost of construction, including the share of the\ncounty, the board of supervisors of the county in which such a county\nhighway has been constructed and the county's share of the expense\nadvanced by the state, may, by resolution, provide for the payment to\nthe state of its share of the cost so advanced, and appropriate and make\nimmediately available an amount sufficient to pay the same. The clerk of\nthe board of supervisors shall transmit certified copies of such\nresolution to the commissioner of transportation and state comptroller.\nIn case there is due to the county a sum of money from any town located\ntherein, the town board of the town is also authorized to appropriate\nits share of the cost and pay the same to the county treasurer of the\ncounty.\n  All moneys paid to the state pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection shall be deposited by the comptroller with the department of\ntaxation and finance to the credit of the highway improvement fund, from\nwhich fund the said moneys so advanced to said counties were originally\ntaken, and may be expended for the construction of state highways in any\ncounty or counties designated by the commissioner of transportation. The\nterm "county highway" shall mean any highway constructed at the joint\nexpense of the state and county classified or referred to as a county\nhighway under former provisions of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>