<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="342-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_342_F">
        <num>342-F</num>
        <heading>Portion of state highway system to be designated as the "Seaway Trail"</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 342-f. Portion of state highway system to be designated as the\n"Seaway Trail". The commissioner of the department of transportation\nshall provide for the adequate signing of the trail. All that portion of\nthe state highway system identified as follows:\n  Beginning at the Pennsylvania-New York state line in the town of\nRipley, the trail follows state route five in a northeasterly direction\ntoward the village of Silver Creek to a point where route five merges\nwith state route twenty. The trail continues along routes five and\ntwenty to the community of Irving where the trail leaves routes five and\ntwenty and follows the Old Lake Shore Road, running roughly along the\nLake Erie shoreline, to the community of Wanakah. At Wanakah, the trail\npicks up state route five and continues northeasterly and then northerly\nto the city of Lackawanna and proceeds across the Skyway to the Delaware\nAvenue exit. The trail then follows Delaware Avenue to Niagara Square in\nthe city of Buffalo and then around Niagara Square to Niagara Street and\nalong Niagara Street to the River Road, state route two hundred\nsixty-five. The trail continues along the River Road, route two hundred\nsixty-five through the cities of Tonawanda and North Tonawanda to\nBuffalo Avenue. Following Buffalo Avenue, the trail then turns onto the\nwestbound lanes of the Robert Moses State Parkway until it reaches the\nQuay Street exit in the city of Niagara Falls. The trail then leaves the\nRobert Moses State Parkway and follows Quay Street until it reaches\nRainbow Boulevard. The trail then continues northerly along Rainbow\nBoulevard, being state route three hundred eighty-four, until it\nintersects with Niagara Street. The trail then turns westerly onto\nNiagara Street and continues until it reaches the Rainbow Bridge. From\nthe Rainbow Bridge in the city of Niagara Falls, the trail follows state\nroute one hundred four east to the community of Lewiston, where the\ntrail intersects with route eighteen-F. The trail continues along route\neighteen-F, until it merges into state route eighteen. Following route\neighteen, the trail passes the villages of Roosevelt Beach, Olcott,\nAshwood and Kuckville. Once inside Lakeside Beach State Park, the trail\nleaves route eighteen and follows Lake Ontario State Parkway, running\nroughly parallel to the Lake Ontario shoreline. In the town of\nIrondequoit, Lake Ontario State Parkway joins with Stutson Street. The\ntrail then follows Stutson Street, turns right onto Saint Paul\nBoulevard, then left onto Lake Shore Boulevard. The trail continues east\non Lake Shore Boulevard to Culver Road. The trail then turns right onto\nCulver Road, then left onto Empire Boulevard, state route four hundred\nfour, then left onto Bay Road and then right onto Lake Road. The trail\nfollows Lake Road through the community of Pultneyville and continues to\nthe village of Sodus Point. At Sodus Point, the trail bears south on\nstate route fourteen to Alton, where it intersects Ridge Road. Following\nRidge Road, the trail passes through the villages of Resort and Wolcott.\nOnce outside of Wolcott, the trail picks up Old Ridge Road until it\nreaches the village of Red Creek. There it joins state route one hundred\nfour-A. The trail continues north on route one hundred four-A through\nthe village of Fair Haven, Sterling and Southwest Oswego to the city of\nOswego, then north on state route one hundred four through the community\nof Scriba to state route one hundred four-B. Proceeding north through\nthe community of Texas, the trail follows route one hundred four-B to\nthe intersection with state route three. There it joins route three\nnorth through Port Ontario, and roughly parallel to the Lake Ontario\nshoreline. At Baggs Corners, the trail follows state route one hundred\neighty north through the village of Dexter to the intersection of state\nroute twelve-E at Limerick. The trail then follows route twelve-E west\nthrough the village of Chaumont to the village of Cape Vincent, and\nnorth along the St. Lawrence River to Clayton where it connects with\nstate route twelve north. The trail follows route twelve past the\nvillage of Alexandria Bay, Chippewa Bay and Oak Point. Near Morristown\nthe trail joins state route thirty-seven north to the city of\nOgdensburg. The trail follows state route one hundred twenty-four onto\nthe state arterial, then north on State street (state routes sixty-eight\nand eighty-seven), and then east on Washington street. The trail turns\nonto North Rossell street, then left on Ford street. The trail turns\nleft onto Proctor avenue, then right onto state route eight hundred\ntwelve and south to state route thirty-seven. After passing through the\nvillage of Waddington, the trail continues on route thirty-seven through\nthe town of Louisville connecting by a left turn onto state route one\nhundred thirty-one. The trail turns right at the intersection of Tunnel\nroad, still on state route one hundred thirty-one. At the junction with\nSt. Lawrence county route forty-two the trail continues straight over\nthe Grasse river bridge to the junction with state route thirty-seven\nnorth. The trail turns left on to state route thirty-seven north to the\ntrail's northern terminus, the Rooseveltown International Bridge.\n  * NB Effective until completion of roadway\n  * ยง 342-e. Portion of state highway system to be designated as the\n"Seaway Trail". The commissioner of the department of transportation\nshall provide for the adequate signing of the trail. All that portion of\nthe state highway system identified as follows:\n  Beginning at the Pennsylvania-New York state line in the town of\nRipley, the trail follows state route five in a northeasterly direction\ntoward the village of Silver Creek to a point where route five merges\nwith state route twenty. The trail continues along routes five and\ntwenty to the community of Irving where the trail leaves routes five and\ntwenty and follows the Old Lake Shore Road, running roughly along the\nLake Erie shoreline, to the community of Wanakah. At Wanakah, the trail\npicks up state route five and continues northeasterly and then northerly\nto the city of Lackawanna and proceeds across the Skyway to the Delaware\nAvenue exit. The trail then follows Delaware Avenue to Niagara Square in\nthe city of Buffalo and then around Niagara Square to Niagara Street and\nalong Niagara Street to the River Road, state route two hundred\nsixty-five. The trail continues along the River Road, route two hundred\nsixty-five through the cities of Tonawanda and North Tonawanda to\nBuffalo Avenue. Following Buffalo Avenue, the trail then turns onto the\nwestbound lanes of the Robert Moses State Parkway until it reaches the\nQuay Street exit in the city of Niagara Falls. The trail then leaves the\nRobert Moses State Parkway and follows Quay Street until it reaches\nRainbow Boulevard. The trail then continues northerly along Rainbow\nBoulevard, being state route three hundred eighty-four, until it\nintersects with Niagara Street. The trail then turns westerly onto\nNiagara Street and continues until it reaches the Rainbow Bridge. From\nthe Rainbow Bridge in the city of Niagara Falls, the trail follows state\nroute one hundred four east to the community of Lewiston, where the\ntrail intersects with route eighteen-F. The trail continues along route\neighteen-F, until it merges into state route eighteen. Following route\neighteen, the trail passes the villages of Roosevelt Beach, Olcott,\nAshwood and Kuckville. Once inside Lakeside Beach State Park, the trail\nleaves route eighteen and follows Lake Ontario State Parkway, running\nroughly parallel to the Lake Ontario shoreline. In the town of\nIrondequoit, Lake Ontario State Parkway joins with Stutson Street. The\ntrail then follows Stutson Street, turns right onto Saint Paul\nBoulevard, then left onto Lake Shore Boulevard. Continuing east on Lake\nShore Boulevard, the trail joins with Lake Road. The trail follows Lake\nRoad through the community of Pultneyville and continues to the village\nof Sodus Point. At Sodus Point, the trail bears south on state route\nfourteen to Alton, where it intersects Ridge Road. Following Ridge Road,\nthe trail passes through the villages of Resort and Wolcott. Once\noutside of Wolcott, the trail picks up Old Ridge Road until it reaches\nthe village of Red Creek. There it joins state route one hundred four-A.\nThe trail continues north on route one hundred four-A through the\nvillage of Fair Haven, Sterling and Southwest Oswego to the city of\nOswego, then north on state route one hundred four through the community\nof Scriba to state route one hundred four-B. Proceeding north through\nthe community of Texas, the trail follows route one hundred four-B to\nthe intersection with state route three. There it joins route three\nnorth through Port Ontario, and roughly parallel to the Lake Ontario\nshoreline. At Baggs Corners, the trail follows state route one hundred\neighty north through the village of Dexter to the intersection of state\nroute twelve-E at Limerick. The trail then follows route twelve-E west\nthrough the village of Chaumont to the village of Cape Vincent, and\nnorth along the St. Lawrence River to Clayton where it connects with\nstate route twelve north. The trail follows route twelve past the\nvillage of Alexandria Bay, Chippewa Bay and Oak Point. Near Morristown\nthe trail joins state route thirty-seven north to the city of\nOgdensburg. The trail follows state route one hundred twenty-four onto\nthe state arterial, then north on State street (state routes sixty-eight\nand eighty-seven), and then east on Washington street. The trail turns\nonto North Rossell street, then left on Ford street. The trail turns\nleft onto Proctor Avenue, then right onto state route eight hundred\ntwelve and south to state route thirty-seven. After passing through the\nvillage of Waddington, the trail continues on route thirty-se</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>