<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="342-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-342-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_342_N">
        <num>342-N</num>
        <heading>Portion of state and county highway system to be designated and known as the "Dude Ranch Trail"</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 342-n. Portion of state and county highway system to be designated\nand known as the "Dude Ranch Trail". All that portion of the state and\ncounty system beginning at the intersection of route nine-N and\ninterstate route eighty-seven, continuing southwesterly on route nine-N;\ncontinuing then along Mill street, Main street and Bridge street (Warren\ncounty route forty-four) through the town of Lake Luzerne; crossing into\nHadley on Rockwell street (Saratoga county route four) after crossing\nthe Hudson River into the County of Saratoga; continuing northerly on\nthe Hadley-Stony Creek road (Saratoga county route one and Warren county\nroute twelve) to the hamlet of Stony Creek; continuing easterly on\nWarren County routes three, two and four and route four hundred eighteen\n(Stony Creek - Warrensburg road) to route nine; continuing south on\nroute nine to Diamond Point road crossing exit twenty-three of the\nAdirondack Northway; continuing on the Diamond Point road (Warren County\nroute thirty-five) to route nine-N; continuing south on route nine-N\nthrough Lake George, terminating at the intersection of route nine-N and\ninterstate route eighty-seven.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>