<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-GG"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-GG"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="343-GG"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_343_GG">
        <num>343-GG</num>
        <heading>Portion of the state highway system to be designated as the "Southern Adirondack Trail"</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 343-gg. Portion of the state highway system to be designated as the\n"Southern Adirondack Trail". All that portion of the state highway\nsystem beginning at the intersection of the New York state thruway and\nstate route twenty-eight in the village of Herkimer, town of Herkimer,\ncontinuing north on state route twenty-eight through the village of\nNewport and through the village of Poland, thence continuing\nnortheasterly on state route eight and terminating at the intersection\nof state routes eight and thirty in the village of Speculator, and all\nthat portion of Old Piseco lake road from its intersection with state\nroute eight in the vicinity of the southwestern end of Piseco lake\nfollowing along the shoreline of Piseco lake to its intersection with\nroute eight northeast of Piseco lake and all that portion of the state\nhighway system beginning at the intersection of the New York state\nthruway and state route one hundred sixty-nine and running thence\nnorthwesterly along route one hundred sixty-nine until its intersection\nwith state route twenty-eight in the village of Middleville, and all\nthat portion of the state highway system beginning with the intersection\nof state route one hundred sixty-nine with state routes five and one\nhundred sixty-seven in the city of Little Falls, continuing\nnortheasterly along route one hundred sixty-seven to the intersection of\nstate route twenty-nine in the village of Dolgeville, continuing north\nand then west along state route twenty-nine to its beginning at its\nintersection with state routes twenty-eight and one hundred sixty-nine\nin the village of Middleville shall be designated and known as the\n"Southern Adirondack Trail".\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>