<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-K*5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-K*5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-09-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="343-K*5"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-K*5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-K*5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-K*5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-343-K*5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_343_K*5">
        <num>343-K*5</num>
        <heading>Portions of the state highway system to be designated as the "Lake Erie Wine Country Trail", the "Canandaigua Wine Trail", the "Cayuga Wi...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 343-k. Portions of the state highway system to be designated as\nthe "Lake Erie Wine Country Trail", the "Canandaigua Wine Trail", the\n"Cayuga Wine Trail East", the "Cayuga Wine Trail West", the "Between\nCayuga and Seneca Lakes Wine Trail", the "Seneca Lake Wine Trail East",\nthe "Seneca Lake Wine Trail West", the "Keuka Lake Wine Trail", the\n"Shawangunk Wine Trail", the "Dutchess Wine Trail", the "North Fork Wine\nTrail", the "Hamptons Wine Trail", the "Long Island Wine Region", the\n"Niagara Wine Trail Ridge", the "Niagara Wine Trail Lake", the "Lake\nOntario Wine Trail", the "Adirondack Coast Wine Trail", the "St.\nLawrence Wine Trail" and the "Upper Hudson Wine Trail". 1. All that\nportion of the state highway system constituting US route 20 from exit\n61 of I-90 near Ripley to route 5 in Silver Creek shall be designated\nand known as the " Lake Erie Wine Country Trail".\n  2. All that portion of the state highway system constituting route 371\nfrom exit 2 of I-390 in Cohocton to route 21 in North Cohocton, route 21\nto route 332 in Canandaigua, route 332 to route 96 and route 96 to\ncounty route 44 in Ontario county shall be designated and known as the\n"Canandaigua Wine Trail".\n  3. All that portion of the state highway system constituting route 13\nfrom exit 54 of route 17 in Horseheads to route 89 in Ithaca and route\n89 to route 318 near Seneca Falls and route 318 to route 414 and route\n414 to exit 41 of route I-90 shall be designated and known as the\n"Cayuga Wine Trail West". Also all that portion of the state highway\nsystem constituting route 13 from exit 54 of route 17 in Horseheads to\nroute 34 near Ithaca and route 34 to route 34B and route 34B to route 90\nand route 90 to routes 5 &amp; 20 and west on routes 5 &amp; 20 and north on\nroute 414 near Seneca Falls to exit 41 of route I-90 shall be designated\nand known as the "Cayuga Wine Trail East".\n  3-a. All that portion of the state highway system constituting state\nroute 96 from its intersection with state route 13 in Ithaca to the\nintersection of state routes 96, 414 and 96A in Ovid, and then\ncontinuing on state route 96A to its intersection with state routes 5 &amp;\n20 in Geneva, and then continuing on state routes 5 &amp; 20 to their\nintersection with state route 14. Such portions of the state highway\nsystem shall be designated and known as the "Between Cayuga and Seneca\nLakes Wine Trail".\n  4. All that portion of the state highway system constituting route 414\nfrom exit 46 of route 17 in Corning to exit 41 of I-90 shall be known as\nthe "Seneca Lake Wine Trail East", and route 14 in Watkins Glen to exit\n42 of I-90 shall be designated and known as the "Seneca Lake Wine Trail\nWest".\n  5. All that portion of the state highway system constituting state\nroutes 54 from exit 38 of route 17 in Bath to route 14 in Dresden and\nroute 54-A from route 54 in Hammondsport to route 54 in Penn Yan shall\nbe designated and known as the "Keuka Lake Wine Trail".\n  6. All that portion of the state highway system constituting route 94\nfrom Warwick to route 208 in Washingtonville and route 208 to route US\n44 in Ireland Corners and west on route US 44 to route 299 shall be\ndesignated and known as the "Shawangunk Wine Trail".\n  6-a. All that portion of the state highway system constituting route\n32 from route 17 in the unincorporated community of Central Valley\nwithin the town of Woodbury to route 94 in the unincorporated community\nof Vails Gate within the town of New Windsor, route 94 to route 9-W in\nthe town of New Windsor, route 9-W to routes 44 and 55 in the\nunincorporated community of Highland within the town of Lloyd, and\nroutes 44 and 55 to its intersection with route 208 in the town of\nGardiner shall be designated and known as the "Shawangunk East Wine\nTrail".\n  6-b. All that portion of the state highway system starting at the\nintersection of route 9 and route 44 in Poughkeepsie and continuing east\non route 44 to route 82 east of the Taconic State parkway in Pleasant\nValley and north on route 82 to route 199 in Pine Plains and west on\nroute 199 to route 9 in Red Hook and south on route 9 to route 44 in\nPoughkeepsie shall be designated and known as the "Dutchess Wine Trail".\n  7. The "Long Island Wine Region" shall include two trails which shall\nbe designated and known as the "North Fork Wine Trail" and the "Hamptons\nWine Trail". All that portion of the state highway system in the county\nof Suffolk beginning at exit 71 of Interstate 495, thence generally\neasterly along state route 24 to its intersection with county route 105,\nthence generally northerly along county route 105 to its intersection\nwith state route 25, thence generally easterly along state route 25 to\nthe intersection of route 48 and route 25, and westerly along county\nroute 48 (alternatively known as North road, Middle road, Sound avenue)\nfrom its eastern terminus to its intersection with Edwards avenue, and\nthence generally southerly along Edwards avenue to its intersection with\ninterstate 495, shall be designated and known as the "North Fork Wine\nTrail". All that portion of the state highway system in the county of\nSuffolk beginning at the intersection of county route 105 and state\nroute 24, thence generally southeasterly along state route 24 to its\nintersection with state route 27, thence generally easterly along state\nroute 27 to its intersection with state route 114, thence generally\nnortherly along state route 114 to its northern terminus shall be\ndesignated and known as the "Hamptons Wine Trail".\n  7-a. All those portions of the state and local highway system\nconstituting route 104 from the intersection with route 62, Ferry Avenue\nin the city of Niagara Falls, eastward to the intersection with route\n390 in Monroe county shall be known as the "Niagara Wine Trail Ridge."\n  All those portions of the state and local highway system constituting\nRoute 269 from the intersection of Route 104 North to route 18, Lake\nRoad, in the town of Somerset, westward to the intersection with route\n425, Lake Street, in the village of Wilson, southward on route 425 to\nthe intersection with route 62, Niagara Falls Boulevard, in the town of\nWheatfield, southward on route 62 to the intersection with I-290, the\nYoungman Memorial Highway, in the town of Amherst, shall be known as the\n"Niagara Wine Trail Lake."\n  8. All that portion of the state highway system constituting route 104\nfrom the Wayne/Monroe county line to its intersection with U.S. route 11\nin Maple View, continuing north on U.S. route 11 to the unincorporated\narea of Adams Center in the town of Adams, Jefferson county. In addition\nall that portion of the state highway system constituting state route\n350 from its intersection with state route 104 in the unincorporated\narea of Ontario Center in the town of Ontario, Wayne county, to the\nintersection of state route 31 in the town of Macedon and state route 31\nto the Wayne/Monroe county line shall be designated and known as the\n"Lake Ontario Wine Trail".\n  9. All that portion of the state highway system starting at exit 35 of\ninterstate route 87 in the town of Peru and continuing west on state\nroute 442 to its intersection with state route 22, and continuing on\nstate route 22 to its intersection with state route 22B, and continuing\nnorth on state route 22B to its intersection with state route 3 in the\ntown of Plattsburgh, and continuing east on state route 3 to its\nintersection with state route 190, and continuing north on state route\n190 to its intersection with state route 374, and continuing easterly on\nstate route 374 to its intersection with state route 22 in the town of\nPlattsburgh, and continuing northerly on state route 22 to its\nintersection with U.S. route 11 in the town of Mooers, and continuing\neasterly on U.S. route 11 to its intersection with U.S. route 9 in the\ntown of Champlain, and continuing southerly on U.S. route 9 to its\nintersection with state route 3 in the city of Plattsburgh, and\ncontinuing westerly on state route 3 to exit 37 of interstate route 87\nin the town of Plattsburgh shall be designated and known as the\n"Adirondack Coast Wine Trail".\n  10. All that portion of the state highway system beginning at the\nintersection of state route 37 and county route 6 in the town of\nHammond, and continuing north on county route 6 to its intersection with\nstate route 37 in the city of Ogdensburg, and continuing east on state\nroute 37 to its intersection with county route 27 in the town of Lisbon,\nand continuing south on county route 27 to its intersection with county\nroute 10 in the town of Lisbon, and continuing south on county route 10\nto its intersection with state route 68 in the town of Canton, and\ncontinuing south on state route 68 to its intersection with United\nStates route 11 in the village of Canton, and continuing north on United\nStates route 11 to its intersection with state route 11-C in the\nunincorporated area of Stockholm Center in the town of Stockholm, and\ncontinuing north on state route 11-C to its intersection with county\nroute 53 in the unincorporated area of Winthrop in the town of Stockholm\nshall be designated and known as the "St. Lawrence Wine Trail".\n  11. The "Upper Hudson Wine Trail" shall include two trails which shall\nbe designated and known as the "Upper Hudson Wine Trail West" and the\n"Upper Hudson Wine Trail East". All that portion of the state highway\nsystem beginning at the intersection of state route US 20 and state\nroute 146 (Altamont Road) in the town of Guilderland, and continuing\nwest on state route US 20 to state route 30 in the town of Duanesburg,\nand continuing north on state route 30 to state route 67 in the city of\nAmsterdam, and continuing east on state route 67 to state route 50 in\nthe village of Ballston Spa, and continuing north on state route 50 to\nWest avenue in the city of Saratoga Springs, and continuing north on\nWest avenue t</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>