<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-344*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-344*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="344*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-344*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-344*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-344*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-344*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_344*2">
        <num>344*2</num>
        <heading>Construction of sections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 344. Construction of sections. Unless express provision has been\nor hereafter shall be made in this chapter, no section hereof shall be\nconstrued as authorizing the construction or maintenance of any portion\nof a highway within the limits of any city, excepting that portion of a\nthird class city lying outside of its corporation tax district where\nsuch city embraces the entire area of a former township; also excepting\nthe construction of the pipe line boulevard in the southern part of the\ncounties of Queens and Kings, but not the maintenance thereof; also\nexcepting the maintenance of that section of state highway number five\nthousand two hundred twenty lying within the limits of the city of North\nTonawanda, county of Niagara, a distance of approximately 1.2 miles; and\nalso excepting the maintenance of that section of state highway number\nfive thousand seventy-eight known as Genesee street, all of state\nhighway 57-4 and the section of state highway number one thousand one\nhundred sixty lying within the corporation tax limits of the city of\nOneida, county of Madison, a distance of approximately nine thousand\nfour hundred thirty-eight and one-half feet. This section shall not be\nconstrued to apply to the construction or maintenance of state thruways\nor any work of construction or maintenance in connection therewith.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 344's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>