<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-347"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-347"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="347"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-347/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-347/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-347/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-347/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_347">
        <num>347</num>
        <heading>Property for state thruways, bridges thereon, and other thruway uses and purposes to be acquired by appropriation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 347. Property for state thruways, bridges thereon, and other thruway\nuses and purposes to be acquired by appropriation. 1. Notwithstanding\nany inconsistent provisions of this chapter or any other law, general or\nspecial, any and all property necessary for the construction,\nreconstruction and maintenance of state thruways and bridges thereon,\nshall be acquired pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law.\n  2. The commissioner of transportation, for the people of the state of\nNew York, shall acquire pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law any\nproperty or interest therein, necessary for any and all purposes\nconnected with the construction, reconstruction and maintenance of the\nthruway system of the state of New York, including the acquisition of\nproperty for drains, ditches, spoil banks, gravel pits, stone quarries;\nalso for the removal of obstructions, improvement of sight distances;\nalso for acquisition of property for the reconstruction of existing\nhighway-railroad separation structures upon incorporation into a state\nthruway of an existing highway or portion thereof of which they form a\npart, and for the separation of thruway-railroad grades on newly\nlaid-out thruways; and for other purposes to improve safety conditions\non the thruway routes.\n  3. The commissioner of transportation shall cause to be prepared an\naccurate acquisition map of any property which he may deem necessary for\npurposes connected with such thruway projects or of any property in and\nto which he may deem the acquisition or exercise of an easement,\ninterest or right to be necessary for such purposes, indicating and\ndescribing in each case the particular easement, interest or right. On\nthe approval of such acquisition map by the commissioner of\ntransportation, he shall acquire such property, easements, interests or\nrights pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law.\n  4. If the commissioner shall determine, prior to the filing of such\ncopy of the acquisition map in the office of the county clerk as\naforesaid, that changes, alterations or modifications of such\ndescription and map as filed in the main office of the New York state\nthruway authority should be made, he or she shall, subject to the\nprovisions in article two of the eminent domain procedure law if\napplicable, direct the preparation of an amended acquisition map, either\nby preparing a new map or by making changes on the original tracing of\nsuch map, with a notation indicating such changes. On the approval of\nsuch amended map by the commissioner, it shall be filed in the main\noffice of the New York state thruway authority in the same manner as the\noriginal map was filed and the amended map shall thereupon in all\nrespects and for all purposes supersede the map previously filed.\n  5. If the commissioner shall determine prior to filing a copy of the\nmap in the office of the county clerk or register as provided in section\nfour hundred two of the eminent domain procedure law, that such map\nshould be withdrawn, he or she shall file a certificate of withdrawal in\nthe offices of the New York state thruway authority and department of\nlaw. Upon the filing of such certificate of withdrawal, the map to which\nit refers shall be cancelled and all rights thereunder shall cease and\ndetermine.\n  6. The commissioner of transportation shall deliver to the attorney\ngeneral a copy of such acquisition map whereupon it shall be the duty of\nthe attorney general to advise and certify to the commissioner of\ntransportation the names of the owners of the property, easements,\ninterests or rights described in the said acquisition map, including the\nowners of any right, title or interest therein pursuant to the\nrequirements of section four hundred three of the eminent domain\nprocedure law.\n  7. If, at or after the vesting of title to such property in the people\nof the state of New York in the manner provided in the eminent domain\nprocedure law, the commissioner of transportation, or such duly\nauthorized representative or agency which has succeeded him in the\njurisdiction of the property so acquired, shall deem it necessary to\ncause the removal of an owner or other occupant from such property, he\nmay cause such owner or other occupant to be removed therefrom by\nproceeding in accordance with section four hundred five of such law. The\nproceedings shall in all instances be brought in the name of the\ncommissioner of transportation as agent of the state. If any person\nproceeded against shall contest the petition by an answer raising any\nmaterial issue, the attorney general shall be notified, and he\nthereafter shall represent the petitioner in the proceedings. No\nexecution shall issue for costs, if any, awarded against the state or\nthe commissioner of transportation, but they shall be part of the costs\nof the acquisition and be paid in like manner. Proceedings may be\nbrought separately against one or more of the owners or other occupants\nof a property, or one proceeding may be brought against all or several\nof the owners or other occupants of any or all property within the\nterritorial jurisdiction of the same justice or judge; judgment shall\neffect or be made for immediate removal of persons defaulting in\nappearance or in answering, or withdrawing their answers, if any,\nwithout awaiting the trial or decision of issues raised by contestants,\nif any.\n  9. The commissioner of transportation upon making any agreement\nprovided for in section three hundred four of the eminent domain\nprocedure law shall deliver to the comptroller such agreement and a\ncertificate stating the amount due such owner or owners thereunder on\naccount of such appropriation of his or their property and the amount so\nfixed shall be paid out of the state treasury from moneys appropriated\nfor the construction, reconstruction and maintenance of state thruways\nand bridges thereon, but not until there shall have been filed with the\ncomptroller a certificate of the attorney general showing the person or\npersons claiming the amount so agreed upon to be legally entitled\nthereto.\n  10. Application for reimbursement of incidental expenses as provided\nin section seven hundred two of the eminent domain procedure law shall\nbe made to the commissioner upon forms prescribed by him and shall be\naccompanied by such information and evidence as the commissioner may\nrequire. Upon approval of such application, the commissioner shall\ndeliver a copy thereof to the comptroller together with a certificate\nstating the amount due thereof, and the amount so fixed shall be paid\nout of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from monies\nappropriated for the acquisition of property under this section.\n  11. The commissioner of transportation, with the approval of the\ndirector of the budget, shall establish and may from time to time amend\nrules and regulations authorizing the payment of actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses of occupants of property acquired pursuant to\nthis section; of actual direct losses of tangible personal property as a\nresult of moving or discontinuing a business or farm operation, but not\nexceeding an amount equal to the reasonable expenses that would have\nbeen required to relocate such property, as determined by the\ncommissioner; and actual reasonable expenses in searching for a\nreplacement business or farm; or in hardship cases for the advance\npayment of such expenses and losses. For the purposes of making payment\nof such expenses and losses only the term "business" means any lawful\nactivity conducted primarily for assisting in the purchase, sale,\nresale, manufacture, processing or marketing of products, commodities,\npersonal property or services by the erection and maintenance of an\noutdoor advertising display or displays, whether or not such display or\ndisplays are located on the premises on which any of the above\nactivities are conducted. Such rules and regulations may further define\nthe terms used in this subdivision. In lieu of such actual reasonable\nand necessary moving expenses, any such displaced owner or tenant of\nresidential property may elect to accept a moving expense allowance,\nplus a dislocation allowance, determined in accordance with a schedule\nprepared by the commissioner and made a part of such rules and\nregulations. In lieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses, any such displaced owner or tenant of commercial property who\nrelocates or discontinues his business or farm operation may elect to\naccept a fixed relocation payment in an amount equal to the average\nannual net earnings of the business or farm operation, except that such\npayment shall be not less than two thousand five hundred dollars nor\nmore than ten thousand dollars. In the case of a business, no such fixed\nrelocation payment shall be made unless the commissioner finds and\ndetermines that the business cannot be relocated without a substantial\nloss of its existing patronage, and that the business is not part of a\ncommercial enterprise having at least one other establishment, which is\nnot being acquired by the state or the United States, which is engaged\nin the same or similar business. In the case of a business which is to\nbe discontinued but for which the findings and determinations set forth\nabove cannot be made, the commissioner may prepare an estimate of what\nthe actual reasonable and necessary moving expenses, exclusive of any\nstorage charges, would be if the business were to be relocated and enter\ninto an agreed settlement with the owner of such business for an amount\nnot to exceed such estimate in lieu of such actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses. Application for payment under this\nsubdivision shall be made to the commissioner upon forms prescribed by\nhim and shall be accompanied by such information and evidence as the\ncommissioner may require. Upon approval of such applica</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>