<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="349-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_349_CC">
        <num>349-CC</num>
        <heading>New York state scenic byways advisory board</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To develop and make recommendations to the commissioner on the\norganization and operation of a scenic byways program. Such\nrecommendations shall include recommendations on the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>consideration of the scenic beauty and historic significance of\nhighways proposed for designation as scenic byways and the areas\nsurrounding such highways;\n  (ii) operation and management standards for highways designated as\nscenic byways, including strategies for maintaining or improving the\nqualities for which a highway is designated as a scenic byway, for\nprotecting and enhancing the landscape and view corridors surrounding\nsuch a highway, and for minimizing traffic congestion on such a highway;\n  (iii) standards for scenic byway related signs, including those which\nidentify highways as scenic byways;\n  (iv) standards for maintaining highway safety on the scenic byway\nsystem;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_CC__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>measures to safely accommodate the largest variety of scenic byway\nusers including, but not limited to, persons travelling by automobile,\nrecreation vehicle, motor coach, bicycle, snowmobile, watercraft, horse\nand by foot;\n  (vi) design review procedures for location of highway facilities,\nlandscaping, and travellers facilities on the scenic byway system;\n  (vii) procedures for reviewing and terminating the designation of a\nhighway designated as a scenic byway;\n  (viii) such other matters as may be necessary or desirable to further\nthe purposes of this program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_349_CC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To evaluate and recommend to the commissioner and the legislature\namendments of the statutes and regulations relevant to the furtherance\nof a cohesive system of scenic byways.\n  3. The advisory board shall report to the governor and the legislature\nwithin one year of the effective date of this article, and by January\nfirst each year thereafter on the implementation of this program. In the\nfirst report required by this subdivision, the advisory board shall\nprovide a scenic byways program implementation plan identifying\nessential components for the New York state scenic byways system, and\nrecommending actions by the legislature that may be necessary to\nimplement a cohesive and coordinated scenic byways program that will\nserve the goals of preserving and protecting scenic, historic,\nrecreational, cultural and archeological resources, enhancing\nrecreation, economic development through tourism and education in the\nhistory and culture of New York state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>