<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-AA"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-AA"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="349-AA"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_349_AA">
        <num>349-AA</num>
        <heading>Statement of intent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 349-aa. Statement of intent. The legislature hereby finds that\ncertain portions of the state highway system are notable for their\nscenic, historic, recreational, cultural and archeological value and\nworthy of designation as scenic byways to provide special consideration\nof their unique features and special role in the highway system.\n  The legislature further finds that the public interest would be served\nby the formation of a coordinated scenic byways program to enhance\nrecreation, preserve and protect scenic, historic, recreational,\ncultural and archeological resources, encourage economic development\nthrough tourism, improve the transportation system, and educate\nresidents and visitors of the history and culture of this state.\n  The legislature further finds that several programs administered by\nvarious agencies of state government exist to assess scenic quality of\nhighway corridors, to maintain state highways and rights-of-way, and to\nplan for recreation to promote economic development through tourism.\n  The legislature further finds that several not-for-profit\norganizations exist to encourage public participation in the enhancement\nof designated highway routes, and to coordinate and promote tourism\nalong such designated highway routes.\n  It is therefore the intent of the legislature to establish a scenic\nbyways program in the department of transportation to guide and\ncoordinate the activities of state agencies, local governments and\nnot-for-profit organizations in order to create a comprehensive program\nthat will better serve the public interest.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>