<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-09-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="349-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_349_B">
        <num>349-B</num>
        <heading>Declaration of policy</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 349-b. Declaration of policy. The modernization and the construction\nof arterial highways which are to pass through cities, will contribute\ngreatly to post-war reemployment and to the stimulation of industrial\nrecovery. The resources and the technical skills that are available to\nthe state for these purposes, should be used for the benefit of the\ncities upon the principle that the construction of such arterial\nhighways is a matter of state concern. However, it is the manifest\nintention of the state to recognize and to preserve the powers or rights\nheretofore conferred upon or delegated to any city to regulate the\nproperty, affairs or government thereof, in the modernization and the\nconstruction of such arterial highways. The integration of such arterial\nhighways in the system of state highways throughout the state\ncontemplates an expenditure of public funds to pay the costs that are\nattendant upon the fulfilment of a program of the work of modernization\nand construction as herein mentioned, as well as of the maintenance of\nsuch public ways. It is hereby declared to be the purpose of this act to\ninitiate the procedure that is prerequisite to any project of the\nmagnitude herein provided, to the end that orderly progress and\nequitable distribution of effort and moneys may be observed in the\nadministration of this article, and, from time to time, when expressly\nauthorized by the legislature, any section of such arterial highways may\nbe constituted, constructed, reconstructed, improved and maintained as a\npart of the state highway system.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>