<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="349-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_349_D">
        <num>349-D</num>
        <heading>Application of law, rules, conditions and regulations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 349-d. Application of law, rules, conditions and regulations. All\nprovisions of this chapter and all rules, conditions and regulations by\nthe commissioner of transportation that are consistent with the\nprovisions of this article, shall be applicable to the performance of\nthe acts herein specified, and, notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovisions of this chapter, or any other laws, general or special, the\ncommissioner is authorized and empowered to carry out the provisions of\nthis article and to perform and do such other and further acts not\nhereby specifically provided in this article as may be necessary\nhereunder, provided however that no public street, main route or\nthoroughfare or any portion thereof, that is designated in this article,\nshall be deemed to be a part of the system of highways of the state of\nNew York for purposes of maintenance and repair, until (1) such public\nstreet, main route or thoroughfare or any portion thereof shall have\nbeen constructed, reconstructed or improved as provided in this article,\nand (2) such commissioner shall have issued an official order declaring\nsuch public street, main route or thoroughfare or any portion thereof,\nexclusive of service roads and intersecting street bridges, to be a part\nof such system of highways for such purposes of maintenance and repair.\nSuch official order shall specify the date when the provisions thereof\nshall become effective, and shall be filed in the office of the\ndepartment of transportation of the state of New York, and a certified\ncopy thereof shall be filed (1) in the office of the department of state\nand (2) in the office of the clerk or of the official who performs the\nrelated functions of the city in which such public street, main route or\nthoroughfare or any portion thereof is located.  Upon completion of such\nfiling, all such provisions of this chapter and all such rules,\nconditions and regulations shall be applicable as stated in this\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>