<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-09-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="349-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-349-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_349_E">
        <num>349-E</num>
        <heading>Cities named; streets designated</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 349-e. Cities named; streets designated. The cities, outside of New\nYork city, affected by this article, and the public streets designated\nherein, as aforesaid, are as follows, viz:\n                             CITY OF ALBANY\n  Southside Route, beginning at the Albany city line west of Krumkill\nroad, thence southeasterly to the Albany city line east of Krumkill road\n-- also from a point on the Albany city line east of the Slingerlands\nby-pass, southeasterly crossing Delaware avenue in the vicinity of the\nNew York State thruway in the city of Albany, thence southeasterly\ngenerally paralleling the New York thruway to an intersection with the\nMid-Crosstown Arterial in the vicinity of McCarthy avenue, continuing\ngenerally easterly crossing South Pearl street near McCarthy avenue and\ngenerally northeasterly through the Delaware and Hudson railroad yards\nto and on or near Green street to a traffic interchange with the South\nMall expressway. Approximate length 4.8 miles.\n  Riverfront Route, beginning at a traffic interchange with the South\nMall expressway, thence northerly along or in the vicinity of the west\nshore of the Hudson river to the northerly city line of Albany.\nApproximate length 2.6 miles.\n  Fuller Road Alternate, beginning at the southerly city line of Albany,\nwest of Fuller road, thence on new location northerly to the north city\nline of Albany. Approximate length 0.9 mile.\n  Washington Avenue-Northside Route, beginning at a traffic interchange\nwith the Fuller Road Alternate, thence southeasterly along or in the\nvicinity of Washington avenue to a point west of Tudor road, thence on\nnew location easterly and southeasterly, generally paralleling the New\nYork Central Railroad to the vicinity of Northern boulevard, continuing\neasterly and southeasterly to the Albany city line, on a new bridge over\nthe Hudson river in the vicinity of Lower Patroon island, including\ntraffic interchanges with the Crosstown Route, Mid-Crosstown Arterial\nand the Riverfront Route. Approximate length 6.3 miles.\n  Crosstown Route, beginning at the southerly city line near Krumkill\nroad, thence northeasterly in the vicinity of Seminole avenue extended,\nSeminole avenue and Brevator street to Washington avenue, thence\nnorthwesterly to an intersection with the Washington Avenue-Northside\nRoute. Approximate length 2.2 miles.\n  Mid-Crosstown Arterial, beginning at the southerly city line, state\nhighway nine thousand one hundred one, thence northerly along Southern\nboulevard to a traffic interchange with the Southside Route near McCarty\navenue, thence continuing northerly on new location to Second avenue\nnear Frisbie avenue, thence northerly and northeasterly on new location\ncrossing Delaware and Holland avenues to a point on Myrtle avenue west\nof Lark street, thence northerly and northeasterly on new location\nthrough Washington park, thence northeasterly on new location generally\nparalleling Northern boulevard to a traffic interchange with the\nWashington Avenue-Northside Route and continuing northeasterly and\nnortherly on or in the vicinity of Loudonville road to the northerly\ncity line, state highway twenty-two, including connections with certain\nexisting streets and/or relocations of certain existing streets as\ndetermined by the commissioner; also from the intersection of\nLoudonville road at or near Northern boulevard, thence northeasterly on\nor along Northern boulevard and northerly on or along Van Rensselaer\nboulevard to the city line, at state highway one thousand five hundred\neighteen. Portions of this arterial route within and in the vicinity of\nWashington park may be built as a depressed highway as determined by the\ncommissioner. Approximate length 4.9 miles.\n  Sheridan Valley Arterial, beginning at an intersection with the\nRiverfront Route in the vicinity of Livingston avenue, as determined by\nthe commissioner, thence generally westerly and northwesterly in the\nvicinity of Clinton avenue to the vicinity of the Mid-Crosstown\nArterial, as determined by the commissioner, including connections with\nexisting streets and/or relocations of such existing streets.\nApproximate length 1.0 mile.\n  Mall Arterial, beginning at an interchange with the Riverfront Route\nin the vicinity of Madison avenue, thence generally northwesterly on new\nlocation in the vicinity of Hudson avenue to a traffic interchange with\nthe Mid-Crosstown Arterial, as determined by the commissioner, including\nconnections with existing streets and/or relocations of such existing\nstreets. Approximate length 1.1 miles.\n  Notwithstanding the provisions of section three hundred forty-nine-c\nof this article, the commissioner of transportation may acquire at state\nexpense, at anytime prior to April first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine,\nfor state highway purposes, pursuant to section thirty of this chapter,\nproperty within three hundred fifty feet of right of way acquired for\narterial highways or interstate highways in the city of Albany, for the\npurpose of controlling access to such highways.\n                            CITY OF AMSTERDAM\n  Beginning at a point on the northwesterly city line of Amsterdam, at\nstate highway one hundred eight thence on or along West Main street to\nthe vicinity of Caroline street, thence on new location south of and\ngenerally parallel to West Main street and East Main street to a point\non the southeasterly city line of Amsterdam, at state highway one\nhundred eighty, including necessary connections to East Main street in\nthe vicinity of Railroad street; also from a point on this route in the\nvicinity of Schuyler street, returning northwesterly on new location to\na point in the vicinity of the intersection of Liberty street and Grove\nstreet, thence on or along Grove street to Market street, thence\ngenerally westerly to a connection with the arterial route in the\nvicinity of Wall street. Approximate length 4.4 miles.\n  Beginning at the southwesterly city line of Amsterdam, at state\nhighway thirty-two, thence northeasterly along Minaville street to the\nvicinity of DeStefano avenue, thence northeasterly on new location to\nRiver street, including a connection to Bridge street in the vicinity of\nRiver street, continuing northeasterly on The New Amsterdam Bridge\ncrossing the Mohawk river and the N. Y. C. R. R. (Main Line) to Church\nstreet at East Main street, including a connection from the northerly\nend of said new bridge southeasterly to a point on the arterial route on\nnew location south of and generally parallel to East Main Street,\ncontinuing along Church street to the vicinity of Gardiner lane,\nincluding any necessary connections between Church street and Guy Park\navenue in the vicinity of High street, thence on new location northerly\nto Market street in the vicinity of Prospect street, including a\nconnection between Church street and Market street, continuing northerly\non or in the vicinity of Market street to the northerly city line of\nAmsterdam, at state highway nine thousand forty-three; also from a point\non this route in the vicinity of Prospect street southwesterly along\nMarket street to a point in the vicinity of Greene street, thence on new\nlocation to Pearl street at Division street, thence on or along Pearl\nstreet to the intersection of West Main street in the vicinity of Pearl\nstreet, also continuing from a point near this intersection and on new\nlocation southeasterly to the approach of said new bridge crossing the\nMohawk river. Approximate length 3.5 miles.\n  Beginning at a point to be determined by the commissioner of\ntransportation on the westerly city line of Amsterdam south of Broadway,\nthence on new location easterly to the vicinity of and on or along\nDeStefano avenue to the vicinity of Saint John street, thence on new\nlocation easterly to a point to be determined by the commissioner of\ntransportation on the southerly city line of Amsterdam, in the vicinity\nof state highway five hundred thirteen. Approximate length 1.6 miles.\n  Beginning on Church street in the vicinity of Gardiner lane, thence\nnortheasterly, easterly and northeasterly along Church street to the\neasterly city line of Amsterdam, at state highway two hundred\nninety-eight. Approximate length 1.5 miles.\n                             CITY OF AUBURN\n  1. Beginning at the westerly Auburn city line, south of Clark street,\nthence easterly on new location to Washington street, easterly on or in\nthe vicinity of Clark and Dill streets and new location to Franklin\nstreet, Franklin street to Grant avenue and northeasterly along Grant\navenue to the northerly Auburn city line, state highway five hundred\nninety-two; also returning from Franklin street in the vicinity of John\nstreet westerly on new location to Jefferson street. Approximate length\n4.4 miles.\n  2. Beginning at the intersection of North street in the vicinity of\nWater street, thence northerly along North street to the northerly\nAuburn city line, state highway one thousand three hundred seventeen.\nApproximate length 1.4 miles.\n  3. Beginning at the intersection of East Genesee and John streets,\nthence easterly along East Genesee street to the easterly Auburn city\nline, state highway nine thousand thirty-seven. Approximate length 1.2\nmiles.\n  4. Beginning at the southerly Auburn city line, state highway three\nhundred eighty-three, thence northwesterly and northerly on or in the\nvicinity of Owasco and Fulton streets to an intersection with Franklin\nstreet, including a connection from Fulton street along Grant avenue to\nFranklin street; also from the intersection of Walnut and Owasco streets\nnorthwesterly on or in the vicinity of Owasco and John streets to\nFranklin street. Approximate length 1.4 miles.\n  5. Beginning at a point on the westerly Auburn city line in the\nvicinity of West Genesee street, as determined by the commissioner of\ntransportation, thence generally southerl</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>