<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-38"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-38"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="38"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-38/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-38/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-38/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-38/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_38">
        <num>38</num>
        <heading>Contracts for construction or improvement of highways</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_38__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a contract shall in the judgment of the commissioner of\ntransportation be substantially completed, the commissioner of\ntransportation may, provided the regional director certifies that the\nessential items in the contract have been completed in accordance with\nthe terms of the contract and the provisions of this chapter, direct the\nregional director to include in the final account such uncompleted items\nand pay therefor at the item prices in the contract upon the contractor\ndepositing with the commissioner of transportation a certified check\ndrawn upon a legally incorporated bank or trust company equal to at\nleast double the value of such uncompleted work or, with the approval of\nthe state comptroller, securities as are listed in subdivision three of\nsection one hundred thirty-nine of the state finance law, equal to at\nleast double the value of such uncompleted work. The deposit may be used\nby the commissioner of transportation to complete the uncompleted\nportion of the contract and shall be returned to the contractor if he\ncompletes the uncompleted portion within a specified number of working\ndays after he has been notified to proceed with the work.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_38__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No certificates approving or authorizing a partial or final\npayment shall be made by the commissioner of transportation until he is\nsatisfied that all laborers employed on the work have been paid for\ntheir services for the last payroll period preceding the said partial or\nfinal payment. The commissioner of transportation may, if he deems\nnecessary, require an affidavit to such effect from the contractor or he\nmay depend on any other source which he deems proper for such\ninformation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_38__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No such certificate approving or authorizing the first partial\npayment or any final payment to a foreign contractor shall be made\nunless such contractor shall furnish satisfactory proof that all taxes\ndue the state tax commission by such contractor, under the provisions of\nor pursuant to a law enacted pursuant to the authority of article nine,\nnine-a, twelve-a, sixteen, sixteen-a, twenty-one, twenty-two,\ntwenty-three, twenty-eight, twenty-nine or thirty of the tax law or\narticle two-E of the general city law have been paid. The certificate of\nthe state tax commission to the effect that all such taxes have been\npaid shall be, for purpose of this paragraph, conclusive proof of the\npayment of such taxes. The term "foreign contractor" as used in this\nsubdivision means, in the case of an individual, a person who is not a\nresident of this state, in the case of a partnership, one having one or\nmore partners not a resident of this state, and in the case of a\ncorporation, one not organized under the laws of this state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_38__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payment of the moneys due under a contract shall be made in\naccordance with the provisions of article eleven-A of the state finance\nlaw, provided failure to make such payment, as heretofore prescribed,\nshall not be due to any fault, neglect, or omission on the part of the\ncontractor or by reason of the filing of any lien, attachment, or other\nlegal process against the money due said contractor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_38__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purpose of making a final payment on a highway\nconstruction contract, the date to be used for determining the receipt\nof an invoice in subdivision two of section one hundred seventy-nine-f\nof the state finance law shall be the date on which the contract work\nhas been accepted as completed by the commissioner of transportation.\n  8. Contingencies and extra work. Whenever the commissioner of\ntransportation determines that from any unforeseen cause the terms of\nany contract should be altered to provide for contingencies or extra\nwork, he may, if funds are available for payment of the cost thereof,\nissue an order on contract therefor to the contractor, a copy of which\nshall be filed with the director of the budget and the state\ncomptroller. The estimated expenditure pursuant to the order on contract\nshall not increase the total amount of the primary contract until the\nestimated expenditure shall have been approved by the commissioner of\ntransportation and a duplicate of such approval shall have been filed\nwith the comptroller. No such extra work shall be commenced or\nundertaken until the commissioner of transportation has issued an order\non contract as herein provided.\n  When such order on contract provides for similar items of work or\nmaterials which increase or decrease the itemized quantity provided for\nin the primary contract, the price to be paid therefor shall not exceed\nthe unit bid price in the primary contract for such items. Agreed prices\nfor new items of work or materials may be incorporated in the order on\ncontract as the commissioner of transportation may deem them to be just\nand fair and beneficial to the state.\n  Whenever the commissioner of transportation also determines that in\nthe cases herein provided it is impracticable for him to ascertain in\nadvance the just and fair price to be paid by the state for new items of\nwork or materials, the order on contract therefor may provide for\nperformance of the work and the fu...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_38__subsec_g__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the\namount involved therein as shown by such petition does not exceed five\nthousand dollars or five per centum of the final estimate of the\ncompleted contract, whichever is greater,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_38__subsec_g__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the contractor has\ncomplied with all provisions of the contract that relate to the filing\nof any protest and also of any statement concerning the subject-matter\nthereof, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_38__subsec_g__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the contractor shall expressly agree in such petition\nthat any determination as hereinafter provided, shall be final and\nconclusive upon all parties thereto. If the commissioner of\ntransportation grants such petition, he shall, within a reasonable time,\nmail a notice to the contractor which shall specify the place of such\nhearing and the date thereof which shall be within thirty days after the\nmailing of such notice. Within ten days after such mailing, the\ncommissioner of transportation shall also mail a copy of the petition\nand of such notice of hearing to the attorney general, who together with\nthe commissioner of transportation, shall constitute a board to</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_38__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hear\nsuch dispute, either personally or by any duly authorized officer or\nemployee of their respective departments, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_38__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>determine the issues\nthereof.\n  Any amount fixed in the determination to be paid to the contractor\nshall be deemed to be a special item to be incorporated in a final\nsupplemental contract and shall be payable from monies available for\nconstruction and reconstruction of state highways, on the audit and\nwarrant of the comptroller on vouchers approved by the commissioner of\ntransportation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>