<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-47"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-47"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="47"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-47/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-47/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-47/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-47/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47">
        <num>47</num>
        <heading>Connecting highways in villages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 47. Connecting highways in villages. The board of trustees of a\nvillage may, by resolution, petition the commissioner of transportation\nfor the construction or improvement of a highway to connect streets or\nhighways within the village which have been paved or improved with state\nhighways which have been heretofore built under the provisions of\nchapter one hundred and fifteen of the laws of eighteen hundred and\nninety-eight, and the acts amendatory thereof.  If in the judgment of\nthe commissioner of transportation public convenience requires the\nconstruction or improvement of such connecting highway, the commissioner\nshall cause plans, specifications and estimates to be prepared, and\nshall cause the same to be transmitted to the board of supervisors of\nthe county wherein such highway is situated.  The board of supervisors\nmay thereupon take action on such plans and specifications and adopt a\nresolution relating to such construction or improvement. Notwithstanding\nany other provision of this chapter, the cost of such construction or\nimprovement shall be borne and payment thereof shall be made in the\nmanner as provided for in section two hundred and sixty-four. A\ncertified copy of such resolution shall be filed in the office of the\ndepartment of transportation. The construction or improvement of such\nconnecting highway shall then be taken up in the order and manner\nprovided in section two hundred and sixty-one for the construction or\nimprovement of state highways. If it is desired to construct or improve\nany portion of such a connecting highway at a width greater than that\nprovided for in the plans and specifications therefor, or if a\nmodification of such plans and specifications is desired by which the\ncost thereof will be increased, the board of trustees of the village\nshall proceed as in section forty-six to secure such a modification of\nthe plans and specifications as will provide for such desired\nconstruction. The provisions of such section shall apply in like manner\nto the connecting highway to be constructed or improved as provided in\nthis section.\n  The provisions of this act shall not prevent the improvement by state\naid under the statute as it existed prior to the passage of this act, of\nstreets in cities of the second and third class, where, prior to the\npassage of this act, highway numbers had been assigned as provided by\narticle twelve of this act; nor shall the provisions of this act prevent\nthe improvement in such cities of streets heretofore petitioned for and\napproved in cases where the proposed improvement of each street does not\nexceed one and one-half miles in length; but the total mileage of all\nsuch streets not exceeding one and one-half miles in length shall not in\nthe aggregate exceed four miles.\n  Wherever plans for such improvement in a city of the second class have\nbeen approved and a highway number assigned, and the work is ready for\ncontract as hereinbefore described and the common council of such city\nhas appropriated and made available the city's share of the cost of such\nimprovement, the city treasurer of such city is hereby authorized,\nempowered and directed to deposit such moneys with the state comptroller\nin the same manner as is provided by this section with regard to the\nimprovement of village streets.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>