<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-57"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-57"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="57"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-57/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-57/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-57/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-57/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_57">
        <num>57</num>
        <heading>Maintenance by state of canal bridge approaches</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 57. Maintenance by state of canal bridge approaches. Where a\nwaterway which is a part of the canal system of the state intersects a\nstate highway which is maintained adjacent to such intersection pursuant\nto this article, the pavement and shoulders of the approaches to the\nbridge structure carrying such highway across such waterway and the area\nformerly occupied by any such bridge which has been removed and replaced\nby a fill by the state commissioner of transportation, shall be\nconsidered eligible for maintenance under this chapter, providing such\napproach or fill has, in the opinion of the commissioner of\ntransportation, been properly graded in connection with the construction\nof the canal system of the state. The commissioner of transportation may\nat any time make an order directing that such section of highway become\na part of the system of state highways in such county, and thereafter\nthe pavement and shoulders of such approach shall be maintained as a\nstate highway. Such order shall be served upon the chairman of the board\nof supervisors and a certified copy thereof shall be filed in the office\nof the county clerk and one in the office of the state comptroller. In\nmaintaining such section of highway the commissioner of transportation\nmay lay such type of pavement as in his opinion is advisable.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>