<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-59"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-59"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="59"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-59/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-59/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-59/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-59/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_59">
        <num>59</num>
        <heading>Additional width, different type of construction or other additional work under repair or reconstruction contracts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 59. Additional width, different type of construction or other\nadditional work under repair or reconstruction contracts. Whenever in\nthe maintenance, repair or reconstruction of state highways the\ncommissioner of transportation shall have determined upon the necessity\nof resurfacing or reconstructing such highway, the county, town or\nvillage wherein the highway is located may petition the commissioner of\ntransportation to provide an additional width, a different type of\npavement, or both, or any additional work or any or all of same, in the\nplans providing for such resurfacing or reconstruction.\n  The additional expense of such widening, different type of\nconstruction or additional work shall be borne wholly by such county,\ntown or village and the provisions of sections forty-six, forty-eight\nand forty-nine shall apply to such additional width, different type of\nconstruction or any additional work under such repair or reconstruction\ncontract in the same manner as under a construction contract as provided\nin those sections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>