<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="80-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_80_A">
        <num>80-A</num>
        <heading>State prefinancing of federal share of non-state highway projects</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 80-a. State prefinancing of federal share of non-state highway\nprojects. In connection with the undertaking by a municipality of a\nnon-state highway project for which the commissioner is authorized to\nuse moneys of the federal government pursuant to the provisions of\nsection eighty of this chapter the commissioner is hereby authorized to\nadvance from any state highway appropriation made in the first instance\nand subject to subsequent reimbursement in accordance with the\nprovisions of Title 23, U.S. Code, "Highways" to such municipality the\nshare of the federal government of such project.\n  The first instance advances herein authorized shall be available only\nafter the Federal Highway Administration, Department of Transportation\nof the United States of America, shall notify the commissioner of\ntransportation that each specific project for which such first instance\nadvances are contemplated have been approved and that the required share\nof federal funds which have been apportioned to the State of New York\nfor expenditure have been entered on the official records of such\nFederal Highway Administration, Department of Transportation, as a\ncommitment of such funds.\n  The commissioner shall undertake such supervision and management of\nthe municipal project so advanced in order to fulfill any and all\nagreements with the Federal Highway Administration in order to assure\nfederal reimbursement of the first instance advances herein authorized.\n  The commissioner shall provide for the management of the first\ninstance advances and federal reimbursements herein authorized in a\nmanner consistent with the management of any other federally aided state\nhighway construction project.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>