<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-12-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="80-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-80-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_80_B">
        <num>80-B</num>
        <heading>Construction or improvement by the department of transportation partly at municipal expense</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_80_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of money that has been deposited by such\nmunicipality with the state comptroller as hereinbefore provided, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_80_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all disbursements made pursuant to this section for such project.\nAny surplus moneys shall be paid to such municipality on the warrant of\nthe comptroller on vouchers therefor approved by the commissioner. When\nthe work of such project has been completed and it is determined by the\ncommissioner that the amount of the cost to be borne by the municipality\nis in excess of the amount deposited by such municipality with the state\ncomptroller, the commissioner shall then notify the municipality of the\ndeficiency of funds. The municipality shall then within ninety days of\nthe receipt of such notice, pay such amount to the state comptroller.\nFor purposes of this section, the term "municipality" shall include a\ncity, county, town, village or two or more of the foregoing acting\njointly.\n  2. For each fiscal year set out in the schedule hereinbelow amounts\nshall be distributed pursuant to annual appropriation from the dedicated\nhighway and bridge trust fund or by authorization by the legislature for\nthe state share of municipal street and highway capital projects in an\namount set out in such schedule for the corresponding state fiscal year:\nState Fiscal Year                                          Appropriation\n1993-94                                                      $45,000,000\n1994-95                                                      $35,000,000\n1995-96                                                      $45,000,000\n1996-97                                                      $35,000,000\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>