<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="HAY">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-84"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-84"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="84"/>
          <FRBRname value="HAY"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-84/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-84/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-84/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/hay/section-84/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_84">
        <num>84</num>
        <heading>Construction or reconstruction of any road or highway in connection with projects on the principal secondary and feeder roads</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 84. Construction or reconstruction of any road or highway in\nconnection with projects on the principal secondary and feeder roads.\nThe commissioner of transporation may, upon the request of a county\nthrough its board of supervisors, include in any project on the federal\nprincipal secondary and feeder road system, any work of construction,\nreconstruction or improvement of any road or highway that is located\nwithin the boundaries of such county and that is or shall form a\ncontinuation or extension of any such principal secondary and feeder\nroad or shall be in connection therewith. Whenever the commissioner of\ntransportation shall approve such a request of a county, he shall cause\nsurveys and plans to be made either by the county or by the department\nof transportation. Estimates of the construction and engineering costs\nshall be made and submitted to the commissioner of transportation for\napproval. If approved, such county shall thereupon deposit such\nestimated amounts of monies with the comptroller, who is authorized to\nreceive and accept the same for the purpose of this section, subject to\nthe draft or requisition of the commissioner of transportation. Upon the\ncompletion and acceptance of the construction work, the commissioner of\ntransportation shall render to the board of supervisors of such county\nan itemized statement showing in full the amount of money deposited by\nsuch county with the comptroller as hereinbefore provided and all\nexpenditures made for the construction and engineering work connected\ntherewith made pursuant to this section. Any surplus money shall be paid\nto such county on the warrant of the comptroller on vouchers therefor\napproved by the commissioner of transportation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>