<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_A">
        <num>11-A</num>
        <heading>Duty of city clerk in certain cities of the first class; facsimile signature of said clerk authorized</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-a. Duty of city clerk in certain cities of the first class;\nfacsimile signature of said clerk authorized. 1. a. The city clerk of a\ncity of the first class of over one million inhabitants may designate in\nwriting any or all of the deputy city clerks and from among the\npermanent members of the city clerk's staff as many staff members as the\ncity clerk deems necessary to perform marriage ceremonies, which\ndesignation shall be in writing and be filed in the office of such city\nclerk. The day of such filing shall be endorsed on the designation. Any\nsuch designation shall be and remain in effect for six months from the\nfiling thereof.\n  b. Whenever persons to whom the city clerk of any such city of the\nfirst class shall have issued a marriage license shall request him to\nsolemnize the rites of matrimony between them and present to him such\nlicense it shall be the duty of such clerk, either in person or by one\nof his deputies or the permanent members of his staff so designated by\nhim to solemnize such marriage; provided, however, that nothing\ncontained either in this section or in subdivision two of section eleven\nof this chapter shall be construed as empowering or requiring either the\nsaid city clerk or any of his designated deputies or the permanent\nmembers of his staff so designated to solemnize marriages at any place\nother than at the office of such city clerk.\n  d. In all cases in which the city clerk of such city or one of his\ndeputies or the permanent members of his staff so designated shall\nperform a marriage ceremony such official shall demand and be entitled\nto collect therefor a fee to be fixed by the council of the city of New\nYork not exceeding twenty-five dollars, which sum shall be paid by the\ncontracting parties before or immediately upon the solemnization of the\nmarriage; and all such fees so received shall be paid over to the\ncommissioner of finance of the city.\n  2. The signature and seal of said clerk of cities of the first class\nof over one million inhabitants upon the marriage license, certificate\nof marriage, registration, and marriage search provided by this article\nmay be a facsimile imprinted, stamped, or engraved thereon.\n  3. The said clerk of cities of the first class of one million\ninhabitants or more may designate among the permanent members of his\nstaff one or more individuals who shall be permitted to sign his name\nand affix his official seal upon the marriage license, certificate of\nmarriage registration, and marriage search provided by this article\nrequiring the signature and seal of the city clerk.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>