<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_C">
        <num>11-C</num>
        <heading>Marriage officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-c. Marriage officers. 1. Notwithstanding the provisions of\nsection eleven of this article or any other law, the governing body of\nany village, town, or city may appoint one or more marriage officers who\nshall have the authority to solemnize a marriage which marriage shall be\nvalid if performed in accordance with other provisions of law. Nothing\nherein contained shall nullify the authority of other persons authorized\nto solemnize marriages.\n  2. The number of such marriage officers appointed for a municipality\nshall be determined by the governing body of the municipality. Such\nmarriage officers shall be eighteen years of age or over, and they shall\nreside in the municipality by which they are appointed.  A marriage\nofficer shall have the authority to solemnize a marriage within the\nterritory of the municipality which makes the appointment.\n  3. A marriage officer may receive a salary or wage in an amount to be\ndetermined by the governing body of the municipality which appoints him\nor her. In the event that a marriage officer receives a salary or wage,\nhe or she shall not receive any remuneration or consideration from any\nother source for performing his or her duties. In the event that a\nmarriage officer does not receive a salary or wage, he or she may accept\nand keep up to seventy-five dollars for each marriage at which he or she\nofficiates, paid by or on behalf of the persons married.\n  4. The term of office of a marriage officer shall be as determined by\nthe governing body which makes the appointment but shall not exceed four\nyears. A marriage officer shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing\nauthority and may be removed from office with or without cause on ten\ndays written notice filed with the clerk of the municipality and sent by\nregistered mail return receipt requested to the marriage officer.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>