<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11">
        <num>11</num>
        <heading>By whom a marriage must be solemnized</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section two\nhundred twelve of the judiciary law, the clerk of the appellate division\nof the supreme court in each judicial department, a retired city clerk\nwho served for more than ten years in such capacity in a city having a\npopulation of one million or more or a county clerk of a county wholly\nwithin cities having a population of one million or more; or,\n  3-a. A judge or peacemaker judge of any Indian tribal court, a chief,\na headman, or any member of any tribal council or other governing body\nof any nation, tribe or band of Indians in this state duly designated by\nsuch body for the purpose of officiating at marriages, or any other\npersons duly designated by such body, in keeping with the culture and\ntraditions of any such nation, tribe or band of Indians in this state,\nto officiate at marriages.\n  3-b. A one-day marriage officiant, as designated by a town or city\nclerk pursuant to section eleven-d of this article; or,\n  4. A written contract of marriage signed by both parties and at least\ntwo witnesses, all of whom shall subscribe the same within this state,\nstating the place of residence of each of the parties and witnesses and\nthe date and place of marriage, and acknowledged before a judge of a\ncourt of record of this state by the parties and witnesses in the manner\nrequired for the acknowledgment of a conveyance of real estate to\nentitle the same to be recorded.\n  5. Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, where either\nor both of the parties is under the age of eighteen years a marriage\nshall be solemnized only by those authorized in subdivision one of this\nsection or by</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the mayor of a city or village, or county executive of\na county, or by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11__subsec_k__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a judge of the federal circuit court of appeals for\nthe second circuit, a judge of a federal district court for the\nnorthern, southern, eastern or western district of New York, a judge of\nthe United States court of international trade, or a justice or a judge\nof a court of the unified court system, or by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11__subsec_k__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a housing judge of the\ncivil court of the city of New York, or by</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11__subsec_k__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a former mayor or the\nclerk of a city of the first class of over one million inhabitants or\nany of his or her deputies designated by him or her for such purposes as\nprovided in section eleven-a of this chapter.\n  6. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this article to the\ncontrary no marriage shall be solemnized by a public officer specified\nin this section, other than a judge of a federal district court for the\nnorthern, southern, eastern or western district of New York, a judge of\nthe United States court of international trade, a federal administrative\nlaw judge presiding in this state, a judge or justice of the unified\ncourt system of this state, a housing judge of the civil court of the\ncity of New York, or a retired judge or justice of the unified court\nsystem or a retired housing judge of the civil court certified pursuant\nto paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section two hundred twelve of the\njudiciary law, nor by any of the persons specified in subdivision\nthree-a of this section, outside the territorial jurisdiction in which\nhe or she was elected, appointed or duly designated. Such a public\nofficer, however, elected or appointed within the city of New York may\nsolemnize a marriage anywhere within such city.\n  7. The term "clergyman" or "minister" when used in this article, shall\ninclude those defined in section two of the religious corporations law.\nThe word "magistrate," when so used, includes any person referred to in\nthe second or third subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>