<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-111-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-111-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="111-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-111-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-111-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-111-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-111-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_111_C">
        <num>111-C</num>
        <heading>Adoption order from foreign country or foreign jurisdiction</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>either adopting parent is a resident of this state; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the validity of the foreign adoption has been verified by the\ngranting of an IR-3, IH-3, or a successor immigrant visa, for the child\nby the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other provision of law or rule or regulation to\nthe contrary, an adoptive parent referred to in subdivision one of this\nsection shall not be required to petition a court in this state for\nadoption of the child provided the conditions of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision one of this section are met. The foreign adoption shall\nbe considered "final" under the laws of New York state upon the\nsatisfaction of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_111_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this\nsection.\n  3. Either adoptive parent or a guardian or a guardian ad litem may\nregister the order in this state with the judge or surrogate of the\ncounty in which the adoptive parent or parents reside. A petition for\nregistration of a foreign adoption order may be combined with a petition\nfor a name change. If the court finds that the foreign adoption order\nmeets the requirements of subdivision one of this section, the court\nshall issue a finding as to aspects of the foreign adoption, to wit, the\nnames of the adoptive parents, the name or names and reported birth date\nof the adoptive child, the country of the adoptive child's birth, the\ncountry and the date of the foreign adoption, the state residency of the\nadoptive parent or parents and adoptive child, and a finding as to the\ndate and issuance of an IR-3, IH-3, or a successor immigrant visa; and,\nthe court shall issue an order of adoption to the party who has\npetitioned for such an order.\n  4. The judge or surrogate is hereby directed to expedite the issuance\nof an order of adoption pursuant to the provisions of subdivision three\nof this section in order to ensure minimal expense of time and money to\nthe petitioning parties in attaining such order of adoption.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>