<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-14"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-14"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14">
        <num>14</num>
        <heading>Town and city clerks to issue marriage licenses; form</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14. Town and city clerks to issue marriage licenses; form. The town\nor city clerk of each and every town or city in this state is hereby\nempowered to issue marriage licenses to any parties applying for the\nsame who may be entitled under the laws of this state to apply therefor\nand to contract matrimony, authorizing the marriage of such parties,\nwhich license shall be substantially in the following form:\nState of New York\nCounty of ................\nCity or town of ..........\n  Know all men by this certificate that any person authorized by law to\nperform marriage ceremonies within the state of New York to whom this\nmay come, he not knowing any lawful impediment thereto, is hereby\nauthorized and empowered to solemnize the rites of matrimony between\n.............. of ........... in the county of ............. and state of\nNew York and ..................  of ................... in the county of\n.............. and state of New York and to certify the same to the said\nparties or either of them under his hand and seal in his ministerial or\nofficial capacity and thereupon he is required to return his certificate\nin the form hereto annexed. The statements endorsed hereon or annexed\nhereto, by me subscribed, contain a full and true abstract of all of the\nfacts concerning  such parties disclosed by their affidavits or verified\nstatements presented to me upon the application for this license.  This\ncertificate  is  to  be  returned  addressed to the undersigned at\n...................., ............................, .................\n         (Street)          (City, Town, Village)              (State)\n  In testimony whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and affixed the seal\nof said town or city at .......... this ....... day of ........\nnineteen ........, at........m. Seal.\n  The form of the certificate annexed to said license and therein\nreferred to shall be as follows:\nI, .... a ....., residing at ......... in the county of ........ and\nstate of New York do hereby certify that I did on this ......... day of\n..... in the year, nineteen ......... at .....m, at ....... in the county\nof .......... and the state of New York, solemnize the rites of\nmatrimony between .... of ..... in the county of ........... and state\nof New York, and .... of ..... in the county of ............. and state\nof New York in the presence of ..... and ..... as witness, and the\nlicense therefor is hereto annexed.\n  Witness my hand ...... in the county of ....... this ....... day of\n......, nineteen .....\n  In the presence of\n  ...............\n                                                         ...............\n  ...............\n  There shall be endorsed upon the license or annexed thereto at the end\nthereof, subscribed by the clerk, an abstract of the facts concerning\nthe parties as disclosed in their affidavits or verified statements at\nthe time of the application for the license made in conformity to the\nprovisions of section fifteen of this chapter.\n  There shall also be stated upon the license the exact period during\nwhich the marriage may be solemnized.\n  The license issued, including the abstract of facts, and the\ncertificate duly signed by the person who shall have solemnized the\nmarriage therein authorized, shall be returned by him, and where the\nmarriage is solemnized by a written contract, the judge before whom\nacknowledgment is made shall forward such contract and marriage license\nto the office of the town or city clerk who issued the license within\nfive days succeeding the date of the solemnizing of the marriage therein\nauthorized and any person or persons who shall wilfully neglect to make\nsuch return within the time above required shall be deemed guilty of a\nmisdemeanor and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of\nnot less than twenty-five dollars or more than fifty dollars for each\nand every offense.\n  When a marriage is solemnized by a city, town or village justice\noutside of the territorial jurisdiction in which such justice was\nelected or appointed, as provided in subdivision six of section eleven\nof this chapter, there shall be affixed to such license prior to filing,\nthe official or common seal of the court or of the municipality in which\nsuch justice was elected or appointed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>