<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="20"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20">
        <num>20</num>
        <heading>Records to be kept by the state department of health and the city clerk of the city of New York</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 20. Records to be kept by the state department of health and the\ncity clerk of the city of New York. All original affidavits, statements,\nconsents and licenses with certificates attached, and also all written\ncontracts of marriages outside of the city of New York shall be kept on\nfile and properly indexed by the state department of health, and such\nsimilar evidences of marriage in the city of New York shall be kept on\nfile and properly indexed by the city clerk of the city of New York.\nThey shall be carefully examined, and if any such are incomplete or\nunsatisfactory the state commissioner of health and in the city of New\nYork the city clerk shall require such further information to be\nsupplied as may be necessary to make the record complete and\nsatisfactory. Whenever it is claimed that a mistake has been made\nthrough inadvertence in any of the statements, affidavits or other\npapers required by this section to be filed with the state department of\nhealth, and in the city of New York with the city clerk's office, the\nstate commissioner of health and in the city of New York the city clerk\nmay file with the same, affidavits upon the part of the person claiming\nto be aggrieved by such mistake, showing the true facts and the reason\nfor the mistake and may make a note upon such original paper, statement\nor affidavit showing that a mistake is claimed to have been made and the\nnature thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>