<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-23"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-23"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23">
        <num>23</num>
        <heading>Supervision of and inspection of town and city clerks' records by state commissioner of health</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 23. Supervision of and inspection of town and city clerks' records\nby state commissioner of health. The registration and recording of all\nmarriages outside the city of New York shall be under the supervision of\nthe state commissioner of health. The commissioner, either personally or\nby an accredited representative, may at any time inspect the record and\nindex of marriage licenses issued by any town or city clerk and\npromulgate rules and regulations for insuring complete registration.\nWhen he shall deem it necessary, he shall report cases of violation of\nany of the provisions of this article to the district attorney of the\ncounty, with a statement of the facts and circumstances; and when any\nsuch case is reported to him by the state commissioner of health, the\nprosecuting attorney shall forthwith initiate and promptly follow up the\nnecessary court proceedings against the person or persons responsible\nfor the alleged violation of law. Upon request of the state commissioner\nof health, the attorney-general shall assist in the enforcement of the\nprovisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>