<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-240-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-240-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="240-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-240-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-240-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-240-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-240-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_240_B">
        <num>240-B</num>
        <heading>Order of support by parent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 240-b. Order of support by parent. When the court makes an order of\nsupport pursuant to section two hundred forty of this article, and where\npermitted under federal law and where the record of the proceedings\ncontains such information, the court shall require the social security\nnumber of such parent to be affixed to such order; provided, however,\nthat no such order shall be invalid because of the omission of such\nnumber. Where the record of the proceedings contains such information,\nsuch order shall also include on its face the name and address of the\nemployer, if any, of the person chargeable with support provided,\nhowever, that failure to comply with this requirement shall not\ninvalidate such order. Where the order of child support or combined\nchild and spouse support is made on behalf of persons in receipt of\npublic assistance or in receipt of services pursuant to section one\nhundred eleven-g of the social services law, the court shall require\neach party to provide, and update upon any change, the following\ninformation to the court by reporting such change to the support\ncollection unit designated by the appropriate social services district:\nsocial security number, residential and mailing addresses, telephone\nnumber, driver's license number; and name, address and telephone number\nof the parties' employers.  Due process requirements for notice and\nservice of process for subsequent hearings are met, with respect to such\nparty, upon sending written notice by first class mail to the most\nrecent residential address on record with the support collection unit;\nor by sending by first class mail written notice to the most recent\nemployer address on record with the support collection unit, if a true\ncopy thereof also is sent by first class mail to the most recent\nresidential address on record with the support collection unit. Any such\norder issued on or after the first day of October, nineteen hundred\nninety-nine shall also include, where available, the social security\nnumber of each child on whose behalf support has been ordered.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>