<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-75-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-75-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-75-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-75-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-75-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-75-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75_J">
        <num>75-J</num>
        <heading>Taking testimony in another state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 75-j. Taking testimony in another state. 1. In addition to other\nprocedures available to a party, a party to a child custody proceeding\nmay offer testimony of witnesses who are located in another state,\nincluding testimony of the parties and the child, by deposition or other\nmeans allowable in this state for testimony taken in another state. The\ncourt on its own motion may order that the testimony of a person be\ntaken in another state and may prescribe the manner in which and the\nterms upon which the testimony is taken.\n  2. A court of this state may permit an individual residing in another\nstate to be deposed or to testify by telephone, audiovisual means, or\nother electronic means before a designated court or at another location\nin that state. A court of this state shall cooperate with courts of\nother states in designating an appropriate location for the deposition\nor testimony and the procedures to be followed by the persons taking\nsuch deposition or testimony. Any such testimony or deposition shall be\nrecorded and preserved for transcription.\n  3. Documentary evidence transmitted from another state to a court of\nthis state by technological means that do not produce an original\nwriting may not be excluded from evidence on an objection based on the\nmeans of transmission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>