<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="DOM">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-76-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-76-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="76-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="DOM"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-76-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-76-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-76-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/dom/section-76-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_76_I">
        <num>76-I</num>
        <heading>Appearance of parties and child</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 76-i. Appearance of parties and child. 1. In a child custody\nproceeding in this state, the court may order a party to the proceeding\nwho is in this state to appear before the court in person with or\nwithout the child. The court may order any person who is in this state\nand who has physical custody or control of the child to appear in person\nwith the child.\n  2. If a party to a child custody proceeding whose presence is desired\nby the court is outside this state, the court may order that a notice\ngiven pursuant to section seventy-five-g of this article include a\nstatement directing the party to appear in person with or without the\nchild and informing the party that failure to appear may result in a\ndecision adverse to the party.\n  3. The court may enter any orders necessary to ensure the safety of\nthe child and of any person ordered to appear under this section.\n  4. If a party to a child custody proceeding who is outside this state\nis directed to appear under subdivision two of this section or desires\nto appear personally before the court with or without the child, the\ncourt may require another party to pay reasonable and necessary travel\nand other expenses of the party so appearing and of the child.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>