<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="100"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_100">
        <num>100</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 100. Definitions. As used in this article:\n  1. "Political subdivision" means a municipal corporation, school\ndistrict, district corporation and board of cooperative educational\nservices.\n  2. "Fire company" means:\n  a. A volunteer fire company of a county, city, town, village or fire\ndistrict fire department, whether or not any such company has been\nincorporated under any general or special law,\n  b. A fire corporation the members of which are volunteer firefighters\nand which was incorporated under or is subject to the provisions of\nsection fourteen hundred two of the not-for-profit corporation law,\nwhich is not included within paragraph a above, if such corporation is\nby law under the general control of, or recognized as a fire corporation\nby, the governing board of a city, town, village or fire district, or\n  c. A fire corporation the members of which are volunteer firefighters\nand which was incorporated under, or established pursuant to the\nprovisions of, any general or special law, which is not included within\nparagraphs a and b above, if such corporation is by law under the\ngeneral control of, or recognized as a fire corporation by, the\ngoverning board of a city, town, village, fire district or a district\ncorporation other than a fire district.\n  3. "Voluntary ambulance service" means a voluntary ambulance service\nas defined in article thirty of the public health law and possessing a\nvalid statement of registration or possessing a valid ambulance service\ncertificate pursuant to article thirty of the public health law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>