<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="103"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_103">
        <num>103</num>
        <heading>Advertising for bids and offers; letting of contracts; criminal conspiracies</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>document the time and date of receipt of each bid and offer received\nelectronically;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>authenticate the identity of the sender;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ensure\nthe security of the information transmitted; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ensure the\nconfidentiality of the bid or offer until the time and date established\nfor the opening of bids or offers. The timely submission of an\nelectronic bid or offer in compliance with instructions provided for\nsuch submission in the advertisement for bids or offers and/or the\nspecifications shall be the responsibility solely of each bidder or\nofferer or prospective bidder or offerer. No political subdivision or\ndistrict therein shall incur any liability from delays of or\ninterruptions in the receiving device designated for the submission and\nreceipt of electronic bids and offers.\n  * NB Effective until June 1, 2028\n  * 1. Except as otherwise expressly provided by an act of the\nlegislature or by a local law adopted prior to September first, nineteen\nhundred fifty-three, all contracts for public work involving an\nexpenditure of more than thirty-five thousand dollars and all purchase\ncontracts involving an expenditure of more than twenty thousand dollars,\nshall be awarded by the appropriate officer, board or agency of a\npolitical subdivision or of any district therein including but not\nlimited to a soil conservation district to the lowest responsible bidder\nfurnishing the required security after advertisement for sealed bids in\nthe manner provided by this section, provided, however, that purchase\ncontracts (including contracts for service work, but excluding any\npurchase contracts necessary for the completion of a public works\ncontract pursuant to article eight of the labor law) may be awarded on\nthe basis of best value, as defined in section one hundred sixty-three\nof the state finance law, to a responsive and responsible bidder or\nofferer in the manner provided by this section except that in a\npolitical subdivision other than a city with a population of one million\ninhabitants or more or any district, board or agency with jurisdiction\nexclusively therein the use of best value of awarding a purchase\ncontract or purchase contracts mus...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section, a\npolitical subdivision, when letting contracts in accordance with this\nsubdivision for the purchase of food products, may require provisions\nthat mandate that the essential components of such food products are\ngrown, produced or harvested in New York state, or that any processing\nof such food products take place in facilities located within New York\nstate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of agriculture and markets shall determine, using\nuniform criteria, those food products for which the requirements of this\nsubdivision are deemed beneficial. The commissioner shall promulgate a\nlist of such food products and ascertain those periods of time each year\nthat the listed food products are available in sufficient quantity for\ncompetitive purchasing and shall forward such information upon request\nto such political subdivisions that shall make determinations as\nprovided herein. The commissioner of agriculture and markets shall\nupdate such list as often as he deems necessary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such political subdivision shall specify, with the advice of\nthe commissioner of agriculture and markets, the percentage of each food\nproduct required to be grown, produced, harvested or processed within\nNew York state.\n  (ii) Upon a determination by such political subdivision that such food\nproducts are not available in sufficient quantity for purchasing, the\nspecifications requiring such purchase shall be waived for that specific\nfood product until the next contract for such food product is let out\nfor bid.\n  (iii) Upon a determination by such political subdivision that food\nprocessing facilities are not available for the processing of food\nproducts purchased under specifications required by this section, the\nspecifications requiring such processing shall be waived.\n  (iv) In the event that such a political subdivision receives no\nacceptable bids it may waive the provisions of this section and shall\naward a contract in accordance with other applicable statutes. In\naddition, if the commissioners of agriculture and markets and economic\ndevelopment agree as to any deleterious economic impact of\nspecifications requiring such purchase, the provisions of this\nsubdivision may be waived by a political subdivision for such purchase.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of the office of general services and the\ncommissioner of agriculture and markets may issue such regulations as\nthey deem necessary to implement this subdivision and to assist\npolitical subdivisions in complying with this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the department of\nagriculture and markets shall supply information required by paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision to the office of general services within one\nhundred eighty days of the effective date of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioners of general services, agriculture and markets,\nand economic development shall provide the legislature with a report on\nthe fifteenth day of January of the second year next succeeding the year\nin which this subdivision became effective, and in their discretion\nperiodically report thereafter, on the effects of this subdivision and\non recommendations on ways to make it more effective.\n  9.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section to the\ncontrary, a board of education, on behalf of its school district, or a\nboard of cooperative educational services, may separately purchase eggs,\nlivestock, fish, dairy products (excluding milk), juice, grains, and\nspecies of fresh fruit and vegetables, grown, produced or harvested, in\nNew York State, provided that such order is for one hundred fifty\nthousand dollars or less as herein authorized, provided however, that a\nschool district or board of cooperative educational services may apply\nto the commissioner of education for permission to purchase orders of\nmore than one hundred fifty thousand dollars from an association of\nowners of such farms when no other producers or growers have offered to\nsell to such school.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All such purchases shall be administered pursuant to regulations\npromulgated by the commissioner of education. Such regulations shall: be\ndeveloped in consultation with the commissioner of agriculture and\nmarkets to accommodate and promote the provisions of the farm-to-school\nprogram established pursuant to subdivision five-b of section sixteen of\nthe agriculture and markets law and subdivision thirty-one of section\nthree hundred five of the education law as added by chapter two of the\nlaws of two thousand two; ensure that the prices paid by a district or\nboard of cooperative educational services for any items so purchased do\nnot exceed the prices of comparable local farm products that are\navailable to districts through their usual purchases of such items;\nensure that all producers and growers who desire to sell to school\ndistricts or boards of cooperative educational services can readily\naccess information in accordance with the farm-to-school law; include\nprovisions for situations when more than one producer or grower seeks to\nsell the same product to a district or board of cooperative educational\nservices to ensure that all such producers or growers have an equitable\nopportunity to do so in a manner similar to the usual purchasing\npractices of such districts or boards of cooperative educational\nservices; and, to the maximum extent practicable, minimize additional\npaperwork, recordkeeping and other similar requirements on both growers\nand producers and school districts.\n  9-a. Notwithstanding any provision of this section to the contrary, a\ncounty may separately purchase eggs, livestock, fish, dairy products,\njuice, grains, and species of fresh fruit and vegetables directly from\nNew York state producers or growers, or associations of producers and\ngrowers, provided that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such association of producers or growers is comprised of ten or\nfewer owners of farms who also operate such farms and who have combined\nto fill the order of a county as herein authorized, provided however,\nthat a county may purchase from an association of more than ten owners\nof such farms when no other producers or growers have offered to sell to\nsuch county;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount that may be expended by a county in any fiscal year for\nsuch purchases shall not exceed the greater of:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the expenditure threshold provided in subdivision one of this\nsection; or\n  (ii) twenty cents multiplied by the total population of such county;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all such purchases shall be administered pursuant to policies and\nprocedures adopted by the county governing board and developed in\nconsultation with the commissioner of agriculture and markets. Such\npolicies and procedures shall ensure that the prices paid by a county\nfor any items so purchased do not exceed the prices of comparable local\nfarm products that are available to the political subdivision or\ndistrict therein through their usual purchases of such items; include\nprovisions for situations when more than one producer or grower seeks to\nsell the same product to a county to ensure that all such producers or\ngrowers have an equitable opportunity to do so in a manner similar to\nthe usual purchasing practices of such county; include guidelines for\nthe approval of purchases of items from associations of more than ten\ngrowers or producers; and, to the maximum extent practicable, minimize\nadditional paperwork, recordkeeping and other similar requirements on\nboth growers and producers and counties.\n  10. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section to the\ncontrary, a board of education may, on behalf of its school district,\nseparately purchase milk produced in New York State, directly from\nlicensed milk processors pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision.\nThe amount that may be expended by a school district in any fiscal year\npursuant to this section shall not exceed an amount equal to twenty-five\ncents multiplied by the total number of days in the school year\nmultiplied by the total enrollment of such school district. All\npurchases made pursuant to this subdivision shall be administered\npursuant to regulations promulgated by the commissioner of education.\nThe regulations promulgated by the commissioner of education shall\nensure that the prices paid by a school district for items purchased\npursuant to this subdivision do not exceed the market value of such\nitems and that all licensed processors who desire to sell to a sch...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In all contracts governed by\nthis section, where a unilateral error or mistake is discovered in a\nbid, such bid may be withdrawn after a showing of the following:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_103__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the\nmistake is known or made known to the awarding officer, board or agency\nprior to the awarding of the contract or within three days after the\nopening of the bid, whichever period is shorter; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_103__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the price bid\nwas based on an error of such magnitude that enforcement would be\nunconscionable; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_103__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the bid was submitted in good faith and the\nbidder submits credible evidence that the mistake was a clerical error\nas opposed to a judgment error; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_103__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the error in the bid is actually\ndue to an unintentional and substantial arithmetic error or an\nunintentional omission of a substantial quantity of work, labor,\nmaterial, goods or services made directly in the compilation of the bid,\nwhich unintentional arithmetic error or unintentional omission can be\nclearly shown by objective evidence drawn from inspection of the\noriginal work paper, documents, or materials used in the preparation of\nthe bid sought to be withdrawn; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_103__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>it is possible to place the\npublic agency, board, officer, or subdivision in status quo ante.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Unless otherwise required by law, the sole remedy for a bid\nmistake in accordance with this section shall be withdrawal of that bid\nand the return of the bid bond or other security, if any, to the bidder.\nThereafter, the awarding officer, board or agency may, in its\ndiscretion, award the contract to the next lowest responsible bidder or\nrebid the contract. Any amendment to or reformation of a bid or a\ncontract to rectify such an error or mistake therein is strictly\nprohibited.\n  12. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or any other\nprovision of law, boards of education shall have the authority to\ndetermine that a bidder on a contract for the purchase of apparel or\nsports equipment is not a responsible bidder for purposes of subdivision\none of this section, based upon either or both of the following\nconsiderations:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the labor standards applicable to the manufacture of\nthe apparel or sports equipment, including but not limited to employee\ncompensation, working conditions, employee rights to form unions, and\nthe use of child labor; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the bidder's failure to provide\ninformation sufficient for boards of education to determine the labor\nstandards applicable to the manufacture of the apparel or sports\nequipment.\n  15.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any general, special or local law or rule or\nregulation to the contrary, an officer, board or agency of any county,\nany school district or any political subdivision of the state with a\npopulation of fifty thousand or more charged with awarding a contract\nfor public work may establish guidelines governing the qualifications of\nbidders seeking to bid or enter into such contracts. If such officer,\nboard or agency maintains an appropriate list of qualified bidders, the\nbidding shall be restricted to those who have qualified prior to the\nreceipt of bids according to standards fixed by such officer, board or\nagency. In determining whether a prospective bidder qualifies for\ninclusion on a list of pre-qualified bidders, the officer, board or\nagency shall consider the experience and record of performance of the\nprospective bidder in the particular type of work, as well as:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nprospective bidder's ability to undertake the particular type and\ncomplexity of work; (ii) the financial capability, responsibility and\nreliability of the prospective bidder for such type and complexity of\nwork; (iii) the record of the prospective bidder in complying with\nexisting labor standards and maintaining harmonious labor relations;\n(iv) the prospective bidder's compliance with equal employment\nopportunity requirements and anti-discrimination laws, and demonstrated\ncommitment to working with minority and women-owned businesses through\njoint ventures or subcontractor relationships; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the record of the\nprospective bidder in protecting the health and safety of workers on\npublic works projects and job sites as demonstrated by the prospective\nbidder's experience modification rate for each of the last three years.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such public officer, board or agency shall, not less than\nannually, publish in a newspaper of general circulation in such\npolitical subdivision an advertisement requesting prospective bidders to\nsubmit qualification statements. Lists of pre-qualified bidders may be\nestablished on a project-specific basis. Prequalified lists shall\ninclude all bidders that qualify; provided, however, that any such list\nshall have no less than five bidders but shall remain open for all\nadditional qualified bidders. The public officer, board or agency's\nprocedures for prequalifying bidders shall include an appeals process\nfor those denied a place on a pre-qualified list. Any denial must be\nbased upon substantial evidence, cannot be arbitrary or capricious, and\nshall be subject to judicial review pursuant to article seventy-eight of\nthe civil practice law and rules. The public officer, board or agency\nmay move forward on the contract award during such appeals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_103__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any school district or political subdivision of the state with a\npopulation of less than fifty thousand may utilize a list of\npre-qualified bidders maintained by the county within which the\nsubdivision is located, if such list is maintained.\n  * 16. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions one, two and\nthree of this section, and section one hundred four of this article, any\nofficer, board or agency of a political subdivision or of any district\ntherein authorized to make purchases of apparatus, materials, equipment\nor supplies, or to contract for services related to the installation,\nmaintenance or repair of apparatus, materials, equipment, and supplies,\nmay make such purchases, or may contract for such services related to\nthe installation, maintenance or repair of apparatus, materials,\nequipment, and supplies, as may be required by such political\nsubdivision or district therein through the use of a contract let by the\nUnited States of America or any agency thereof, any state or any other\npolitical subdivision or district therein if such contract was let to\nthe lowest responsible bidder or on the basis of best value in a manner\nconsistent with this section and made available for use by other\ngovernmental entities; provided, however, that no political subdivision\nor district therein, other than a city with a population of one million\nor more inhabitants or any district, board or agency with jurisdiction\nexclusively therein, may make such purchases or contract for such\nservices through the use of such a contract let on the basis of best\nvalue in a manner consistent with this section unless the political\nsubdivision or district shall first adopt a local law, rule, regulation\nor resolution, as the case may be, pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection, authorizing the use of best value for awarding purchase\ncontracts.\n  The authority provided to political subdivisions and districts therein\npursuant to this subdivision shall not reliev...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>