<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-10-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="109-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_109_C">
        <num>109-C</num>
        <heading>Purchases through county contracts by certain not-for-profit corporations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 109-c. Purchases through county contracts by certain not-for-profit\ncorporations. Not-for-profit corporations that provide a service to a\ncounty are authorized to make purchases or to contract for services\nother than services subject to article eight or any provisions of the\nlabor law and other than purchases of motor fuel, diesel motor fuel or\ncigarettes, through the county which the not-for-profit has a contract\nwith. Such purchases or contracts for services made through a county\ncontract by a not-for-profit shall directly relate to the service for\nwhich the not-for-profit provides to such county. The county may\nestablish limitations with respect to commodities and services and\nimpose such other appropriate conditions upon purchasing as deemed\nnecessary by the chief fiscal officer of the county in order to protect\nthe county's own purchasing interests; and such not-for-profit\ncorporation shall make any purchase pursuant to this section in its own\nname and accept sole responsibility for any payment due to the vendor\nand such not-for-profit corporation and vendor shall each be responsible\nfor any tax due with respect to the purchases by the not-for-profit\ncorporation. Nothing in this section shall be construed as altering any\ntax exemption afforded to the not-for-profit corporation or as creating\na principal/agent relationship between the county and not-for-profit\ncorporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>