<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="109-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-109-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_109_A">
        <num>109-A</num>
        <heading>Purchases through the office of general services by certain public associations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 109-a. Purchases through the office of general services by certain\npublic associations. The New York State Association of Counties, the\nAssociation of Towns of the State of New York, the New York State Town\nClerk's Association, Inc., the New York State Conference of Mayors and\nOther Municipal Officials, the New York State School Boards Association,\nInc., the New York Planning Federation and the Association of Fire\nDistricts of the State of New York, the New York State Association of\nSchool Business Officials, the New York state council of school\nsuperintendents, any nonpublic elementary and/or secondary school of the\nstate of New York, which provides the instruction required by section\nthirty-two hundred four and article seventeen of the education law, and\nwhich is chartered by, registered with or subject to examination and\ninspection by the department of education and which is a not for profit\ninstitution and any public library, association library, library system,\ncooperative library system, the New York Library Association, and the\nNew York State Association of Library Boards or any other library except\nthose which are operated by for profit entities, may make purchases\nthrough the office of general services subject to such rules as may be\npromulgated pursuant to section one hundred sixty-three of the state\nfinance law and subdivision eight-a of section one hundred three of this\narticle which may establish limitations with respect to commodities and\nimpose such other appropriate conditions upon purchasing as deemed\nnecessary by the commissioner of general services in order to protect\nthe state's own purchasing interests; and that such association, school,\nlibrary, library system or cooperative library system shall accept sole\nresponsibility for any payment due the vendor. Boards of education may\npermit such nonpublic schools to make purchases pursuant to this section\nthrough the school district in which the nonpublic school is located,\nprovided that any administrative costs incurred by the school district\nwill be paid by the nonpublic school.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>