<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-112"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-112"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="112"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-112/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-112/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_112">
        <num>112</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of a common supply</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 112. Acquisition of a common supply.  A common supply of water may\nbe acquired and developed (including acquisition or construction of all\nfacilities necessary for distribution of water in bulk) by all of the\ncontracting municipalities acting jointly or by the individual action of\none of the contracting municipalities, acting for all of the contracting\nmunicipalities, as such municipalities may provide in the contract, or,\npursuant to contract therewith, by a public authority which possesses\nexpress reciprocal powers of contract. Regardless of the method agreed\nupon, title to all real or personal property acquired or constructed\nshall be held jointly in the names of all of the contracting\nmunicipalities subject to such provisions for disposition as the\ncontract between such municipalities may contain.\n  Rider I. Such water authority shall be deemed the agent of the county\nor counties which are a party or parties to such contract. If such\ncontract shall authorize the water authority to purchase supplies or\nequipment or to construct public works, such authority shall be subject\nto all provisions of law to which a county would be subject in relation\nto advertising and awarding any such contracts for supplies, equipment\nor public works.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>