<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="119-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_119_N">
        <num>119-N</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 119-n. Definitions. As used herein:\n  a. The term "municipal corporation" means a county outside the city of\nNew York, a city, a town, a village, a board of cooperative educational\nservices, fire district or a school district.\n  b. The term "district" means a county or town improvement district for\nwhich the county or town or towns in which such district is located is\nor are required to pledge its or their faith and credit for the payment\nof the principal of and interest on all indebtedness to be contracted\nfor the purposes of such district. The term "district" shall also mean,\nfor the purposes of joining a municipal cooperative health benefit plan\nauthorized under article forty-seven of the insurance law, a soil and\nwater conservation district established under the soil and water\nconservation districts law.\n  c. The term "joint service" means joint provision of any municipal\nfacility, service, activity, project or undertaking or the joint\nperformance or exercise of any function or power which each of the\nmunicipal corporations or districts has the power by any other general\nor special law to provide, perform or exercise, separately and, to\neffectuate the purposes of this article, shall include extension of\nappropriate territorial jurisdiction necessary therefor.\n  d. The term "joint water, sewage or drainage project" means a joint\nproject to provide for a common supply of water, the common conveyance,\ntreatment and disposal of sewage or a common drainage system, as\ndescribed in paragraphs B, D and F of section two-a of article eight of\nthe constitution.\n  e. The term "voting strength" means the aggregate number of votes\nwhich all the members of the local governing body of a municipal\ncorporation or district are entitled to cast.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>