<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-OOO"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-OOO"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="119-OOO"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-OOO/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-OOO/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-OOO/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-OOO/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_119_OOO">
        <num>119-OOO</num>
        <heading>Inclusion of Cornell University as a member of the governing body of an entity created by intermunicipal agreement to construct and opera...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 119-000. Inclusion of Cornell University as a member of the\ngoverning body of an entity created by intermunicipal agreement to\nconstruct and operate water treatment plants and water distribution\nsystems in or adjoining the county of Tompkins. 1. Notwithstanding any\nother provision of law to the contrary, the municipalities in or\nadjoining the county of Tompkins including, but not limited to, the\ntowns of Ithaca, Dryden and Lansing, the villages of Cayuga Heights and\nLansing, and the city of Ithaca, and Cornell University may jointly\nprovide for water services in the municipalities in and adjoining the\ncounty of Tompkins and the water districts located within the\nmunicipalities in or adjoining the county of Tompkins.\n  2. In addition to the powers set forth in article five-B of this\nchapter and this article, the municipalities in or adjoining the county\nof Tompkins and water districts within such municipalities, shall have\nthe power to, jointly with Cornell University:\n  a. Contract, acquire, finance and sell common water supplies;\n  b. Construct, operate, maintain, lease, sell, and otherwise deal in\nand supervise water intakes, water treatment plants, water lines, pumps,\nstorage facilities, distribution facilities and all other activities\nnormally or reasonably related to the provision of such services which\nmunicipalities individually are authorized to undertake; and\n  c. Create, continue, maintain and modify by agreement a governing body\nto supervise and operate such facilities which governing body may be\nmade up of representatives from the participating municipalities and\nrepresentatives from Cornell University.\n  3. The inclusion of Cornell University as a party to any such\nagreement, and the inclusion of any representatives of Cornell\nUniversity as members of any governing body, shall not be deemed to\nchange the characterization of such body as a municipal body with all of\nthe benefits, liabilities, immunities and responsibilities of a\nmunicipal body.\n  4. The powers granted by this section shall be in addition to and not\nin substitution of any other powers granted to the municipalities in or\nadjoining the county of Tompkins and Cornell University to provide water\nservices, including, without limitation, the power to jointly contract\nfor obtaining and operating such services pursuant to article five-B of\nthis chapter and this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>