<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="119-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_119_J">
        <num>119-J</num>
        <heading>Costs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 119-j. Costs. The share of each participating municipality of the\ncost of providing common drainage facilities shall be fixed by the\ncontract.  In the event that the acquisition and development of common\ndrainage facilities shall be effected by the individual action of one of\nthe participating municipalities, it shall be lawful for any of the\nother participating municipalities to make a lump sum payment of its\nshare from moneys on hand and available for such purpose. Nothing herein\ncontained shall prevent the purchase or condemnation of existing\ndrainage facilities or portions thereof necessary for the purposes of\nthe joint project, provided, however, that there shall be no power to\ncondemn property the legal title to which is vested in a public\ncorporation, district corporation or a special improvement district\nunless the owner shall consent thereto. In the event that any drainage\nfacility owned by one of the participating municipalities is acquired\nfor the purpose of the common facilities, such municipality may be\nallowed a credit against its share of the cost equal to the agreed value\nof the assets so acquired. The share of each participating municipality\nmay be paid from taxes levied for the fiscal year in which such\nexpenditure is to be made or may be financed as provided in title one-A\nof article two of the local finance law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>