<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-DD"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-DD"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="119-DD"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_119_DD">
        <num>119-DD</num>
        <heading>Local historic preservation programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 119-dd. Local historic preservation programs. In addition to\nexisting powers and authorities for local historic preservation programs\nincluding existing powers and authorities to regulate by planning or\nzoning laws and regulations or by local laws and regulations for\npreservation of historic landmarks and districts and use of techniques\nincluding transfer of development rights, the legislative body of any\ncounty, city, town or village is hereby empowered to:\n  1. Provide by regulations, special conditions and restrictions for the\nprotection, enhancement, perpetuation and use of places, districts,\nsites, buildings, structures, works of art and other objects having a\nspecial character or special historical, cultural or aesthetic interest\nor value. Such regulations, special conditions and restrictions may\ninclude appropriate and reasonable control of the use or appearance of\nneighboring private property within the public view, or both.\n  2. Establish a landmark or historical preservation board or commission\nwith such powers as are necessary to carry out all or any of the\nauthority possessed by the municipality for a historic preservation\nprogram, as the local legislative body deems appropriate.\n  3. After due notice and public hearing, by purchase, gift, grant,\nbequest, devise, lease or otherwise, acquire the fee or any lesser\ninterest, development right, easement, covenant or other contractual\nright necessary to achieve the purposes of this article, to historical\nor cultural property within its jurisdiction. After acquisition of any\nsuch interest pursuant to this subdivision, the effect of the\nacquisition on the valuation placed on any remaining private interest in\nsuch property for purposes of real estate taxation shall be taken into\naccount.\n  4. Designate, purchase, restore, operate, lease and sell historic\nbuildings or structures. Sales of such buildings and structures shall be\nupon such terms and conditions as the local legislative body deems\nappropriate to insure the maintenance of the historic quality of the\nbuildings and structures, after public notice is appropriately given at\nleast thirty days prior to the anticipated date of availability and\nshall be for fair and adequate consideration of such buildings and\nstructures which in no event shall be less than the expenses incurred by\nthe municipality with respect to such buildings and structures for\nacquisition, restoration, improvement and interest charges.\n  5. Provide for transfer of development rights for purposes consistent\nwith the purposes of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>