<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="119-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_119_CC">
        <num>119-CC</num>
        <heading>Local historic preservation report</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_119_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement of the present status of historic preservation\nactivities and land use or other regulations relating thereto as they\nare being administered within the reporting jurisdiction by the local\ngoverning body and its appointed agents including a landmarks\ncommission, planning board, environmental management council or other\nagency;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119_CC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Proposals, if any, for the preservation and use of registered\nproperty and other historic and cultural properties within the reporting\njurisdiction;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_119_CC__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An identification and analysis of any problems or issues relating\nto the effectiveness of local development or administration of historic\npreservation plans and programs, including problems of funding and\npersonnel requirements, procedural problems, enforcement problems, or\nany other issue. After a public hearing has been held on a draft report\nsuch report in final form shall be submitted to the commissioner of\nparks and recreation and a copy shall be available for public inspection\nin the municipal office of the reporting jurisdiction. It may be\nreviewed and updated as necessary.\n  2. The commissioner of the office of parks and recreation shall\nprepare and distribute a format which may be used or completed by\nreporting jurisdictions to satisfy the provisions of this section.  The\npurposes of such report are informational and compliance by a reporting\njurisdiction shall not be used by the commissioner or any other state\nofficial as a condition for the performance of any state service,\nassistance or other action.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>