<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="119-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-119-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_119_P">
        <num>119-P</num>
        <heading>Projects relating to the use of atmospheric water resources</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 119-p. Projects relating to the use of atmospheric water resources.\nEvery municipal corporation is, and any two or more municipal\ncorporations are, hereby authorized and empowered to conduct or engage\nin projects, experiments and other activities designed to develop the\nuse of atmospheric water resources, and to make scientific evaluations\nof such projects, experiments and other activities, or to contract\ntherefor, and to appropriate and expend moneys therefor. In the case of\na joint project by two or more municipal corporations, the share of the\ncost of such project or activity to be borne by each such municipal\ncorporation shall be fixed by contract. The expenditure of moneys for\nsuch purpose by a municipal corporation shall be deemed a lawful\nmunicipal purpose and the moneys appropriated therefor shall be raised\nby tax upon the taxable real property within the municipal corporation\nin the same manner as moneys for other lawful municipal purposes. Each\nmunicipal corporation is hereby authorized to accept and disburse grants\nof public or private money or other aid paid or made available by the\nstate or federal government for any such purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>