<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="120-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_120_N">
        <num>120-N</num>
        <heading>Maps and plans of sewers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 120-n. Maps and plans of sewers. Before taking any proceedings for\nthe construction of any sewer or of any system of sewers or of any\naddition thereto or alteration thereof, such municipality or\nmunicipalities acting severally or jointly shall cause to be made a map\nand plan therefor, or an amendment of any map and plan previously\napproved, as the case may be, and shall submit the same to the state\ncommissioner of health for his approval, and upon his approval the same\nshall be filed in his office.  A copy of such map and plan or of any\nsuch amendment thereof shall also be filed in the office of the clerk of\neach such municipality.  Any such map and plan shall include\nspecifications of dimensions, connections and outlets or sewage disposal\nworks and may also include any existing sewer which it shall be found\nfeasible and proper to incorporate or include in the proposed system. No\nwork of any kind shall be done on or for the construction, extension,\nreconstruction, removal or modification of any system of sewers or of\nany sewer thereof until a map and plan covering the entire system shall\nfirst have been duly approved and filed as above provided, and in the\nexecution of the construction, extension, reconstruction, removal or\nmodification of any system of sewers or of any sewer thereof no\ndeviations from the plans as finally approved and filed shall be made\nuntil plans or descriptions adequately showing such deviations are first\napproved and filed as above provided. The state commissioner of health,\nin approving said map and plan or by a certificate supplementing any\nsuch approval, may authorize such municipality or municipalities to\ntemporarily omit or defer the construction of any portion of any such\nsewer or system of sewers. A copy or copies of his approval or of any\nsuch supplemental certificate shall be certified to each such\nmunicipality and filed in the office of the clerk thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>