<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-X"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-X"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="120-X"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-120-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_120_X">
        <num>120-X</num>
        <heading>Agreements for joint acquisition, construction and operation of public docks</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 120-x. Agreements for joint acquisition, construction and operation\nof public docks. A town and one or more villages situated wholly or\npartly within such town are hereby empowered to enter into an agreement\nfor the joint acquisition, construction and operation of a public dock.\nSuch agreement shall provide for the method of acquisition or\nconstruction of the public dock; the management and operation thereof;\nthe method of fixing the proportionate share of each participating\nmunicipality and of making contributions; the method of making annual\nadjustments of the proportionate shares of the annual cost and expense;\nthe adoption of rules and regulations in relation to the operation of\nthe dock and the conditions of use; the adjudication of disputes; and\nother matters necessary to effectuate such an arrangement.  The share of\nthe capital cost apportioned to the town and the village or villages\nrespectively may be financed by each such municipality respectively in\nthe manner provided in the local finance law. The share of the cost of\noperation and maintenance to be paid by the town and debt service on\nobligations issued to finance the town's share of capital cost shall be\nincluded in the annual budget of the town and shall be levied against\nthe taxable real property in the town situated outside of such\nparticipating village or villages. The share of the cost of operation\nand maintenance to be paid by a village and debt service on obligation\nissued to finance a village's share of capital cost shall be included in\nthe annual budget of such village and shall be levied against the\ntaxable real property in the village. Nothing herein contained shall be\nconstrued to restrict or prohibit the exercise by the town of any\nexisting power or authority to provide dock facilities in any village\nsituated within such town.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>