<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-121-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-121-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="121-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-121-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-121-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-121-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-121-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_121_B">
        <num>121-B</num>
        <heading>Care of children admitted to certain places of amusement in certain cities, villages and towns under a local law or ordinance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 121-b. Care of children admitted to certain places of amusement in\ncertain cities, villages and towns under a local law or ordinance. The\nboard of aldermen, common council or other legislative body of a city\nhaving a population of less than one million, or of any village or town\nmay adopt a local law or ordinance, subject to the provisions of this\nsection, for the licensing of theatres in such city or village or town,\nwherein there shall be exhibited those films which have been licensed by\nthe education department of the state of New York to admit children over\nthe age of eight years and under the age of sixteen years, unaccompanied\nby a parent or guardian or other adult person.\n  No child under the age of sixteen years shall be admitted to any\ntheatre unaccompanied by a parent, guardian or other adult person,\nunless such theatre is licensed pursuant to and complies with the terms\nof a local law or ordinance adopted pursuant to this section.  Any such\nlocal law or ordinance, and every license issued thereunder, shall\nrequire:\n  1. That seats shall be provided on the main or orchestra floor by the\nowner, operator or management of such theatre for use by such\nunaccompanied children. No unaccompanied children shall be permitted in\nany balcony or box.\n  2. A seat in such section of the theatre shall be provided for every\nsuch child admitted to the theatre.\n  3. Such children shall not be admitted to such theatre during the time\nwhen their school classes within the city or village or town are in\nsession, or after the hour of six o'clock in the evening, provided\nhowever, that for children aged thirteen, fourteen and fifteen a later\nhour in the evening for admission and the hour at which such children\nshall be required to leave the theatre may be provided for by such local\nlaw or ordinance.\n  4. A matron or supervisor and such other assistants as may be\nspecified in such local law or ordinance shall be provided by such\nowner, operator or management of such theatre for the supervision of\nsuch children, who shall give undivided attention to such supervision\nduring the time such children shall be in such theatre. Such matron or\nsupervisor shall be licensed by such city or village or town and the\nlicense fee, not exceeding two dollars, shall be paid by such owner,\noperator or management of such theatre.\n  Such local law or ordinance may provide other and additional\nconditions or limitations in regard to the care of children so admitted,\nbut such conditions or limitations shall not require any additional\napproval of and shall not prohibit the exhibition of any motion picture\nfilm duly licensed by the board of education of the state of New York.\n  Such local law or ordinance may provide for the enforcement thereof\nand may prescribe penalties for violations thereof or of licenses issued\nthereunder.\n  The admission of a child between eight and sixteen years of age to a\ntheatre licensed under authority of a local law or ordinance adopted\npursuant to the provisions of this section, where such theatre complies\nwith the terms of this section and of the license, shall not be deemed a\nviolation of the provisions of section 260.20 of the penal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>