<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-124"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-124"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="124"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_124">
        <num>124</num>
        <heading>Inspection of building elevators in Nassau county</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 124. Inspection of building elevators in Nassau county. 1.  All\nelevators in buildings in Nassau county shall be inspected periodically\nfor the purposes of public safety. Except as otherwise provided in\nsubdivision three hereof, each city, town or village shall inspect, or\ncause to be inspected, those elevators in buildings under their\njurisdiction in conformance with the local building code of such city,\ntown or village, if there be one, and only if the provisions of such\ncode are at least as stringent as the minimum standards set forth in the\nNew York state building code with respect to the installation, operation\nand maintenance of building elevators. Any city, town or village in\nNassau county which does not have a local building code or regulation\nwith respect to the installation, operation and maintenance of building\nelevators or has a building code or regulation with respect to the\ninstallation, operation and maintenance of building elevators which are\nless stringent than the minimum standards set forth in the New York\nstate building code with respect to the installation, operation and\nmaintenance of building elevators shall within one year next succeeding\nthe effective date of this section, adopt a local law providing for a\nbuilding code or a regulation relating to the installation, operation\nand maintenance of building elevators or amend any existing provision of\na building code or regulation with respect to the installation,\noperation and maintenance of building elevators so as to assure that the\nprovisions of such building code or regulation as adopted or amended\nwith respect to the installation, operation and maintenance of building\nelevators shall be at least as stringent as the minimum standards set\nforth in the New York state building code with respect to the\ninstallation, operation and maintenance of building elevators provided,\nhowever, that any village within a town within such county may consent\nby adoption of a resolution of its governing body, to permit the\ninstallation, operation and maintenance of building elevators within\nsuch village to be subject to the provisions of a local building code or\nregulation of such town with respect to the installation, operation and\nmaintenance of building elevators within such town and the adoption of\nsuch resolution shall exempt such village from adopting or amending a\nbuilding code or regulation with respect to the installation, operation\nand maintenance of building elevators within such village.\n  2. It shall be a further duty of such cities, towns or villages in\nNassau county to require by local law or ordinance in the same manner as\nprovided for in subdivision one of this section that mirrors be placed\nin the rear of elevators subject to inspection in subdivision one hereof\nso as to make the interior thereof visible prior to entering such\nelevators.\n  3. Each town within Nassau county shall, upon the request of a village\nlocated within such town, perform or cause to be performed the\ninspection required by subdivision one hereof, provided however, that no\nvillage may make such request unless the village has adopted a\nresolution of their governing body consenting to subject the\ninstallation, operation and maintenance of building elevators within\nsuch village to the provisions of the local building code or regulation\nof the town relating thereto.\n  4. Any person who knowingly and wilfully violates any provision of\nthis section or who violates or fails to comply with any order or\nrequirement of an inspector or other officer charged with the duty of\ninspecting elevators, shall be guilty of a violation punishable by a\nfine of not more than five hundred dollars or by imprisonment for not\nmore than fifteen days.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>