<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-126-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-126-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="126-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-126-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-126-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-126-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-126-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_126_A">
        <num>126-A</num>
        <heading>Joint hospitals for cities, towns or villages</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_126_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The proportion which the village shall\nbear shall be based upon the ratio which the assessed valuation of that\nportion of the town lying within said village bears to the total\nassessed valuation of the town;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_126_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The proportion which the town shall\nbear shall be based upon the ratio which the assessed valuation of that\nportion of the town lying outside such village bears to the total\nassessed valuation of the town. Such agreement shall be made upon\nauthorization therefor by the governing boards of such town and village\nand shall be executed by the supervisor and mayor, respectively, in\nbehalf of such town and village. Such agreed proportion of cost, and\ndebt service therefor, to be borne by such village shall be raised by\ntaxation upon the real estate located within the village. Such agreed\nproportion of cost, and debt service therefor, to be borne by such town\nshall be raised by taxation on real estate located in the town without\nthe territorial limits of the village. The assessed valuations of\nproperty to be used in determining the above ratios shall be taken from\nthe latest assessment-roll of the town prior to the time such agreement\nis entered into and as shown therein at the time of the completion and\nfiling of such assessment-roll. The cost of operation of any such\nhospital for which the cost and debt service has been apportioned upon\nthe above basis shall be apportioned annually prior to December\nthirty-first in each year for the next calendar year and in the same\nmanner as the cost of the project as herein provided and for such\npurpose the latest preceding town assessment-roll shall be used, and the\nassessed valuations of property to be used shall be as shown therein at\nthe time of the completion and filing thereof. In the event that any\nsuch town and village join with an adjoining town or towns to effectuate\nthe purposes of this section, the proportion of cost, debt service and\noperating expense to be borne by such town and village may by written\nagreement be fixed in the aggregate in the ratio which the equalized\nassessed valuation of such town bears to the total equalized assessed\nvaluation of all towns joining in such project.  The pro...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>