<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-127"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-127"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="127"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-127/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-127/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-127/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-127/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_127">
        <num>127</num>
        <heading>Appointment and terms of office of managers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 127. Appointment and terms of office of managers.  1. Except as\nprovided in subdivision two, when a governing board of a county, town,\ncity or village shall have determined to establish a public general\nhospital for the care and treatment of the sick, the board of\nsupervisors of the county, the supervisor of the town, the mayor of the\ncity or the president of the board of trustees of the village shall\nappoint not less than five and not more than fifteen citizens of the\ncounty, town, city or village, respectively, who shall constitute a\nboard of managers of the said hospital. The term of office of each\nmember of said board shall be five years, and the term of one of such\nmanagers shall expire annually; the first appointments, however, being\nmade for the respective terms of five, four, three, two and one years.\nAppointments of successors shall be for the full term of five years,\nexcept that the appointment of a person to fill a vacancy occurring by\ndeath, resignation or cause other than the expiration of a term shall be\nmade for the unexpired term.\n  2. When the board of supervisors of any county having a population of\nmore than six hundred thousand but less than one million shall have\ndetermined to establish a public general hospital for the care and\ntreatment of the sick, the board of supervisors of such county shall\nappoint seven citizens of the county who shall constitute a board of\nmanagers of such hospital. The members of such board first appointed\nshall be appointed for terms of office as follows: one for a term of one\nyear, two for terms of two years each, one for a term of three years,\ntwo for terms of four years each, and one for a term of five years.\nTheir successors shall be appointed for terms of five years each.\nVacancies occurring by death, resignation or cause other than the\nexpiration of a term shall be made for the remainder of the unexpired\nterm.\n  3. Failure of any manager to attend three consecutive meetings of the\nboard shall cause a vacancy in his office, unless said absence is\nexcused by formal action of the board of managers. The managers shall\nreceive no compensation for their services, but shall be allowed their\nactual and necessary traveling and other expenses, to be audited by the\ngoverning board, and paid in the same manner as the other expenses of\nthe hospital. Any manager may be removed from office at any time by the\nappointing authority after having received notice in writing of the\ncause of the proposed removal and after an opportunity to be heard\nthereon. Unless a treasurer for the hospital is appointed as herein\nprovided the treasurer of the county, town, city or village by which the\nhospital is maintained shall be treasurer of the hospital.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>