<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-129"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-129"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="129"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-129/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-129/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-129/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-129/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_129">
        <num>129</num>
        <heading>General powers and duties of superintendent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 129.  General powers and duties of superintendent.  The\nsuperintendent shall be the chief executive officer of the hospital and,\nsubject to the by-laws, rules and regulations thereof, and to the\ngeneral control of the board of managers, shall:\n  1.  Equip the hospital with all necessary furniture, appliances,\nfixtures and other needed facilities for the care and treatment of\npatients and for the use of officers and employees thereof, and purchase\nall necessary supplies, unless the board of managers shall designate the\npurchasing agent of a municipality as the purchasing agent of said board\nas provided in subdivision five of section one hundred twenty-eight.\n  2.  Have general supervision and control of the records, accounts, and\nbuildings of the hospital and all internal affairs, and maintain\ndiscipline therein, and enforce compliance with, and obedience to, all\nrules, by-laws, and regulations adopted by the board of managers for the\ngovernment, discipline and management of said hospital, and the\nemployees and inmates thereof.  He shall make and enforce such further\nrules, regulations and orders as he may deem necessary, not inconsistent\nwith law, or with the rules, regulations and directions of the board of\nmanagers.\n  3.  Appoint such employees as he may think proper and necessary for\nthe efficient performance of the business of the hospital, and prescribe\ntheir duties; and discharge any such employee pursuant to the provisions\nof the civil service law.\n  4.  Cause proper accounts and records of the business and operations\nof the hospital to be kept regularly from day to day, in books and on\nforms provided for that purpose; and see that such accounts and records\nare correctly made up for the annual report to the governing board, as\nrequired by subdivision seven of section one hundred and twenty-eight of\nthis chapter, and present the same to the board of managers, who shall\nincorporate them in their annual report to the said governing board.\n  5.  Receive into the hospital, under the rules established by the\nboard of managers, any person in the county, town, city or village who\nis sick or maimed or injured and who is in need of hospital care,\nirrespective of whether such person is able to pay for his care or not;\nand may also receive persons from without the county, town, city or\nvillage, provided there is a vacancy in the hospital, and provided the\nreception of such person does not interfere with the proper care and\ntreatment of persons received from the county, town, city or village.\n  6. Cause to be kept proper records of the admission of all patients,\ntheir name, age, sex, color, marital condition, residence, occupation,\nplace of last employment and the names and addresses of their nearest\nrelatives or friends.  He shall also cause a careful examination to be\nmade of the physical condition of all persons admitted to the hospital;\nand shall cause a record to be kept of the condition of each patient\nwhen admitted, and from time to time thereafter.\n  7.  Discharge from said hospital any patient who is found to have\nrecovered from his illness sufficiently to be no longer in need of\nhospital care, or who shall wilfully or habitually violate the rules\nthereof, or who for any other reason is no longer a suitable patient for\ntreatment therein; and shall make a full report thereof at the next\nmeeting of the board of managers.\n  8.  Collect and receive all money due the hospital, keep an accurate\naccount of the same, report the same at the ensuing monthly meeting of\nthe board of managers, and transmit the same within ten days after such\nmeeting to the treasurer of the county, town, city or village by which\nthe hospital is maintained.  When a treasurer has been appointed as\nherein provided, all moneys collected and received by the superintendent\nshall be transmitted to the treasurer who shall deposit the same in a\nbank or banks in the name of the hospital and he shall also at least\nonce in each month transmit to the governing board an itemized statement\nthereof.\n  9.  Give a bond before entering upon the discharge of his duties, in\nsuch sum as the board of managers may determine, to secure the faithful\nperformance of such duties.\n  10. Notwithstanding any provisions of law, rule or regulation to the\ncontrary, the board of managers of the hospital may authorize the\nsuperintendents of said hospital to establish a system for the billing\nof patients for the care, maintenance or treatment received or furnished\nto patients in such facility.  Payment of such charges by means of a\ncredit card may be authorized pursuant to section five of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>