<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="130"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-130/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-130/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_130">
        <num>130</num>
        <heading>Admission and maintenance of patients</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Employment agreement shall mean the agreement between the hospital\nand the salaried physicians and dentists as approved by the governing\nbody of the municipality operating such hospital.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Private patient shall mean only such patient for whom the salaried\nphysician or dentist has rendered a service as now or hereafter so\ndescribed by the Social Security Administration for Title 18, Part B, of\nthe Federal Social Security Act of l965.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Teaching hospital shall, for the purposes of this chapter, mean a\nhospital having a contractual agreement with a medical school, as such\nmedical school is defined in section sixty-five hundred one of the\neducation law, for the training of medical students.\n  5. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision two of this section,\nwhenever a contract shall be in effect with any medical expense\nindemnity corporation governed by the provisions of article forty-three\nof the insurance law or any other authorized insurer for the rendering\nof medical care by a duly licensed physician or dentist to the\nsubscribers of such corporation or authorized insurer, the rendering of\nmedical care by a salaried physician or dentist, other than an interne\nor resident, employed by any such public general teaching hospital, to\nsuch subscribers insofar as payment for such medical care is concerned\nshall be subject to the provisions of such contract and the terms of the\nemployment agreement, provided such salaried physician or dentist\ntreated such individual as his private patient and personally performed\nthe services involved, and in such case the provisions of subdivision\ntwo, to the extent inconsistent therewith shall be inapplicable.\n  6. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision two of this section,\nwhenever any person eligible for benefit payments for services of a\nphysician or dentist under Title 18, Part B, of the Federal Social\nSecurity Act of l965 shall have received medical care as a private\npatient of a salaried physician or dentist other than an interne or\nresident, employed by any such public general teaching hospital, the\nrendering of and payment for such medical care shall be subject to the\nprovisions of such title and the terms of the employment agreement and\nin such case the provisions of subdivision two, to the extent\ninconsistent therewith, shall be inapplicable.\n  7. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision two of this section,\nwheneve...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the hospital or any of the professional employees have failed\nto comply with the provisions of the approved clinical practice plan; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the hospital or any of the professional employees have failed to\nprovide the state commissioner of health with the data necessary to\nevaluate the operation of the clinical practice plan; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_130__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\napproved clinical practice plan has not met the requirements of this\nsubdivision. No revocation, suspension or limitation of such plan may be\nmade without providing an opportunity for a formal hearing conducted in\naccordance with section twelve-a of the public health law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>