<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-135-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-135-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="135-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-135-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-135-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-135-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-135-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_135_A">
        <num>135-A</num>
        <heading>Workshops in connection with hospitals and facilities for the aged</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 135-a. Workshops in connection with hospitals and facilities for the\naged.\n  1. Any municipal corporation maintaining a hospital, sanitorium, home\nfor the indigent or aged or facility for the chronically ill, may\nestablish and maintain workshops in connection therewith for the\nproduction of articles or supplies required by such institution, or by\nany other institution or department of such municipality. Except in a\nsupervisory or teaching capacity no person shall be employed in such\nworkshop or workshops unless he is or shall have been a patient or\nresident in such institution. The appropriate municipal authorities may\nappropriate or provide funds for the establishment and maintenance of\nthe said workshops in the same manner as for the establishment and\nmaintenance of such institutions. Notwithstanding the provisions of the\ncorrection law in relation to the sale of articles manufactured in the\nstate prisons, the products of such workshops may be used in such\ninstitution or by any other institution or department of such\nmunicipality. Such workshops shall be under the direction and control of\nthe municipal authority having direction and control of the institution\nto which they may be attached.\n  2. The provisions of the workmen's compensation law, the unemployment\ninsurance law, and of articles thirteen, nineteen and twenty of the\nlabor law shall be inapplicable to any patient of a hospital maintained\nand operated by any municipal corporation with respect to his\nparticipation in a sheltered workshop program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>