<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-145"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-145"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="145"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-145/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-145/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-145/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-145/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_145">
        <num>145</num>
        <heading>Subject to visitation of supreme court</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 145. Subject to visitation of supreme court. All corporations\nexisting under this article, together with their books and vouchers,\nshall be subject to the visitation and inspection of the justices of the\nsupreme court, or of any person or persons who shall be appointed by the\nsupreme court for that purpose; and it shall be the duty of the trustees\nor a majority of them, in the month of December in each year, to make\nand file in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the\ninterested city, village or town is situate, a certificate under their\nhands, stating the names of the trustees and officers of such\ncorporation, with an inventory of the property, effects and liabilities\nthereof, with an affidavit of the truth of such inventory and\ncertificate. Said trustees shall be entitled to such compensation as\nsaid court shall fix. Said court shall also have power to control the\ndiscretion of said trustees in determining what property may be demised\nand for how long; also how much money may be invested and kept invested\non interest to produce an income for the purpose of aiding and\ninstructing children or to keep up and maintain the parks or libraries,\nor either of such purposes; and also in a summary way to determine the\nreasonableness of any rules and regulations, upon complaint of any\ninhabitant of the interested city, village or town, and upon notice to\nsaid trustees.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>