<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-181"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-181"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-09-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="181"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-181/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-181/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-181/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-181/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_181">
        <num>181</num>
        <heading>Ordinances to regulate taxicabs and limousines</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 181. Ordinances to regulate taxicabs and limousines. The municipal\nofficers and boards in the several cities, towns and villages of this\nstate now having the authority to enact ordinances, may adopt ordinances\nregulating:\n  1. The registration and licensing of taxicabs and may limit the number\nof taxicabs to be licensed and the county of Westchester may adopt\nordinances regulating the registration and licensing of taxicabs and\nlimousines and may limit the number to be licensed; the county of Nassau\nmay adopt ordinances regulating the registration of taxicabs and\nlimousines; and the county of Suffolk may adopt local laws or ordinances\nregulating the registration of taxicabs, limousines, and livery\nvehicles; the county of Rockland may adopt local laws or ordinances\nregulating the registration and licensing of taxicabs, limousines, and\nlivery vehicles and may limit the number to be licensed; and the county\nof Dutchess may adopt local laws or ordinances regulating the\nregistration and licensing of taxicabs, limousines and livery vehicles;\nand the county of Ulster may adopt local laws or ordinances regulating\nthe registration and licensing of taxicabs, limousines, and livery\nvehicles.\n  2. Parking and passenger pick-up and discharge by taxicabs, limousines\nand livery vehicles. Establishment of such local laws or ordinances and\nregulations regulating parking and passenger pick-up and discharges may\nbe based upon recommendations from municipal planning officials or other\npublic entities and may address and take into consideration such\nfactors, including, but not limited to, geographic areas, vehicle type,\nlimiting the number of parked vehicles and activities undertaken while\nparked, and periods of idling.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>