<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-182"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-182"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-06-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="182"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-182/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-182/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-182/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-182/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_182">
        <num>182</num>
        <heading>Local regulation of transportation network companies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 182. Local regulation of transportation network companies. 1. Every\ncounty, and any city with a population of one hundred thousand or more\nas of the last decennial census, may prohibit the pick-up of any person\nby a transportation network company as defined by article forty-four-B\nof the vehicle and traffic law within their geographic boundaries\npursuant to the enactment of a local law or ordinance, except that any\ncounty that contains a city with a population of one hundred thousand or\nmore as of the last decennial census shall only be authorized to\nprohibit the pick-up of any person by a transportation network company\nas defined by article forty-four-B of the vehicle and traffic law\noutside of the geographic boundaries of such city.\n  2. Any county or city that enacts a local law or ordinance pursuant to\nthis section or repeals such local law or ordinance shall notify the\ndepartment of motor vehicles. Such department shall maintain on its\npublic website a list of all counties and cities that have enacted a\nlocal law or ordinance pursuant to this section and shall remove from\nsuch list any county or city that repeals such local law or ordinance.\n  3. This section shall not apply to a city with a population of one\nmillion or more.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>