<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-188-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-188-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="188-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-188-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-188-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-188-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-188-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_188_A">
        <num>188-A</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the board</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_188_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commission shall have the power to approve and establish a\nstandard set of games of chance equipment and shall by its rules and\nregulations prescribe the manner in which such equipment is to be\nreproduced and distributed to licensed authorized organizations. The\nsale or distribution to a licensed authorized organization of any\nequipment other than that contained in the standard set of games of\nchance equipment shall constitute a violation of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_188_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After the effective date of this paragraph, no electronic bell jar\nvending machine shall be sold, leased, distributed, installed, or\noperated by any manufacturer, distributor, or charitable organization\nuntil such machine has been approved by the commission. No electronic\nbell jar vending machine shall be approved by the commission unless the\noperation of the game demonstrates that there is a finite probability\nbasis of having a predetermined quantity of chances among which there is\na predetermined quantity of winners that pay a fixed and predetermined\nvalue of prizes, regardless of the symbols that are used or how those\nsymbols are displayed on pre-printed bell jar tickets.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_188_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commission shall promulgate such rules and regulations as may\nbe necessary for the approval and implementation of electronic bell jar\nvending machine gaming. The commission may revoke, suspend, or condition\napproval of an electronic bell jar vending machine. Upon request for\nauthorization, the commission shall approve or deny such request within\nthirty days. If the commission denies such request for approval, it\nshall provide the reasons for such determination.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>