<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-189-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-189-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="189-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-189-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-189-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-189-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-189-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_189_A">
        <num>189-A</num>
        <heading>Authorized supplier of games of chance equipment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The following shall be ineligible for such a license:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a person convicted of a crime if there is a direct relationship\nbetween one or more of the previous criminal offenses and the integrity\nor safety of charitable gaming, considering the factors set forth in\narticle twenty-three-A of the correction law;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a person who is or has been a professional gambler or gambling\npromoter or who for other reasons is not of good moral character;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a public officer or employee;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>an authorized games of chance lessor;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a firm or corporation in which a person defined in paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_189_A__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this subdivision has greater than a ten percent\nproprietary, equitable or credit interest or in which such a person is\nactive or employed.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_189_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board shall have power to examine or cause to be examined the\nbooks and records of any applicant for a license, under this section.\nAny information so received shall not be disclosed except so far as may\nbe necessary for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_189_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any solicitation of an organization licensed to conduct games of\nchance, to purchase or induce the purchase of games of chance supplies\nand equipment, other than by a person licensed or otherwise authorized\npursuant to this section shall constitute a violation of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_189_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person who willfully shall make any material false statement\nin any application for a license authorized to be issued under this\nsection or who willfully shall violate any of the provisions of this\nsection or of any license issued hereunder shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor and, in addition to the penalties in such case made and\nprovided, shall forfeit any license issued to him or it under this\nsection and be ineligible to apply for a license under this section for\none year thereafter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_189_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the end of such period specified in the license, a\nrecapitulation shall be made as between the licensee and the board in\nrespect of the gross sales and rentals actually recorded during that\nperiod and the fee paid therefor, and any deficiency of fee thereby\nshown to be due shall be paid by the licensee and any excess of fee\nthereby shown to have been paid shall be credited to said licensee in\nsuch manner as the board by the rules and regulations shall prescribe.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>