<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-194"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-194"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-02-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="194"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-194/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-194/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-194/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-194/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_194">
        <num>194</num>
        <heading>Control and supervision; suspension of identification numbers and licenses; inspection of premises</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 194. Control and supervision; suspension of identification numbers\nand licenses; inspection of premises. 1. The officer or department,\nshall have and exercise rigid control and close supervision over all\ngames of chance conducted under such license, to the end that the same\nare fairly conducted in accordance with the provisions of such license,\nthe provisions of the rules and regulations promulgated by the board,\nand the provisions of this article. Such officer or department and the\nboard shall have the power and the authority to temporarily suspend any\nlicense issued by the clerk or department and/or impose fines for\nviolations not to exceed one thousand dollars. Temporary suspension of\nlicenses shall be promptly followed by a hearing, and after notice and\nhearing, the clerk, department, or board may suspend or revoke the same\nand declare the violator ineligible to apply for a license for a period\nnot exceeding twelve months thereafter. Any fines tendered to the clerk,\ndepartment, or board shall not be paid from funds derived from the\nconduct of games of chance. The officer and the department or the board\nshall additionally have the right of entry, by their respective officers\nand agents, at all times into any premises where any game of chance is\nbeing conducted or where it is intended that any such game shall be\nconducted, or where any equipment being used or intended to be used in\nthe conduct thereof is found, for the purpose of inspecting the same.\nUpon suspension or revocation of any license or upon declaration of\nineligibility to apply for a license, the board may suspend or revoke\nthe identification number issued pursuant to section one hundred\neighty-eight-a of this article. An agent of the appropriate officer or\ndepartment shall make an on site inspection during the conduct of all\ngames of chance licensed pursuant to this article.\n  2. A municipality may, by local law or ordinance enacted pursuant to\nthe provisions of section one hundred eighty-eight of this article,\nprovide that the powers and duties set forth in subdivision one of this\nsection, shall be exercised by the chief law enforcement officer of the\ncounty.  In the event a municipality exercises this option the fees\nprovided for by subdivision two of section one hundred ninety-five-f of\nthis article, shall be remitted to the chief fiscal officer of the\ncounty.\n  3. Subject to the applicable provisions of the alcoholic beverage\ncontrol law, beer, cider, mead, braggot and wine may be offered for sale\nduring the conduct of games of chance on games of chance premises as\nsuch premises are defined in subdivision nineteen of section one hundred\neighty-six of this article; provided, however, that nothing herein shall\nbe construed to limit the offering for sale of any other alcoholic\nbeverage in areas other than the games of chance premises or the sale of\nany other alcoholic beverage in premises where only the games of chance\nknown as bell jar or raffles are conducted.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>