<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-07-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="195-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_195_E">
        <num>195-E</num>
        <heading>Advertising games</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 195-e. Advertising games. A licensee may advertise the conduct of\ngames of chance to the general public by means of newspaper, circular,\nhandbill and poster, and by one sign not exceeding sixty square feet in\narea, which may be displayed on or adjacent to the premises owned or\noccupied by a licensed authorized organization, through the internet or\ntelevision as may be regulated by the rules and regulations of the\ncommission. When an organization is licensed or authorized to conduct\ngames of chance on the premises of an authorized games of chance lessor,\none additional such sign may be displayed on or adjacent to the premises\nin which the games are to be conducted. Additional signs may be\ndisplayed upon any firefighting or ambulance equipment belonging to any\nlicensed authorized organization that is a volunteer fire company,\nvolunteer ambulance corps or upon any equipment of a first aid or rescue\nsquad in and throughout the community served by such volunteer fire\ncompany, volunteer ambulance corps or such first aid or rescue squad, as\nthe case may be. All advertisements shall be limited to the description\nof such event as "Games of chance" or "Las Vegas Night", the name of the\nauthorized organization conducting such games, the license number of the\nauthorized organization as assigned by the clerk or department, the\nprizes offered and the date, location and time of the event.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>