<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="195-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_195_N">
        <num>195-N</num>
        <heading>Manufacturers of bell jars; reports and records</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_195_N__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon such first offense, have their license suspended\nfor a period of thirty days;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_195_N__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon such second offense, participate\nin a hearing to be conducted by the commission, and surrender their\nlicense for such period as recommended by the commission; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_195_N__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon\nsuch third or subsequent offense, have their license suspended for a\nperiod of one year and shall be guilty of a class E felony. Any\nunlicensed manufacturer who violates the provisions of this section\nshall be guilty of a class E felony.\n  2. Bar codes. The manufacturer shall affix to the flare of each bell\njar game a bar code that provides all information prescribed by the\nboard and shall require that the bar code include the serial number of\nthe game the flare describes. A manufacturer shall also affix to the\noutside of the container or wrapping containing  a deal of bell jar\ntickets a bar code providing all information prescribed by the board and\ncontaining the same information as the bar code affixed to the flare.\nThe board may also prescribe additional bar code requirements. No person\nmay alter the bar code that appears on the flare or on the outside of\nthe container or wrapping containing a deal of bell jar tickets.\nPossession of a deal of bell jar tickets that has a bar code different\nfrom the serial number of the deal inside the container or wrapping as\nevidenced on the flare is prima facie evidence that the possessor has\naltered the bar code on the container or wrapping.\n  3. Bell jar flares.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_195_N__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A manufacturer shall not ship or cause to be\nshipped into this state any deal of bell jar tickets that does not have\nits own individual flare as required for that deal by rule of the board.\nA person other than a licensed manufacturer shall not manufacture,\nalter, modify, or otherwise change a flare for a deal of bell jar\ntickets except as authorized by this article or rules and regulations\npromulgated by the board.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_195_N__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The flare for each deal of bell jar tickets sold by a manufacturer\nin this state shall be placed inside the wrapping of the deal which the\nflare describes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_195_N__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The bar code affixed to the flare of each bell jar game shall bear\nthe serial number of such game as prescribed by the board.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_195_N__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The flare of each bell jar game shall have affixed a bar code that\nprovides:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_195_N__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the game code;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_195_N__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the serial number of the game;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_195_N__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the\nname of the manufacturer; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_195_N__subsec_d__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>other information the board by rule\nmay require. The serial number included on the bar code shall be the\nsame as the serial number of the tickets included in the deal. A\nmanufacturer who manufactures a deal of bell jar tickets shall affix to\nthe outside of the container or wrapping containing the bell jar tickets\nthe same bar code that is affixed to the flare for that deal.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_195_N__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No person shall alter the bar code that appears on the outside of\na container or wrapping containing a deal of bell jar tickets.\nPossession of a deal of bell jars that has a bar code different from the\nbar code of the deal inside the container or wrapping is prima facie\nevidence that the possessor has altered the bar code on the box.\n  4. Reports of sales. A manufacturer who sells bell jar tickets for\nresale in this state shall file with the commission, on a form\nprescribed by the commission a report of all bell jar tickets sold to\ndistributors in the state. The report shall be filed quarterly on or\nbefore the twentieth day of the month succeeding the end of the quarter\nin which the sale was made. The commission may require that the report\nbe submitted via magnetic media or electronic data transfer. Such report\nshall also include information regarding any electronic bell jar vending\nmachines sold or leased to a distributor licensed by the commission.\n  5. Inspection. The board may inspect the premises, books, records, and\ninventory of a manufacturer without notice during the normal business\nhours of the manufacturer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>