<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="195-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-195-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_195_G">
        <num>195-G</num>
        <heading>Examination of books and records; examination of officers and employees; disclosure of information</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 195-g. Examination of books and records; examination of officers and\nemployees; disclosure of information. The clerk or department and the\nboard shall have power to examine or cause to be examined the books and\nrecords of:\n  1. Any authorized organization which is or has been licensed to\nconduct games of chance, so far as they may relate to games of chance\nincluding the maintenance, control and disposition of net proceeds\nderived from games of chance or from the use of its premises for games\nof chance, and to examine any manager, officer, director, agent, member\nor employee thereof under oath in relation to the conduct of any such\ngame under any such license, the use of its premises for games of\nchance, or the disposition of net proceeds derived from games of chance,\nas the case may be.\n  2. Any authorized games of chance lessor so far as they may relate to\nleasing premises for games of chance and to examine said lessor or any\nmanager, officer, director, agent or employee thereof under oath in\nrelation to such leasing.\n  Any information so received shall not be disclosed except so far as\nmay be necessary for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>