<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-200-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-200-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="200-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-200-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-200-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-200-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-200-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_200_B">
        <num>200-B</num>
        <heading>Leaves of absence for volunteer firefighters entering the armed forces of the United States prior to July first, nineteen hundred sixty-six</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 200-b. Leaves of absence for volunteer firefighters entering the\narmed forces of the United States prior to July first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-six. 1. When, prior to July first, nineteen hundred sixty-six, a\nvolunteer firefighter in good standing in the fire company or department\nof which he is a member enters upon active duty in the armed forces of\nthe United States (1) during any war between the United States and any\nother nation, or (2) during the period beginning with the commencement\nof the military and naval preparedness in the year nineteen hundred\nforty and continuing on July first, nineteen hundred sixty-six, and by\nreason of such active duty is prevented from actually performing duty as\na volunteer firefighter in his fire company or department, he shall be\ngiven a leave of absence from said company or department for a period\nwhich, when added to his period of service as a volunteer firefighter,\nshall not exceed five years. The fire company or department, however,\nmay grant a volunteer firefighter on such active duty a leave of absence\nfor a period longer than the mandatory period above specified. Any\ncertificate issued to the volunteer firefighter as provided in section\ntwo hundred two of this article shall credit him with the period of any\nsuch leave of absence in the same manner as if he had served during such\nperiod as a member of his fire company or department and had rendered\nservice in all respects as specified in section two hundred of this\narticle. The period of any such leave of absence shall be included in\ndetermining the period of service necessary to qualify him as an exempt\nvolunteer firefighter pursuant to section two hundred of this article.\nDuring the period of any such leave of absence such volunteer\nfirefighter shall not perform any services or duties as a volunteer\nfirefighter except for services and duties performed pursuant to\nsubdivision one-a of this section.\n  1-a. A volunteer firefighter on leave of absence, pursuant to this\nsection, may perform services and duties as a volunteer firefighter\nduring any period in which the armed forces of the United States grants\nthe volunteer firefighter a temporary leave from military service,\nprovided that such services and duties would not violate any law,\nregulation, rule or order of the United States or of the armed forces of\nthe United States. This subdivision shall not be construed to require a\nvolunteer firefighter on such temporary leave to perform services and\nduties as a volunteer firefighter during any temporary leave from\nmilitary service.\n  2. During the period of any such leave of absence the fire company or\ndepartment may enroll another person as a member to take the place of\nthe volunteer firefighter on such active duty. Any person so enrolled\nmay continue as a member of the company or department until he or she\nshall have served the time necessary to qualify him or her as an exempt\nvolunteer firefighter, even though the person whose place he or she took\nmay have resumed his or her duties as a volunteer firefighter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>