<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-06-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="205-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_205_CC">
        <num>205-CC</num>
        <heading>Volunteer firefighter enhanced cancer disability benefits</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_205_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A volunteer firefighter having five or more years of faithful\nand actual service in the protection of life and property from fire in\nthe interior of buildings subsequent to having successfully passed a\nphysical examination which failed to reveal any evidence of cancers as\ndefined in paragraph b of this subdivision; and\n  * NB Effective until December 23, 2029\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_205_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A volunteer firefighter having five or more years of faithful\nand actual service in the protection of life and property from fire in\nthe interior of buildings and having successfully passed a physical\nexamination on entry to the firefighter service, which examination\nfailed to reveal any evidence of cancers as defined in paragraph b of\nthis subdivision; and\n  * NB Effective December 23, 2029\n  * (ii) Having submitted proof of five years of interior firefighting\nservice by providing verification that he or she has passed at least\nfive yearly certified mask fitting tests as set forth in 29 CFR 1910.134\nor the applicable National Fire Protection Association standards for\nmask fit testing or, for firefighters who entered the fire service prior\nto January first, two thousand twenty, documentation identified by the\noffice of fire prevention and control in rules and regulations\npromulgated pursuant to subdivision seven of this section which shall\ninclude, but not be limited to, training or certification records,\nhealth care provider records, internal fire department records, or any\ncombination of official documents capable of evidencing that the\nfirefighter meets the requirements of this section.\n  * NB Effective until December 23, 2029\n  * (ii) Having submitted proof of five years of interior firefighting\nservice by providing verification that he or she has passed at least\nfive yearly certified mask fitting tests as set forth in 29 CFR 1910.134\nor the current National Fire Protection Association standards for mask\nfit testing.\n  * NB Effective December 23, 2029\n  b. "Cancer" means:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_205_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A disease caused by an uncontrolled division of abnormal cells in\na part of the body or a malignant growth or tumor resulting from the\ndivision of abnormal cells; and\n  (ii) Affecting the prostate or breast, lymphatic, hematological\ndigestive, urinary, neurological, or reproductive systems, or melanoma.\n  2. An eligible volunteer firefighter shall be entitled to payment of\nenhanced cancer benefits as follows:\n  a. A lump sum benefit of twenty-five thousand dollars for each\ndiagnosis payable to such firefighter upon acceptable proof to the\ninsurance carrier or other payor of a diagnosis by a board certified\nphysician in the medical specialty appropriate for the type of cancer\ndiagnosed that there are one or more malignant tumors characterized by\nthe uncontrollable and abnormal growth and spread of malignant cells\nwith invasion of normal tissue and that either:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_205_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is metastasis; and\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_205_CC__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>surgery, radiotherapy, or chemotherapy is medically necessary; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_205_CC__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>there is a tumor of the prostate, provided that it is treated with\nradical prostatectomy or external beam therapy; or\n  (ii) The firefighter has terminal cancer, his or her life expectancy\nis twenty-four months or less from the date of diagnosis, and will not\nbenefit from, or has exhausted, curative therapy.\n  b. A lump sum benefit of six thousand two hundred fifty dollars for\neach diagnosis payable to such firefighter upon acceptable proof to the\ninsurance carrier or other payor of a diagnosis by a board certified\nphysician in the medical specialty appropriate for the type of cancer\ninvolved that either:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_205_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is carcinoma in situ such that surgery, radiotherapy, or\nchemotherapy has been determined to be medically necessary;\n  (ii) There are malignant tumors which are treated by endoscopic\nprocedures alone; or\n  (iii) There are malignant melanomas.\n  c. A monthly benefit of one thousand five hundred dollars, of which\nthe first payment shall be made six months after total disability and\nsubmission of acceptable proof of said disability to the insurance\ncarrier or other payor that such disability is caused by cancer and that\nsuch cancer precludes the firefighter from serving as a firefighter.\nSuch benefit shall continue for up to thirty-six consecutive monthly\npayments.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_205_CC__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such monthly benefit shall be subordinate to any other benefit\nactually paid to the firefighter solely for such disability from any\nother source, not including private insurance purchased solely by the\nfirefighter, and shall be limited to the difference between the amount\nof such other paid benefit and the amount specified herein; and\n  (ii) Any firefighter receiving such monthly benefits may be required\nto have his or her condition reevaluated. In the event any such\nreevaluation reveals that such person has regained the ability to\nperform duties as a firefighter, then his or her monthly benefits shall\ncease the last day of the month of reevaluation.\n  (iii) In the event that there is a subsequent reoccurrence of a\ndisability caused by cancer which precludes the firefighter from serving\nas a firefighter, he or she shall be entitled to receive any remaining\nmonthly payments.\n  d. An eligible volunteer firefighter shall also be entitled to an\nadditional payment of enhanced cancer death benefits in the amount of\nfifty thousand dollars which is payable to such volunteer or his or her\nbeneficiary upon acceptable proof by a board certified physician that\nsuch firefighter's death resulted from complications associated with\ncancer.\n  e. Provided however, an eligible volunteer firefighter shall be\nineligible for these benefits if they are already provided paid\nfirefighter benefits under this article.\n  3. The combined total of all benefits received by any eligible\nvolunteer firefighter pursuant to paragraphs a and b of subdivision two\nof this section during his or her lifetime shall not exceed fifty\nthousand dollars.\n  4. An eligible volunteer firefighter shall remain eligible for\nbenefits pursuant to paragraphs a, b and d of subdivision two of this\nsection for sixty months after the formal cessation of the volunteer\nfirefighter's status as an active volunteer firefighter. The fire\ndistrict, department or company in which such firefighter serve...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>