<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="205-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-205-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_205_C">
        <num>205-C</num>
        <heading>Payments pending controversies where volunteer firefighters are killed or injured</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 205-c. Payments pending controversies where volunteer firefighters\nare killed or injured. In order to provide for the prompt payment of\nbenefits under sections two hundred five and two hundred nine-a of this\narticle, and under the workers' compensation law, where such benefits\nare conceded to be due to any person because of the death of or injuries\nto a volunteer firefighter but controversy exists as to which city,\nvillage, town or fire district is liable for the payment thereof, the\nmunicipalities and districts involved in such controversy and their\ninsurance carriers, if any, may agree that any one or more of such\nmunicipalities or districts or its insurance carrier shall pay the\nbenefits to, or in relation to, the person conceded to be entitled to\nsuch benefits without waiting for a final determination of the\ncontroversy, and may carry out the provisions of such an agreement.\nNotwithstanding any such payment, any party to the agreement may seek a\nfinal determination of the controversy in the same manner as if such\npayment had not been made. After a final determination the parties to\nthe agreement shall make any necessary and proper reimbursement to\nconform to the determination. The term "insurance carrier" as used\nherein shall mean an insurance company, or a county mutual\nself-insurance plan in accordance with subdivision three-a of section\nfifty of the workers' compensation law, or any plan which shall be\nprovided for by law in amendment of or substitution for such a plan.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>