<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-I*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-I*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207-I*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-I*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-I*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-I*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-I*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207_I*2">
        <num>207-I*2</num>
        <heading>Supplemental retirement allowances of retired firefighters of cities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 207-i. Supplemental retirement allowances of retired firefighters\nof cities. Nothing in any general, special or local law, administrative\ncode, ordinance, rule or regulation or pension contract to the contrary\nnotwithstanding a supplemental retirement allowance shall be paid\npursuant to the provisions of subdivisions a and b of this section to\npensioners of a pension or retirement system of a paid fire department\nof a city who have retired prior to the calendar year nineteen hundred\nseventy. Such supplemental retirement allowance under such subdivisions\na and b shall be payable on the basis provided for herein, commencing\nwith a payment for the month of October, nineteen hundred sixty-seven,\nand continuing through the month of September, nineteen hundred\nseventy-three, except that in the case of pensioners of a pension or\nretirement system of a paid fire department of a city having a\npopulation of one million or more, such payments shall continue monthly\nthereafter.\n  a. The supplemental retirement allowance provided for in this\nsubdivision and in subdivision b of this section shall be a percentage\nof the retirement allowance computed without optional modification and\nshall be determined on the basis of the consumer price index (all items\n-- United States city average), published by the United States Bureau of\nLabor Statistics. Said percentage shall be determined in the manner set\nforth in this section. Said supplemental retirement allowance shall be\ncomputed on the basis of the first ten thousand five hundred dollars of\nsuch annual retirement allowance and shall be payable commencing October\nfirst, nineteen hundred sixty-seven, to all disability pensioners, and\nto other pensioners who have attained age sixty-two on or before\nSeptember thirtieth, nineteen hundred sixty-seven and commencing on\nApril first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, to such other pensioners who\nshall have attained age sixty-two on or after October first, nineteen\nhundred sixty-seven and on or before September thirtieth, nineteen\nhundred sixty-eight, and commencing on October first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-eight, to such other pensioners who shall have attained age\nsixty-two on or after April first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight and on\nor before September thirtieth, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, and\ncommencing on October first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, to such other\npensioners who shall have attained age sixty-two on or after October\nfirst, nineteen hundred sixty-eight and on or before September\nthirtieth, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, and commencing on October first,\nnineteen hundred seventy, to such other pensioners who shall have\nattained age sixty-two on or after October first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-nine and on or before September thirtieth, nineteen hundred\nseventy, and commencing on October first, nineteen hundred seventy-two,\nto such other pensioners who shall have attained age sixty-two on or\nafter October first, nineteen hundred seventy and on or before September\nthirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-two, and to each such other\npensioner of a pension or retirement system of a paid fire department of\na city having a population of one million or more who shall have\nattained age sixty-two on or after October first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-two, commencing with a payment for the later of the month of\nJuly, nineteen hundred eighty-one or the month of July next following\nthe twelve-month period ending June thirtieth in which such other\npensioner who shall have attained age sixty-two on or after October\nfirst, nineteen hundred seventy-two shall have attained such age, and\ncontinuing thereafter.\n  b. The percentage referred to in subdivision a hereof shall be\ndetermined from the ratio of two indexes, in the following manner. The\naverage of the twelve monthly consumer price indexes of the calendar\nyear nineteen hundred sixty-six or, for a supplemental retirement\nallowance payable pursuant to this section on or after October first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-eight, the average of the twelve monthly consumer\nprice indexes of the calendar year nineteen hundred sixty-seven or, for\na supplemental retirement allowance payable pursuant to this section on\nor after October first, nineteen hundred sixty-nine, the average of the\ntwelve monthly consumer price indexes of the calendar year nineteen\nhundred sixty-eight, or, for a supplemental retirement allowance payable\npursuant to this section on or after October first, nineteen hundred\nseventy, the average of the twelve monthly consumer price indexes of the\ncalendar year nineteen hundred sixty-nine, divided by the average of the\ntwelve monthly consumer price indexes of the calendar year of retirement\nshall be the ratio of the indexes. Said ratio, minus one, shall be\nexpressed as a percentage and shall be adjusted to the lower one-tenth\nof one per centum. Such adjusted percentage shall be the percentage of\nthe applicable portion of the retirement allowance, computed without\noptional modification which shall be payable as a supplemental\nretirement allowance under subdivision a of this section and under this\nsubdivision. However, no such supplement shall be paid where such\npercentage is less than three per centum. Such percentage for pensioners\nwho retired prior to April first, nineteen hundred fifty-eight shall be\nincreased by one hundred percentum thereof and the adjusted percentage\nshall be further adjusted to the lower one-tenth of one percentum. Such\npercentage shall be computed by the actuary each year and certified to\nthe comptroller who shall, by directive, promulgate a schedule of\npercentages to be used for this purpose.\n  b-1. (1) In addition to any supplemental retirement allowance payable\nin accordance with the provisions of subdivisions a and b of this\nsection, commencing with a payment for the month of July, nineteen\nhundred eighty-one and continuing monthly thereafter, there shall be\npaid to each disability pensioner of a pension or retirement system of a\npaid fire department of a city having a population of one million or\nmore who retired prior to April first, nineteen hundred seventy, an\namount of supplemental retirement allowance determined pursuant to the\nprovisions of paragraph three of this subdivision.\n  (2) In the case of each pensioner of such a pension or retirement\nsystem of such a city who retired prior to April first, nineteen hundred\nseventy other than for disability, commencing with a payment for the\nlater of the month of July, nineteen hundred eighty-one or the month of\nJuly next following the twelve-month period ending June thirtieth in\nwhich such pensioner shall have attained age sixty-two, and continuing\nmonthly thereafter, there shall be paid to such pensioner, in addition\nto any supplemental retirement allowance payable in accordance with the\nprovisions of subdivisions a and b of this section, an amount of\nsupplemental retirement allowance determined pursuant to the provisions\nof paragraph three of this subdivision.\n  (3) The amount of such additional supplemental retirement allowance\nreferred to in paragraphs one and two of this subdivision shall equal a\npercentage of the first ten thousand five hundred dollars of the annual\nretirement allowance computed without optional modification. Such\npercentage shall be determined by the date or year of retirement in\naccordance with the table set forth below:\n    YEAR OR DATE OF RETIREMENT               PERCENTAGE\n    April 1, 1969 to\n    and including March 31, 1970             twenty-one\n    January 1, 1968 to\n    and including March 31, 1969             twenty-two\n    1967                                     twenty-three\n    1966                                     twenty-four\n    1965                                     twenty-four\n    1964                                     twenty-five\n    1963                                     twenty-five\n    1962                                     twenty-six\n    1961                                     twenty-six\n    1960                                     twenty-seven\n    1959                                     twenty-seven\n    1958                                     twenty-seven\n    1957                                     twenty-seven\n    1956                                     twenty-eight\n    1955                                     twenty-eight\n    1954                                     twenty-eight\n    1953                                     twenty-eight\n    1952                                     twenty-eight\n    1951 and earlier                         twenty-nine\n  b-2. (1) Commencing with a payment for the month of July, nineteen\nhundred eighty-one and continuing monthly thereafter, there shall be\npaid to each disability pensioner of a pension or retirement system of a\npaid fire department of a city having a population of one million or\nmore who retired on or after April first, nineteen hundred seventy and\nbefore January first, nineteen hundred seventy-three, a supplemental\nretirement allowance determined pursuant to the provisions of paragraph\nthree of this subdivision.\n  (2) In the case of each pensioner of such a pension or retirement\nsystem of such a city who retired on or after April first, nineteen\nhundred seventy and before January first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-three, other than for disability, commencing with a payment for\nthe later of the month of July, nineteen hundred eighty-one or the month\nof July next following the twelve-month period ending June thirtieth in\nwhich such pensioner shall have attained age sixty-two and continuing\nmonthly thereafter, there shall be paid to such pensioner a supplemental\nretirement allowance determined pursuant to the provisions of paragraph\nthree of this subdivision.\n  (3) The amount of such supplemental retirement allowance referred to\nin paragraphs one and two of this sub</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>