<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207_N">
        <num>207-N</num>
        <heading>Performance of duty disability retirement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 207-n. Performance of duty disability retirement. Notwithstanding\nthe provisions of any general, special or local law or administrative\ncode to the contrary, but except for the purposes of the workers'\ncompensation law and the labor law, a paid member of the uniformed force\nof a paid correction department, where such paid member is drawn from\ncompetitive civil service lists, who successfully passed a physical\nexamination on entry into the service of such department, who contracts\nHIV (where there may have been exposure to a bodily fluid of an\nincarcerated individual or any person confined in an institution under\nthe jurisdiction of the department of corrections and community\nsupervision, or the department of health, or any person who has been\ncommitted to such institution by any court as a natural and proximate\nresult of an act of any incarcerated individual or person described\nabove, that may have involved transmission of a specified transmissible\ndisease from an incarcerated individual or person described above to the\nmember), tuberculosis or hepatitis will be presumed to have contracted\nsuch disease in the performance or discharge of his or her duties,\nunless the contrary be proved by competent evidence.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>