<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-Q*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-Q*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207-Q*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-Q*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-Q*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-Q*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-Q*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207_Q*2">
        <num>207-Q*2</num>
        <heading>Disabilities of emergency medical technicians or advanced emergency medical technicians in certain cities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 207-q. Disabilities of emergency medical technicians or advanced\nemergency medical technicians in certain cities. a. Disabilities of\npersons performing emergency medical services in certain cities.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local law or\nadministrative code to the contrary, but except for the purposes of the\nworkers' compensation law and the labor law, any condition of impairment\nof health caused by diseases of the heart resulting in total or partial\ndisability or death to a paid employee of a fire department who performs\nthe functions of an emergency medical technician or advanced emergency\nmedical technician in a city with a population of one million or more,\nwhere such employee is drawn from competitive civil service lists, who\nsuccessfully passed a physical examination on entry into the service of\nsuch department, which examination failed to reveal any evidence of such\ncondition, shall be presumptive evidence that it was incurred in the\nperformance of duty, unless the contrary be proved by competent\nevidence.\n  b. The provisions of this section shall remain in full force and\neffect to and including the thirtieth day of June, two thousand three.\n  * NB Expired July 1, 2003 per subdivision 2; see retirement and social\nsecurity law ยง 480 for expiration\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 207-q's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>