<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207_B">
        <num>207-B</num>
        <heading>Additional retirement benefits for certain firefighters in cities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 207-b. Additional retirement benefits for certain firefighters in\ncities. 1. As used in this section:\n  a. "Final compensation" means the average annual salary or wages for\nservices as a firefighter earned from the date of his or her minimum\nperiod to the date of his or her retirement.\n  b. " Firefighter" means a paid officer or member of the uniformed\nforce of the fire department of a city.\n  c. "Minimum period" means a fixed number of years of service as a\nfirefighter specified in a plan or option elected by him or her as a\nnecessary prerequisite for a pension or retirement allowance upon\nretirement from such service.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local\nlaw, charter or administrative code and in lieu of any lesser amount\nthereby prescribed, in the event a firefighter has served as such for\nhis or her minimum period and thereafter continues in such service, upon\nhis or her subsequent retirement for any cause whatsoever, there shall\nbe added to the amount of the annual pension or retirement allowance to\nwhich he or she was entitled upon such retirement, an additional amount\ncomputed at the rate of one-sixtieth of his or her final compensation\nfor each year of such additional service.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not apply to members of the\nNew York state and local police and fire retirement system.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>