<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-H*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-H*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207-H*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-H*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-H*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-H*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-H*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207_H*2">
        <num>207-H*2</num>
        <heading>Death benefits of members of certain police pension systems</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_H*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Member" means a contributor to a non-actuarial pension system of\nany city maintaining a police pension fund.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_H*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Accumulated deductions" means the sum of all the amounts,\ndeducted from the compensation of a member of such pension system or\ncontributed by him, standing to his credit therein, together with the\ninterest thereon, if any, as provided by the law, charter or\nadministrative code governing such system.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_H*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Pension" means payments for life derived from appropriations for\nand payments into such pension system by such city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_H*2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Minimum period of service" means a fixed number of years of\nservice specified in a plan or option provided by such police pension\nsystem and elected by such member, as a necessary prerequisite for a\npension or retirement allowance upon retirement from service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_H*2__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Minimum age" means the age specified in a plan or option provided\nby such police pension system and elected by such member, as a necessary\nprerequisite for a pension or retirement allowance upon retirement from\nservice.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local\nlaw, charter or administrative code, and in lieu of any lesser amount\ntherein prescribed, upon the death of a member of a non-actuarial police\npension system, prior to the first payment of a retirement benefit, who\nhas attained the minimum age or completed the minimum period of service,\nas elected by him for retirement, and whether or not such member shall\nhave filed application for retirement, there shall be paid to his\nestate, or to the person or persons he shall have nominated by written\ndesignation duly executed and filed in accordance with the requirements\nof such police pension system:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_H*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>His accumulated deductions; and in addition thereto,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_H*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An amount equal to the present value of the pension he would have\nreceived if he had retired and become entitled to a pension on the day\nimmediately preceding his death, computed on the basis of the American\nExperience Table of Mortality.\n  A beneficiary of such deceased member shall have the right to accept\nsuch benefits in lump sums or in such periodic payments, on an annuity\nbasis, as such beneficiary shall elect.\n  3. Nothing contained in the foregoing provisions of this section shall\nbe held or deemed to affect or to lessen any benefits greater than those\nset forth in subdivision two of this section which are or shall be\nprovided for by any such police pension system in respect of a member or\nmembers thereof dying in the course of or as the result of the\nperformance of his duties.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall not apply to members of the\nNew York state and local police and fire retirement system.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 207-h's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>