<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-K*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-K*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207-K*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-K*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-K*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-K*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-K*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207_K*2">
        <num>207-K*2</num>
        <heading>Disabilities of policemen and firemen in certain cities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 207-k. Disabilities of policemen and firemen in certain cities. a.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local law or\nadministrative code to the contrary, but except for the purposes of\nsections two hundred seven-a and two hundred seven-c of this article,\nthe workers' compensation law and the labor law, any condition of\nimpairment of health caused by diseases of the heart, or by a stroke,\nresulting in total or partial disability or death to a paid member of\nthe uniformed force of a paid police department or fire department,\nwhere such paid policemen or firemen are drawn from competitive civil\nservice lists, who successfully passed a physical examination on entry\ninto the service of such respective department, which examination failed\nto reveal any evidence of such condition, shall be presumptive evidence\nthat it was incurred in the performance and discharge of duty, unless\nthe contrary be proved by competent evidence.\n  b. The provisions of this section shall remain in full force and\neffect to and including the thirtieth day of June, nineteen hundred\nseventy-four.\n  * NB Expired July 1, 1995 per subdivision 2; see retirement and social\nsecurity law ยง 480 for expiration\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 207-k's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>