<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207_O">
        <num>207-O</num>
        <heading>Performance of duty disability retirement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 207-o. Performance of duty disability retirement. Notwithstanding\nthe provisions of any general, special or local law or administrative\ncode to the contrary, but except for the purposes of the workers'\ncompensation law and the labor law, a paid employee who performs the\nfunctions of an emergency medical technician or advanced emergency\nmedical technician, where such employee is drawn from competitive civil\nservice lists and successfully passed a physical examination on\nemployment, who, on or after March seventeenth, nineteen hundred\nninety-six, contracts HIV (where the employee may have been exposed to a\nbodily fluid of a person under his or her care or treatment, or while\nthe employee examined, transported or otherwise had contact with such\nperson, in the performance of his or her duties) tuberculosis or\nhepatitis, will be presumed to have contracted such disease as a natural\nand proximate result of an accidental injury received in the performance\nor discharge of his or her duties and not resulting from his or her\nwillful negligence, unless the contrary be proved by competent evidence.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 207-o's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>