<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207_G">
        <num>207-G</num>
        <heading>Ordinary death benefits of members of police retirement systems</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Member" means a contributor to the pension system of any city\nmaintaining a police pension fund based upon the accumulation of\ndeductions from the compensation or the contributions of the members\nthereof and payments made by such city to pension reserves for such\nmembers, and such pension system provides for optional retirement\nallowances.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Accumulated deductions" shall mean the sum of all the amounts,\ndeducted from the compensation of a member of such pension system or\ncontributed by him, standing to his credit therein; together with the\ninterest thereon, if any, as provided by the law, charter or\nadministrative code governing such system.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_G__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Pension" shall mean payments for life derived from appropriations\nfor and payments into such pension system by such city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_G__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Minimum period of service" shall mean a fixed number of years of\nservice specified in a plan or option provided by such police pension\nsystem and elected by such member, as a necessary pre-requisite for a\npension or retirement allowance upon retirement from service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_G__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Minimum age" means the age specified in a plan or option provided\nby such police pension system and elected by such member, as a necessary\npre-requisite for a pension or retirement allowance upon retirement from\nservice.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local\nlaw, charter or administrative code, and in lieu of any lesser amount\ntherein prescribed, upon the death of a member, prior to the first\npayment of a retirement benefit, who has attained the minimum age or\ncompleted the minimum period of service, as elected by him for\nretirement, and whether or not such member shall have filed application\nfor retirement, there shall be paid to his estate, or to such person as\nhe has nominated or shall nominate by written designation duly executed\nand filed in accordance with the requirements of such respective police\npension systems:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>His accumulated deductions; and in addition thereto,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amount of the reserve equal to the present value of the\npension he would have received, under the provisions of the law, charter\nor administrative code governing such police pension system, if he had\nretired and become entitled to a pension on the day immediately\npreceding the day of his death.\n  The beneficiary of such deceased member shall have the right to accept\nsuch benefits in lump sums or in such periodic payments, on an annuity\nbasis, as such beneficiary shall elect.\n  3. Nothing contained in the foregoing provisions of this section shall\nbe held or deemed to affect or to lessen any benefits greater than those\nset forth in the foregoing paragraph two which are or shall be provided\nfor by any such police pension system in respect of a member or members\nthereof dying in the course of or as the result of the performance of\nhis duties.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall not apply to members of the\nNew York state and local police and fire retirement system.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>