<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207">
        <num>207</num>
        <heading>Hospitalization of members of fire departments in certain cities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 207. Hospitalization of members of fire departments in certain\ncities. Paid members of the fire department of any city of this state\nhaving a population of one million or more who shall be injured while\nactually employed in the discharge of duty or who, as a result of\nillness traceable directly to the performance of duty, shall, when\ncertified by the fire chief or commissioner, be received by any public,\nprivate or semi-private hospital for care and treatment in semi-private\npatient facilities or accommodations. The bill for such semi-private\npatient facilities or accommodations, including charges, at the\nprevailing semi-private patient rates, for necessary nursing, laboratory\ntests, X-ray examinations and physical therapy, when certified by the\nsuperintendent or other person in charge of such hospital and approved\nby the fire chief or commissioner, be paid by the city in which such\nfire department is located.\n  Nothing in this section shall be construed as excluding an injured\nmember from being received in a ward accommodation in an emergency, if\nsemi-private accommodations are not available at a hospital.\n  Notwithstanding any provision of law contrary thereto contained herein\nor elsewhere, a cause of action shall accrue to the city for\nreimbursement in such sum or sums actually paid for medical or hospital\ntreatment, as against any third party against whom a member of the fire\ndepartment shall have a cause of action for the injuries sustained.\n  Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a provider of\nmedical treatment or hospital care furnished pursuant to the provisions\nof this section shall not collect or attempt to collect reimbursement\nfor such treatment or care from any such member of the fire department\nof any such city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>