<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-208-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-208-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-08-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="208-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-208-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-208-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-208-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-208-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_208_A">
        <num>208-A</num>
        <heading>School guards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 208-a. School guards. The duly constituted authorities of any city,\ntown, or village or any county police department or police district may\ndesignate, authorize and appoint such a number of persons as such\nauthority shall deem necessary, and at such salaries as such authority\nshall deem advisable, as school crossing guards to aid in protecting\nschool children going to and from school, and church crossing guards to\naid in protecting persons going to and from places of worship, and for\nsuch purpose shall have power to control vehicular traffic within such\nmunicipality. A board of education or trustees of a school district may\nenter into an agreement with any city, town, village or county police\ndepartment or police district whereby such school district pays for all\nor any portion of the salaries of the school crossing guards providing\nservices pursuant to this section to the students of such district.\nNotwithstanding any agreement entered into pursuant to this section,\nschool crossing guards shall not be considered employees of the school\ndistrict. The authority of a board of education or trustees of a school\ndistrict to enter into such agreement shall only exist when such\nagreement results in an increase to the number of school crossing guards\nemployed by the city, town, village, county police department or police\ndistrict.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>