<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_D">
        <num>209-D</num>
        <heading>Contracts for outside service by volunteer fire departments and companies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-d. Contracts for outside service by volunteer fire departments\nand companies. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no contract\nshall be made by a municipality or fire district whereby the services of\na volunteer fire department or company are to be supplied outside of\nsuch municipality or fire district to provide (1) fire protection, (2)\nemergency service in case of accidents, calamities or other emergencies,\nor (3) general ambulance service pursuant to the provisions of section\ntwo hundred nine-b of this article, unless such volunteer fire\ndepartment or company consents thereto. Any such contract may provide\nfor the payment of a portion of the consideration expressed therein to\nsuch volunteer fire department or company to be expended for fire\ndepartment or company purposes only. If the municipality or fire\ndistrict owns all of the fire apparatus to be used in carrying out the\ncontract, the portion of the consideration which may be paid to such\nvolunteer fire department or company shall not exceed thirty-five per\ncentum, unless a greater portion was being so paid on March fifteenth,\nnineteen hundred forty-one, under a contract entered into on or before\nthat date, in which event a not greater portion than was being paid on\nsaid date may be paid to such volunteer fire department or company in\nrespect to any contract entered into on or after such date. No payments\nshall be made to individual volunteer firefighters as compensation for\nrendering such outside service.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>