<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-X"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-X"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-X"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-X/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-X/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_X">
        <num>209-X</num>
        <heading>Training of certain paid city firefighters promoted to a first-line supervisory position</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-x. Training of certain paid city firefighters promoted to a\nfirst-line supervisory position. 1. Notwithstanding the provisions of\nany general, special or local law or charter to the contrary, any\nofficer of a paid fire department promoted to a first-line supervisory\nposition after passing a civil service examination shall, on and after\nApril first, nineteen hundred eighty-five, attend a training program,\nnot to exceed four weeks, in fire supervision at the New York city fire\nacademy in accordance with rules and regulations promulgated pursuant to\narticle six-C of the executive law.\n  2. The expenses incurred in furnishing such program in fire\nsupervision to an officer referred to in subdivision one hereof,\nincluding the furnishing of meals and lodging at such academy, shall be\npaid by the city of New York. Reasonable travel expenses incurred by\nsaid officer shall also be paid by said city but only if such travel\nexpense would not otherwise be incurred by said officer in the regular\ncourse of this employment.\n  3. The expenses incurred by the city of New York pursuant to this\nsection shall be reimbursed by the state, except that expenses incurred\nby such city in excess of one million dollars and directly attributable\nto training any officers of such city's fire department shall not be\nsubject to state reimbursement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>