<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_C">
        <num>209-C</num>
        <heading>Fire police squads of fire departments and fire companies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-c. Fire police squads of fire departments and fire companies.\nThe authorities having control of fire departments and fire companies\nmay organize within such departments or companies fire police squads\ncomposed of volunteer firefighters who are members of such departments\nor companies. Members of fire police squads, so organized, at such times\nas the fire department, fire company or an emergency rescue and first\naid squad of the fire department or fire company are on duty, or when,\non orders of the chief of the fire department or fire company of which\nthey are members, they are separately engaged in response to a call for\nassistance pursuant to the provisions of section two hundred nine of\nthis article, shall have the powers of and render service as peace\nofficers. A member of a fire police squad shall take an oath of office\nas a fire police officer in the following form: "I do solemnly swear (or\naffirm) that I will support the constitution of the United States, and\nthe constitution of the State of New York, and that I will faithfully\ndischarge the duties of the office of fire police officer of the\n....................... fire company (or fire department), according to\nthe best of my ability." Such oath shall be filed in the office of the\ncity clerk in the case of a firefighter of a fire company or fire\ndepartment in a city, in the office of the village clerk in the case of\na firefighter of a fire company or fire department in a village, and in\nthe office of the town clerk in all other cases. Notwithstanding any\nother provision of law to the contrary, a member of a fire police squad\nshall have satisfied any requirement for training as provided by any\ngeneral or local law if the person has satisfactorily completed a\ntraining course offered by the state office of fire prevention and\ncontrol, or an equivalent course as approved by the state office of fire\nprevention and control.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>