<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-FF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-FF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-FF"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-FF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-FF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-FF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-FF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_FF">
        <num>209-FF</num>
        <heading>Provisions relating to certain accidental disability benefits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-ff. Provisions relating to certain accidental disability\nbenefits.  1. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions a and b of\nsection five hundred seven of the retirement and social security law, a\npolice/fire member in active service, a New York city uniformed\ncorrection/sanitation revised plan member in active service or an\ninvestigator revised plan member in active service shall be eligible for\nthe accidental disability benefit provided in such section five hundred\nseven, regardless of whether he or she is eligible for a normal service\nretirement benefit. For the purposes of this section, the terms\n"police/fire member" and "active service" shall have the same meanings\nas defined in section five hundred one of the retirement and social\nsecurity law.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provision of any general, special or local law,\ncharter or administrative code to the contrary, subdivision d of section\nfive hundred seven of the retirement and social security law shall not\napply to retired police/fire members, retired New York city uniformed\ncorrection/sanitation revised plan members and retired investigator\nrevised plan members who receive accidental disability retirement\nallowances. Such retirees shall be subject to post retirement medical\nexaminations, and where applicable, modification of retirement\nallowance, following such examinations, in the same manner and under the\nsame conditions prescribed by law immediately prior to the first of\nApril, two thousand twelve for retired New York city uniformed\ncorrection/sanitation revised plan members, and prior to the first of\nJuly, two thousand nine for retired police/fire members and retired\ninvestigator revised plan members.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>