<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_B">
        <num>209-B</num>
        <heading>Emergency rescue and first aid squads</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the restrictions set\nforth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, emergency and general\nambulance service, including emergency medical service as defined in\nsection three thousand one of the public health law, authorized pursuant\nto this section may be furnished without cost to the person served;\nprovided, however, that the authorities having control of a fire\ndepartment or fire company that have authorized such fire department or\nfire company to provide such service or services may fix a schedule of\nfees or charges to be paid by persons requesting such service or\nservices. The authorities having control of a fire department or fire\ncompany may provide for the collection of fees and charges or may\nformulate rules and regulations for the collection thereof by the fire\ndepartment or fire company. When fees and charges are authorized\npursuant to this subdivision, the fees and charges collected shall be\ndisbursed in accordance with a written contract entered into between the\nauthority having control of a fire department or fire company and the\nfire department or fire company itself. If the authorities having\ncontrol of a fire department or fire company have authorized such fire\ndepartment or fire company to fix a schedule of fees or charges to be\npaid by persons requesting such service or services, and seek\nparticipation in and reimbursement from the medical assistance program,\nthe authorities having control of a fire department or fire company\nshall adhere to any medical assistance enrollment and billing\nrequirements applicable to such services prior to receiving\nreimbursement. The acceptance by any firefighter of any personal\nremuneration or gratuity, directly or indirectly, from a person served\nshall be a ground for his or her expulsion or suspension as a member of\nthe fire department or fire company.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, a basic life support service which establishes a schedule\nof fees for service shall enter into a contract with a provider or\nproviders of advanced life support services to provide such advanced\nlife support services. Such contract shall at a minimum establish the\nfees for advanced life support services and the means by which said\nprovider will be reimbursed when the ambulance service bills for\nemergency medical service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An emergency and general ambulance service, including emergency\nmedical service as defined in section three thousand one of the public\nhealth law, authorized pursuant to this section which does not issue a\nbill for its services and which requests an Advanced Life Support (ALS)\nintercept from another ambulance service furnishing service in an area\nthat is designated as a rural area by any law or regulation of the\nstate, or that is located in a rural census tract of a metropolitan\nstatistical area (as determined under the most recent Goldsmith\nModification), shall pay the ambulance service providing the ALS\nintercept an ALS Rural Intercept Fee at rates negotiated between the\nproviders of such services. In the absence of any agreed upon rates, the\nservice receiving such ALS intercept shall pay the service providing the\nALS intercept for such services at the usual and customary charge, which\nshall not be excessive or unreasonable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An emergency and general ambulance service, including emergency\nmedical service as defined in section three thousand one of the public\nhealth law, authorized pursuant to this section to fix a schedule of\nfees or charges to be paid by persons requesting such service or\nservices, may apply such fees and charges only within such service's\nprimary response territory as assigned and evidenced by a valid\nambulance service certificate issued by the commissioner of health\npursuant to section three thousand five of the public health law, on or\nbefore January first, two thousand twenty-two.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An emergency and general ambulance service, including emergency\nmedical service as defined in section three thousand one of the public\nhealth law, authorized pursuant to this section shall not directly issue\na bill for its services to any uninsured recipient of such services.\n  * NB Effective until April 9, 2031\n  * 4. Fees and charges prohibited. Emergency and general ambulance\nservice authorized pursuant to this section shall be furnished without\ncost to the person served. The acceptance by any firefighter of any\npersonal remuneration or gratuity, directly or indirectly, from a person\nserved shall be a ground for his or her expulsion or suspension as a\nmember of the fire department or fire company.\n  * NB Effective April 9, 2031\n  5. The term "emergency", as used in this chapter, or in any other law\nof general application, in relation to the operations of fire\ndepartments, includes, unless a contrary intent is clearly expressed or\nindicated, the search for persons and the search for, and attempts to\nrecover or the recovery of, bodies of persons even though it is posible\nor is known that all hope of life is gone.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>