<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_M">
        <num>209-M</num>
        <heading>Outside service by local police; civil disturbance control</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-m. Outside service by local police; civil disturbance control.\n1. As used in this section:\n  a. The term "local government" shall mean a county, a city, a town, or\na village, as the case may be.\n  b. The term "chief executive officer" shall mean:\n  (1) In the case of a county, the county executive unless there is\nnone, in which case it shall mean the county manager if there is one, or\nthe chairman of the board of supervisors if there is neither a county\nexecutive nor county manager.\n  (2) In the case of cities, the mayor, except in those cities having a\ncity manager, it shall mean such city manager.\n  (3) In the case of towns, the supervisor or presiding supervisor.\n  (4) In the case of villages, the mayor, except in those villages\nhaving a president or manager, it shall mean such latter officer.\n  c. The term "chief of police" shall include any police officer in\ncommand of the police department or police force of a local government\nduring the absence, illness or disability of the chief of police or who\nis authorized to exercise the powers of the chief of police in emergency\nsituations.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local law\nor of any county, city or village charter, the chief executive officer\nof a local government, whenever he deems that the public interest\nrequires it, may request the chief executive officer of any other local\ngovernment to detail, assign and make available for duty and use in the\nlocal government for which the request is made any part of the forces,\nequipment and supplies of the police department, police force or parkway\npolice force of the local government of which the request is made. The\nchief executive officer of the local government of which the request is\nmade is hereby authorized and empowered to grant the request so made.\n  3. A local government may, by local law, delegate to the chief of\npolice of its police department or police force the powers hereby\ngranted to a chief executive officer to request and grant police\nassistance.\n  4. If the chief executive officer of any such local government is\nabsent or disabled, the chief of police of the local government may make\nany such request or may grant any such request, as the case may be.\n  5. The local government receiving police aid pursuant to this section\nshall assume the liability for all damages arising out of any act\nperformed in rendering such aid and shall reimburse the assisting local\ngovernment for any moneys paid by it for salaries or for other expenses\nincurred by it including damage to or loss of equipment and supplies. An\nassisting local government may assume such loss, damage, expenses or\ncost for such equipment and supplies and donate such services to the\nreceiving local government. While engaged in duty and rendering services\nin such local government the officers and members of such police\ndepartment or police force shall have the same powers, duties, rights,\nbenefits, privileges and immunities as if they were performing their\nduties in the local government in and by which they are normally\nemployed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>