<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_E">
        <num>209-E</num>
        <heading>Fire mobilization and mutual aid plan</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-e. Fire mobilization and mutual aid plan. 1. Plan. The state\nfire administrator shall prepare a state fire mobilization and mutual\naid plan which may provide for the establishment of fire mobilization\nand mutual aid zones of the state. Upon filing of the plan in the office\nof fire prevention and control such plan shall become the state fire\nmobilization and mutual aid plan. Such plan may be amended from time to\ntime in the same manner as originally adopted.\n  2. Regional fire administrators. The state fire administrator may\nappoint and remove a regional fire administrator for each fire\nmobilization and mutual aid zone established pursuant to the state fire\nmobilization and mutual aid plan. Before he or she enters on the duties\nof the office, each regional fire administrator shall take and subscribe\nbefore an officer authorized by law to administer oaths the\nconstitutional oath of office, which shall be administered and certified\nby the officer taking the same without compensation and shall be filed\nin the office of the secretary of state.\n  3. Regulations. The commissioner of the division of homeland security\nand emergency services, in consultation with the state fire\nadministrator, may make regulations and issue orders which he or she may\ndeem necessary to implement the state fire mobilization and mutual aid\nplan and carry out the purposes of this section.\n  4. Powers. Whenever a county, city, town, village or fire district\nshall request, or whenever the governor shall determine that the public\ninterest so requires, the state fire administrator shall possess and\nexercise the powers, functions and duties set forth in the state fire\nmobilization and mutual aid plan.\n  5. Standard thread. The state fire mobilization and mutual aid plan\nshall prescribe a standard hose thread for the state, and each county,\ncity, town, village or fire district not equipped with the same may be\nrequired either to recut its threads to such standard or provide\nadapters whereby the same may be brought to such standards.\n  6. Records. The state fire administrator shall keep a permanent public\nrecord of the activations of the state fire mobilization and mutual aid\nplan, showing how, when and where it was activated and when such\nactivation was terminated.\n  7. Reimbursement of assisting municipal corporations or fire\ndistricts.  Whenever the governor activates the state fire mobilization\nand mutual aid plan pursuant to subdivision four of this section, claims\nsubmitted by an assisting municipal corporation or fire district for\nexpenses allowed by subdivision two of section two hundred nine-g of\nthis article made in performance of its duties on behalf of a receiving\nmunicipality or fire district pursuant to such plan may be reimbursed in\nthe first instance by the state from any local assistance appropriation\nestablished for such purpose. Reimbursements of such claims from such\nappropriation may be made only upon certification of such claim by the\nstate fire administrator to the state comptroller and audit of such\nclaim by the state comptroller prior to payment. Expenditures for such\nreimbursements from such appropriation shall be considered a liability\nfor outside aid as described in section two hundred nine-g of this\narticle and shall be repaid by the municipality or fire district\nreceiving assistance pursuant to the state fire mobilization and mutual\naid plan.\n  8. Hazardous materials incident plan. The state fire administrator\nshall prepare a hazardous materials incident plan which shall complement\nand become a part of the plan required by subdivision one of this\nsection.  The plan shall provide for the mobilization and coordination\nof fire service resources in response to emergencies which involve or\nmay involve hazardous materials and shall establish hazardous materials\nincidents response zones and criteria for recognized regional hazardous\nmaterials incidents response teams. The office of fire prevention and\ncontrol, by and through the state fire administrator or his or her duly\nauthorized officers and employees, is authorized to approve grants of\nfunds from monies allocated and appropriated therefor for expenditures\nof municipal corporations for hazardous materials incidents planning and\nequipment, pursuant to applicable rules and regulations promulgated by\nthe commissioner of the division of homeland security and emergency\nservices, in consultation with the state fire administrator, and\napproved by the director of the budget.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>