<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_A">
        <num>209-A</num>
        <heading>Relations with other states and the dominion of Canada</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-a. Relations with other states and the dominion of Canada. 1.\nWhenever a volunteer fire company or department of this state shall\nanswer a call for assistance from any political subdivision or territory\nof another state of the United States, or of the Dominion of Canada, or\nproperty ceded to the federal government, the provisions of section two\nhundred five of this chapter and the provisions of the workers'\ncompensation law shall apply with respect to the volunteer firefighters\nof such fire company or department, while such assistance is being\nrendered or while going to or returning from the place from whence such\ncall came, to the same extent and in the same manner as if such service\nhad been rendered in the area regularly served by such volunteer\nfirefighters; provided, however, that there shall be deducted from any\namounts payable under such section or such law, any amounts recoverable\nby or payable to such volunteer firefighters under the laws applicable\nin the political subdivision or territory from whence the call for\nassistance came.\n  2. The provisions of sections two hundred five and two hundred nine of\nthis chapter shall apply with respect to volunteer firefighters, fire\ndepartments and companies of other states of the United States and of\nthe Dominion of Canada that render service in this state in answer to a\ncall for assistance, provided that the laws of the state served by such\nvolunteer firefighters, fire departments or companies, or of the\nDominion of Canada, as the case may be, contain provisions under which\nsubstantially similar benefits are granted to volunteer firefighters,\nfire departments and companies of this state when rendering service in\nsuch other states, or the Dominion of Canada, as the case may be, in\nanswer to a call for assistance, and provided further that there shall\nbe deducted from any amounts payable under the provisions of section two\nhundred five of this article to volunteer firefighters of such other\nstates or of the Dominion of Canada, any amounts recoverable by or\npayable to such volunteer firefighters under the laws of the state\nserved by such volunteer firefighters or of the Dominion of Canada, as\nthe case may be.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not apply where a volunteer\nfirefighter of this state, or of another state, or of the Dominion of\nCanada, as the case may be, is killed or injured, on or after the first\nday of March, nineteen hundred fifty-seven, or dies from the effects of\ninjuries received on or after such date.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>