<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-CC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-CC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-CC"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-CC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-CC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_CC">
        <num>209-CC</num>
        <heading>Notification of presence of wild animals and dangerous dogs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "emergency services personnel" means fire, police, and\nambulance personnel.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "person" means any individual, partnership, corporation,\nassociation, or other entity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "wild animal" means any or all of the following orders\nand families:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nonhuman primates and prosimians;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Felidae (with the exception of domesticated cats);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Canidae (with the exception of domesticated dogs);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Ursidae;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All venomous snakes and all constrictors and python snakes that\nare ten feet or greater in length; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_c__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Crocodilia that are five feet or greater in length.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209_CC__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "dangerous dog" means a dog found dangerous pursuant to\nthe provisions of section one hundred twenty-three of the agriculture\nand markets law.\n  3. The state fire administrator, in consultation with the department\nof environmental conservation, shall develop and maintain a list of the\ncommon names of wild animals to be reported.\n  4. Except for pet dealers as defined in section seven hundred\nfifty-two-a of the general business law and zoological facilities and\nother exhibitors licensed pursuant to title 7 U.S.C. sections 2133 and\n2134, and in the case of dangerous dogs except for licensed\nveterinarians in temporary possession of such dogs, every person owning,\npossessing, or harboring a wild animal or a dangerous dog within this\nstate shall report the presence thereof to the clerk of the city, town,\nor village in which such wild animal or dangerous dog is owned,\npossessed, or harbored. Such report shall be filed annually on a date to\nbe determined by the state fire administrator in the manner prescribed\nby the state fire administrator. A separate report shall be filed for\neach street address at which any such wild animal or dangerous dog may\nbe found.\n  5. Such clerk shall forward a copy of such report to each state police\ntroop, county sheriff, and municipal police agency having jurisdiction\nover the location of such wild animal or dangerous dog. A copy thereof\nshall also be forwarded to each fire department, fire corporation, or\nfire company serving such location and to each ambulance or emergency\nmedical service department, ambulance corporation, or ambulance or\nemergency medical service company serving such location. In lieu of\nforwarding a copy of each report, the clerk may compile the contents of\nthe several reports, and forward the compilation.\n  6. Any person who fails to report the presence of a wild animal or\ndangerous dog as required in this section shall be subject to a civil\npenalty of not more than two hundred fif...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>