<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-209-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209_P">
        <num>209-P</num>
        <heading>Relay of fire and emergency calls</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 209-p. Relay of fire and emergency calls. The fire department of any\ncity may accept any calls for aid in cases of fire or other emergencies\nmade to its fire headquarters from territory outside the city and may\nrelay such calls for aid in fires or other emergencies by such means as\nmay be expedient to the fire department, fire company or fire district\nserving said territory. This section shall apply only to cities\nparticipating in any legally authorized or recognized plan for\nfurnishing mutual aid in cases of fire and other emergencies in which\nthe services of firefighters would be used. Any city, village or fire\ndistrict, any town which has a town fire department, or any town board\non behalf of a fire protection district, fire alarm district or\nterritory outside any such municipal corporation or district, for which\naid is to be furnished, may contract with a city to accept and relay\nsuch calls, as aforesaid, and the amounts payable under any such\ncontract shall be a lawful charge against and paid as contracted for by\nthe city, village, fire district, town which has a town fire department,\nfire protection district, fire alarm district or territory outside any\nsuch municipal corporation or district. Any city accepting and\ntransmitting fire calls from territory outside the city, pursuant to any\nsuch contract, shall not be liable for any injury or death to persons or\ndamage to property as the result thereof, when it, in good faith,\ncomplies with or attempts to comply with the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>