<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="219-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_219_E">
        <num>219-E</num>
        <heading>Participation, vesting and service credit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Training courses -- twenty-five points maximum.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Courses under twenty hours duration -- one point per hour, with a\nmaximum of five points.\n  (ii) Courses of twenty to forty-five hours duration -- one point per\nhour for each hour over initial twenty hours, with a maximum of ten\npoints.\n  (iii) Courses over forty-five hours duration -- fifteen points per\ncourse.\nFor purposes of this paragraph, the term "training course" shall mean a\ncourse of instruction having a prescribed topic and syllabus. Points for\na training course shall be awarded only upon the successful completion\nof the course and only in the year in which the course is successfully\ncompleted.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Drills and seminars -- twenty points maximum. One point per\nminimum two hour drill or seminar. For purposes of this paragraph, the\nterm "drill" shall mean a skills practice or skills training session\nrelated to emergency medical service and the term "seminar" shall mean a\nlecture on a topic relating to the emergency medical service.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sleep-in or stand-by -- twenty points maximum.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sleep-in -- one point each full night.\n  (ii) Stand-by -- one point each. A stand-by is defined as line of duty\nactivity of the volunteer ambulance company, lasting for four hours, not\nfalling under one of the other categories. A service award program may\nnot provide points pursuant to this paragraph if the program provides\npoints for tours of duty pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Tours of duty.  A maximum of twenty points may be granted for\nserving tours of duty at a rate equal to no more than one-sixth of a\npoint per hour served as determined by the sponsor. For purposes of this\nparagraph, the term "tour of duty" shall mean a line of duty activity,\nnot falling under one of the other paragraphs of this subdivision,\ninvolving a period of time scheduled or assigned by an ambulance company\nduring which a volunteer ambulance worker is responsible for providing\nemergency medical service or general ambulance service, including\nsleep-ins, stand-bys and backup duty, by reason of being stationed at an\nevent, as part of a rostered duty crew or as otherwise provided by the\nregular procedures of the ambulance company. A sponsor may also define\ntwo or more activities included within the meaning of the term tour of\nduty and provide for points to be granted for the performance of such\nactivities at different rates, provided, that points for such activities\nshall not be granted at a rate in excess of one-sixth of a point per\nhour served and no more than twenty points shall be granted for all such\nactivities. A service award program may not provide points pursuant to\nthis paragraph if the program provides points for sleep-ins or stand-bys\npursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Elected or appointed position -- twenty-five points maximum.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Completion of one year term in an elected or appointed position.\n  (ii) A volunteer ambulance worker elected to serve as a delegate to an\nambulance workers' convention shall also be eligible to receive one\npoint per meeting.\n  (iii) A volunteer ambulance worker appointed to serve on the New York\nstate emergency medical services council, the state emergency medical\nadvisory committee, a regional emergency medical services council or a\nregional emergency medical advisory committee, established pursuant to\narticle thirty of the public health law shall also be eligible to\nreceive one point per meeting.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Attendance at meetings -- twenty points maximum.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Attendance at any official meetings of the ambulance company --\none point per meeting.\n  (ii) Attendance at official meetings of a standing committee of the\nambulance company by a member of the committee -- one point per meeting.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Participation in ambulance company responses -- twenty-five points\nfor responding on the minimum number of calls, as outlined below:\nTotal number of calls         0         500       1000      1500\nambulance company responds    to        to        to        and\nto annually                   500       1000      1500      over\nMinimum  number of calls      10%       7.5%      5%        2.5%\nvolunteer\nambulance worker\nmust run annually in order to\nreceive twenty-five points credit\n  A volunteer ambulance worker who is granted points toward a year of\nambulance service pursuant to this paragraph may not be granted points\ntoward the same year of ambulance service for alternative participation\ncompany responses pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Alternative participation in company responses. A maximum of\ntwenty-five points may be granted for participation in company responses\nat a rate equal to no more than one-half point per response as\ndetermined by the sponsor. A volunteer ambulance worker who is granted\npoints toward a year of ambulance service pursuant to this paragraph may\nnot be granted points toward the same year of ambulance service for\nparticipation in company responses pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Miscellaneous activities -- maximum fifteen points. Participation\nin inspections and other activities covered by the volunteer ambulance\nworkers' benefit law and not otherwise listed -- one point per activity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_E__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The sponsor may designate less than all the activities specified\nin this subdivision as activities for which points may be earned.\n  4. Points toward a year of ambulance service may be granted for\nactivities performed after a participant reaches entitlement age, but\nshall not be granted for activities performed after a participant\napplies for a service award.\n  5. A service award program which is to take effect on a day other than\nthe first day of January may provide for points to be granted toward a\nyear of ambulance service for activities performed prior to the\neffective date of the program and on or after the immediately preceding\nfirst day of January, provided, the proposition authorizing adoption of\nthe program contains a statement authorizing points to be granted for\nsuch activities. Points attributable to such activities shall be granted\nin accordance with the point system adopted by the sponsor pursuant to\nsubdivision three of this section.\n  6. In computing credit for those volunteer ambulance workers who also\nserve as paid employees within a political subdivision of the state,\ncredit shall not be given for activities performed during the\nindividual's regularly assigned work periods.\n  7. A participant whose ambulance service is interrupted by full-time\nextended obligatory military service or by a single voluntary enlistment\nnot to exceed four years in the armed forces of the United States shall\nbe considered on military leave. During such period of military leave,\nthe participant shall receive fifty points for each full year of\nmilitary service, prorated for military service of less than a year.\n  7-a. An active volunteer ambulance worker's service award program may\nprovide for the crediting of years of and points for volunteer ambulance\nservice for periods after an active volunteer ambulance worker has\nreached the entitlement age and is receiving a service award.\n  8. The state comptroller may promulgate rules and regulations\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>