<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="219-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_219_S">
        <num>219-S</num>
        <heading>Participation and service credit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_S__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section two\nhundred seventeen or subdivision three of section two hundred nineteen-m\nof this chapter and adopted by the sponsor shall be used. Approval for\nsuch prior service shall require certification by the president,\nsecretary and chief of the volunteer fire company.\n  4. In computing credit for those participants who also serve as paid\nemployees within a political subdivision of the state, credit shall not\nbe given for activities performed during the individual's regularly\nassigned work periods.\n  5. Sponsors may provide credit to participants whose service was\ninterrupted by full-time extended obligatory military service or by a\nsingle voluntary enlistment not to exceed four years in the armed forces\nof the United States.\n  6. The president, secretary and chief or comparable officers of each\nvolunteer company shall submit to the governing board of the sponsor a\nlist of all participants, certified under oath, which shall identify\nthose participants who have qualified for credit under the award program\nfor the previous year. Such list shall be submitted annually by March\nthirty-first or otherwise as provided by local resolution and shall be\naccompanied by such membership records as the governing board may\nrequire to substantiate the accuracy of the list. Notwithstanding the\nprovision of this subdivision a participant may request that his or her\nname be deleted from said list as a "participant." Such request for\ndeletion shall be in writing and shall remain effective until withdrawn\nin the same manner.\n  7. The governing board of the sponsor shall review the list and may\ndelete the name of any person whose point accumulation has not been\nadequately documented. Thereafter, the governing board shall approve the\nlist and return a copy of the list to the appropriate company and\nforward a certified copy of the approved list to the program\nadministrator.\n  8. Upon receipt of the approved list the company shall post the list\nat its pri...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>