<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="219-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-219-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_219_G">
        <num>219-G</num>
        <heading>Funding</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Before or after a service award program is adopted for the\nvolunteer ambulance workers of an ambulance company which contracts to\nprovide service to one or more political subdivisions other than the\nprospective or actual sponsor of the program, the governing boards of\nthe sponsor and one or more of such other political subdivisions may\nenter into agreements to apportion the cost of the program in any\nequitable manner between the sponsor and such other political\nsubdivisions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No such agreement shall be entered into by a political subdivision\nother than the sponsor unless a resolution authorizing the agreement is\napproved by the affirmative vote of at least sixty percent of the\ngoverning board of the political subdivision and a proposition\nauthorizing the agreement or amendment is approved at a referendum of\nthe electors of the political subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_G__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The proposition authorizing the agreement or amendment shall be\nsubmitted to referendum not less than thirty days and not more than\nninety days after the governing board votes to authorize the agreement\nor amendment.  Notice of the referendum shall be published at least\nonce, not less than fourteen days prior to the date of the referendum,\nin the official newspaper of the political subdivision or, if the\npolitical subdivision does not have an official newspaper, in one or\nmore newspapers having general circulation in the political subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_G__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any such agreement shall remain in effect until amended or\nterminated by resolution and submission of a proposition to referendum\nas provided in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_G__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, but shall be\nsuspended with respect to any such political subdivision which ceases to\ncontract with the ambulance company or in the event the sponsor ceases\nto contract with the ambulance company.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_219_G__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The amount to be paid by a political subdivision under any such\ncontract shall be a charge against the political subdivision and shall\nbe paid to the sponsor.  The governing board of the sponsor shall apply\nthe amount received under any such contract to reduce the amount that\nwould otherwise be raised for the program from the sponsor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>