<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-23"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-23"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23">
        <num>23</num>
        <heading>Flexible benefits program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the city\nuniversity of New York, (ii) the New York city health and hospitals\ncorporation, (iii) the New York city transit authority, (iv) the New\nYork city housing authority,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the New York city off-track betting\ncorporation, (vi) the New York city rehabilitation mortgage insurance\ncorporation, (vii) the New York city board of education, or (viii) the\nNew York city school construction authority.\n  d. "Employee" shall mean any officer or employee of a city having a\npopulation of one million or more, or any officer or employee of any of\nthe entities set forth in subparagraph two of paragraph c of this\nsubdivision who are eligible to receive benefits from the New York city\nemployee benefits program.\n  For purposes of this section, an independent contractor shall not be\nconsidered an employee.\n  e. "Flexible benefits program" shall mean the program established\npursuant to this section, qualifying as a cafeteria plan as defined in\nsection one hundred twenty-five of the code or any successor section\nthereto providing similar benefits, and provided as a part of the\nemployee benefits program administered by the commissioner of labor\nrelations.\n  f. "Program administrator" shall mean that agent, as determined by the\ncommissioner of labor relations, responsible for the maintenance and\nmanagement of the flexible benefits program as authorized in subdivision\ntwo of this section.\n  2. Any city having a population of one million or more, acting by the\ncommissioner of labor relations, subject to the approval of the director\nof the budget of such city, is authorized to establish and implement a\nflexible benefits program for its employees and the employees of any\nemployer as defined in subparagraph two of paragraph c of subdivision\none of this section, consistent with applicable provisions of the code.\nThe commissioner of labor relations is authorized to enter into\nagreements with persons or entities, on behalf of such city or employer,\nto act as program administrators of the flexible benefits program. The\ncommissioner of labor relations shall promulgate rules for the\nappropriate administration of such flexible benefits progr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>