<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-234"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-234"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="234"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_234">
        <num>234</num>
        <heading>Creation, appointment and qualifications</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 234. Creation, appointment and qualifications. Each city and\nincorporated village is hereby authorized and empowered to create a\ncommission to be known as the city or village planning commission. Such\ncommission shall be so created in incorporated villages by resolution of\nthe trustees, in cities by ordinance of the common council, except that\nin cities of the first class, having more than a million inhabitants, it\nshall be by resolution of the board of estimate and apportionment or\nother similar local authority. In cities of the first class such\ncommission shall consist of not more than eleven, in cities of the\nsecond class of not more than nine, in cities of the third class and\nincorporated villages of not more than seven members. Such ordinance or\nresolution shall specify the public officer or body of said municipality\nthat shall appoint such commissioners, and shall provide that the\nappointment of as nearly as possible one-third of them shall be for a\nterm of one year; one-third for a term of two years, and one-third for a\nterm of three years; and that at the expiration of such terms, the terms\nof office of their successors shall be three years; so that the term of\noffice of one-third of such commissioners, as nearly as possible, shall\nexpire each year. All appointments to fill vacancies shall be for the\nunexpired term. Not more than one-third of the members of said\ncommission shall hold any other public office in said city or village.\nIn a county containing a population of over three hundred thousand one\nof the members of any such commission may reside outside of such village\nor city as the case may be.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>