<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-238"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-238"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="238"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-238/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-238/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-238/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-238/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_238">
        <num>238</num>
        <heading>Private streets</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 238. Private streets. The body creating such planning commission may\nat any time, by ordinance or resolution provide that no plan, plot or\ndescription, showing the layout of any highway or street upon private\nproperty, or of building lots in connection with or in relation to such\nhighway or street shall, within the limits of any municipality having a\nplanning commission, as aforesaid, be received for record in the office\nof the clerk of the county where such real property is situated, until a\ncopy of said plan, plot or description has been filed with said\ncommission and it has certified, with relation thereto, its approval\nthereof. Such certificate shall be recorded as a part of the record of\nsaid original instrument containing said plan, plot, or description. No\nsuch street or highway which has not received the approval of the\nplanning commission shall be accepted by said city or village until the\nmatter has been referred to such commission under the provision of\nsection two hundred and thirty-six of this article. But if any such\nstreet is plotted or laid out in accordance with the map of said\nmunicipality, adopted according to law, then it shall not be necessary\nto file such copy, or obtain or record such certificate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>