<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-N*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-N*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="239-N*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-N*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-N*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-N*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-N*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_239_N*2">
        <num>239-N*2</num>
        <heading>Intergovernmental relations councils</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 239-n. Intergovernmental relations councils. 1. Any county outside\nthe city of New York, city, town, village, school district, board of\ncooperative educational services, or fire district or any combination\nthereof, may create by agreement an intergovernmental relations council\nto strengthen local governments and to promote efficient and economical\nprovision of local governmental services within or by such participating\nmunicipalities, and to that end such council shall have power to:\n  a. Make surveys and studies and conduct research programs to aid in\nthe solution of local governmental problems and in efforts to improve\nadministration and services.\n  b. Provide for the distribution of information resulting from such\nsurveys, studies and programs.\n  c. Consult and cooperate with appropriate state, municipal and public\nor private agencies in matters affecting municipal government.\n  d. Devise practical ways and means for obtaining greater economy and\nefficiency in the planning and provision of municipal services and make\nrecommendations in accordance therewith.\n  e. Promote the general commercial, industrial and cultural welfare of\nthe participating municipalities.\n  f. Otherwise promote strong and effective local government, public\nhealth, safety, morals and general welfare by means of local and\nintercommunity planning or performance of municipal services.\n  g. Employ such persons and adopt such rules and regulations as shall\nbe necessary and proper to effectuate the purposes of this section.\n  h. Provide a forum for local governments to explore and develop areas\nfor municipal cooperative activities pursuant to article five-G of this\nchapter.\n  i. Operate as a purchasing consortium, where authorized by\nparticipating municipalities, for the purpose of obtaining economies\nthrough joint bidding and purchasing.\n  j. Purchase and make available to participating municipalities, where\nauthorized by participating municipalities, goods and equipment,\nincluding but not limited to computer hardware and software.\n  k. Gather and make available information on surplus goods and\nequipment for sale or lease.\n  2. The members of an intergovernmental relations council shall adopt\nby-laws to govern its activities and shall elect from their own number a\nchairman and secretary and other necessary officers to serve for such\nperiod as the members shall decide.\n  3. The board of supervisors of a county, the appropriate officials of\na city, the governing body of a school district, board of cooperative\neducational services or fire district, the board of trustees of a\nvillage, or the town board of a town, is hereby authorized to include\nannually in the budget and raise by taxation in such county, city,\nschool district, village or town a sum to meet all or an appropriate\nshare of the actual and necessary expenses of establishing, maintaining\nand continuing such intergovernmental relations council.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 239-n's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>