<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-AA"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-AA"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="239-AA"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-AA/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-239-AA/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_239_AA">
        <num>239-AA</num>
        <heading>Creation of councils on the disabled</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 239-aa. Creation of councils on the disabled. 1. The local\nlegislative body of any county or city with a population of ninety\nthousand or more, may by resolution, create one or more councils on the\ndisabled. Such council shall develop a program of community\nparticipation regarding the needs and problems of disabled persons in\nthe community and may direct its efforts toward accomplishing the\nfollowing:\n  a. Develop and implement community programs for the disabled.\n  b. Conduct researches into the accessibility to the disabled of public\nplaces in the community.\n  c. Advise and assist the local legislative body and local governmental\nboards and agencies, including agencies dealing with planning, zoning\nand the planning of public buildings.\n  d. Recruit, train and use volunteers from the community to serve\nwithout charge in its programs.\n  e. Create a climate in which disabled persons seeking assistance can\nmeet with responsible individuals or agencies in a position to render\nassistance.\n  f. Cooperate with other councils on the disabled, and with appropriate\nstate and federal agencies in planning and implementing local programs\nfor the benefit of the disabled.\n  g. Carry out any other duties consistent with the objectives of this\narticle, assigned to it by resolution of the local legislative body\ncreating the said council.\n  2. When authorized by resolution of the local legislative body, a\ncouncil may accept by gift, grant, bequest, or otherwise, money or\npersonal property in the name of the municipality, for use in the\nfurtherance of the provisions of this act. A local legislative body may\naccept by gift, conditional or unconditional grant, devise or otherwise\nreal property in fee or any lesser interest, including conveyance with\nlimitations or reversions, for the purposes of this act.\n  In addition, upon the written recommendation of the council, the local\nlegislative body may acquire by purchase in fee or any lesser interest,\nthrough negotiation or by eminent domain such real or personal property\nas may be needed to fulfill the purpose of this act.\n  3. Such council shall consist of not less than three nor more than\nnine members, of whom at least one-third of the members shall be\ncomprised of disabled individuals and, or the parent or parents of a\ndisabled child or disabled children, who shall be appointed by the local\nlegislative body and serve at the pleasure of such body for a term not\nexceeding two years.  Such local legislative body may, notwithstanding\nany inconsistent provision of law, appoint up to two members to the\ncouncil who are between the ages of sixteen and twenty-one.\n  4. The presiding officer or chairman of the council shall be\ndesignated by the local legislative body from among the members so\nappointed to the council. The local legislative body shall have\nauthority to remove any member of said council so appointed for cause,\nafter a public hearing, if requested. A vacancy shall be filled for the\nunexpired term in the same manner as an original appointment.\n  The local legislative body may provide for compensation to be paid to\nthe members of the council and may provide for the payment of the\nexpenses of the members of the council actually and necessarily incurred\nin the performance of their duties. Such council may appoint such\nemployees as it may from time to time see fit, all within appropriation\nmade therefor.\n  5. Within thirty days following the establishment of a council,\nwritten notification thereof shall be sent by the local legislative body\nto the state advocate for the disabled.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>