<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-243"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-243"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="243"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-243/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-243/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-243/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-243/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_243">
        <num>243</num>
        <heading>Recreation commission</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 243. Recreation commission. 1. If the board of estimate and\napportionment, or if there be no such board, the common council, board\nof aldermen, or corresponding legislative body, or the governing board\nof any such county, town or village shall determine that the power to\nequip, operate and maintain playgrounds and recreation centers shall be\nexercised by a recreation commission, they may, by resolution, establish\nin such municipality a recreation commission, which shall possess all\nthe powers and be subject to all the responsibilities of local\nauthorities under this article.\n  2. Such a commission, if established, shall consist of at least five\nand not more than seven persons who are residents of such municipality\nor of such other municipality or school districts as shall pursuant to\nagreement with such municipality contribute to the expense of operating\nand maintaining any such playgrounds and recreation centers, to be\nappointed by the mayor of such city or the governing board of such\ncounty, town or village to serve for terms as set forth herein or until\ntheir successors are appointed. The members of such commission first\nappointed shall be appointed for such terms that the term of one\ncommissioner shall expire annually thereafter, and their successors\nshall thereafter be appointed to serve terms of years which shall total\nin number the membership of such commission. When the membership of an\nexisting commission is increased from five members to six or from six\nmembers to seven, the new member shall be appointed to serve for a term\nof years which shall total in number the increased membership of such\ncommission, and thereafter upon the expiration of the term of each\nmember, his reappointment or the appointment of his successor shall be\nfor a like term. When the membership of an existing commission is\nincreased from five members to seven, one of the new members shall be\nappointed to serve for a term of six years and the other for a term of\nseven years, and thereafter upon the expiration of the term of each\nmember, his reappointment or the appointment of his successor shall be\nfor a term of seven years.\n  3. If pursuant to this section a recreation commission be established\nin a city, the board or body establishing such commission may, by\nresolution, provide that the president of the park board of such city,\nor an officer having corresponding functions, shall be ex-officio a\nmember of the commission except that in a city of the second class,\nlocated in a county having a population of not less than two hundred\nthousand nor more than two hundred and fifty thousand, the mayor may\nappoint any resident of the city a member of such recreation commission\nin lieu of the above mentioned ex-officio member.\n  4. Members of such commission shall serve without pay, except that\nthose members serving on such a commission in the town of Clarkstown in\nthe county of Rockland shall be entitled to pay not to exceed three\nthousand dollars per member if approved by the town board of such town\nas part of the town budget. Vacancies in such commission occurring\notherwise than by expiration of term shall be for the unexpired term and\nshall be filled in the same manner as original appointments.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>