<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="244-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_244_D">
        <num>244-D</num>
        <heading>Joint recreation commission</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 244-d. Joint recreation commission. 1. Two or more municipalities\nwhich have established recreation commissions, as provided in section\ntwo hundred forty-three of the general municipal law, may join for the\npurpose of establishing a joint recreation commission.\n  2. The board of municipalities desiring to establish a joint\nrecreation commission shall informally agree on the use of facilities,\npersonnel, and the distribution of financial support. After informal\nagreement has been reached, the common council or board of each\nparticipating municipality shall pass an ordinance embodying the terms\nof the agreement, before the agreement becomes final. Failure of one of\nthe municipalities to pass the ordinance within ninety days after the\ninformal agreement has been reached shall void the arrangement as to all\nparties; but the remaining parties may proceed with a new agreement.\n  3. A joint recreation commission shall be organized and function in\nthe same manner as a recreation commission and shall be composed of all\nthe members of the commissions of the participating municipalities. A\njoint recreation commission, however, may create an executive committee\nfrom its membership composed of an equal number of members from each\nparticipating municipality. Under the same limitations as the recreation\ncommission, the executive committee may exercise all of the authority of\nthe joint recreation commission, except that any executive committee\nmember by demand may require an issue to be submitted to the joint\nrecreation commission.\n  4. The joint recreation commission shall determine its total budget\nrequest. The members of each participating municipality shall present to\ntheir appropriating body the total budget and shall set forth the amount\nchargeable to their municipality by the terms of the agreement and\nordinance. In case their appropriating body does not appropriate an\namount sufficient to meet its proportionate share, the joint recreation\ncommission may reduce the expenditures attributable to that municipality\nor treat the reduced appropriation as a repudiation of the agreement and\nterminate the relationship according to the provisions of subdivision\nsix of this section.\n  5. A fiscal officer of one such municipality shall be the custodian of\nthe moneys made available for expenditure for such purposes by all such\nmunicipalities and that such fiscal officer may make payments therefrom\nupon audit of the appropriate auditing body or officer of his\nmunicipality.\n  6. A municipality may withdraw from a recreation commission board at\nthe close of a fiscal year by repealing its adopting ordinance and\nfiling a copy of the repeal ordinance with the other participating\nmunicipalities. The joint recreation commission may terminate the\nparticipation of a municipality when it does not contribute its\nproportion of the total budget agreed upon in the original agreement and\nordinance. The termination shall occur at the conclusion of the fiscal\nyear in which the joint recreation commission makes its finding.\n  The joint recreation commission at the conclusion of a fiscal year in\nwhich a discontinuance occurs, shall fairly and equitably distribute to\nthe participating municipalities all moneys remaining in the fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>