<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="244-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-244-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_244_C">
        <num>244-C</num>
        <heading>Proposition for establishment or maintenance of recreation system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 244-c. Proposition for establishment or maintenance of recreation\nsystem.  The term "recreation system," as used in this section means\nplaygrounds and neighborhood recreation centers as referred to in this\narticle. The local legislative body of a city or the governing body of\nany other municipality to which this article is applicable may, and on\nthe petition signed and acknowledged by qualified electors of such\nmunicipality in number equal to at least five per centum of the total\nnumber of votes cast for governor at the last gubernatorial election in\nsuch municipality shall, submit to the electors at a general election\nheld in such municipality a proposition for the establishment and\nmaintenance of a recreation system, if there be no recreation system\ntherein, or for the maintenance of an existing recreation system in such\nmunicipality. The proposition shall specify the minimum amount which\nshall be annually levied and appropriated for maintenance of a\nrecreation system in such municipality, which shall not exceed an amount\nequal to two mills upon every dollar of the assessed valuation of real\nand personal property in such municipality on the last preceding\nassessment-roll. Such petition shall be filed within sixty days and not\nlater than thirty days before such election with the officer or board\ncharged by law with the duty of preparing ballots for such election.\nThe petition may be made upon separate sheets and the signatures to each\nsheet shall be authenticated in the manner provided by section 6-140 of\nthe election law, for the authentication of nominating petitions. The\nseveral sheets so signed and authenticated, when fastened together and\noffered for filing, shall be deemed to constitute one petition. The\nproposition shall be in the following form: "Shall the (city, county,\ntown, that part of a town not included within the boundaries of a\nvillage or village) of (naming it) establish a recreation system and\nannually levy and appropriate for the maintenance of such system not\nless than ............. dollars?" Or, if such petition be for\nmaintenance only, the proposition shall be in the following form: "Shall\nthe (city, county, town, that part of a town not included within the\nboundaries of a village or village) of (naming it) annually levy and\nappropriate for the maintenance of its recreation system, not less than\n............ dollars?" Such proposition shall be submitted, the vote\nthereon canvassed and the result declared in the same manner as for\nother propositions submitted in such municipality.  If a proposition for\nthe establishment and maintenance of a system be adopted, jurisdiction\nand administration thereof shall be vested in such local authority as\nshall be determined in accordance with section two hundred forty-two of\nthis chapter, and all the provisions of this article shall be applicable\nthereto. If either of such propositions be adopted, an amount not less\nthan that specified therein for the maintenance of a recreation system\nin such municipality shall be annually levied by the officer, board or\nbody thereof charged with the duty of levying taxes therein, and shall\nbe annually appropriated for the maintenance of the recreation system of\nsuch municipality.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>