<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-280"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-280"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="280"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-280/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-280/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-280/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-280/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_280">
        <num>280</num>
        <heading>Establishment or extension of residential or residential and recreational areas in the Lake George park</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 280. Establishment or extension of residential or residential and\nrecreational areas in the Lake George park. 1. The legislature hereby\ndeclares that the preservation, protection, development and proper use\nof real property in the Lake George park is a matter of interest to all\nthe people of the state and that it is, accordingly, necessary to enact\nthis article as a means of providing for such preservation, protection,\ndevelopment and use.\n  2. For the purposes described in subdivision one of this section and\nfor the further purposes of preserving and developing the residential\nand recreational facilities of the state for the benefit of the public\nand promoting the health, safety, morals or general welfare of the\ncommunity, the village board of any village or the town board of any\ntown lying wholly or partly within the Lake George park, upon a petition\nas hereinafter provided, is hereby empowered to establish in such\nvillage or town by ordinance or local law, a residential or a\nresidential and recreational area consisting of any area of land therein\nincluding at least forty acres and lying within the Lake George park, or\nto extend such an area once established, which has not been previously\nrestricted to residential or residential and recreational purposes by a\nzoning ordinance or local law enacted pursuant to article seven of the\nvillage law or article sixteen of the town law.  Such board is further\nempowered to prohibit, restrict, regulate and control by such ordinance\nor local law, and such ordinances or local laws as thereafter amended,\nthe use of all buildings, structures and land within such an area for\nany industrial or commercial purpose and to limit by such ordinance or\nlocal law, and such ordinance or local law as thereafter amended, the\nuse of all buildings, structures and land within such an area to use for\none or two family residential purposes, or to use for one or two family\nresidential and non-profit recreational purposes. Any such ordinance or\nlocal law shall not apply to a non-conforming use in existence at the\ntime of the effective date of any such ordinance or local law. Any such\nordinance or local law may provide that a violation thereof is an\noffense punishable by a fine not to exceed one hundred dollars or\nimprisonment for not to exceed sixty days, or both, and that each\ncalendar week's continued violation shall constitute a separate\nadditional violation.  In the event that a provision of an ordinance or\nlocal law adopted pursuant to this article conflicts with a provision of\na zoning ordinance or local law subsequently adopted pursuant to article\nseven of the village law or article sixteen of the town law, the\nprovision of the zoning ordinance or local law so subsequently adopted\nshall govern.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>