<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-291"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-291"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="291"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-291/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-291/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-291/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-291/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_291">
        <num>291</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of real property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 291. Acquisition of real property. When the legislative body shall\nhave resolved to establish a facility and programs for the elderly, it\nmay use for such purpose real property owned by the county, town, city\nor village which, in its judgment, is not needed for any other public\nuse or it may purchase or lease real property or interest or easement\ntherein, or acquire such real property interest and easement therein by\ncondemnation proceedings in the manner provided by the provisions of the\ncondemnation law. The purchase price or award for the real property or\ninterest or easement therein acquired may be paid for by appropriation\nof monies available therefor or may be financed, in whole or in part,\npursuant to the local finance law. Real property and interests or\neasements therein may be acquired, pursuant to this section, for use on\na determined or undetermined future date upon a determination by the\nlocal legislative body that such action is necessary in order to obtain\nproperty which is desirable because of its reasonable cost, advantageous\nlocation or any other factor recommending immediate acquisition.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>