<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="30"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_30">
        <num>30</num>
        <heading>Reports</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each town or village having a population, as shown by the latest\npreceding decennial federal census, between five thousand to nineteen\nthousand nine hundred ninety-nine, shall file their respective reports\nwith the comptroller within ninety days after the close of the fiscal\nyear of such town or village. Upon written request from the chief fiscal\nofficer of such a town or village, the comptroller may extend such\nninety day period for an additional thirty days.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each town or village having a population, as shown by the latest\npreceding decennial federal census, with twenty thousand or more, and\nall cities and counties, irrespective of their populations, shall file\ntheir respective reports with the comptroller within one hundred twenty\ndays after the close of the fiscal year of such county, city, town or\nvillage.\n  6. Annually, each industrial development agency, the Troy industrial\ndevelopment authority established pursuant to title eleven of article\neight of the public authorities law, and the Auburn industrial\ndevelopment authority established pursuant to title fifteen of article\neight of the public authorities law, shall file a financial report\npursuant to section eight hundred fifty-nine of this chapter.\n  7. Each municipal corporation shall make accessible to the public on\nits municipal website required under article thirteen-E of this chapter\ndocumentation pertaining to its most recent annual financial reports,\ncurrent year budget, most recent independent audit report and most\nrecent fiscal performance plan or multiyear financial plan required\npursuant to paragraph g of subdivision ten of section fifty-four of the\nstate finance law, unless such information is covered by subdivision two\nof section eighty-seven of the public officers law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>