<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-353-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-353-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="353-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-353-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-353-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-353-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-353-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_353_A">
        <num>353-A</num>
        <heading>Joint airports for counties, cities, towns or villages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 353-a. Joint airports for counties, cities, towns or villages.  Two\nor more adjoining counties or two cities in the same county or adjoining\ncounties, or a city and one or more villages located within the same\ncounty or adjoining counties, or two or more villages, located within\nthe same county, or adjoining counties, or two or more towns in the same\ncounty or adjoining counties, or a city and one or more towns located\nwithin the same county or adjoining counties, or a town and one or more\nvillages (including a village or villages within such town), located\nwithin the same county or adjoining counties, may jointly acquire real\nproperty by purchase, lease or condemnation for the purposes of this\narticle and establish, construct, equip, maintain and operate for such\nmunicipalities jointly an airport or landing field. The ordinance, local\nlaw or resolution providing for such action shall be adopted by the\nlocal legislative body or board of trustees of each municipality and\nshall create a committee to be at all times composed of members of each\nof such bodies or boards to acquire necessary real property, in the name\nof the municipalities jointly, and as their joint agent, and to have\ncharge of the construction, equipment, maintenance and operation of such\nairport or landing field. The ordinance, local law or resolution may\nspecify matters as to which the action of the committee shall require\nthe joint approval of such bodies or boards.  The ordinance, local law\nor resolution also shall prescribe the proportions of the cost of such\nproject to be borne by the municipalities respectively.  The moneys to\npay the share to be borne by each municipality may be provided in the\nmanner prescribed by this article. The ordinance, local law or\nresolution may be amended from time to time with the concurrence of each\nof such bodies or boards, and the boundaries of the airport or landing\nplace may be extended or the project abandoned in like manner at any\ntime. A joint airport or landing place established under this article\nshall be located in one or more of the counties participating in the\njoint undertaking, or within the county in which the cities or one of\nthem is located, or the county in which the villages or towns are\nlocated.  The limitation contained in section three hundred and fifty as\nto distance from the boundaries of any such city, village or town shall\nnot apply to such a joint airport or landing place.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>