<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-363"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-363"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="363"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-363/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-363/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-363/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-363/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_363">
        <num>363</num>
        <heading>Construction of public utility service</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 363. Construction of public utility service.  The purchase,\nacquisition, leasing, and construction of such public utility service\nshall, in so far as is practicable, be effected by such municipal\ncorporation in the same manner and by the same officers or boards as\nother authorized public improvements are effected for and by such\ncorporation. The provisions of law in force in such municipal\ncorporation applicable to the purchase, acquisition, leasing and\nconstruction of the public utility service provided for in this article\nshall apply when not inconsistent with the provisions of this article.\nThe local law, ordinance or resolution provided for in section three\nhundred and sixty of this article may, however, provide a different\nmethod or authority or agency for the purchase, acquisition, leasing and\nconstruction of such service, not inconsistent with state law applicable\nthereto. Funds to be used for any of the purposes set forth in section\nthree hundred and sixty of this article shall be paid out in the manner\nprescribed by law for the payment of the expenses of other public\nimprovements authorized for and effected by the municipal corporation\naffected.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>