<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-370-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-370-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-06-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="370-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-370-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-370-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-370-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-370-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_370_A">
        <num>370-A</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 370-a. Definitions. For the purpose of this article:\n  1. "Traffic and parking violations agency" shall mean a department of\nthe Nassau county government established pursuant to subdivision two of\nsection three hundred seventy of this article or a department in the\nSuffolk county government established pursuant to subdivision three of\nsuch section to administer and dispose of traffic and parking\ninfractions.\n  1-a. "Traffic violations agency" shall mean an executive department of\nthe city of Buffalo established pursuant to subdivision four of section\nthree hundred seventy of this article to administer and dispose of\ntraffic infractions as authorized pursuant to this article.\n  1-b. "Traffic violations agency" shall mean an executive department of\nthe city of Rochester established pursuant to subdivision five of\nsection three hundred seventy of this article to administer and dispose\nof traffic infractions as authorized pursuant to this article.\n  2. "Traffic prosecutor" shall mean an attorney duly admitted to\npractice law in the state of New York who, having been appointed and\neither hired or retained pursuant to section three hundred seventy-four\nof this article, has the responsibility of prosecuting any traffic and\nparking infractions returnable before the Nassau county district court\nor the Suffolk county district court or any traffic infractions\nreturnable before the Buffalo city court pursuant to the jurisdictional\nlimitations of section three hundred seventy-one of this article.\n  2-a. "Traffic prosecutor" shall also mean an attorney duly admitted to\npractice law in the state of New York who, having been appointed and\neither hired or retained pursuant to section three hundred\nseventy-four-b of this article, has the responsibility of prosecuting\nany traffic infractions returnable before the Rochester city court\npursuant to the jurisdictional limitations of section three hundred\nseventy-one of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>