<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-452"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-452"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="452"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-452/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-452/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-452/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-452/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_452">
        <num>452</num>
        <heading>Sewer rents</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_452__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as upon contract for sewer rents in\narrears, including penalties and interest, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_452__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to foreclose liens for\nsuch sewer rents; provided, however, that in the case of a sewer\ndistrict or wastewater disposal district in a town which district has a\nboard of sewer commissioners any such action shall be brought and\nmaintained by such board. As an alternative to the maintenance of any\nsuch action, any such local legislative body or board of sewer\ncommissioners of a sewer district or wastewater disposal district, as\nthe case may be, may annually cause a statement to be prepared setting\nforth the amount of each lien for sewer rents in arrears, the real\nproperty affected thereby and the name of the person in whose name such\nreal property is assessed. Such statement shall be presented to the\nboard or body empowered to levy city, village, county or town taxes, as\nthe case may be, on or before a date to be specified by such board or\nbody. Such board or body shall levy the amounts contained in such\nstatement against the real property liable at the same time and in the\nsame manner as city, village, county or town taxes, as the case may be,\nand such amounts shall be set forth in a separate column in the annual\ntax rolls. The amounts so levied shall be collected and enforced in the\nsame manner and at the same time as may be provided by law for the\ncollection and enforcement of city, village, county or town taxes, as\nthe case may be.\n  5. The local law or ordinance establishing and imposing sewer rents:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_452__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall describe the sewer system or the part or parts of the sewer\nsystem for which such rents shall be established and imposed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_452__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall prescribe the basis of the charge for such rents.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_452__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall provide for the date or dates on which sewer rents shall\nbecome due and payable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_452__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>May provide for penalties for sewer rents in arrears or for\ndiscounts for the prompt payment of such rents, or for both penalties\nand discounts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>