<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-453"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-453"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="453"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_453">
        <num>453</num>
        <heading>Sewer rent fund</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 453. Sewer rent fund. Revenues derived from sewer rents, including\npenalties and interest, shall be credited to a special fund, to be known\nas the "sewer rent fund." Moneys in such fund shall be used in the\nfollowing order:\n  1. For the payment of the costs of operation, maintenance and repairs\nof the sewer system or such part or parts thereof for which sewer rents\nhave been established and imposed.\n  2. For the payment of the interest on and amortization of, or payment\nof, indebtedness which has been or shall be incurred for the\nconstruction of the sewer system or such part or parts thereof for which\nsewer rents have been established and imposed (other than indebtedness,\nand the interest thereon, which is to be paid in the first instance from\nassessments upon benefited real property).\n  3. For the construction of sewage treatment and disposal works with\nnecessary appurtenances including pumping stations, or for the\nextension, enlargement, or replacement of, or additions to, such sewer\nsystems, or part or parts thereof.\n  Such revenues from sewer rents shall not be used (1) to finance the\ncost of any extension of any part of a sewer system (other than any\nsewage treatment and disposal works with necessary appurtenances\nincluding pumping stations) to serve unsewered areas if such part has\nbeen constructed wholly or partly at the expense of real property\nespecially benefited, or (2) for the payment of the interest on, and the\namortization of, or payment of, indebtedness which is to be paid in the\nfirst instance from assessments upon benefited real property.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>