<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-469"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-469"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="469"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-469/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-469/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-469/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-469/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_469">
        <num>469</num>
        <heading>Approval of attorney general and other state officials</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 469. Approval of attorney general and other state officials.  Prior\nto and as a condition precedent to its entry into force,\n  1. An interlocal agreement or any amendment thereto shall be submitted\nto the attorney general, who shall determine whether the agreement or\namendment is in proper form and compatible with the laws and public\npolicy of this state. The attorney general shall approve the interlocal\nagreement or amendment unless he shall find that it does not meet the\nconditions and requirements set forth herein. He shall report in writing\nto the governing boards of the contracting public agencies the specific\nrespects in which the proposed agreement or amendment fails to meet the\nconditions or requirements of law or of public policy. The failure of\nthe attorney general to disapprove an interlocal agreement or amendment\nwithin ninety days after receipt of the approvals required by\nsubdivision two of this section, or within such longer period as shall\nbe consented to by the contracting public agencies, shall constitute\napproval thereof.\n  2. In the event that an interlocal agreement or amendment thereto\nshall deal in whole or in part with the receiving, obtaining, providing\nor furnishing of services, facilities, personnel, equipment, or other\nproperty or resources, or the engaging in or performance of functions or\nactivities with regard to which the attorney general shall certify that\na department, officer or agency of this state has constitutional or\nstatutory responsibilities, powers, functions or duties or acts as agent\nof the state in connection with any federal or interstate program, the\nagreement or amendment shall be submitted to such department, officer or\nagency, and shall be approved or disapproved by it or him as to all\nmatters within its or his jurisdiction. This approval shall be subject\nto the same requirements governing the action of the attorney general\nunder subdivision one of this section. This requirement of submission\nand approval shall be in addition to and not in substitution for the\nrequirement of submission to and approval by the attorney general.\n  3. A legal opinion or opinions must be submitted to the attorney\ngeneral, in such form as shall be prescribed or approved by him,\nconcerning the authority of the contracting public agency or agencies of\nthe other state or states to enter into the interlocal agreement or any\namendment thereto.\n  4. A copy of the interlocal agreement and of any amendment thereto,\ncertified by the clerk or other appropriate officer of the governing\nboard of the contracting public agency of this state, shall be filed\nwith the county clerk of each of the counties of this state in which\nsuch contracting public agency is located; and another copy, similarly\ncertified, shall be filed with the secretary of state of this state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>