<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-479"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-479"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-07-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="479"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-479/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-479/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-479/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-479/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_479">
        <num>479</num>
        <heading>Restrictions upon conduct of bingo games</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 479. Restrictions upon conduct of bingo games. The conduct of bingo\ngames authorized by local law or ordinance shall be subject to the\nfollowing restrictions irrespective of whether the restrictions are\ncontained in such local law or ordinance; but nothing herein shall be\nconstrued to prevent the inclusion within such local law or ordinance of\nother provisions imposing additional restrictions upon the conduct of\nbingo games:\n  1. No person, firm, association, corporation or organization, other\nthan a licensee under the provisions of this article, shall conduct such\ngame or shall lease or otherwise make available for conducting bingo a\nhall or other premises for any consideration whatsoever, direct or\nindirect.\n  2. No bingo games shall be held, operated or conducted on or within\nany leased premises if rental under such lease is to be paid, wholly or\npartly, on the basis of a percentage of the receipts or net profits\nderived from the operation of such game.\n  3. No authorized organization licensed under the provisions of this\narticle shall purchase, lease, or receive any supplies or equipment\nspecifically designed or adapted for use in the conduct of bingo games\nfrom other than a supplier licensed under the bingo control law or from\nanother authorized organization.\n  4. The entire net proceeds of any game of bingo and of any rental\nshall be exclusively devoted to the lawful purposes of the organization\npermitted to conduct the same.\n  5. No prize shall exceed the sum or value of five thousand dollars in\nany single game of bingo.\n  6. No series of prizes on any one bingo occasion shall aggregate more\nthan fifteen thousand dollars.\n  7. No person except a bona fide member of any such organization shall\nparticipate in the management or operation of such game.\n  8. No person shall receive any remuneration for participating in the\nmanagement or operation of any game of bingo.\n  9. The unauthorized conduct of a bingo game and any wilful violation\nof any provision of any local law or ordinance shall constitute and be\npunishable as a misdemeanor.\n  9-a. No person licensed to sell bingo supplies or equipment, or their\nagents, shall conduct, participate in, or assist in the conduct of\nbingo. Nothing herein shall prohibit a licensed distributor from\nselling, offering for sale, or explaining a product to an authorized\norganization, or installing, or servicing bingo equipment, upon the\npremises of a bingo game licensee.\n  10. Limited period bingo shall be conducted in accordance with the\nprovisions of this article and the rules and regulations of the\ncommission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>