<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-488"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-488"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="488"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-488/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-488/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-488/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-488/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_488">
        <num>488</num>
        <heading>Persons operating and conducting games; equipment; expenses; compensation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 488. Persons operating and conducting games; equipment; expenses;\ncompensation.  1. No person shall hold, operate or conduct any game of\nbingo under any license issued under this article except a bona fide\nmember of the authorized organization to which the license is issued,\nand no person shall assist in the holding, operating or conducting of\nany game of bingo under such license except such a bona fide member or a\nbona fide member of an organization or association which is an auxiliary\nto the licensee or a bona fide member of an organization or association\nof which such licensee is an auxiliary or a bona fide member of an\norganization or association which is affiliated with the licensee by\nbeing, with it, auxiliary to another organization or association and\nexcept bookkeepers or accountants as hereinafter provided. Provided,\nhowever, any person may assist the licensed organization in any activity\nrelated to the game of bingo which does not actually involve the\nholding, conducting, managing or operating of such game of bingo. No\ngame of bingo shall be conducted with any equipment except such as shall\nbe owned absolutely or leased by the authorized organization so licensed\nor used without payment of any compensation therefor by the licensee.\nLease terms and conditions shall be subject to rules and regulations\npromulgated by the board. This article shall not be construed to\nauthorize or permit an authorized organization to engage in the business\nof leasing bingo supplies or equipment. No items of expense shall be\nincurred or paid in connection with the conducting of any game of bingo\npursuant to any license issued under this article, except those that are\nreasonable and are necessarily expended for bingo supplies and\nequipment, prizes, stated rental if any, bookkeeping or accounting\nservices according to a schedule of compensation prescribed by the\ncommission, janitorial services and utility supplies if any, and license\nfees, and the cost of bus transportation, if authorized by the control\ncommission.\n  2. Notwithstanding any provision of this article to the contrary, a\nperson who is a bona fide member of an organization licensed to conduct\nthe game of bingo and is also a bona fide member of one or more other\norganizations which are also licensed to conduct the game of bingo, and\nsuch organizations are not affiliates or auxiliaries of the others,\nshall be authorized to operate, conduct or assist in the operation or\nconduct of games of bingo held by any of such organizations licensed to\nconduct bingo.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>