<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-490"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-490"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-07-14" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="490"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-490/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-490/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-490/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-490/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_490">
        <num>490</num>
        <heading>Advertising of bingo games</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 490. Advertising of bingo games. A licensee may advertise the\nconduct of an occasion of bingo to the general public by means of\nnewspaper, radio, circular, handbill and poster, by one sign not\nexceeding sixty square feet in area, which may be displayed on or\nadjacent to the premises owned or occupied by a licensed authorized\norganization, and through the internet or television as may be regulated\nby the rules and regulations of the commission. When an organization is\nlicensed to conduct bingo occasions on the premises of another licensed\nauthorized organization or of a licensed commercial lessor, one\nadditional such sign may be displayed on or adjacent to the premises in\nwhich the occasions are to be conducted. Additional signs may be\ndisplayed upon any firefighting or ambulance equipment belonging to any\nlicensed authorized organization which is a volunteer fire company,\nvolunteer ambulance corps or upon any equipment of a first aid or rescue\nsquad in and throughout the community served by such volunteer fire\ncompany, volunteer ambulance corps or such first aid or rescue squad, as\nthe case may be. All advertisements shall be limited to the description\nof such event as "bingo", the name of the licensed authorized\norganization conducting such bingo occasions, the license number of the\nauthorized organization as assigned by the clerk; the prizes offered and\nthe date, location and time of the bingo occasion.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>