<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-5-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-5-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-5-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-5-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-5-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-5-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_B">
        <num>5-B</num>
        <heading>Collection of fines, civil penalties, rent, rates, taxes, fees, charges and other amounts via the internet</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>authenticate\nthe identity of the sender; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>ensure the security of the\ninformation transmitted.\n  2. Any local government authorizing the payment of taxes via the\ninternet shall provide or direct its vendor to provide a confirmation\npage to the taxpayer following the completion of the internet\ntransaction. Such confirmation page shall include, at least, the\nfollowing:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the date the internet transaction was completed and sent by the\ntaxpayer;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount paid;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a unique confirmation number; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a notice advising the taxpayer to print out and retain the\nconfirmation page as his or her receipt.\n  3. Payments received via the internet shall be considered received by\nthe appropriate officer and paid by the taxpayer at the time the\ninternet transaction is completed and sent by the taxpayer.\n  4. The underlying debt, lien, obligation, bill, account or other\namount owed to the local government for which payment by internet is\naccepted by the local government shall not be expunged, cancelled,\nreleased, discharged or satisfied, and any receipt or other evidence of\npayment shall be deemed conditional, until the local government has\nreceived final and unconditional payment of the full amount due.\n  5. The governing board, in enacting a local law, ordinance or\nresolution pursuant to this section, shall designate which of its\nofficers, charged with the duty of collecting or receiving moneys on\nbehalf of the local government, shall be authorized to accept such\npayments via the internet.\n  6. The state comptroller shall issue such guidelines as he or she\ndeems appropriate governing the use of third-party vendors for this\npurpose.  Any local government contracting with a third-party vendor for\nthis purpose shall follow the guidelines issued by the state\ncomptroller.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>