<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_B">
        <num>50-B</num>
        <heading>Municipal liability for negligent operation of vehicles or other facility of transportation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-b. Municipal liability for negligent operation of vehicles or\nother facility of transportation. 1. Every county, city, town, village\nand other subdivision of government, notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovisions of law, general, special or local or any limitation contained\nin the provision of any city charter, shall be liable and shall assume\nthe liability for the negligence of, and shall save harmless, a person\nduly appointed by the governing board or body of the municipality, or by\nany board, body, commission or other officer thereof, in the operation\nof a municipally owned vehicle or other facility of transportation\nwithin the state in the discharge of a statutory duty imposed upon such\nperson or municipality, provided the appointee at the time of the\naccident or injury was acting in the discharge of his duties and within\nthe scope of his employment. Every such appointee shall, for the purpose\nof this section, be deemed an employee of the municipality,\nnotwithstanding the vehicle or other facility of transportation was\nbeing operated in the discharge of a public duty for the benefit of all\ncitizens of the community and the municipality derived no special\nbenefit in its corporate capacity.\n  2. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the city of New\nYork.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>