<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_G">
        <num>50-G</num>
        <heading>Recording of notice of defect</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-g. Recording of notice of defect. 1. Wherever any statute, city\ncharter or local law provides that no civil action shall be maintained\nagainst a city for damages or injuries to person or property sustained\nin consequence of any street, highway, bridge, culvert, sidewalk or\ncrosswalk being out of repair, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed, or in\nconsequence of the existence of snow or ice thereon, unless it appear\nthat written notice of the defective, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed\ncondition, or of the existence of the snow or ice, was actually given to\nthe city or its specified officer or employee and there was a failure or\nneglect within a reasonable time after the giving of such notice to\nrepair or remove the defect, danger or obstruction complained of, or to\ncause the snow or ice to be removed, or the place otherwise made\nreasonably safe, the city shall keep an indexed record, in a separate\nbook, of all written notices which it shall receive of the existence of\nsuch defective, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed condition, or of such\nsnow or ice, which record shall state the date of receipt of the notice,\nthe nature and location of the condition stated to exist, and the name\nand address of the person from whom the notice is received. All such\nwritten notices shall be indexed according to the location of the\nalleged defective, unsafe, dangerous or obstructed condition, or the\nlocation of accumulated snow or ice.\n  2. Where the statute, charter or local law requires that the written\nnotice be given to a specified city officer or employee the record shall\nbe made and kept by the person so specified. Where the statute, charter\nor local law requires that the written notice be given to any of several\nspecified city officers or employees, or omits to specify the officer or\nemployee to whom the written notice shall be given, the record shall be\nmade and kept by an officer or employee designated for that purpose by\nthe governing body of the city. In the absence of such designation the\nrecord shall be made and kept by the commissioner of public works of the\ncity or, if there be no officer of that title, by an officer exercising\ncorresponding duties. The record of notices of defects shall be a public\nrecord. The record of each notice shall be preserved for a period of\nfive years after the date it is received.\n  3. This section shall be applicable notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovisions of law, general, special or local, or any limitation\ncontained in the provisions of any city charter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>