<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_K">
        <num>50-K</num>
        <heading>Civil actions against employees of the city of New York</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_50_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>delivery to the corporation\ncounsel at the office of the law department of the city by the employee\nof the original or a copy of any summons, complaint, process, notice,\ndemand or pleading within ten days after he is served with such\ndocument, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_50_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the full cooperation of the employee in the defense of\nsuch action or proceeding and in defense of any action or proceeding\nagainst the city based upon the same act or omission, and in the\nprosecution of any appeal.  Such delivery shall be deemed a request by\nthe employee that the city provide for his defense pursuant to this\nsection. In the event that the corporation counsel shall assume an\nemployee's defense and thereafter the employee fails to or refuses to\ncooperate in the formation or presentation of his defense, the court\nshall permit the corporation counsel to withdraw his representation ten\ndays after giving written notice to the employee of his intention to\ndiscontinue such representation.\n  5. In the event that the act or omission upon which the court\nproceeding against the employee is based was or is also the basis of a\ndisciplinary proceeding by the employee's agency against the employee,\nrepresentation by the corporation counsel and indemnification by the\ncity may be withheld</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_50_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>until such disciplinary proceeding has been\nresolved and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_50_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>unless the resolution of the disciplinary proceeding\nexonerated the employee as to such act or omission.\n  6. Every action or proceeding instituted hereunder, including an\naction brought to enforce a provision of sections nineteen hundred\neighty-one through nineteen hundred eighty-eight of title forty-two of\nthe United States code, shall be commenced pursuant to the provisions of\nsection fifty-i of this chapter and within one year and ninety days. No\naction or proceeding instituted hereunder, other than one instituted\npursuant to sections nineteen hundred eighty-one through nineteen\nhundred eighty-eight of title forty-two of the United States code shall\nbe prosecuted or maintained against the city or any agency or an\nemployee unless notice of claim shall have been made and served upon the\ncity in compliance with section fifty-e of this chapter and within\nninety days after the claim arises.\n  7. The provisions of this section shall not be construed to impair,\nalter, limit or modify the rights and obligations of any insurer under\nany policy of insurance.\n  8. The provisions of this section shall apply to all actions and\nproceedings pending upon the effective date thereof or thereafter\ninstituted, except that the provisions of subdivision six shall apply\nonly to actions and proceedings instituted on or after the effective\ndate of this section.\n  9. The provisions of this section shall not be construed in any way to\nimpair, alter, limit, modify, or abrogate or restrict any immunity\navailable to or conferred upon any unit, entity, officer or employee of\nthe city or any agency or any other level of government, or any right to\ndefense and/or indemnification provided for any governmental officer or\nemployee by, in accordance with, or by reason of, any other provision of\nstate, federal or local law or common law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>