<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="50-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-50-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_50_L">
        <num>50-L</num>
        <heading>Civil actions against employees of the Nassau county police department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 50-l. Civil actions against employees of the Nassau county police\ndepartment. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, code or\ncharter, the county of Nassau shall provide for the defense of any civil\naction or proceeding brought against a duly appointed police officer of\nthe Nassau county police department and shall indemnify and save\nharmless such police officer from any judgment of a court of competent\njurisdiction whenever such action, proceeding or judgment is for\ndamages, including punitive or exemplary damages, arising out of a\nnegligent act or other tort of such police officer committed while in\nthe proper discharge of his duties and within the scope of his\nemployment. Such proper discharge and scope shall be determined by a\nmajority vote of a panel consisting of one member appointed by the\nNassau county board of supervisors, one member appointed by the Nassau\ncounty executive, and the third member being the Nassau county police\ncommissioner or a deputy police commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>