<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-505"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-505"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="505"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-505/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-505/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-505/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-505/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_505">
        <num>505</num>
        <heading>Urban renewal plan and approval thereof</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_505__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the commission shall have certified its unqualified approval,\napprove the plan by a majority vote;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_505__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the commission shall have certified its disapproval or shall\nhave failed to make its report within ten weeks from the date such plan\nwas submitted to it by the agency, nevertheless approve the plan, but\nonly by a three-fourths vote;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_505__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the commission shall have certified its qualified approval\ntogether with recommendations for modifications, approve the plan\ntogether with the modifications recommended by the commission by a\nmajority vote, or approve the plan without such modifications but only\nby a three-fourths vote.\n  4. Upon approving the urban renewal plan for the designated area, or\nfor a part or portion of such area, with or without modifications\nrecommended by the commission, the governing body shall by resolution\nfind that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_505__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The area is a substandard or insanitary area, or is in danger of\nbecoming a substandard or insanitary area and tends to impair or arrest\nthe sound growth and development of the municipality.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_505__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The financial aid to be provided to the municipality is necessary\nto enable the project to be undertaken in accordance with the plan.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_505__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The plan affords maximum opportunity to private enterprise,\nconsistent with the sound needs of the municipality as a whole, for the\nundertaking of an urban renewal program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_505__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The plan conforms to a comprehensive community plan for the\ndevelopment of the municipality as a whole.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_505__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is a feasible method for the relocation of families and\nindividuals displaced from the urban renewal area into decent, safe and\nsanitary dwellings, which are or will be provided in the urban renewal\narea or in other areas not generally less desirable in regard to public\nutilities and public and commercial facilities, at rents or prices\nwithin the financial means of such families or individuals, and\nreasonably accessible to their places of employment.\n  Upon approving an urban renewal plan for a part or portion of a\ndesignated area, the governing body shall, in addition to the foregoing,\nalso find that the undertaking and carrying out of the urban renewal\nactivities in stages is in the best public interest and will not cause\nany additional or increased hardship to the residents of such designated\narea.\n  5. In a city having a population of one million or more, any action of\nthe council approving an urban renewal plan shall be filed with the\nmayor within five days of such action for approval or disapproval.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>