<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-514"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-514"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="514"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-514/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-514/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-514/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-514/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_514">
        <num>514</num>
        <heading>Filing of proposed plans</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 514. Filing of proposed plans. The municipality or agency, as the\ncase may be, shall file with the commissioner a copy of any proposed\nurban renewal program assisted by state loans, periodic subsidies or\ncapital grants, embodying the plans, layout, estimated cost and proposed\nmethod of financing. Any change made in an urban renewal program\nassisted by state loans, periodic subsidies or capital grants shall be\nfiled with the commissioner. From time to time prior to completion, and\nwith reasonable promptness after any urban renewal program assisted by\nstate loans, periodic subsidies or capital grants shall have been\ncompleted, upon request of the commissioner, the municipality or agency\nshall file with the commissioner a detailed statement of the cost\nthereof.\n  Upon receipt of a copy of a proposed urban renewal program, or any\nproposed change therein, the commissioner may transmit his criticism and\nsuggestions to the municipality or agency, as the case may be. No change\nin an urban renewal program assisted by state loans, periodic subsidies\nor capital grants may be made by a municipality or agency without the\napproval of the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>