<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-53"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-53"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="53"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53">
        <num>53</num>
        <heading>Alternative service of notice of claim upon the secretary of state</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_53__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the secretary of state shall set and notify the public, on his or\nher website, of times, places and manner of service upon him or her of\nnotices of claims necessary to comply with the provisions of this\nsection;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_53__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon receipt of a notice of claim, the secretary of state shall\nissue a receipt or other document acknowledging his or her receipt of\nsuch notice, and such receipt shall contain the date and time of receipt\nof the notice, an identifying number or name particular to the notice\nreceived, and the logo or seal of the department of state embossed upon\nit. Such receipt shall be prima facie evidence of service upon the\nsecretary of state for all purposes;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_53__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>nothing in this section shall be deemed to alter, waive or\notherwise abrogate any defense available to a public corporation as to\nthe nature, sufficiency, or appropriateness of the notice of claim\nitself, or to any challenges to the timeliness of the service of a\nnotice of claim. Timely service upon the secretary of state shall be\ndeemed timely service upon the public corporation for purposes of\ninstituting an action or proceeding or other requirement imposed by law.\n  4. The secretary of state may impose a fee upon any person who serves\na notice of claim with the department. Such fee shall not exceed two\nhundred fifty dollars for each such notice filed. One-half of the fee\nimposed shall be retained by the secretary of state as payment for its\nservices provided in accordance with this section. The remaining\none-half of such fee shall be forwarded to the public corporation named\nin the notice of claim provided, however, if more than one such public\ncorporation is named, each named public corporation shall be entitled to\nan equal percentage of the one-half amount.\n  5. The secretary of state shall within sixty days after the effective\ndate of this section post on the departmental website a list of any\npublic corporation, including any public authority, public benefit\ncorporation or any other entity entitled to receive a notice of claim as\na condition precedent to commencement of an action or proceeding, and\nthat has filed, pursuant to this section, a certificate with the\nsecretary of state designating the secretary as the agent for service of\na notice of claim. The list should identify the entity, the post office\naddress and electronic mail address, if available, of the public\ncorporation to which the notice of claim shall be forwarded by the\nsecretary of state, and any statutory provisions uniquely pertaining to\nsuch public corporation and the commencement of an action or proceeding\nagainst it.\n  6. The secretary of state is authorized to...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>