<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-580-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-580-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="580-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-580-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-580-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-580-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-580-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_580_A">
        <num>580-A</num>
        <heading>Glen Cove community development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 580-a. Glen Cove community development agency. A municipal community\ndevelopment agency, to be known as the Glen Cove community development\nagency, is hereby established for the accomplishment of any and all of\nthe purposes specified in articles fifteen and fifteen-A of this\nchapter, and in accordance with article eighteen of the constitution of\nthe state of New York. It shall constitute a body corporate and politic,\nbe perpetual in duration. It shall consist of the mayor, who shall be\nthe chairman, and six other members to be appointed by the mayor (no\nmore than two of whom may be members of the common council of the city\nof Glen Cove excluding the mayor) subject to the approval of the common\ncouncil of the city of Glen Cove. It shall have the powers and duties\nnow or hereafter conferred by article fifteen-A of this chapter upon\nmunicipal urban renewal agencies. It shall be organized in a manner\nprescribed by and subject to the provisions of article fifteen-A of this\nchapter and the agency, its members, officers and employees and its\noperation and activities shall in all respects be governed by the\nprovisions of such article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>