<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-583"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-583"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="583"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-583/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-583/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-583/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-583/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_583">
        <num>583</num>
        <heading>White Plains urban renewal agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 583. White Plains urban renewal agency. 1. A municipal urban renewal\nagency, to be known as the White Plains urban renewal agency, is hereby\nestablished for the accomplishment of any or all of the objects or\npurposes specified in articles fifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter and\nin accordance with article eighteen of the constitution of the state of\nNew York. Such agency shall constitute a body corporate and politic, and\nshall consist of five members. The members of such agency shall be\nappointed by the mayor of such city who may appoint himself as one of\nsuch members. Such agency shall be perpetual in duration, except that in\nthe event that the certificate to be executed and filed by such mayor\npursuant to subdivision one of section five hundred fifty-three of this\nchapter is not filed and approved by the state commissioner of housing\nand community renewal prior to July first, nineteen hundred sixty-five,\nthen the corporate existence of such agency shall thereupon terminate\nand such agency shall thereupon be deemed to be and shall be dissolved.\n  2. Such agency shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter\nconferred by article fifteen-A of this chapter upon municipal urban\nrenewal agencies, and shall be organized in the manner prescribed by and\nshall be subject to the provisions of such article. Such agency, its\nmembers, officers and employees and its operations and activities,\nshall, in all respects, be governed by the provisions of articles\nfifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>