<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-585-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-585-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="585-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-585-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-585-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-585-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-585-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_585_A">
        <num>585-A</num>
        <heading>Incorporated village of Hempstead community development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 585-a. Incorporated village of Hempstead community development\nagency. 1. A community development agency to be known as the\nincorporated village of Hempstead community development agency, is\nhereby established for the accomplishment of any or all of the purposes\nspecified in articles fifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter and in\naccordance with article eighteen of the constitution of the state of New\nYork. It shall constitute a body corporate and politic, be perpetual in\nduration and consist of not less than three and not more than five\nmembers including the mayor. The additional members shall be appointed\nby the mayor with the concurring approval of the village board. It shall\nhave the powers and duties now or hereafter conferred by article\nfifteen-A of this chapter upon municipal renewal agencies. It shall be\norganized in the manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions\nof article fifteen-A of this chapter and the agency, its members,\nofficers and employees and its operations and activities shall in all\nrespect be governed by the provisions of such article.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law unless the\ncontext clearly requires otherwise, any reference in any other law,\ngeneral, special or local, ordinance or resolution to the incorporated\nvillage of Hempstead urban renewal agency shall be deemed a reference to\nthe incorporated village of Hempstead community development agency. All\nacts, proceedings, rights and remedies of the incorporated village of\nHempstead urban renewal agency, created by chapter two hundred sixty-six\nof the laws of nineteen hundred sixty-four effective or occurring prior\nto the effective date of this section shall be and remain valid and\npreserved and shall in no manner be lost, impaired or affected by reason\nof the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>