<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-589"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-589"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="589"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-589/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-589/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-589/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-589/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_589">
        <num>589</num>
        <heading>Gloversville community development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 589. Gloversville community development agency. A municipal\ncommunity development agency, to be known as the Gloversville community\ndevelopment agency, is hereby established for the accomplishment of any\nor all of the purposes specified in articles fifteen and fifteen-A of\nthis chapter and in accordance with article eighteen of the constitution\nof the state of New York.  It shall constitute a body corporate and\npolitic, be perpetual in duration and consist of five members to be\nappointed by the mayor subject to the approval of the common council,\none of which members may be the mayor of the city of Gloversville and\none of which members may be a member of the common council of the city\nof Gloversville. It shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter\nconferred by article fifteen-A of this chapter upon municipal urban\nrenewal agencies. It shall be organized in the manner prescribed by and\nbe subject to the provisions of article fifteen-A of this chapter and\nthe agency, its members, officers and employees and its operations and\nactivities shall in all respects be governed by the provisions of such\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>