<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-591"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-591"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="591"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-591/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-591/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-591/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-591/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_591">
        <num>591</num>
        <heading>Village of Spring Valley urban renewal agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 591. Village of Spring Valley urban renewal agency. An urban renewal\nagency, to be known as the village of Spring Valley urban renewal\nagency, is hereby established for the accomplishment of any or all of\nthe purposes specified in articles fifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter\nand in accordance with article eighteen of the constitution of the state\nof New York. It shall constitute a body corporate and politic, be\nperpetual in duration and consist of five members, including the mayor,\nwho shall be the chairman. The additional members shall be appointed by\nthe mayor. It shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter\nconferred by article fifteen-A of this chapter upon municipal renewal\nagencies. It shall be organized in the manner prescribed by and be\nsubject to the provisions of article fifteen-A of this chapter and the\nagency, its members, officers and employees and its operations and\nactivities shall in all respects be governed by the provisions of such\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>