<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-595"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-595"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="595"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-595/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-595/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-595/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-595/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_595">
        <num>595</num>
        <heading>Lockport urban renewal agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 595. Lockport urban renewal agency.  An urban renewal agency, to be\nknown as the Lockport urban renewal agency, is hereby established for\nthe accomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in articles\nfifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter and in accordance with article\neighteen of the constitution of the state of New York. It shall\nconstitute a body corporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration\nand consist of seven members, including the mayor. Four of the members\nshall be appointed by the mayor from the common council with the\nconcurring approval of the common council. Two of the members shall not\nbe members of the common council, and they shall be appointed by the\nmayor, with the concurring approval of the common council. It shall have\nthe power and duties now or hereafter conferred by article fifteen-A of\nthis chapter upon municipal renewal agencies. It shall be organized in\nthe manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions of article\nfifteen-A of this chapter and the agency, its members, officers and\nemployees and its operations and activities shall in all respects be\ngoverned by the provisions of such article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>