<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-6-R"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-6-R"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-R"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-6-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-6-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-6-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-6-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_R">
        <num>6-R</num>
        <heading>Retirement contribution reserve funds 1</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a participating employer as\ndefined in subdivision twenty of section two of the retirement and\nsocial security law or in subdivision twenty of section three hundred\ntwo of such law; or (ii) a participating employer as defined in\nsubdivision three of section five hundred one of the education law.\n  c. "Retirement contribution" shall mean all or any portion of the\namount payable by a municipal corporation to:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>either the New York\nstate and local employees' retirement system or the New York state and\nlocal police and fire retirement system pursuant to section seventeen or\nthree hundred seventeen of the retirement and social security law; or\n(ii) the New York state teachers' retirement system pursuant to section\nfive hundred twenty-one of the education law.\n  2. The governing board of any municipal corporation which is also a\nparticipating employer by resolution may establish a retirement\ncontribution reserve fund for the purpose of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>financing retirement\ncontributions, and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of a municipal corporation which\nis a participating employer as defined in subdivision three of section\nfive hundred one of the education law, financing appropriations\nauthorized by law in order to offset all or a portion of the amount\ndeducted from the moneys apportioned to the municipal corporation from\nthe state for the support of common schools pursuant to section five\nhundred twenty-one of the education law.\n  2-a. With respect to a municipal corporation which is a participating\nemployer as defined in subdivision three of section five hundred one of\nthe education law, which elects to utilize a retirement contribution\nreserve fund</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to finance retirement contributions to the New York\nstate teachers' retirement system pursuant to section five hundred\ntwenty-one of the education law and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to offset all or a portion of\nthe amount deducted from the moneys apportioned to the municipal\ncorporation from the state for the support of common schools pursuant to\nsection five hundred twenty-one of the education law, such municipal\ncorporation shall establish a sub-fund within the retirement\ncontribution reserve fund, which shall be separately administered\nconsistent with the provisions of this section. Such municipal\ncorporation may pay into such sub-fund during any particular fiscal year\nan amount not to exceed two per centum of the total compensation or\nsalaries of all teachers in the employ of said municipal corporation who\nare members of the New York state teachers' retirement system paid\nduring the immediately preceding fiscal year. The balance of such\nsub-fund may not exceed ten per centum of the total compensation or\nsalaries of all teachers in the employ of the municipal corporation who\nare members of the New York state teachers' retirement system paid\nduring the immediately preceding fiscal year. For the purposes of this\nsubdivision, the term "teacher" shall have the same meaning as such term\nis defined under subdivision four of section five hundred one of the\neducation law.\n  3. There may be paid into a retirement contribution reserve fund:\n  a. such amounts as may be provided therefor by budgetary appropriation\nor raised by tax therefor;\n  b. such revenues as are not required by law to be paid into any other\nfund or account;\n  c. such other funds as may be legally appropriated; and\n  d. notwithstanding any law to the contrary, such amounts as may be\ntransferred from a reserve fund established pursuant to section six-c,\nsix-d, six-e, six-f or six-g of this article comprised of moneys raised\nfrom the same tax base as the moneys in the retirement contribution\nreserve fund, or a reserve fund established pursuant to section\nthirty-six hundred fifty-one of the education law, provided, that any\nsuch transfer shall only be mad...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to finance retirement\ncontributions, and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of a municipal corporation which\nis a participating employer, as defined in subdivision three of section\nfive hundred one of the education law, for appropriations authorized by\nlaw in order to offset all or a portion of the amount deducted from the\nmoneys apportioned to the participating employer from the state for the\nsupport of common schools pursuant to section five hundred twenty-one of\nthe education law. With respect to a municipal corporation which is a\nparticipating employer as defined in subdivision three of section five\nhundred one of the education law, expenditures from the retirement\ncontribution reserve fund to finance retirement contributions to the New\nYork State teachers' retirement system pursuant to section five hundred\ntwenty-one of the education law and/or to offset all or a portion of the\namount deducted from the moneys apportioned to the municipal corporation\nfrom the state for the support of common schools pursuant to section\nfive hundred twenty-one of the education law may only be made from the\nsub-fund established pursuant to subdivision two-a of this section.\n  6. The governing board of such municipal corporation by resolution may\nauthorize the transfer of a portion of the moneys in a retirement\ncontribution reserve fund to a reserve fund of the municipal corporation\nestablished pursuant to section six-c, six-d, six-e, six-f or six-g of\nthis article comprised of moneys raised from the same tax base as the\nmoneys in the retirement contribution reserve fund, or a reserve fund\nestablished pursuant to section thirty-six hundred fifty-one of the\neducation law, provided, that any such transfer shall only be made by\nresolution of the governing board of such municipal corporation adopted\nafter a public hearing held on at least fifteen days prior published\nnotice in the official newspaper of the municipal corporation or, if the\nmunicipal corporation does not have an official newspaper, in at least\none newspaper...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>authorize a withdrawal from a retirement contribution reserve fund\nfor any purpose except as provided in this section; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>expend any money withdrawn from such fund for a purpose other than\nas provided in this section.\n  Any member of the governing board who violates the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall be guilty of a misdemeanor.\n  10. The governing board of such municipal corporation by resolution\nmay determine that a retirement contribution reserve fund is no longer\nneeded and terminate the fund. Such resolution shall transfer any moneys\nremaining in such fund to one or more reserve funds of the municipal\ncorporation established pursuant to section six-c, six-d, six-e, six-f\nor six-g of this article comprised of moneys raised from the same tax\nbase as the moneys in the retirement contribution reserve fund, or one\nor more reserve funds established pursuant to section thirty-six hundred\nfifty-one of the education law.\n  11. The governing board of a municipal corporation which is a\nparticipating employer as defined in subdivision three of section five\nhundred one of the education law by resolution may</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>authorize the\ntransfer of all or a portion of the monies in the separately\nadministered sub-fund as established under subdivision two-a of this\nsection to the retirement contribution reserve fund, and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nauthorize the transfer of all or a portion of the monies in the\nretirement contribution reserve fund to the separately administered\nsub-fund as provided in subdivision two-a of this section, subject to\nthe limits on annual payments into the sub-fund and the balance of the\nsub-fund specified by subdivision two-a of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>