<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-623"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-623"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="623"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-623/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-623/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-623/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-623/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_623">
        <num>623</num>
        <heading>Albany community development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 623. Albany community development agency. A community development\nagency, to be known as the Albany community development agency, is\nhereby established for the accomplishment of any or all of the purposes\nspecified in articles fifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter and in\naccordance with article eighteen of the constitution of the state of New\nYork. It shall constitute a body, corporate and politic, be perpetual in\nduration and consist, notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of\nsection five hundred fifty-three of this chapter, of seven members,\nincluding the mayor, who shall be chairman, the chief fiscal officer,\nthe corporation counsel, the president of the common council, or other\npresiding officer thereof, the director of community development who\nshall also serve as secretary of said agency, the clerk of the city, and\nthe director of the office of equal employment opportunity for the city\nof Albany, all of whose terms shall expire with the term of the mayor.\nIt shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter covered by article\nfifteen-A of this chapter upon municipal renewal agencies. It shall be\norganized in the manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions\nof article fifteen-A of this chapter and the agency, its members,\nofficers and employees and its operations and activities shall in all\nrespects be covered by the provisions of such article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>