<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-633"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-633"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="633"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-633/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-633/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-633/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-633/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_633">
        <num>633</num>
        <heading>Town of Islip community development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 633. Town of Islip community development agency. An urban renewal\nagency, to be known as the Town of Islip community development agency,\nis hereby established for the accomplishment of any or all of the\npurposes specified in articles fifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter and\nin accordance with article eighteen of the constitution of the state of\nNew York. It shall constitute a body corporate and politic, and be\nperpetual in duration. It shall have the powers and duties now or\nhereafter conferred by articles fifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter\nupon municipal renewal agencies and provided that the exercise of the\npowers by such agency with respect to the acquisition of real property\nwhether by purchase, condemnation or otherwise, shall be limited to the\ncorporate limits of the Town of Islip, and such agency shall take into\nconsideration the local zoning and planning regulations as well as the\nregional and local comprehensive land use plans. It shall be organized\nin a manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions of articles\nfifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be appointed by\nthe governing body of the Town of Islip. The agency, its members,\nofficers and employees and its operations and activities shall in all\nrespects be governed by the provisions of articles fifteen and fifteen-A\nof this chapter.\n  Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section or any other law,\nrule or regulation to the contrary, on July first, nineteen hundred\neighty-one, new members of the agency shall be appointed or old members\nshall be reappointed, and they shall be appointed for fixed terms. One\nshall hold office for the term of one year, one for the term of two\nyears, and one for the term of three years. If a fourth member shall be\nappointed on such date, his term of office shall be four years. If a\nfifth member shall be appointed on such date, his term of office shall\nbe five years. The successors to all such members shall be appointed for\na term of five years from the expiration of the terms of their\npredecessors.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>