<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-634"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-634"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="634"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-634/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-634/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-634/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-634/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_634">
        <num>634</num>
        <heading>Jamestown urban renewal agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 634. Jamestown urban renewal agency. An urban renewal agency, to be\nknown as the Jamestown urban renewal agency, is hereby established for\nthe accomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in articles\nfifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter and in accordance with article\neighteen of the constitution of the state of New York. It shall\nconstitute a body, corporate and politic, be perpetual in duration and\nconsist of five members, including the mayor, who shall be chairman, the\nchief fiscal officer, the president of the common council, or other\npresiding officer thereof, and two other persons to be appointed by the\nmayor and approved by a majority of the common council, one of whom\nshall be a member of the city planning commission and who shall also\nserve as secretary of said agency, all of whose terms shall expire with\nthe term of the mayor. It shall have the powers and duties now or\nhereafter covered by article fifteen-A of this chapter upon municipal\nrenewal agencies. It shall be organized in the manner prescribed by and\nbe subject to the provisions of article fifteen-A of this chapter and\nthe agency, its members, officers and employees and its operations and\nactivities shall in all respects be covered by the provisions of such\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>