<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-640"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-640"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="640"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-640/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-640/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-640/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-640/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_640">
        <num>640</num>
        <heading>City of Hudson community development and planning agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 640. City of Hudson community development and planning agency.  An\nurban renewal agency, to be known as the city of Hudson community\ndevelopment and planning agency, is hereby established for the\naccomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in articles\nfifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter and in accordance with article\neighteen of the constitution of the state of New York. It shall\nconstitute a body corporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration\nand shall consist of five members, including the mayor, majority leader\nof the common council, minority leader of the common council, chairman\nof planning commission and chairman of the housing authority. It shall\nhave the powers and duties now or hereafter conferred by article\nfifteen-A of this chapter upon municipal renewal agencies. It shall be\norganized in the manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions\nof article fifteen-A of this chapter and the agency, its members,\nofficers and employees and its operations and activities shall in all\nrespects be governed by the provisions of such article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>