<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-669"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-669"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="669"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-669/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-669/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-669/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-669/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_669">
        <num>669</num>
        <heading>Village of Rockville Centre community development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 669. Village of Rockville Centre community development agency.  A\ncommunity development agency, to be known as the Rockville Centre\ncommunity development agency, is hereby established for the\naccomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in articles\nfifteen and fifteen-A of the general municipal law, and in accordance\nwith article eighteen of the constitution of the state of New York. It\nshall constitute a body corporate and politic and be perpetual in\nduration. It shall consist of five members including the village mayor,\nwho shall be its chairman, and the four village trustees. It shall have\nthe powers and duties now or hereafter conferred by article fifteen-A of\nthe general municipal law upon municipal renewal agencies. It shall be\norganized in the manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions\nof article fifteen-A of the general municipal law, and the agency, its\nmembers, officers and employees and its operations and activities shall\nin all respects be governed by the provisions of such article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>