<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-680-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-680-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="680-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-680-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-680-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-680-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-680-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_680_C">
        <num>680-C</num>
        <heading>Town of Riverhead community development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 680-c. Town of Riverhead community development agency. For the\nbenefit of the town of Riverhead and the inhabitants thereof, a\ncommunity development agency, to be known as the TOWN OF RIVERHEAD\nCOMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is hereby established for the\naccomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in articles\nfifteen and fifteen-A of this chapter. It shall constitute a body\ncorporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration. It shall have the\npowers and duties now or hereafter conferred by articles fifteen and\nfifteen-A of this chapter upon community development agencies and\nprovided that the exercise of the powers by such agency with respect to\nthe acquisition of real property whether by purchase, condemnation or\notherwise, shall be limited to the corporate limits of the town of\nRiverhead, and such agency shall take into consideration the local\nzoning and planning regulations as well as the regional and local\ncomprehensive land use plans. It shall be organized in a manner\nprescribed by and be subject to the provisions of articles fifteen and\nfifteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall consist of the supervisor\nof the town of Riverhead, who shall be its chair and the four council\nmembers of the town of Riverhead. The agency, its members, officers and\nemployees and its operations and activities shall in all respects be\ngoverned by the provisions of articles fifteen and fifteen-A of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>