<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-692"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-692"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="692"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-692/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-692/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-692/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-692/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_692">
        <num>692</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 692. Definitions. As used in this article the following terms shall\nmean:\n  1. "Governing body". The local legislative body.\n  2. "Municipality". A city having a population of one hundred thousand\nor more and the town of Huntington.\n  3. " Eligible area". Real property, title to which is held by a\nmunicipality. Provided, however, that in a city of one million or more,\nproperty that the city conveys by deed made pursuant to a judgment of\nforeclosure in an in rem tax lien foreclosure proceeding, or property\nwhose conveyance is caused by, or the result of, the city's foreclosure\nof a tax lien thereon, including property to which title has not vested\nin the city, which is then acquired by a third party, shall also be\ndeemed an eligible area under this article. Provided further, however,\nthat in a city of one million or more, property that has been acquired\nby the federal government as the result of the foreclosure of a mortgage\nloan insured or held by the federal government shall also be deemed an\neligible area under this article. Provided further, however, that real\nproperty consisting of two contiguous acres or more of wooded land which\nexists as substantially undeveloped at the time this article becomes\neffective shall not be included as an eligible area for purposes of this\narticle.\n  4. "Agency". The officer, board, commission, department, or other\nagency of the municipality designated by the governing body, or as\notherwise provided by law, to carry out the functions vested in the\nagency under this article or delegated to the agency by the governing\nbody in order to carry out the purpose and provisions of this article,\nexcept that in a city having a population of one million or more, the\nterm "agency" shall mean a department of housing preservation and\ndevelopment.\n  5. "Urban development action area". An area designated by the\ngoverning body, or by the commission where so authorized to act by the\ngoverning body, pursuant to section six hundred ninety-three of this\narticle as appropriate for urban development, at least sixty percent of\nwhich constitutes an eligible area.\n  6. "Urban development action area project". A project which shall be\nconsistent with the policy and purposes stated in section six hundred\nninety-one of this article, and located in an urban development action\narea, unless the area designation requirement is waived pursuant to\nsection six hundred ninety-three of this article. The project summary\nfor an urban development action area project shall include but shall not\nbe limited to: a statement of proposed land uses; proposed public,\nsemi-public, private or community facilities or utilities; a statement\nas to proposed new codes and ordinances and amendments to existing codes\nand ordinances as are required or necessary to effectuate the project; a\nproposed time schedule for the effectuation of such project, and such\nadditional statements or documentation as the agency may deem\nappropriate.\n  7. "Commission". The local commission or board charged with the\nplanning of land use within the municipality or other analogous body or,\nif there be none, the board of estimate or other governing body of the\nmunicipality.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>