<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-696-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-696-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="696-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-696-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-696-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-696-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-696-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_696_D">
        <num>696-D</num>
        <heading>Neighborhood improvement projects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_696_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in an urban\ndevelopment action area; (ii) in proximity to an urban development\naction area; or (iii) in proximity to an urban development action area\nproject for which the area designation requirement was waived pursuant\nto section six hundred ninety-three of this article.\n  3. Any loan made in accordance with this section shall be secured by a\nnote and mortgage upon the property improved. Such note and mortgage\nshall specify the term and manner of repayment of such loan, and may\nauthorize the owner, with the consent of such agency, to prepay the\nprincipal of the loan subject to such terms and conditions as therein\nprovided. Such note and mortgage may contain such other terms and\nconditions not inconsistent with the provisions of this article as such\nagency may deem necessary or desirable to carrying out the purposes and\nprovisions of this article, including, but not limited to: provisions\nconcerning the repayment of the loan, the interest, if any, thereon, and\nother charges in connection therewith.\n  4. After June thirtieth, two thousand twelve, authorization to make or\ncontract to make loans or to participate in the making of loans pursuant\nto the provisions of this section and subdivision forty-one-d of\nparagraph a of section 11.00 of the local finance law shall be\nrestricted to loans made only within targeted commercial corridors\ndesignated by the agency prior to June thirtieth, two thousand ten.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>