<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-697"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-697"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="697"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-697/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-697/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-697/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-697/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_697">
        <num>697</num>
        <heading>Application of article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 697. Application of article. The provisions of this article shall be\napplicable in any municipality wherein the local legislative body has\nadopted a resolution providing therefor, provided however, that at any\ntime subsequent to the adoption of such a resolution the local\nlegislative body may adopt a further resolution providing that the\nprovisions of this article will no longer be applicable in the\nmunicipality and thereafter this article shall cease to be of force or\neffect therein. Upon adoption of a resolution providing for the\napplication of this article in any municipality by the local legislative\nbody, a copy of such resolution shall be filed within thirty days with\nthe commissioner of the state division of housing and community renewal.\nThe commissioner shall prescribe rules and regulations requiring\nsubsequently timely notice of all area designations and approved\nprojects therein. Rules and regulations prescribed by the commissioner\nshall be limited exclusively to procedures, content and format for\ntimely notification. The commissioner shall thereupon report to the\nlegislature annually, commencing on January one, nineteen hundred eighty\nconcerning all municipal applications of the provisions of this article.\nFor purposes of this section the term "local legislative body" in any\ncity having a population of one million or more means a city council of\nany such city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>