<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-699-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-699-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="699-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-699-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-699-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-699-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-699-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_699_A">
        <num>699-A</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 699-a. Definitions. As used in this article:\n  1. "Affordable workforce housing" means housing for individuals and\nfamilies at or below one hundred thirty percent of the median income for\nthe Nassau-Suffolk primary metropolitan statistical area as defined by\nthe federal Department of Housing and Urban Development. For the\npurposes of this article, the affordable workforce housing units shall\nbe of consistent design to those of the rest of the development.\n  2. "Density bonus" means a density increase of at least ten percent\nover the otherwise maximum allowable residential density or floor area\nratio if part of a mixed-use development under the applicable zoning\nordinance and comprehensive plan as of the date of the application by\nthe applicant to the local government. All density calculations\nresulting in fractional units shall be rounded up to the nearest whole\nnumber. The granting of a density bonus shall not require, in and of\nitself, a comprehensive plan amendment, zoning change or other\ndiscretionary local approval. The density bonus shall not be included as\npart of the calculation which determines the number of affordable units\nthat constitute ten percent of the total.\n  3. "Local government", for the purposes of this article, means any\nvillage, city or town within the county of Nassau or Suffolk acting\npursuant to the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>