<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-714"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-714"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="714"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_714">
        <num>714</num>
        <heading>Annexation after election approving proposition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 714. Annexation after election approving proposition.  1. Upon the\nfiling of the certificate or certificates of election approving the\nproposition together with the notice of entry of a final judgment of a\ncourt or of the approving orders of the governing boards of the affected\nlocal governments, the governing board or boards of the local government\nor governments to which such territory is to be annexed shall forthwith\nby local law, and without any hearing thereon, annex to such local\ngovernment the territory described in the petition. In the case of a\nmunicipality consisting of wards, councilmanic districts or other\nsubdivisions from which representation on any elective board or body is\nselected, such local law shall designate the wards, councilmanic\ndistricts or other such subdivisions within which the territory so\nannexed shall be included, which local law shall be adopted without\nreferendum notwithstanding any inconsistent general, special or local\nlaw.\n  2. A local law annexing territory to a local government pursuant to\nthis section shall specify the date on which such annexation shall\nbecome effective, giving due regard to the taxable status dates of all\nthe local governments to which and from which such territory is so\nannexed and to the fiscal years of such local governments for which\ntaxes, special ad valorem levies or special assessments are imposed.\nSuch date shall be no earlier than the date of filing such local law in\nthe office of the secretary of state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>