<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-716"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-716"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="716"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-716/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-716/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-716/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-716/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_716">
        <num>716</num>
        <heading>Restrictions and prohibitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 716. Restrictions and prohibitions.  Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of this article or of any other law:\n  1. An annexation shall not affect the boundaries of any congressional\ndistrict, senate district or assembly district.\n  2. The date on which any such annexation shall take effect shall be\nsuch that it will not deprive a qualified elector of his right to vote\nat the general election to be held on the first Tuesday next succeeding\nthe first Monday in November of the year in which the annexation is to\nbecome effective.\n  3. A county shall not annex territory situated in another county\nunless the territory so annexed shall on the same date be annexed to\neither a city situated in whole or in part, or to a town situated in the\ncounty to which the territory is annexed.\n  4. A city shall not annex territory situated in a county other than a\ncounty in which such city is situated unless the territory so annexed\nshall on the same date be annexed to the county, or one of the counties,\nin which such city is situated.\n  5. A town shall not annex territory situated in a county other than\nthe county in which such town is situated unless the territory so\nannexed shall on the same date be annexed to the county in which such\ntown is situated.\n  6. A village shall not annex territory of a city unless the territory\nso annexed shall on the same date be annexed to the town, or to one or\nmore of the towns, in which the village is situated.\n  7. A village may annex territory of another village, but such\nannexation shall not result in any change of the boundaries of any\ncounty or town.  This provision shall not be deemed to prevent any such\nannexation simultaneously with an annexation of the same territory by a\ncounty and the town or towns in which the village to which such\nterritory is to be annexed is situated in whole or in part or, when the\nterritory so annexed is situated in the same county as such village,\nwith an annexation of the same territory by the town or towns in which\nsuch village is situated in whole or in part.\n  8. A town may annex territory of a city, but such annexation shall not\nresult in any change of the boundaries of a village. This provision\nshall not be deemed to prevent any such annexation by a town\nsimultaneously with an annexation of the same territory by a county and\nby a village or villages situated in whole or in part in such town or\nwith an annexation by a village or villages situated in whole or in part\nin such town.\n  9. A town may annex territory of another town, but such annexation\nshall not result in any change in the boundaries of a village. This\nprovision shall not be deemed to prevent any such annexation by a town\nsimultaneously with an annexation of the same territory by a village or\nvillages situated in whole or in part in either or both of such towns.\n  10. An annexation by a county shall not increase the area of any\ncounty improvement district in such county. If a county annexes\nterritory in another county and such territory includes in whole or in\npart the area of a county improvement district situated in the other\ncounty, the area of the county improvement district located in the\nterritory annexed shall cease to be a part of such district when such\nannexation becomes effective.\n  11. If a city annexes territory of a town and such territory includes\nin whole or in part the area of any fire district, fire protection\ndistrict or fire alarm district or of any town special district or of\nany town improvement district, the area of any such district located in\nthe territory annexed shall cease to be a part of such district when\nsuch annexation becomes effective.\n  12. If a village annexes territory of the town in which it is situated\nor of another village located in such town or in another town, any such\nannexation shall not affect the boundaries of any town special or\nimprovement district in such town or the boundaries of any fire\ndistrict, fire protection district or fire alarm district.\n  13. If a town annexes territory of another town, such annexation shall\nnot affect the boundaries of any fire district, fire protection district\nor fire alarm district, but the territory so annexed shall cease to be a\npart of any town special or improvement district in such other town when\nthe annexation becomes effective.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>