<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-718"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-718"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="718"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-718/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-718/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-718/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-718/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_718">
        <num>718</num>
        <heading>Construction</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 718. Construction. 1. References in other laws, etc. With respect to\nannexation proceedings commenced on or after January first, nineteen\nhundred sixty-four, reference in any general, special or local law,\ncounty, city or village charter, ordinance, resolution, rule, regulation\nor document to any provision of the general city law, village law, town\nlaw, county law, or other law repealed by this chapter, in force at the\ntime this chapter shall take effect, shall be deemed and construed to\nrefer to the corresponding provision of this article to the extent\nconsistent with the provisions of this article.\n  2. Pending actions and proceedings.  No action or proceeding pending\nat the time when this chapter shall take effect shall be affected by any\nprovision of this chapter, but the same may be prosecuted, defended or\nenforced as if this chapter had not been enacted.\n  3. Existing rights and remedies preserved.  No existing right or\nremedy of any character shall be lost, impaired or affected by reason of\nthis article, nor shall the validity of any action taken by any public\nofficial under the law in force immediately prior to the time this\narticle shall take effect be affected by the enactment of this article.\n  4. Severability.  If any clause, sentence, paragraph, section or part\nof this article shall be adjudged by any court of competent jurisdiction\nto be invalid, such judgment shall not affect, impair or invalidate the\nremainder thereof, but shall be confined in its operation to the clause,\nsentence, paragraph, section or part thereof directly involved in the\ncontroversy in which such judgment shall have been rendered.\n  5. Article controlling.  The provisions of this article shall be\ncontrolling notwithstanding any inconsistent act of the legislature to\nthe contrary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>