<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_E">
        <num>72-E</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of lands for park and parkway purposes and dedication of the same by the counties of Broome, Monroe and Erie</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 72-e. Acquisition of lands for park and parkway purposes and\ndedication of the same by the counties of Broome, Monroe and Erie. The\nboard of supervisors of the county of Broome, Monroe or Erie may acquire\nby purchase, gift, devise or acquisition pursuant to the provisions of\nthe eminent domain procedure law, real estate or any interest therein\nnecessary for or incidental to the construction of a state park,\nparkway, or boulevard or incidental to the separation of grades at the\nintersection of the state parkway or boulevard and a county, town or\nvillage road, highway or street, and may donate or dedicate the same to\nthe state or may release to the state for such purpose existing rights\nof way or easements not required for county purposes. The board of\nsupervisors of said county of Broome, Monroe or Erie may cause such\nmoneys as may be required to pay for real estate or interest therein so\nacquired to be raised, in whole or in part, by taxation and levied and\ncollected as other taxes in such county or such moneys may be raised, in\nwhole or in part, pursuant to the local finance law. In the event\ninvoluntary proceedings are had to acquire lands for the above purposes,\nthen, and in that case, upon the  vesting of the title to the lands\ndescribed in the petition  as provided in the eminent domain procedure\nlaw said lands may be conveyed by warranty deed for a nominal\nconsideration by said county to the people of the state of New York, if\nand when it becomes necessary to make such conveyance to effect the\npurposes of this act.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>