<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_F">
        <num>72-F</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of lands for parkway and airport purposes and dedication of the same by counties and municipal corporations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 72-f. Acquisition of lands for parkway and airport purposes and\ndedication of the same by counties and municipal corporations.  1.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of any general or special act or the\nprovisions of this article, the governing board of any municipal\ncorporation or the board of supervisors of any county may acquire by\npurchase, gift, devise or condemnation real estate or any interest\ntherein for conservation purposes or for a state park, parkway or\nboulevard or incidental to the separation of grades at the intersection\nof a state parkway or boulevard and a county, town or village road,\nhighway or street, and may donate or dedicate the same to the state or\nmay release and convey to the state for such purpose presently owned\nlands, existing rights of way or easements, wheresoever located, not\nrequired for county, city, town or village purposes. Such municipal\ncorporations or boards of supervisors may also purchase options to carry\nout the purposes of this section in aid of the state park and parkway\nsystem. Such municipal corporations or boards of supervisors may acquire\nsuch real estate or interest therein by purchase, gift, devise, or by\ncondemnation in the manner provided by law. Several of the\nmunicipalities herein mentioned may contribute toward the cost of\nacquisition of a state park wholly or partly within their boundaries or\nadjacent or near to them on the basis of probable benefit to such\nmunicipalities. In the event that a state park is acquired by agreement\ninvolving contributions by several municipalities, the purchase price\nmay be met by one or more payments over a period of not to exceed two\nyears in accordance with the terms of the agreement.\n  2. The board of supervisors of any county is hereby authorized to\nagree with owners respecting the extent and use of easements for slope\nprotection acquired prior to March first, nineteen hundred thirty-one,\nand to grant to owners of lands abutting upon lands heretofore acquired\nby such board for such purpose pursuant to authority conferred by this\nsection rights of way over and access to lands so acquired upon such\nterms and for such considerations, as to such board may seem reasonable\nand proper.\n  3. If the acquisition be by a county, the governing board thereof may\ncause such moneys to be raised, in whole or in part, by taxation and\nlevied and collected as other taxes in such county or such moneys may be\nraised, in whole or in part, pursuant to the local finance law; if the\nacquisition be by a town, the moneys necessary therefor shall constitute\na town charge and be raised, in whole or in part, by taxation as other\ntown charges or such moneys may be raised, in whole or in part, pursuant\nto the local finance law; if the acquisition be by a village, the moneys\ntherefor may be raised, in whole or in part, by taxation, as other\nvillage taxes or such moneys may be raised, in whole or in part,\npursuant to the local finance law.\n  * 4. The governing board of any municipal corporation in the county of\nSuffolk or the board of supervisors of said county of Suffolk may\nacquire by purchase, gift, devise or condemnation, real estate or any\ninterest therein necessary for or incidental to the establishment,\nconstruction, equipment, maintenance and operation of an airport or\nlanding field and may enter into a contract or agreement with any other\ngovernmental authority, both federal and state, in relation to the\nestablishment, construction, equipment, maintenance and operation of an\nairport or landing field. Such municipal corporations or the board of\nsupervisors may acquire such real estate or interest therein in the\nmanner provided by chapter one hundred ninety of the laws of nineteen\nhundred twenty-seven as amended, and all provisions of such act shall,\nas far as practicable, apply to the acquisition of real estate or\ninterest therein in the same manner and with the same effect as though\nthe lands herein authorized to be acquired were mentioned in such act.\n  If the acquisition be by the county of Suffolk, the board of\nsupervisors may cause such moneys to be raised by taxation and levy and\ncollected as other taxes in such county or may borrow money therefor on\nthe credit of such county by the issuance and sale of county bonds in\nthe manner provided by law for the issuance and sale of other county\nobligations.  If the acquisition be by a town, the moneys necessary\ntherefor shall constitute a town charge and be raised by taxes as other\ntown charges or the town board may in its discretion cause town bonds to\nbe issued and sold in the manner provided by law for the issuance and\nsale of town bonds under the town law. If the acquisition be by a\nvillage, the moneys therefor may be raised by taxes as other village\ntaxes or by the issuance and sale of village bonds in the manner\nprovided by the laws governing such village relating to village\nobligations after the adoption of a resolution therefor by the board of\ntrustees, without other authorization.\n  * NB Expired July 1, 1946\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>