<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_G">
        <num>72-G</num>
        <heading>Expenses of volunteer firefighters attending training schools and instruction courses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 72-g. Expenses of volunteer firefighters attending training schools\nand instruction courses. 1. The chief officer of the fire department of\na municipal corporation or fire district, subject to any rules or\nregulations governing such department, may authorize the volunteer\nmembers of the department to attend training schools or courses of\ninstruction for firefighters.\n  a. If any such school is located, or any such course is given, outside\nthe county or outside one of the counties in which the municipal\ncorporation or fire district is located, such authorization shall be\nsubject to the prior approval of the governing board of the municipal\ncorporation or fire district.\n  b. If any such school is located, or any such course is given, outside\nthe state, in addition to the approval required in paragraph a of this\nsubdivision, such authorization shall be subject to a finding from the\ngoverning board that such training course or school of instruction is\nnecessary and in the public interest and is not available within a\nreasonable distance and time period in the state.\n  c. Notification and proof of attendance of any out-of-state training\nschool from the chief officer shall be provided to the state office of\nfire prevention and control.\n  2. The governing board by resolution may provide for the payment, in\nthe same manner as other claims against the municipal corporation or\nfire district are audited, allowed and paid, of all actual and necessary\nregistration fees not in excess of fifty dollars and all actual and\nnecessary expenses of travel, meals and lodging and all necessary\ntuition fees incurred by such volunteer members in attending such a\ntraining school, or course of instruction, in this country or in Canada.\n  3. If such travel is by car owned by the volunteer firefighter, he or\nshe may be paid a reasonable mileage allowance for each mile actually\nand necessarily traveled by him or her in attending such school or\ncourse of instruction. Such mileage allowance shall not exceed the\nstandard travel allowance for mileage adopted or prescribed for federal\nincome tax purposes. Any claim for such expenses or reimbursement shall\nhave endorsed thereon, or attached thereto, a statement by the chief\nofficer of the fire department that the attendance had been duly\nauthorized by him or her. The provisions of this section shall not be\ndeemed to have amended the provisions of subdivision one of section two\nhundred nine of this chapter in relation to participation in fire\ntraining programs which are not conducted as training schools or regular\nor special courses of instruction for firefighters.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>