<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_H">
        <num>72-H</num>
        <heading>Sale, lease and transfer to municipal corporations of certain public lands</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_72_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of any general, special\nor local law or of any charter, the supervisors of a county, the town\nboard of a town, the board of trustees of a village, the board of fire\ncommissioners of a fire district, the board of estimate of a city, or if\nthere be none the local legislative body of such city, and, in a city\nhaving a population of one million or more, the mayor, subject to\ndisapproval by the council within thirty days following receipt of\nnotice of the approval of the mayor, may sell, transfer or lease to or\nexchange with any municipal corporation or municipal corporations,\nschool district, board of cooperative educational services, fire\ndistrict, the state of New York, or the government of the United States\nand any agency or department thereof, either without consideration or\nfor such consideration and upon such terms and conditions as shall be\napproved by such officer or body, any real property owned by such\ncounty, town, village, fire district or city; and any municipal\ncorporation or fire district may acquire or lease such real property as\nprovided in this section. The term of any lease entered into pursuant to\nthe provisions of this section shall not exceed ten years but nothing\nherein contained shall prevent the renewal of any such lease.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_72_H__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of this section shall not apply to any real\nproperty which is made inalienable under the provisions of any general,\nspecial or local law or of any charter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>