<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_I">
        <num>72-I</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of lands and erection of memorial buildings by adjoining villages</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 72-i. Acquisition of lands and erection of memorial buildings by\nadjoining villages. The governing boards of two or more villages, of\nwhich at least one boundary of any one adjoins that of any other, may,\nupon the adoption of a proposition therefor by a majority vote of the\nelectors of each such village, as herein provided, jointly acquire lands\nand erect a memorial building, or lands with buildings thereon and\nremodel such buildings as a memorial building or remove such building\nand erect a memorial building, in commemoration of the services of the\nmembers of the armed forces of the United States in any of the wars of\nthe United States.  Unless otherwise provided in the proposition voted\nupon or unless otherwise agreed upon by the governing boards of each\nparticipating village, the share of each such village in the cost\nthereof shall be in the same proportion as the ratio of its population\nto the other participating village or villages. Money to be borrowed for\npayment of the cost thereof shall be borrowed pursuant to the provisions\nof the local finance law and each village shall be subject to the\nlimitations therein contained.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>