<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-M*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-M*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-M*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-M*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-M*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-M*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-72-M*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_M*2">
        <num>72-M*2</num>
        <heading>Emergency transportation plans</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 72-m. Emergency transportation plans. Within sixty days after this\nsection becomes law any transportation authority and any city, county or\nmunicipality operating a public transportation system and any county\nwithin the geographical territory of any transportation authority shall\nprepare and publicize a plan for transportation to be followed in the\nevent mass transportation services are discontinued due to a labor\ndispute, fire, accident, flood, storm or any other emergency, provided,\nhowever, that in the case of the five counties comprising the city of\nNew York such plan shall be filed by the city of New York. Such plan\nshall designate the persons responsible for its implementation and shall\nprovide for designation of emergency routes for vehicular traffic,\nmaximum utilization of existing and emergency parking and alternative\nmass transportation facilities and such other matters as such\ntransportation authority, city, county or municipality shall determine\nappropriate.\n  A plan and any amendment thereto, prepared pursuant to the provisions\nof this section shall be filed with the department of transportation at\nits Albany office. The department shall examine the plan and determine\nits feasibility. The plan shall be made available to any and all\npersons, corporations, departments and agencies necessary to enable\ntimely publication and implementation in the event of any such\nemergency.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 72-m's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>