<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-74-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-74-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="74-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-74-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-74-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-74-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-74-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_74_C">
        <num>74-C</num>
        <heading>Taking of billboards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 74-c. Taking of billboards. 1. If any local law, ordinance or\nresolution adopted by a municipal corporation in the exercise of its\npolice power shall require the removal of any legally erected and\nmaintained billboard or like outdoor advertising device, which is leased\nor rented for profit in areas zoned industrial or manufacturing, just\ncompensation for said taking shall be determined in accordance with the\nprovisions of article five of the eminent domain procedure law;\nprovided, however, section five hundred two of such law shall not be\napplicable in any such proceeding.\n  2. Unless compensation therefor is provided pursuant to section\neighty-eight of the highway law, if any local law, ordinance or\nresolution adopted by a municipal corporation in the exercise of its\npolice power shall require the removal of any legally erected and\nmaintained billboard or like outdoor advertising device, which is leased\nor rented for profit, and which is located in an area or zone, other\nthan an industrial or manufacturing zone, the display shall be allowed\nto remain in existence for the period of time set forth below after\ngiving notice of the removal requirement:\n          fair market value on date of            minimum years\n          notice of removal requirement              allowed\n                  under     $1,999                      3\n                  $2,000 to $3,999                      4\n                  $4,000 to $5,999                      6\n                  $6,000 to $7,999                      7\n                  $8,000 to $9,999                      9\n                  $10,000 and over                     10\n  If the removal is required sooner than the amortization periods\nspecified herein, such removal by any local law, ordinance or resolution\nadopted by the municipal corporation shall be with just compensation\nbeing paid for such taking and removal determined in accordance with the\nprovisions of article five of the eminent domain procedure law or in\naccordance with any table of values established by the state department\nof transportation; provided however section five hundred two of the\neminent domain procedure law shall not be applicable to any such\nproceeding.\n  Notwithstanding any other law, rule or regulation, all amortization\nperiods under such laws, ordinances or resolutions shall commence not\nearlier than January first, nineteen hundred ninety.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any city having a\npopulation of one million or more.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>