<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-759"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-759"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="759"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-759/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-759/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-759/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-759/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_759">
        <num>759</num>
        <heading>Canvassing of vote; moratorium on further referendum</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 759. Canvassing of vote; moratorium on further referendum. 1. In any\nreferendum held pursuant to this title, the ballots cast shall be\ncounted, returns made and canvassed and results certified in the same\nmanner as other municipal elections or referendums for the local\ngovernment entities to be consolidated.\n  2. Consolidation shall not take effect unless a majority of the\nelectors voting in each local government entity to be consolidated vote\nin favor of consolidation. If in any one of the entities such a majority\nvote does not result, the referendum shall fail and consolidation shall\nnot take effect.\n  3. If consolidation is approved by a majority of the electors voting\nin each local government entity to be consolidated, certificates of such\nresult shall be immediately filed with the secretary of state and with\nthe clerks of the entities and county in which any part of the entities\nis situated.\n  4. If the referendum shall fail, the consolidation process specified\nby this title shall not be initiated for the same purpose within four\nyears of the date of such referendum. This subdivision, however, does\nnot apply to a permissive referendum conducted pursuant to section seven\nhundred sixty-three of this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>