<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-765"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-765"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="765"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-765/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-765/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-765/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-765/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_765">
        <num>765</num>
        <heading>General effect of consolidation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 765. General effect of consolidation. 1. On and after the effective\ndate of a consolidation, the consolidating local government entities\nshall be treated and considered for all purposes as one local government\nentity, under the name and on the terms and conditions set forth in the\njoint consolidation agreement or the elector initiated consolidation\nplan, as the case may be.\n  2. All rights, privileges and franchises of each component local\ngovernment entity and all assets, real and personal property, books,\nrecords, papers, seals and equipment, as well as other things in action,\nbelonging to each component local government entity shall be deemed as\ntransferred to and vested in the consolidated local government entity\nwithout further act or deed.\n  3. All property, rights-of-way and other interests shall be as\neffectually the property of the consolidated local government entity as\nthey were of the component local government entities prior to their\nconsolidation. The title to real estate, either by deed or otherwise,\nunder the laws of the state of New York vested in any of the component\nlocal government entities shall not be deemed to revert or be in any way\nimpaired by reason of the consolidation.\n  4. The consolidated local government entity shall in all respects be\nsubject to all the obligations and liabilities imposed and shall possess\nall the rights, powers, and privileges vested by law in other similar\nentities.\n  5. Upon the effective date of the consolidation, the joint\nconsolidation agreement or the elector initiated consolidation plan, as\nthe case may be, shall be subordinate in all respects to the contract\nrights of all holders of any securities or obligations of the local\ngovernment entities outstanding at the effective date of the\nconsolidation.\n  6. If a joint consolidation agreement or elector initiated\nconsolidation plan provides for the dissolution of a local justice\ncourt, all court records of such court shall be deposited with a justice\ncourt judge to be designated by the administrative judge of the judicial\ndistrict within which the dissolving justice court is located. The\ndesignated justice court judge shall have authority to execute and\ncomplete all unfinished business.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>