<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-766"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-766"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="766"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-766/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-766/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-766/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-766/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_766">
        <num>766</num>
        <heading>Election and appointment of officials</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 766. Election and appointment of officials. New officials of the\nconsolidated local government entity required to be elected shall take\noffice on the first Monday of January following the election designated\nin the joint consolidation agreement or elector initiated consolidation\nplan, as the case may be. At such election, the necessary officials of\nthe consolidated local government entity shall be elected in accordance\nwith the terms of the general law affecting entities of the kind or\nclass of the consolidated local government entity. Except as otherwise\nspecified in the joint consolidation agreement or elector initiated\nconsolidation plan, all appointive officials of the consolidated local\ngovernment entity thereafter shall be appointed by the individual or\nentity upon whom the power to appoint such officials is conferred by the\nterms of the general law affecting entities of the kind or class of the\nconsolidated local government entity. Successors in office for such\nelected or appointed positions shall thereafter be elected or appointed\nat the time, in the manner and for the terms provided by the general law\naffecting entities of the kind or class of the consolidated local\ngovernment entity.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>