<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-77-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-77-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="77-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-77-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-77-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-77-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-77-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_77_A">
        <num>77-A</num>
        <heading>Construction and maintenance of memorial building or monument by county or city</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 77-a. Construction and maintenance of memorial building or monument\nby county or city. A county, or a city by resolution adopted by the\ngoverning board of such municipality by a two-thirds vote of its\nmembers, may construct and maintain a memorial building, park or a\nmonument at a place within the municipality or upon any public park\nthereof, in commemoration of soldiers and sailors of the United States\nin any war or wars in which the United States shall have engaged, at an\nexpense to be borne by the city or county at large. Such resolution\nshall create a committee, to be at all times composed of members of such\ngoverning boards, to have charge of such construction and of such\nmaintenance, direct expenditures therefor and let a contract or\ncontracts for such construction. Upon the adoption of such resolution,\nthe governing board or other proper authorities of such municipality\nshall appropriate, raise by tax in the city or county, as the case may\nbe, and make available from time to time to the order of such committee,\nthe amount chargeable to the city or county for such construction and\nmaintenance. In a city having a board of estimate and apportionment, the\nconcurrence of such board, with any action by the governing board, shall\nbe necessary to any action by the city under this section. A county and\na city wholly contained therein may unite in the construction and\nmaintenance of such a memorial by such resolution being so adopted by\nthe governing board of each municipality, at an expense to be borne by\nthe city and county at large, or by the city and taxable property of the\ncounty outside of the city, in such manner and in such proportions as\nthe resolution shall prescribe. Such resolution shall create a committee\nto be at all times composed of members of each of such governing boards,\nto have charge of construction and of such maintenance, direct\nexpenditures therefor and let a contract or contracts for such\nconstruction. Upon adoption of such resolutions the governing board or\nother proper authorities of such municipality shall appropriate, raise\nby tax in the city or county, as the case may be, and make available\nfrom time to time to the order of such committee, the amount chargeable\nto the city or county for such construction and maintenance.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>