<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-781"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-781"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="781"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-781/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-781/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-781/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-781/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_781">
        <num>781</num>
        <heading>Canvassing of vote; moratorium on further referendum</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 781. Canvassing of vote; moratorium on further referendum. 1. In any\nreferendum held pursuant to this title, the ballots cast shall be\ncounted, returns made and canvassed and results certified in the same\nmanner as other municipal elections or referendums for the local\ngovernment entity affected by the proposed dissolution.\n  2. Dissolution shall not take effect unless a majority of the electors\nvoting in the local government entity in which the referendum is held\nvote in favor of dissolution. If such a majority vote does not result,\nthe referendum shall fail and dissolution shall not take effect.\n  3. If dissolution is approved by a majority of the electors voting in\nthe local government entity in which the referendum is held,\ncertificates of such result immediately shall be filed with the\nsecretary of state and with the clerks of the local government entity or\nentities and county in which is situated any part of the entity to be\ndissolved.\n  4. If the referendum shall fail, the dissolution process specified by\nthis title shall not be initiated for the local government entity within\nfour years of the date of such referendum. This subdivision, however,\ndoes not apply to a permissive referendum conducted pursuant to section\nseven hundred eighty-five of this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>