<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-802"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-802"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="802"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-802/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-802/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_802">
        <num>802</num>
        <heading>Exceptions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_802__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section two of the rural\nelectric cooperative law;\n  g. The sale of bonds and notes pursuant to section 60.10 of the local\nfinance law;\n  h. A contract in which a municipal officer or employee has an interest\nif such contract was entered into prior to the time he was elected or\nappointed as such officer or employee, but this paragraph shall in no\nevent authorize a renewal of any such contract;\n  i. Employment of a duly licensed physician as school physician for a\nschool district upon authorization by a two-thirds vote of the board of\neducation of such school district, notwithstanding the fact that such\nphysician shall have an interest, as defined in section eight hundred\none of this chapter, in such employment.\n  j. Purchases or public work by a municipality, other than a county,\nlocated wholly or partly within a county with a population of two\nhundred thousand or less pursuant to a contract in which a member of the\ngoverning body or board has a prohibited interest, where:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_802__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the member of the governing body or board is elected and serves\nwithout salary;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_802__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the purchases, in the aggregate, are less than five thousand\ndollars in one fiscal year and the governing body or board has followed\nits procurement policies and procedures adopted in accordance with the\nprovisions of section one hundred four-b of this chapter and the\nprocurement process indicates that the contract is with the lowest\ndollar offer;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_802__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the contract for the purchases or public work is approved by\nresolution of the body or board by the affirmative vote of each member\nof the body or board except the interested member who shall abstain.\n  2. a. A contract with a corporation in which a municipal officer or\nemployee has an interest by reason of stockholdings when less than five\nper centum of the outstanding stock of the corporation is owned or\ncontrolled directly or indirectly by such officer or employee;\n  b. A contract for the furnishing of public utility services when the\nrates or charges therefor are fixed or regulated by the public service\ncommission;\n  c. A contract for the payment of a reasonable rental of a room or\nrooms owned or leased by an officer or employee when the same are used\nin the performance of his official duties and are so designated as an\noffice or chamber;\n  d. A contract for the payment of a portion of the compensation of a\nprivate employee of an officer when such employee performs p...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>