<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-804-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-804-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="804-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-804-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_804_A">
        <num>804-A</num>
        <heading>Certain interests prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 804-a. Certain interests prohibited. No member of the governing\nboard, of a municipality shall have any interest in the development or\noperation of any real property located within Nassau County and\ndeveloped or operated by any membership corporation originally formed\nfor purposes among which are the following:\n  1. to plan for, advise, recommend, promote and in all ways encourage,\nalone or in concert with public officials and bodies and interested\nlocal associations, the development and establishment of any lands in\nNassau County publically owned with particular emphasis on industrial,\nbusiness, commercial, residential and public uses, the augmention of\npublic revenues and furtherance of the public interest of the citizens\nof Nassau County;\n  2. to conduct studies to ascertain the needs of Nassau County as\npertains to such publically owned lands and supporting facilities and in\nNassau County generally for the purpose of aiding the County of Nassau\nin attracting new business, commerce and industry to it and in\nencouraging the development and retention of business, commerce and\nindustry;\n  3. to relieve and reduce unemployment, promote and provide for\nadditional and maximum employment, better and maintain job opportunities\nand instruct or train individuals to improve or develop their\ncapabilities for such jobs;\n  4. to implement and engage itself in plans of development of such\npublically owned lands and other areas in connection with private\ncompanies and citizens and with public bodies and officials, and to\nparticipate in such operations, leaseholds, loans, ownerships with\nrespect to land, buildings or public facilities or interest therein as\nmay be lawful and desirable to effectuate its corporate purposes and the\nbest interests of the people of Nassau County.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>