<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-81"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-81"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="81"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-81/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-81/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_81">
        <num>81</num>
        <heading>Peddling and hawking farm produce</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 81. Peddling and hawking farm produce. The governing board of a\nmunicipal corporation shall not by ordinance or otherwise regulate or\nprohibit the pursuit or exercise of hawking and peddling farm produce\nexcept hay and straw within the limits of any such municipal\ncorporation, if such farm produce is hawked or peddled by the producer\nthereof, or his servants or employees; nor shall the governing board of\nany such municipal corporation pass an ordinance requiring such producer\nof farm produce to secure a license for peddling and hawking such farm\nproduce within the limits of such municipal corporation.  Nothing\ncontained herein shall affect any pending action or proceeding to\nrecover penalties imposed for violations of existing ordinances and\nregulations. Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit wagons\nfrom which farm produce is sold to stand in front of stores or private\nresidences for a longer time than may be necessary for the sale and\ndelivery of produce purchased by the occupants of such stores or\nresidences; nor to permit the congregating of such wagons upon any\nstreet or thoroughfare not set apart by the municipality as a public\nmarket for the sale of farm produce. This section shall not apply to\nvillages, or to cities of the first class.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>