<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-812"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-812"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="812"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-812/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-812/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_812">
        <num>812</num>
        <heading>Financial disclosure for local elected officials and certain officers and employees of counties, cities, towns and villages</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any political subdivision or other county, city, town or\nvillage to which all of the provisions of this section are made\napplicable, whether as the result of the provisions contained in\nsubdivision two of section eight hundred eleven of this article or as a\nresult of an election to be subject to the provisions of this section as\npermitted by subdivision two of this section, shall require</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>each of\nits local elected officials and local officers and employees, (ii) each\nlocal political party official and (iii) each candidate for local\nelected official with respect to such political subdivision, to file an\nannual statement of financial disclosure containing the information and\nin the form set forth in subdivision five of this section except that\ndisclosure requirements for assessors who are not covered by this\narticle shall be governed by the requirements of section three hundred\nthirty-six of the real property tax law. Such statement shall be filed\non or before the fifteenth day of May with respect to the preceding\ncalendar year, except that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person who is subject to the reporting requirements of this\nsubdivision and who timely filed with the internal revenue service an\napplication for automatic extension of time in which to file his or her\nindividual income tax return for the immediately preceding calendar or\nfiscal year shall be required to file such financial disclosure\nstatement on or before May fifteenth but may, without being subjected to\nany civil penalty on account of a deficient statement, indicate with\nrespect to any item of the disclosure statement that information with\nrespect thereto is lacking but will be supplied in a supplementary\nstatement of financial disclosure, which shall be filed on or before the\nseventh day after the expiration of the period of such automatic\nextension of time within which to file such individual income tax\nreturn, provided that failure to file or to timely file such\nsupplementary statement of financial disclosure or the filing of an\nincomplete or deficient supplementary statement of financial disclosure\nshall be subject to the notice and penalty provisions of this section\nrespecting annual statements of financial disclosure as if such\nsupplementary statement were an annual statement;\n  (ii) candidates for local elected official who file designating\npetitions for nomination at a primary election shall file such statement\nwithin seven days after the last day allowed by law for the filing of\ndesignating petitions naming them as candidates for the next succeeding\nprimary election;\n  (iii) candidates for independent nomination for local elected official\nwho have not been designated by a party to receive a nomination shall\nfile such statement within seven days after the last day allowed by law\nfor the filing of independent nominating petitions naming them as\ncandidates for local elected official in the next succeeding general or\nspecial or village election; and\n  (iv) candidates for local elected official who receive the nomination\nof a p...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this subdivision, the terms "party", "committee" (when\nused in conjuction with the term "party"), "designation", "primary",\n"primary election", "nomination", "independent nomination", "ballot" and\n"uncontested office" shall have the same meanings as those contained in\nsection 1-104 of the election law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such statement shall be filed with the appropriate body, as\ndefined in section eight hundred ten of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The appropriate body, as defined in section eight hundred ten of\nthis article, shall obtain from the "board of elections", as such term\nis defined in section 1-104 of the election law, lists of all candidates\nfor local elected official, and from such lists, shall determine and\npublish lists of those candidates who have not, within ten days after\nthe required date for filing such statement, filed the statement\nrequired by this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Local political party officials and any person required to file\nsuch statement who commences employment after May fifteenth of any year\nshall file such statement within thirty days after commencing employment\nor of taking the position of local political party official, as the case\nmay be.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person who is subject to the filing requirements of both\nsubdivision two of section seventy-three-a of the public officers law\nand of this subdivision may satisfy the requirements of this subdivision\nby filing a copy of the statement filed pursuant to section\nseventy-three-a of the public officers law with the appropriate body, as\ndefined in section eight hundred ten of this article, on or before the\nfiling deadline provided in such section seventy-three-a,\nnotwithstanding the filing deadline otherwise imposed by this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A person who is subject to the filing requirements of this\nsubdivision from more than one political subdivision within the same\ncounty may satisfy the requirements of this subdivision by filing only\none annual statement of financial disclosure with the appropriate body\n(as is required in that county) for the county in which such political\nsubdivisions are located or if such political subdivisions cross one or\nmore county boundary lines, then such single filing may be made for any\nof the counties in which one of such political subdivisions is located\nprovided, however, that the appropriate bodies (as required by such\nother counties) are notified of the name of the county of such\ncompliance by the person who is subjected to the filing requirements of\nthis subdivision, within the time limit for filing specified in this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A local elected official who is simultaneously a candidate for\nlocal elected official shall satisfy the filing deadline requirements of\nthis subdivision by complying only with the deadline applicable to one\nwho holds such local elected office.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A candidate whose name will appear on both a party designating\npetition and on an independent nominating petition for the same office\nor who will be listed on the election ballot for the same office more\nthan once shall satisfy the filing deadline requirements of this\nsubdivision by complying with the earliest applicable deadline only.\n  2. The governing body of a county, city, town or village having a\npopulation of less than fifty thousand may by local law or ordinance\nelect to be subject to the provisions of this section. In such event,\nany such city, county, town or village shall be deemed to be a political\nsubdivision under this section.\n  3. Any political subdivision or other county, city, town or village to\nwhich all of the provisions of this section are made applicable, whether\nas a result of the provisions contained in subdivision two of section\neight hundred eleven of this article or as a result of an election to be\nsubject to the provisions of this section as permitted by subdivision\ntwo of this section, may elect to remove itself from the ambit of all\n(but not some) provisions of this section (other than this subdivision)\nby adopting a local law, ordinance or resolution specifically referring\nto the authority conferred by this subdivision. Provided, however, that\nthe terms of such local law, ordinance or resolution shall be subject to\nthe following conditions and limitations:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such local law, ordinance or resolution must provide for the\npromulgation of a form of an annual statement of financial disclosure\ndescribed in subdivision one of section eight hundred eleven of this\narticle for use with respect to information the governing body requires\nto be reported for the calendar year next succeeding the year in which\nsuch local law, ordinance or resolution is adopted and for use with\nrespect to information required to be reported for subsequent calendar\nyears; and shall provide for the filing of completed statements with the\nboard of ethics of the political subdivision or other municipality.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such removal shall not be effective with respect to the annual\nfinancial disclosure statement for the calendar year in which the local\nlaw, ordinance or resolution is adopted (the filing of which statement\nis due on May fifteenth of the next succeeding year with certain\nexceptions), nor shall such removal be effective with respect to any\nrequired annual financial disclosure statement for the immediately\npreceding calendar year (the filing of which statement is due on May\nfifteenth (with certain exceptions) of the calendar year in which such\nlocal law, ordinance or resolution is adopted), nor shall such removal\nbe effective with respect to any other preceding year but such removal\nshall apply first to the statement which would have been due on May\nfifteenth (with certain exceptions) of the second year next succeeding\nthe year in which such local law, ordinance or resolution is adopted,\nand such removal shall apply thereafter to subsequent statements\notherwise due pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such removal shall not affect the power to impose, or the\nimposition of, a penalty for failure to file, or for false filing, of\nany required annual financial disclosure statement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The local law, ordinance or resolution referred to in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision or any other such local law, ordinance or\nresolution so adopted may make provision for any other right, power or\nprivilege granted by subdivision one of such section eight hundred\neleven.\n  4. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed as precluding\nthe governing body of a political subdivision from requiring additional\nand/or more detailed items of financial disclosure than are set forth in\nsubdivision five hereinbelow.\n  5. The annual statement of financial disclosure shall contain the\ninformation and shall be in the form set forth hereinbelow:\n              ANNUAL STATEMENT OF FINANCIAL DISCLOSURE FOR\n  (Insert Name of Political Subdivision) - (For calendar year ________)\n1. Name ________________________________________________________________\n2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Title of Position _______________________________________________\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Department, Agency or other Governmental Entity _________________\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Address of Present Office _______________________________________\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Office Telephone Number _________________________________________\n3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Marital  Status  ______________. If married, please give spouse's\n       full name including maiden name where applicable.\n       ________________________________________ .\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>List the names of all unemancipated children.\n       ___________________________________\n       ___________________________________\n       ___________________________________\n       ___________________________________\n       ___________________________________\n     Answer each of the following questions completely, with respect to\n   calendar year _________, unless another period or date is otherwise\n   specified. If additional space is needed, attach additional pages.\n     Whenever a "value" or "amount" is required to be reported herein,\n   such value or amount shall be reported as being within one of the\n   following Categories: Category A - under $5,000; Category B - $5,000\n   to under $20,000; Category C - $20,000 to under $60,000; Category D -\n   $60,000 to under $100,000; Category E - $100,000 to under $250,000;\n   and Category F - $250,000 or over. A reporting individual shall\n   indicate the Category by letter only.\n     For the purposes of this statement, anywhere the term "local\n   agency" shall appear such term shall mean a local agency, as defined\n   in section eight hundred ten of the general municipal law, of the\n   political subdivision for which this financial disclosure statement\n   has been filed.\n4.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>List any office, trusteeship, directorship, partnership, or\n   position of any nature including honorary positions, if known, and\n   excluding membership positions, whether compensated or not, held by\n   the reporting individual with any firm, corporation, association,\n   partnership, or other organization other than the State of New York\n   or (insert name of political subdivision). If said entity was\n   licensed by any state or local agency, was regulated by any state\n   regulatory agency or local agency, or, as a regular and significant\n   part of the business or activity of said entity, did business with,\n   or had matters other than ministerial matters before, any state or\n   local agency, list the name of any such agency.\n                                                             State or\n   Position             Organization                        Local Agency\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>List  any  office,  trusteeship,  directorship,  partnership,  or\n   position of any nature including honorary positions,  if  known,  and\n   excluding  membership  positions, whether compensated or not, held by\n   the spouse or unemancipated child of the reporting  individual,  with\n   any   firm,   corporation,   association,   partnership,   or   other\n   organization other than the State of New York.  If  said  entity  was\n   licensed  by  any  state  or local agency, was regulated by any state\n   regulatory agency or local agency, or, as a regular  and  significant\n   part  of  the business or activity of said entity, did business with,\n   or had matters other than ministerial matters before,  any  state  or\n   local agency, list the name of any such agency.\n                                                             State or\n   Position             Organization                        Local Agency\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n5.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>List  the  name,  address  and  description  of  any  occupation,\n   employment, trade, business or profession engaged in by the reporting\n   individual. If such activity was  licensed  by  any  state  or  local\n   agency, was regulated by any state regulatory agency or local agency,\n   or,  as a regular and significant part of the business or activity of\n   said entity, did business with, or had matters other than ministerial\n   matters before, any state or local agency, list the name of any  such\n   agency.\n                                                            State or\n                     Name &amp; Address                          Local\n      Position       of Organization       Description       Agency\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If  the spouse or unemancipated child of the reporting individual\n   was  engaged  in  any  occupation,  employment,  trade,  business  or\n   profession  which activity was licensed by any state or local agency,\n   was regulated by any state regulatory agency or local agency, or,  as\n   a  regular  and  significant part of the business or activity of said\n   entity, did business with, or  had  matters  other  than  ministerial\n   matters before, any state or local agency, list the name, address and\n   description  of  such  occupation,  employment,  trade,  business  or\n   profession and the name of any such agency.\n                                                            State or\n                     Name &amp; Address                          Local\n      Position       of Organization       Description       Agency\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n6. List any interest, in excess of $1,000, excluding  bonds  and  notes,\n   held  by  the  reporting  individual,  such  individual's  spouse  or\n   unemancipated child, or partnership of which any  such  person  is  a\n   member,  or corporation, ten per centum or more of the stock of which\n   is owned  or  controlled  by  any  such  person,  whether  vested  or\n   contingent,  in  any  contract  made  or executed by a state or local\n   agency and include the name of the entity which holds  such  interest\n   and the relationship of the reporting individual or such individual's\n   spouse  or  such  child  to  such  entity  and  the  interest in such\n   contract. Do not list any interest in  any  such  contract  on  which\n   final  payment  has  been made and all obligati...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If  the  reporting  individual  practices law, is licensed by the\n   department of state as a real estate broker or agent or  practices  a\n   profession  licensed  by  the department of education, give a general\n   description of the principal subject areas of matters  undertaken  by\n   such  individual.  Additionally, if such an individual practices with\n   a firm or corporation and is a partner or shareholder of the firm  or\n   corporation, give a general description of principal subject areas of\n   matters  undertaken by such firm or corporation. Do not list the name\n   of the individual clients, customers or patients.\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>List the name, principal address and general description  or  the\n   nature  of the business activity of any entity in which the reporting\n   individual or such individual's spouse had an investment in excess of\n   $1,000 excluding investments in  securities  and  interests  in  real\n   property.\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n9. List  each  source  of  gifts,  excluding  campaign contributions, in\n   excess of $1,000, received during the reporting period for which this\n   statement is filed by the reporting individual or  such  individual's\n   spouse  or  unemancipated  child from the same donor, excluding gifts\n   from a relative. Include the name and address of the donor. The  term\n   "gifts"  does  not  include  reimbursements, which term is defined in\n   item 10.  Indicate the value and nature of each such gift.\n                                                                Category\n   Self,                                                           of\n   Spouse or      Name of                       Nature          Value of\n   Child           Donor         Address        of Gift           Gift\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n   _____________________________________________________________________\n10. Identify and briefly describe the source of any  reimbursements  for\n    expenditures,  excluding  campaign  expenditures and expenditures in\n    connect...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Describe the  terms  of,  and  the  parties  to,  any  contract,\n    promise, or other agreement between the reporting individual and any\n    person,  firm, or corporation with respect to the employment of such\n    individual after leaving office or position (other than a  leave  of\n    absence).\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Describe  the  parties  to  and  the  terms  of  any  agreement\n    providing for continuation of payments or benefits to the  reporting\n    individual  in excess of $1,000 from a prior employer other than the\n    political subdivision for  which  this  statement  is  filed.  (This\n    includes   interests   in   or  contributions  to  a  pension  fund,\n    profit-sharing  plan,  or  life   or   health   insurance;   buy-out\n    agreements; severance payments; etc.)\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n    ____________________________________________________________________\n13. List  below  the nature and amount of any income in excess of $1,000\n    from each source for the reporting individual and such  individual's\n    spouse  for  the  taxable  year  last occurring prior to the date of\n    filing.  Nature of income includes, but is not  limited  to,  salary\n    for  government employment, income from other compensated employment\n    whether  public  or  private,  directorships  and  other   fiduciary\n    positions,  contractual arrangements, teaching income, partnerships,\n    honorariums, lecture fees, consultant fees, bank and bond  interest,\n    dividends,  income  derived  from  a  trust,  real estate rents, and\n    recognized gains  from  the  sale  or  exchange  of  real  or  other\n    property. Income from a business or profession and real estate rents\n    shall be reported with the source identified by the building address\n    in  the  case  of real estate rents and otherwise by the name of the\n    entity and not by the name of the individual customers,  clients  or\n    tenants,  with  the  aggregate  net  income  before  taxes  for each\n    building address or entity. The receip...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_812__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or if the security is\n    corporate stock, not publicly traded, in a trade or  business  of  a\n    reporting individual or a reporting individual's spouse.\n                                       Category of\n                                       Market Value as\n                                       of the close of\n                                       the taxable year\n                                       last occurring   Percentage\n                                       prior to the     of corporate\n    Self/       Issuing    Type of     filing of this   stock owned or\n    Spouse      Entity     Security    statement        controlled\n    __________  _________  __________  ______________   ______________\n    __________  _________  __________  ______________   ______________\n    __________  _________  __________  ______________   ______________\n    __________  _________  __________  ______________   ______________\n    __________  _________  __________  ______________   ______________\n17. List  below  the  location,  size, general nature, acquisition date,\n    market value and percentage of ownership of  any  real  property  in\n    which  any vested or contingent interest in excess of $1,000 is held\n    by the reporting individual or the  reporting  individual's  spouse.\n    Also   list  real  property  owned  for  investment  purposes  by  a\n    corporation more than fifty percent of the stock of which  is  owned\n    or  controlled  by  the  reporting  individual  or such individual's\n    spouse. Do not list any  real  property  which  is  the  primary  or\n    secondary  personal  residence  of  the  reporting individual or the\n    reporting individual's spouse, except where there is a co-owner  who\n    is other than a relative.\n    Self/                                           Category\n    Spouse/                                            of     Percentage\n    Other                    General  Acquisition    Market       of\n    P...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>