<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-858"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-858"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-02-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="858"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-858/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-858/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-858/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-858/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_858">
        <num>858</num>
        <heading>Purposes and powers of the agency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_858__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To appoint an attorney, who may be the counsel of the\nmunicipality, and to fix the attorney's compensation for services which\nshall be payable to the attorney, and to retain and employ private\nconsultants for professional and technical assistance and advice;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_858__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An attorney acting as bond counsel for a project must file with\nthe agency a written statement in which the attorney identifies each\nparty to the transaction which such attorney represents. If bond counsel\nprovides any legal services to parties other than the agency the written\nstatement must describe the nature of legal services provided by such\nbond counsel to all parties to the transaction, including the nature of\nthe services provided to the agency.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To make contracts and leases, and to execute all instruments\nnecessary or convenient to or with any person, firm, partnership or\ncorporation, either public or private; provided, however, that any\nextension of an existing contract, lease or other agreement entered into\nby an agency with respect to a project shall be guided by the provisions\nof this article;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To acquire, construct, reconstruct, lease, improve, maintain,\nequip or furnish one or more projects;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To accept gifts, grants, loans, or contributions from, and enter\ninto contracts or other transactions with, the United States and the\nstate or any agency of either of them, any municipality, any public or\nprivate corporation or any other legal entity, and to use any such\ngifts, grants, loans or contributions for any of its corporate purposes;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To borrow money and to issue bonds and to provide for the rights\nof the holders thereof;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To grant options to renew any lease with respect to any project\nor projects and to grant options to buy any project at such price as the\nagency may deem desirable;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To designate the depositories of its money either within or\nwithout the state;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To enter into agreements requiring payments in lieu of taxes.\nSuch agreements shall be in writing and in addition to other terms shall\ncontain: the amount due annually to each affected tax jurisdiction (or a\nformula by which the amount due can be calculated), the name and address\nof the person, office or agency to which payment shall be delivered, the\ndate on which payment shall be made, and the date on which payment shall\nbe considered delinquent if not paid. Unless otherwise agreed by the\naffected tax jurisdictions, any such agreement shall provide that\npayments in lieu of taxes shall be allocated among affected tax\njurisdictions in proportion to the amount of real property tax and other\ntaxes which would have been received by each affected tax jurisdiction\nhad the project not been tax exempt due to the status of the agency\ninvolved in the project. A copy of any such agreement shall be delivered\nto each affected tax jurisdiction within fifteen days of signing the\nagreem...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To establish and re-establish its fiscal year; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_858__subsec_b__subsec_17">
            <num>(17)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To do all things necessary or convenient to carry out its\npurposes and exercise the powers expressly given in this title.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>