<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-875"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-875"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="875"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-875/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-875/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-875/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-875/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_875">
        <num>875</num>
        <heading>Special provisions applicable to state sales and compensating use taxes and certain types of facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An IDA shall include within its resolutions and project\ndocuments establishing any project or appointing an agent or project\noperator for any project the terms and conditions in this subdivision,\nand every agent, project operator or other person or entity that shall\nenjoy state sales and use tax exemption benefits provided by an IDA\nshall agree to such terms as a condition precedent to receiving or\nbenefiting from such state sales and use exemptions benefits.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The IDA shall recover, recapture, receive, or otherwise obtain\nfrom an agent, project operator or other person or entity state sales\nand use exemptions benefits taken or purported to be taken by any such\nperson to which the person is not entitled or which are in excess of the\namounts authorized or which are for property or services not authorized\nor taken in cases where such agent or project operator, or other person\nor entity failed to comply with a material term or condition to use\nproperty or services in the manner required by the person's agreement\nwith the IDA.  Such agent or project operator, or other person or entity\nshall cooperate with the IDA in its efforts to recover, recapture,\nreceive, or otherwise obtain such state sales and use exemptions\nbenefits and shall promptly pay over any such amounts to the IDA that it\nrequests. The failure to pay over such amounts to the IDA shall be\ngrounds for the commissioner to assess and determine state sales and use\ntaxes due from the person under article twenty-eight of the tax law,\ntogether with any relevant penalties and interest due on such amounts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If an IDA recovers, recaptures, receives, or otherwise obtains,\nany amount of state sales and use tax exemption benefits from an agent,\nproject operator or other person or entity, the IDA shall, within thirty\ndays of coming into possession of such amount, remit it to the\ncommissioner, together with such information and report that the\ncommissioner deems necessary to administer payment over of such amount.\nAn IDA shall join the commissioner as a party in any action or\nproceeding that the IDA commences to recover, recapture, obtain, or\notherwise seek the return of, state sales and use tax exemption benefits\nfrom an agent, project operator or other person or entity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An IDA shall prepare an annual compliance report detailing its\nterms and conditions described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision and\nits activities and efforts to recover, recapture, receive, or otherwise\nobtain state sales and use exemptions benefits described in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, together with such other information as the\ncommissioner and the commissioner of economic development may require.\nThe report required by this subdivision shall be filed with the\ncommissioner, the director of the division of the budget, the\ncommissioner of economic development, the state comptroller, the\ngoverning body of the municipality for whose benefit the agency was\ncreated, and may be included with the annual financial statement\nrequired by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section eight hundred\nfifty-nine of this title. Such report required by this subdivision shall\nbe filed regardless of whether the IDA is required to file such\nfinancial statement described by such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one\nof section eight hundred fifty-nine. The failure to file or\nsubstantially complete the report required by this subdivision shall be\ndeemed to be the failure to file or substantially complete the statement\nrequired by such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of such section eight\nhundred fifty-nine, and the consequences shall be the same as provided\nin paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of such section eight hundred\nfifty-nine.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_875__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This subdivision shall apply to any amounts of state sales and use\ntax exemption benefits that an IDA recovers, recaptures, receives, or\notherwise obtains, regardless of whether the IDA or the agent, project\noperator or other person or entity characterizes such benefits\nrecovered, recaptured, received, or otherwise obtained, as a penalty or\nliquidated or contract damages or otherwise. The provisions of this\nsubdivision shall also apply to any interest or penalty that the IDA\nimposes on any such amounts or that are imposed on such amounts by\noperation of law or by judicial order or otherwise. Any such amounts or\npayments that an IDA recovers, recaptures, receives, or otherwise\nobtains, together with any interest or penalties thereon, shall be\ndeemed to be state sales and use taxes and the IDA shall receive any\nsuch amounts or payments, whether as a result of court action or\notherwise, as trustee for and on account of the state.\n  4. The commissioner shall deposit and dispose of any amount of any\npayments or moneys received from or paid over by an IDA or from or by\nany person or entity, or received pursuant to an action or proceeding\ncommenced by an IDA, together with any interest or penalties thereon,\npursuant to subdivision three of this section, as state sales and use\ntaxes in accord with the provisions of article twenty-eight of the tax\nlaw. The amount of any such payments or moneys, together with any\ninterest or penalties thereon, shall be attributed to the taxes imposed\nby sections eleven hundred five and eleven hundred ten, on the one hand,\nand section eleven hundred nine of the tax law, on the other hand, or to\nany like taxes or fees imposed by such article, based on the proportion\nthat the rates of such taxes or fees bear to each other, unless there is\nevidence to show that only one or the other of such taxes or fees was\nimposed or received or paid over.\n  5. The statement that an IDA is required by subdivision nine of\nsection eig...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>