<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-88-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-88-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-08-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="88-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-88-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-88-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-88-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-88-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_88_A">
        <num>88-A</num>
        <heading>Merit award board to reward employees for suggestions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 88-a. Merit award board to reward employees for suggestions. 1. Any\ncity, county, town, village, school district or board of cooperative\neducational services is hereby authorized and empowered to establish a\nmerit award board for the purpose of rewarding its employees for\nsuggestions which result in a more efficient and economical operation of\nits government and may raise and expend moneys for the purposes thereof.\n  2. In cities such board shall consist of the mayor, corporation\ncounsel and such council members as may be designated by the council and\nin counties such board shall consist of the chair of the board of\nsupervisors and such members thereof as shall be chosen by the board. In\ntowns such board shall consist of the town supervisor and such members\nas the town council shall designate. In villages such board shall\nconsist of the mayor and members designated by the board of trustees. In\nschool districts, such board shall consist of the president of the board\nof education and such members thereof as shall be chosen by the board of\neducation. In boards of cooperative educational services, such board\nshall consist of the president of the board of cooperative educational\nservices and such members thereof as shall be chosen by the board of\ncooperative educational services.\n  3. Such merit award boards when so established shall make rules and\nregulations to provide for the rewarding of employees of the\nmunicipality, school district or board of cooperative educational\nservices for the purposes hereinbefore set forth.\n  4. Nothing herein contained shall in any way add to or diminish the\nexisting powers of the city of New York with reference to establishment\nof a merit award board, and its powers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>