<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-890-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-890-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="890-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-890-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-890-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-890-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-890-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_890_C">
        <num>890-C</num>
        <heading>Counties of Warren and Washington industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * § 890-c. Counties of Warren and Washington industrial development\nagency. For the benefit of the counties of Warren and Washington and the\ninhabitants thereof, an industrial development agency, to be known as\nthe COUNTIES OF WARREN AND WASHINGTON INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is\nhereby established for the accomplishment of any or all of the purposes\nspecified in title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall\nconstitute a body corporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration.\nIt shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter conferred by title\none of article eighteen-A of this chapter upon industrial development\nagencies and provided that the exercise of the powers by such agency\nwith respect to the acquisition of real property whether by purchase,\ncondemnation or otherwise, shall be limited to the corporate limits of\nthe counties of Warren and Washington, and such agency shall take into\nconsideration the local zoning and planning regulations as well as the\nregional and local comprehensive land use plans. It shall be organized\nin a manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions of title one\nof article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be appointed by\nthe governing bodies of the counties of Warren and Washington. The\nagency, its members, officers and employees and its operations and\nactivities shall in all respects be governed by the provisions of title\none of article eighteen-A of this chapter, except that notwithstanding\nthe provisions of subdivision two of section eight hundred fifty-six of\narticle eighteen-A of this chapter, the counties of Warren and\nWashington industrial development agency shall consist of not less than\nsix nor more than ten members who shall be appointed by the governing\nbody of each municipality and who shall serve at the pleasure of the\nappointing authority.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>