<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-891-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-891-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="891-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-891-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-891-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-891-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-891-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_891_E">
        <num>891-E</num>
        <heading>Town of Shawangunk, Ulster county industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 891-e. Town of Shawangunk, Ulster county industrial development\nagency. For the benefit of the town of Shawangunk, Ulster county, and\nthe inhabitants thereof, an industrial development agency, to be known\nas the TOWN OF SHAWANGUNK, ULSTER COUNTY, INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY,\nis hereby established for the accomplishment of any or all of the\npurposes specified in title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter.\nIt shall constitute a body corporate and politic, and be perpetual in\nduration. It shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter conferred\nby title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter upon industrial\ndevelopment agencies and provided that the exercise of the powers by\nsuch agency with respect to the acquisition of real property whether by\npurchase, condemnation or otherwise, shall be limited to the corporate\nlimits of the town of Shawangunk, Ulster county, and such agency shall\ntake into consideration the local zoning and planning regulations as\nwell as the regional and local comprehensive land use plans. It shall be\norganized in a manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions of\ntitle one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be\nappointed by the governing body of the town of Shawangunk, Ulster\ncounty. The agency, its members, officers and employees and its\noperations and activities shall in all respects be governed by the\nprovisions of title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter.\n  * NB Agency expired per ยง 856\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>