<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-892-G*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-892-G*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="892-G*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-892-G*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-892-G*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-892-G*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-892-G*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_892_G*2">
        <num>892-G*2</num>
        <heading>County of Orleans industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * § 892-g. County of Orleans industrial development agency. For the\nbenefit of the county of Orleans and the inhabitants thereof, an\nindustrial development agency, to be known as the COUNTY OF ORLEANS\nINDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is hereby established for the\naccomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in title one of\narticle eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall constitute a body corporate\nand politic, and be perpetual in duration. It shall have the powers and\nduties now or hereafter conferred by title one of article eighteen-A of\nthis chapter upon industrial development agencies and provided that the\nexercise of the powers by such agency with respect to the acquisition of\nreal property whether by purchase, condemnation or otherwise, shall be\nlimited to the corporate limits of the county of Orleans, and such\nagency shall take into consideration the local zoning and planning\nregulations as well as the regional and local comprehensive land use\nplans. It shall be organized in a manner prescribed by and be subject to\nthe provisions of title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its\nmembers shall be appointed by the governing body of the county of\nOrleans. The agency, its members, officers and employees and its\noperations and activities shall in all respects be governed by the\nprovisions of title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter.\n  The original appointment of the members of the COUNTY OF ORLEANS\nINDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY is hereby ratified, validated and\nconfirmed, notwithstanding any purported irregularities in said original\nappointment, and the continuous existence of the COUNTY OF ORLEANS\nINDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY since June twenty-fifth, nineteen hundred\nseventy-one and all acts and proceedings heretofore had and taken by the\nCOUNTY OF ORLEANS INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY are hereby ratified,\nvalidated and confirmed.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n  * NB There are 2 § 892-g's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>