<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-893"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-893"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="893"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-893/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-893/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-893/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-893/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_893">
        <num>893</num>
        <heading>Madison county industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 893. Madison county industrial development agency. For the benefit\nof the county of Madison and the inhabitants thereof, an industrial\ndevelopment agency, to be known as the MADISON COUNTY INDUSTRIAL\nDEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is hereby established for the accomplishment of any\nor all of the purposes specified in title one of article eighteen-A of\nthis chapter. It shall constitute a body corporate and politic, and be\nperpetual in duration. It shall have the powers and duties now or\nhereafter conferred by title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter\nupon industrial development agencies and provided that the exercise of\nthe powers by such agency with respect to the acquisition of real\nproperty whether by purchase, condemnation or otherwise, shall be\nlimited to the corporate limits of the county of Madison, and such\nagency shall take into consideration the local zoning and planning\nregulations as well as the regional and local comprehensive land use\nplans. It shall be organized in a manner prescribed by and be subject to\nthe provisions of title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its\nmembers shall be appointed by the governing body of the county of\nMadison. The agency, its members, officers and employees and its\noperations and activities shall in all respects be governed by the\nprovisions of title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter.\n  * NB Agency expired per ยง 856\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>