<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-895-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-895-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="895-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-895-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-895-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-895-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-895-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_895_J">
        <num>895-J</num>
        <heading>Greene county industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * § 895-j. Greene county industrial development agency. For the\nbenefit of the county of Greene and the inhabitants thereof, an\nindustrial development agency, to be known as the GREENE COUNTY\nINDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is hereby established for the\naccomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in title one of\narticle eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall constitute a body corporate\nand politic, and be perpetual in duration. It shall have the powers and\nduties now or hereafter conferred by title one of article eighteen-A of\nthis chapter upon industrial development agencies and provided that the\nexercise of the powers by such agency with respect to the acquisition of\nreal property whether by purchase, condemnation or otherwise, shall be\nlimited to the corporate limits of the county of Greene, and such agency\nshall take into consideration the local zoning and planning regulations\nas well as the regional and local comprehensive land use plans. It shall\nbe organized in a manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions\nof title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be\nappointed by the governing body of the county of Greene. The agency, its\nmembers, officers and employees and its operations and activities shall\nin all respects be governed by the provisions of title one of article\neighteen-A of this chapter.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>