<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-897-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-897-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="897-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-897-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-897-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-897-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-897-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_897_A">
        <num>897-A</num>
        <heading>The village of Sackets Harbor industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * § 897-a. The village of Sackets Harbor industrial development\nagency.  For the benefit of the village of Sackets Harbor and the\ninhabitants thereof, an industrial development agency, to be known as\nThe Village of Sackets Harbor Industrial Development Agency, is hereby\nestablished for the accomplishment of any or all of the purposes\nspecified in title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall\nconstitute a body corporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration.\nIt shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter conferred by title\none of article eighteen-A of this chapter upon industrial development\nagencies and provided that the exercise of the powers by such agency\nwith respect to the acquisition of real property whether by purchase,\ncondemnation or otherwise, shall be limited to the corporate limits of\nthe village of Sackets Harbor, and such agency shall take into\nconsideration the local zoning and planning regulations as well as the\nregional and local comprehensive land use plans. It shall be organized\nin a manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions of title one\nof article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be appointed by\nthe governing body of the village of Sackets Harbor. The agency, its\nmembers, officers and employees and its operations and activities shall\nin all respects be governed by the provisions of title one of article\neighteen-A of this chapter.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>