<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-902-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-902-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="902-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-902-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-902-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-902-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-902-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_902_C">
        <num>902-C</num>
        <heading>City of Mount Vernon industrial development agency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_902_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For\nthe purposes of this section "governing body" as used in title one of\narticle eighteen-A of this chapter shall mean the mayor of the city, and\n"city" shall mean the city of Mount Vernon.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_902_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the benefit of the city of Mount Vernon and the inhabitants\nthereof, an industrial development agency, to be known as the CITY OF\nMOUNT VERNON INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is hereby established for\nthe accomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in title one\nof article eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall constitute a body\ncorporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration. It shall have the\npowers and duties now or hereafter conferred by title one of article\neighteen-A of this chapter upon industrial development agencies, except\nthat the agency's power of condemnation shall not be exercised without\nprior approval of the city council of the city, and provided that the\nexercise of the powers by such agency with respect to the acquisition of\nreal property, whether by purchase, condemnation or otherwise, shall be\nlimited to the corporate limits of the city of Mount Vernon, and such\nagency shall take into consideration the local zoning and planning\nregulations as well as the regional and local comprehensive land use\nplans. It shall be organized in a manner prescribed by and be subject to\nthe provisions of title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter,\nexcept that the members shall be appointed by the mayor of said city and\nshall serve at the pleasure of the mayor. The mayor shall designate the\nfirst chairman. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the\nagency, its members, officers and employees and its operations and\nactivities shall in all respects be governed by the provisions of title\none of article eighteen-A of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_902_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The city shall have the power to make, or contract to make grants\nor loans, including but not limited to grants or loans of money, to the\nagency in such amounts, upon such terms and conditions and for such\nperiod or periods of time as in the judgment of the city and the agency\nare necessary or appropriate for the accomplishment of any of the\npurposes of the agency.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>