<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="903"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_903">
        <num>903</num>
        <heading>City of Yonkers industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * § 903. City of Yonkers industrial development agency. For the\nbenefit of the city of Yonkers and the inhabitants thereof, an\nindustrial development agency, to be known as the CITY OF YONKERS\nINDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is established to accomplish any or all\nof the purposes specified in title one of this article. It shall\nconstitute a body corporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration.\nIt shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter conferred by title\none of this article upon industrial development agencies and provided\nthat the exercise of the powers by such agency with respect to the\nacquisition of real property whether by purchase, condemnation or\notherwise, shall be limited to the corporate limits of the city of\nYonkers, and such agency shall take into consideration the local zoning\nand planning regulations as well as the regional and local comprehensive\nland use plans. It shall be organized in a manner prescribed by and be\nsubject to the provisions of title one of this article. Six of such\nmembers shall be appointed by the mayor of the city of Yonkers and one\nsuch member shall be appointed by majority vote of the city council of\nthe city of Yonkers. The agency, its members, officers and employees and\nits operations and activities shall in all respects be governed by the\nprovisions of title one of this article.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>