<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-906"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-906"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="906"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-906/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-906/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_906">
        <num>906</num>
        <heading>County of Sullivan industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 906. County of Sullivan industrial development agency. For the\nbenefit of the county of Sullivan and the inhabitants thereof, an\nindustrial development agency, to be known as the county of Sullivan\nindustrial development agency, is hereby established for the\naccomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in title one of\narticle eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall constitute a body corporate\nand politic, and be perpetual in duration. It shall have the powers and\nduties now or hereafter conferred by title one of article eighteen-A of\nthis chapter upon industrial development agencies. It shall be organized\nin a manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions of title one\nof article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be appointed by\nthe governing body of the county of Sullivan. The agency, its members,\nofficers and employees, and its operations and activities shall in all\nrespects be governed by the provisions of title one of article\neighteen-A of this chapter provided, however, that notwithstanding the\nprovisions of subdivision two of section eight hundred fifty-six of this\nchapter requiring a municipal industrial development agency to consist\nof no more than seven members, the Sullivan county legislature is hereby\nauthorized to appoint nine members to the county of Sullivan industrial\ndevelopment agency.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>