<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-92-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-92-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="92-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-92-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-92-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-92-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-92-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_92_C">
        <num>92-C</num>
        <heading>Emergency service volunteer; paid leave</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 92-c. Emergency service volunteer; paid leave. Notwithstanding any\nprovisions of law to the contrary, public officers and employees of\nmunicipal corporations and school districts who are certified by the\nAmerican Red Cross as disaster volunteers shall be granted leave from\nwork with pay to participate in specialized disaster relief operations\nupon written request for such services by the American Red Cross and\nupon the approval of the chief executive of the municipal corporation\nfor which the public officer or employee serves or upon the approval of\nthe superintendent of the school district for which the employee serves.\nThe public officer or employee shall be compensated at his or her\nregular rate of pay for those regular work hours during which the public\nofficer or employee is absent from work while participating in\nauthorized specialized disaster relief operations. Such leave shall be\nprovided without loss of seniority, compensation, sick leave, vacation\nleave or other overtime compensation to which the volunteer is otherwise\nentitled and shall not exceed twenty days in any calendar year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>