<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-Z"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-Z"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="925-Z"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-Z/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-Z/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_925_Z">
        <num>925-Z</num>
        <heading>Town of Waterford industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * § 925-z. Town of Waterford industrial development agency. For the\nbenefit of the town of Waterford and the inhabitants thereof, an\nindustrial development agency, to be known as the WATERFORD INDUSTRIAL\nDEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is hereby established for the accomplishment of any\nor all of the purposes specified in title one of article eighteen-A of\nthis chapter. It shall constitute a body corporate and politic, and be\nperpetual in duration. It shall have the powers and duties now or\nhereafter conferred by title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter\nupon industrial development agencies and provided that, except as\nprovided herein, the exercise of the powers by such agency with respect\nto the acquisition of real property whether by purchase, condemnation or\notherwise, shall be limited to the corporate limits of the town of\nWaterford, and such agency shall take into consideration the local\nzoning and planning regulations as well as the regional and local\ncomprehensive land use plans; provided, however, that in the event a\nproject which is to be located partially outside the corporate limits of\nthe town of Waterford and on a parcel or parcels of land contiguous to\nthe town of Waterford, such agency may acquire real property without the\ncorporate limits of the town of Waterford, whether by purchase,\ncondemnation or otherwise, only after it has obtained the prior consent\nof the governing bodies of all the other municipal corporations in which\na part or parts of the project is to be located. It shall be organized\nin a manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions of title one\nof article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be appointed by\nthe governing body of the town of Waterford. The agency, its members,\nofficers and employees and its operations and activities shall in all\nrepects be governed by the provisions of title one of article eighteen-A\nof this chapter.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>