<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-V"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-V"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="925-V"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-925-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_925_V">
        <num>925-V</num>
        <heading>Town of Hamburg industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * § 925-v. Town of Hamburg industrial development agency. 1. For the\nbenefit of the town of Hamburg in the county of Erie, and the\ninhabitants thereof, an industrial development agency, to be known as\nthe TOWN OF HAMBURG INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is hereby established\nfor the accomplishment of any or all of the purposes specified in title\none of article eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall constitute a body\ncorporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration. It shall have the\npowers and duties now or hereafter conferred by title one of article\neighteen-A of this chapter upon industrial development agencies and\nprovided that the exercise of the powers by such agency with respect to\nthe acquisition of real property whether by purchase, condemnation or\notherwise, shall be limited to the corporate limits of the town of\nHamburg, and such agency shall take into consideration the local zoning\nand planning regulations as well as the regional and local comprehensive\nland use plans. It shall be organized in a manner prescribed by and be\nsubject to the provisions of title one of article eighteen-A of this\nchapter. Its members shall be appointed by the governing body of the\ntown of Hamburg. The agency, its members, officers and employees and its\noperations and activities shall in all respects be governed by the\nprovisions of title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision two of section eight\nhundred fifty-six of article eighteen-A of this chapter, the agency\nshall consist of not less than three nor more than nine members who\nshall be appointed by the governing body of the town of Hamburg.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>