<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-926-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-926-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="926-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-926-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-926-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-926-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-926-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_926_I">
        <num>926-I</num>
        <heading>Village of Groton industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 926-i. Village of Groton industrial development agency. For the\nbenefit of the village of Groton, county of Tompkins, and the\ninhabitants thereof, an industrial development agency, to be known as\nthe village of Groton industrial development agency, is hereby\nestablished for the accomplishment of any or all of the purposes\nspecified in title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall\nconstitute a body corporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration.\nIt shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter conferred by title\none of article eighteen-A of this chapter upon industrial development\nagencies, provided that the exercise of the powers by such agency with\nrespect to the acquisition of real property whether by purchase,\ncondemnation or otherwise shall be limited to the corporate limits of\nthe village of Groton, and such agency shall abide by the local zoning\nordinances and planning regulations and shall take into consideration\nthe regional and local comprehensive land use plans. It shall be\norganized in a manner prescribed by and be subject to the provisions of\ntitle one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be\nappointed by the governing body of the village of Groton. The agency,\nits members, officers and employees, and its operations and activities\nshall in all respects be governed by the provisions of title one of\narticle eighteen-A of this chapter.\n  * NB Expired July 20, 2003\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>