<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-928"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-928"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="928"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-928/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-928/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-928/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-928/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_928">
        <num>928</num>
        <heading>Town of Lockport industrial development agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * § 928. Town of Lockport industrial development agency. For the\nbenefit of the town of Lockport in the county of Niagara, and the\ninhabitants thereof, an industrial development agency, to be known as\nthe TOWN OF LOCKPORT INDUSTRIAL DEVELOPMENT AGENCY, is hereby\nestablished for the accomplishment of any or all of the purposes\nspecified in title one of article eighteen-A of this chapter. It shall\nconstitute a body corporate and politic, and be perpetual in duration.\nIt shall have the powers and duties now or hereafter conferred by title\none of article eighteen-A of this chapter upon industrial development\nagencies; provided that the exercise of the powers by such agency with\nrespect to the acquisition of real property whether by purchase,\ncondemnation or otherwise, shall be limited to the corporate limits of\nthe town of Lockport and such agency shall take into consideration the\nlocal zoning and planning regulations as well as the regional and local\ncomprehensive land use plans. It shall be organized in a manner\nprescribed by and be subject to the provisions of title one of article\neighteen-A of this chapter. Its members shall be appointed by the\ngoverning body of the town of Lockport. The agency, its members,\nofficers and employees and its operations and activities shall in all\nrespects be governed by the provisions of title one of article\neighteen-A of this chapter.\n  * NB Agency expires per §§ 856 and 882\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>