<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="93-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_93_C">
        <num>93-C</num>
        <heading>The appropriate disbursing or fiscal officer of any municipality or other political subdivision of the state is hereby authorized to dedu...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 93-c. The appropriate disbursing or fiscal officer of any\nmunicipality or other political subdivision of the state is hereby\nauthorized to deduct from the salary of any employee of such\nmunicipality or political subdivision such amount as such employee may\nspecify in writing filed with such appropriate disbursing or fiscal\nofficer for payment to any credit union doing business in the state of\nNew York, and to transmit the sums so deducted to the said credit union.\nThe disbursing or fiscal officer hereinbefore referred to is hereby\nauthorized to make such rules and regulations governing the payments to\ncredit unions as he deems necessary, such rules and regulations to be\nincorporated in the employee's written authorization of payroll\ndeduction, filed with the fiscal or disbursing officer of every\nmunicipal corporation or other civil division or political subdivision\nof the state. Any such written authorization may be withdrawn by such\nemployee at any time by filing written notice of such withdrawal with\nsuch appropriate disbursing or fiscal officer. As used in this section\n"credit union" means a non-profit organization which serves only its\nmembers and is chartered pursuant to the banking law of the state of New\nYork, or by the United States government pursuant to the federal credit\nunion act.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>