<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="93"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-93/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_93">
        <num>93</num>
        <heading>Payment of certain insurance premiums for officers and employees of municipal corporations and agencies or instrumentalities thereof</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 93. Payment of certain insurance premiums for officers and employees\nof municipal corporations and agencies or instrumentalities thereof. 1.\nThe fiscal or disbursing officer of every municipal corporation is\nhereby authorized to deduct from the wage or salary of any officer or\nemployee of the municipality who is insured under any group or group\nplan of life, group accident or group health insurance or who is a\nmember of a corporation existing by virtue of article forty-three of the\ninsurance law, such amounts for the payment of the premium or premiums\nor payments thereon, as such officer or employee may specify in a\nwriting filed with the said fiscal or disbursing officer and transmit to\nthe insurer the sum so deducted. Any such written authorization may be\nwithdrawn by such officer or employee or member at any time upon filing\nwritten notice of such withdrawal with the fiscal or disbursing officer.\nThe provisions of this section shall apply to and be effective within\nevery city, county, town, village, school district and organized public\ndistrict in the state.\n  2. A municipal corporation, including a fire district, or town\nimprovement district governed by a separate board of commissioners, if a\ngroup plan of life insurance provides that the employer shall contribute\na share of the cost of such insurance for its officers and employees, or\nfor the officers or employees of an agency or instrumentality thereof,\nis authorized to appropriate a sum required to be paid under such plan\nby the municipal corporation as employer. The sum to be paid by it under\nsuch plan, in the discretion of the municipal corporation, may be any\npercentage of the total cost, including the whole thereof. For the\npurposes of this section, the term employee shall include the volunteer\nfirefighters of the municipality or fire district or employees,\ncommissioners, or officers of a town improvement district governed by a\nseparate board of commissioners.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>