<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-956"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-956"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="956"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-956/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-956/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-956/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-956/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_956">
        <num>956</num>
        <heading>Statement of legislative findings and declaration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 956. Statement of legislative findings and declaration.  It is\nhereby found and declared that there exist within the state certain\nareas characterized by persistent and pervasive poverty, high\nunemployment, limited new job creation, a dependence on public\nassistance income, dilapidated and abandoned industrial and commercial\nfacilities, and shrinking tax bases. These severe conditions require\nstate government to target for these areas extraordinary economic and\nhuman resource development programs in order to stimulate private\ninvestment, private business development and job creation. It is the\npublic policy of the state to offer special incentives and assistance\nthat will promote the development of new businesses, the expansion of\nexisting businesses and the development of human resources within these\neconomically impoverished areas and to do so without encouraging the\nrelocation of business investment from other areas of the state. It is\nfurther found and declared that it is the public policy of the state to\nachieve these goals through the mutual cooperation of all levels of\nstate and local government and the business community.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>