<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-96-A*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-96-A*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="96-A*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-96-A*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-96-A*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-96-A*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-96-A*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_A*2">
        <num>96-A*2</num>
        <heading>Protection of historical places, buildings and works of art</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 96-a. Protection of historical places, buildings and works of art.\nIn addition to any power or authority of a municipal corporation to\nregulate by planning or zoning laws and regulations or by local laws and\nregulations, the governing board or local legislative body of any\ncounty, city, town or village is empowered to provide by regulations,\nspecial conditions and restrictions for the protection, enhancement,\nperpetuation and use of places, districts, sites, buildings, structures,\nworks of art, and other objects having a special character or special\nhistorical or aesthetic interest or value. Such regulations, special\nconditions and restrictions may include appropriate and reasonable\ncontrol of the use or appearance of neighboring private property within\npublic view, or both. In any such instance such measures, if adopted in\nthe exercise of the police power, shall be reasonable and appropriate to\nthe purpose, or if constituting a taking of private property shall\nprovide for due compensation, which may include the limitation or\nremission of taxes.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 96-a's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>