<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-965"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-965"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="965"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-965/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-965/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-965/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-965/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_965">
        <num>965</num>
        <heading>Designation of empire zone as a foreign trade zone</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 965. Designation of empire zone as a foreign trade zone. Any city,\ncounty, town or village which contains an area which is designated an\nempire zone in accordance with this article, is hereby authorized to\nmake application to the foreign trade zones board established by an act\nof Congress, approved June eighteenth, nineteen hundred thirty-four,\nentitled "An Act to provide for the establishment, cooperation and\nmaintenance of foreign trade zones in ports of entry of the United\nStates, to expedite and encourage foreign commerce, and for other\npurposes," for a grant to said city, county, town or village for the\nprivilege of establishing, operating, and maintaining a foreign trade\nzone within such area, pursuant to the provisions of such act, and if\nsuch application be granted, to establish, operate and maintain such\nforeign trade zone within such area in accordance with law. Any such\ncity, county, town or village may contract with a not-for-profit agency\nand may appropriate such sums of money as it may deem proper, subject to\nthe provisions of this section, toward the promotion and establishment\nof such foreign trade zone in such area.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>