<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="970-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_970_C">
        <num>970-C</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Blighted area" means an area within a\nmunicipality in which one or more of the following conditions exist:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\na predominance of buildings and structures which are deteriorated or\nunfit or unsafe for use or occupancy; or (ii) a predominance of\neconomically unproductive lands, buildings or structures, the\nredevelopment of which is needed to prevent further deterioration which\nwould jeopardize the economic well being of the people.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Legislative body" means the governing body of a municipality\nempowered to adopt and amend local laws and ordinances.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Low and moderate income families and persons" means those persons\nwho would qualify as low and moderate income persons and families under\nSections 1715z and 1715z-1 of Title 12 of the United States Code as\nthose definitions in those sections now exist or may be amended,\nreplaced, or superseded.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Master plan" means the plan for development of a municipality\nadopted by the planning agency of the municipality.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Municipality" means a city, village, town or a county other than\na county located wholly within a city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Planning agency" means the planning board or commission of a\nmunicipality or the planning board or committee of a school district if\none exists.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Project area" means an area of a community which is a blighted\narea, the redevelopment of which is necessary to effectuate the purposes\nof this article. A project area need not be restricted to buildings,\nimprovements or lands which are detrimental or inimical to the public\nhealth, safety or welfare, but may consist of an area in which such\nconditions predominate and adversely affect the entire area. A project\narea may include lands, buildings or improvements which are not\ndetrimental or inimical to the public health, safety or welfare, but\nwhose inclusion is found necessary by the municipality for the effective\nredevelopment of the area of which they are a part. All lands, buildings\nor improvements included in a project area shall be necessary for\neffective redevelopment and shall not be included for the purposes of\nobtaining the allocation of tax increment revenue without clear\njustification for their inclusion. A project area shall not include land\nutilized for agricultural production.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Real property" means:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>land, including land under water and\nwaterfront property; (ii) buildings, structures, fixtures, and\nimprovements on the land; (iii) any property appurtenant to or used in\nconnection with the land; and (iv) every estate, interest, privilege,\neasement, franchise, and right in land, including rights-of-way, terms\nfor years, and liens, charges, or encumbrances by way of judgment,\nmortgage, or otherwise and the indebtedness secured by such liens.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"School district" means any school district, a city school\ndistrict or a school district in a city, as those terms are defined in\nsection 2.00 of the local finance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>