<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="970-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_970_K">
        <num>970-K</num>
        <heading>Clearance, improvements and site preparation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A\nmunicipality may demolish or move buildings, structures, or other\nimprovements from any real property acquired. The municipality may\ndevelop as a building site any real property owned or acquired by it. In\nconnection with such development it may cause, provide or undertake or\nmake provision with other agencies for the installation, or construction\nof streets, utilities, parks, playgrounds and other public improvements\nnecessary for carrying out the redevelopment plan.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any work of grading, clearing, demolition, or construction or\ninstallation of public improvements shall be done by contract subject to\nprovisions of state and local law applicable to the letting of public\nworks contracts.  Where the work does not require competitive bids the\nagency may give priority for such work to the residents of such\nredevelopment project areas and to persons displaced from such areas as\na result of redevelopment activities. To the greatest extent feasible,\ncontracts for work to be performed in connection with any redevelopment\nproject shall be awarded to business concerns which are located in, or\nowned in the substantial part, by persons residing in the project area.\nTo the greatest extent feasible, opportunities for training and\nemployment arising from any contract for work to be performed in\nconnection with any redevelopment project shall be given to low-income\npersons who are residents of the project area. The municipality shall\nrequire each successful bidder to file with it good and sufficient\nbonds, to be approved by it. The bonds shall be conditioned upon the\nfaithful performance of the contract and upon the payment of all claims\nfor labor and material in connection with the contract.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>