<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="970-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-970-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_970_G">
        <num>970-G</num>
        <heading>Plan review</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_G__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Submit such plan to the planning agency for its review and\nrecommendations. Such review shall consider the conformity of such\nredevelopment plan with any master plan which has been adopted by the\nplanning agency and approved by the legislative body. The planning\nagency may recommend for or against the approval of the redevelopment\nplan. Within thirty days after a redevelopment plan is submitted to it\nfor consideration, the planning agency shall make and file its review\nand recommendations with the legislative body. If the planning agency\ndoes not report upon the redevelopment plan within thirty days after its\nsubmission, the legislative body may thereafter approve the plan without\nthe review and recommendations of the planning agency;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_970_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Submit such plan to the boards of education of the school\ndistricts impacted by the redevelopment plan for review and approval of\nany tax allocation pursuant to section nine hundred seventy-p of this\narticle in relation to bonds issued under section nine hundred seventy-o\nof this article. To be subject to such redevelopment plan and allocation\nof taxes pursuant to section nine hundred seventy-p of this article, the\nboard of education of an impacted school district shall adopt a\nresolution approving such plan and allocation and transmit such\nresolution to the legislative body.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>