<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-975"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-975"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="975"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-975/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-975/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-975/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-975/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_975">
        <num>975</num>
        <heading>Town of Islip Foreign Trade Zone Authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_975__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the town and county will not limit or alter the rights hereby\nvested in the authority to acquire, construct, maintain, reconstruct,\nand operate any project or projects, to establish and collect rentals,\nfees and other charges and to fulfill the terms of any agreements made\nwith the holders of the bonds and notes, or in any way impair the rights\nand remedies of the bondholders or noteholders, until the bonds or\nnotes, together with interest thereon, with interest on any unpaid\ninstallments of interest, and all costs and expenses in connection with\nany action or proceeding by or on behalf of the bondholders or\nnoteholders, are fully met and discharged; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_975__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no facilities except those acquired, constructed and operated by\nthe authority created herein shall be acquired, constructed and operated\nfor foreign trade zone purposes by the town or county or by any public\nbenefit or other corporation whose members, or any member, are elected\nor appointed by the town board of the town of Islip until the bonds or\nnotes, together with interest thereon, with interest on any unpaid\ninstallment of interest, and all costs and expenses in connection with\nany action or proceeding by or on behalf of the bondholders or\nnoteholders are fully met and discharged.\n  2. Any public officer or employee of the town of Islip or county of\nSuffolk, selected by the authority may, with the consent of the\nmunicipality, by which he or she has been employed, be transferred to\nthe authority and shall be eligible for such transfer to the authority.\nThe salary or compensation of any such officer or employee shall, after\nsuch transfer, be paid and fixed by the authority. Any such officers or\nemployees so transferred to the authority pursuant to the provisions of\nthis section, who are members of or beneficiaries under an existing\npension or retirement system, shall continue to have all rights,\nprivileges, obligations and status with respect to such fund system or\nsystems as are now prescribed by law, but during the period of their\nemployment by the authority, all contributions to a pension or\nretirement system to be paid by the employer on account of such officers\nor employees, shall be paid by the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>