<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-980-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-980-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="980-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-980-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-980-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-980-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-980-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_980_J">
        <num>980-J</num>
        <heading>Expense of the district</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_980_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The expense incurred in the\nconstruction or operation of any improvement or provision of additional\nservices in a district pursuant to this article shall be financed in\naccordance with the district plan upon which the establishment or\nextension of the district was based. Services for which district\nproperty owners are charged pursuant to the plan must be in addition to\nor an enhancement of those provided by the municipality prior to the\nestablishment of the district. The expense and cost apportioned to\nbenefited real property in accordance with the plan shall be a charge\nupon each benefited parcel of real property within the district.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_980_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The charge upon benefited real property pursuant to this article\nshall be imposed as provided in the district plan. If the formula\nincludes an ad valorem component, this component shall be determined by\nthe assessed value of each parcel as entered on the latest completed\nassessment roll used by the municipality for the levy of general\nmunicipal taxes. The charge shall be determined, levied and collected in\nthe same manner, at the same time and by the same officers, as general\nmunicipal taxes are levied and collected.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_980_J__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any municipality which has established a district pursuant to this\narticle, may, for the purpose of providing funds for making capital\nimprovements within a district, issue and sell bonds or other municipal\nobligations as provided in the local finance law and other applicable\nlaws and statutes. Principal and interest payments on these bonds or\nother municipal obligations may be made in whole or in part from the\nproceeds of charges imposed upon benefited real property within the\ndistrict.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>