<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="99-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_99_E">
        <num>99-E</num>
        <heading>Operation, improvement and maintenance of parks</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 99-e. 1. Operation, improvement and maintenance of parks.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local law, or\nof any charter, ordinance, rule or regulation, any county, except a\ncounty wholly included within a city and except a county operating under\nan alternative form of county government or under a county charter, may\nundertake to operate, maintain and improve public parks and recreational\nfacilities theretofore established by a municipal corporation within its\nboundaries on land owned by such municipal corporation. Such county and\nany municipal corporation located therein may, when authorized by\nmajority vote of the whole number of the members of its governing body,\nenter into an agreement for the aforesaid purpose for a term not to\nexceed thirty years, upon such other terms and conditions as such bodies\nshall determine. Such operation, maintenance and improvement shall be\ncounty purposes and the board of supervisors of such county may\nappropriate and expend county funds for such purposes.\n  2. After such an agreement has been executed, employees of the\nmunicipal corporation so contracting with the county, who at the time of\nthe execution of such agreement were employed in the operation and\nmaintenance of the parks and recreational facilities covered by any such\nagreement, shall be transferred to the employ of the county in the\nmanner set forth in section seventy of the civil service law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>