<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="99-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_99_J">
        <num>99-J</num>
        <heading>Control of aquatic plant growth</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 99-j. Control of aquatic plant growth. Every municipal corporation\nis, and any two or more municipal corporations jointly are, hereby\nauthorized and empowered to take such action as may be required to adopt\nplans and specifications and enter into a contract or contracts, or take\nsuch other action as may be required for the control of aquatic growth\nas it may deem to be necessary or desirable, in the case of a joint\nproject by two or more municipal corporations, the share of the cost of\nsuch project or activity to be borne by each such municipal corporation\nshall be fixed by contract. The expenditure of moneys for such purpose\nby a municipal corporation shall be deemed a lawful municipal purpose\nand the moneys appropriated therefor shall be raised by tax upon the\ntaxable real property within the municipal corporation in the same\nmanner as moneys for other lawful municipal purposes. Each municipal\ncorporation is hereby authorized to accept and disburse grants of public\nor private money or other aid paid or made available by the state or\nfederal government for any such purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>