<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-R"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-R"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="99-R"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_99_R">
        <num>99-R</num>
        <heading>Contracts for services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 99-r. Contracts for services. Notwithstanding any other provisions\nof law to the contrary, the governing board of any municipal corporation\nmay enter into agreements and/or contracts with any state agency\nincluding any department, board, bureau, commission, division, office,\ncouncil, committee, or officer of the state, whether permanent or\ntemporary, or a public benefit corporation or public authority, or a\nsoil and water conservation district, and any unit of the state\nuniversity of New York, pursuant to and consistent with sections three\nhundred fifty-five and sixty-three hundred one of the education law\nwithin or without such municipal corporation to provide or receive fuel,\nequipment, maintenance and repair, supplies, water supply, street\nsweeping or maintenance, sidewalk maintenance, right-of-way maintenance,\nstorm water and other drainage, sewage disposal, landscaping, mowing,\ntechnology services, or any other services of government. Such state\nagency, soil and water conservation district, or unit of the state\nuniversity of New York, within the limits of any specific statutory\nappropriation authorized and made available therefor by the legislature\nor by the governing body responsible for the operation of such state\nagency, soil and water conservation district, or unit of the state\nuniversity of New York may contract with any municipal corporation for\nsuch services as herein provided and may provide, in agreements and/or\ncontracts entered into pursuant to this section, for the reciprocal\nprovision of services or other consideration of approximately equivalent\nvalue, including, but not limited to, routine and/or emergency services,\nmonies, equipment, buildings and facilities, materials or a commitment\nto provide future routine and/or emergency services, monies, equipment,\nbuildings and facilities or materials. Any such contract may be entered\ninto by direct negotiations and shall not be subject to the provisions\nof section one hundred three of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>