<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GMU">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="99-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="GMU"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gmu/section-99-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_99_S">
        <num>99-S</num>
        <heading>Transfer and sale of delinquent real estate tax receivables</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_99_S__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The time and date for the opening of bids, which shall be only\non weekdays, Saturdays and holidays excluded, between the hours of ten\no'clock ante meridian and four o'clock post meridian, eastern standard\ntime.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_99_S__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In lieu of the statement of the time and date for the opening of\nbids required by clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_99_S__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subparagraph, a statement</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_99_S__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that\nthe time and date for the opening of bids will be provided on not less\nthan twenty-four hours prior notice by means of a supplemental notice of\nsale and indicating the manner in which such supplemental notice will be\nprovided, or (ii) setting a time and date for the opening of bids,\nstating that notice of a change in the time or date for the opening of\nbids may be provided not less than twenty-four hours prior to the time\noriginally scheduled for the opening of bids by means of a supplemental\nnotice of sale and indicating the manner in which such supplemental\nnotice will be provided. Where notice is given that the time or date of\na sale will be changed without specifying the new time or date, notice\nof the new time or date of sale must be provided by means of a second\nsupplemental notice of sale at least twenty-four hours prior to the new\ntime for the opening of bids.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_99_S__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A supplemental notice of sale shall refer to and be deemed a part\nof the notice of sale required by this section and shall not establish\nor change the terms of the sale other than the time or date for the\nopening of bids. The time set for the opening of bids in the\nsupplemental notice of sale shall not be less than five nor more than\nthirty days after publication of the notice of sale required pursuant to\nparagraph a of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_99_S__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Public notice of the time and date set for the opening of bids\nshall be given to the news media and shall be posted in one or more\ndesignated public locations within such city at least twenty-four hours\nprior to the time and date set for the opening of bids or, in the case\nof a time and date set or changed in a supplemental notice of sale, at\nleast twenty-four hours prior to such time and date; provided, however,\nthat such public notice shall not be construed to require publication as\na legal notice.\n  d. All bids shall be opened publicly at the time and place stated in\nthe notice of sale, and not before, and shall be publicly announced.\nPrior to the time fixed for such public opening of bids, a sealed bid\nmay be amended by a bidder by delivery to the official to whom the\nsealed bid was delivered of a sealed amendment to such bid. No bid shall\nbe amended by a telegraphic or telephonic communication.\n  e. Advertisements shall contain a provision to the effect that such\ncity, in its discretion, may reject any or all bids made in pursuance of\nsuch advertisements, and in the event of such rejection, such city is\nauthorized to readvertise for bids in the form and manner above\ndescribed as many times as, in its judgement, may be necessary to effect\na satisfactory sale.\n  3. Without limitation of the foregoing, any sale or transfer agreement\nentered into pursuant hereto may also contain provisions requiring such\ncity to undertake to replace such receivable with the transferee or\npurchaser for any misrepresentation or mistake as to the description or\nstatus of any delinquent real estate tax receivable which is the subject\nof such sale or transfer agreement.\n  4. In no event shall such city pay any such receivable other than from\nmoneys collected thereon by such city. Any revenues received by such\ncity for payment of delinquent real estate taxes including any penalties\nand interest thereon where the interest in such delinquent real estate\ntax re...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>