<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1005"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1005"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1005"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1005/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1005/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1005/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-1005/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1005">
        <num>1005</num>
        <heading>Administration and services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1005. Administration and services. 1. There is hereby established\nwithin the department a New York youth jobs connector program to connect\nunemployed and underemployed individuals between the ages of sixteen and\ntwenty-four years with targeted educational, occupational, and training\nservices to help prepare such individuals for employment and improve\nopportunities for such individuals to become employed. The New York\nyouth jobs connector program shall be responsible for facilitating the\ncoordination and delivery of existing programs and resources throughout\nthe state which are designed to assist individuals identified in this\narticle with opportunities for employment, skills development, job\ntraining, and the other related services described in subdivision two of\nthis section.\n  2. The department shall coordinate with the office of strategic\nworkforce development, the department of education, the state university\nof New York, the city university of New York, the office of temporary\nand disability assistance, the office of children and family services,\nthe urban development corporation and its subsidiaries, and any other\nrelevant agency or entity, to carry out the purposes of this article and\nleverage existing funds and programs for unemployed and underemployed\nyouth consistent with the purposes described herein. Services provided\nby such programs may include, but are not limited to, high school\nequivalency, basic education, job skills training, English-as-a-second\nlanguage, job readiness training, job placement services, case\nmanagement, career counseling and assessment, pre-apprenticeships and\napprenticeships, pre-vocational skills training, employability planning,\nsupportive services, proactive outreach to unemployed and underemployed\nyouths, skills and vocational programs leading to career pathways and\ngainful employment, and the development or promulgation of other\nresources and programs to assist youths between the ages of sixteen and\ntwenty-four years, particularly at-risk youths in such category.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>