<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12_C">
        <num>12-C</num>
        <heading>Passenger tramway advisory council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 12-c. Passenger tramway advisory council. 1. To advise the\ncommissioner of labor in relation to his duties and responsibilities\nunder the provisions of section two hundred two-c and article twenty-six\nof this chapter, there shall be in the department an advisory council,\nto be known as the passenger tramway advisory council, consisting of\nseven members to be appointed by the governor, by and with the advice\nand consent of the senate, and one of whom shall be designated as\nchairman by the governor. Each of four members of the council shall be\nan officer or employee of a ski center, and three members of the council\nshall be representatives of the public and shall not be, nor within five\nyears immediately preceding appointment have been an officer or employee\nof a ski center.\n  2. The term of each member of such advisory board shall be for five\nyears, or until a successor is appointed. Any member of the board chosen\nto fill a vacancy occurring otherwise than by expiration of term shall\nbe appointed for the unexpired term of the member whom he is to succeed.\nAny member of the council may be removed by the governor for misconduct,\nincompetence or neglect of duty after being given a written statement of\nthe charges and an opportunity to be heard thereon.\n  3. Each member of the advisory council shall serve without salary or\nother compensation, but shall be allowed necessary and actual\ntransportation expenses incurred in the performance of his or her\nduties, and when in travel status shall receive an additional fifty-five\ndollars and when in travel status in a county or a city with a\npopulation in excess of seven hundred thousand an additional\nseventy-five dollars.\n  4. The advisory council shall consider all matters in connection with\nski tows, other passenger tramways and downhill skiing referred to it by\nthe commissioner and advise him with respect thereto, and on its own\ninitiative, or upon the suggestion of others, may make such\nrecommendations to the commissioner in connection with ski tows, other\npassenger tramways and downhill skiing as, after consideration by it,\nmay be deemed necessary.\n  5. The commissioner shall designate an officer or employee of the\ndepartment to act as secretary of the advisory council, who shall not be\na member of such council and who shall not receive any additional\ncompensation therefor.\n  6. The advisory council may adopt rules and regulations to govern its\nown proceedings. The secretary shall keep a complete record of all\nproceedings of the advisory council which shall show the names of the\nmembers present at each meeting and every matter considered by the\nadvisory council and the action taken thereon. Such records shall be\nfiled in the office of the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>