<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-12-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12_D">
        <num>12-D</num>
        <heading>Advisory council on farm labor safety</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_12_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nunique and special conditions involved in farm safety;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the need for\neducation and training programs for the protection of farm workers\nagainst accidents;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the identification of areas where existing\neducational and training programs are insufficient to provide adequate\nprotection to farm workers against accidents;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the methods of\nencouraging farmers and farm groups to establish such education and\ntraining programs; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_12_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all matters and approaches for the protection\nof farm workers against accidents referred by the industrial\ncommissioner.\n  2. The advisory council shall consist of ten members appointed by the\nindustrial commissioner. The members shall be representative of farmers,\ngrowers, farm workers and other persons and groups concerned with\nagricultural safety. One of the members shall be designated as chairman\nby the industrial commissioner. The chairman of the board of standards\nand appeals, the commissioner of agriculture and markets, the\ncommissioner of education, and the dean of the college of agriculture at\nCornell University, or their designated representatives, shall be\nadditional members of the council, who shall serve by virtue of their\npositions, without voting power.\n  The industrial commissioner shall designate an officer or employee of\nthe department of labor to act as secretary of the advisory council, who\nshall not be a member of such council and who shall not receive any\nadditional compensation therefor.\n  3. The advisory council may take testimony, subpoena witnesses, and\nrequire the production of books, records and papers, and hold public or\nprivate hearings.\n  4. The advisory council may request and shall receive such assistance,\nservice and data from any agency of the state or from any political\nsubdivision thereof as will enable it properly to carry out its\nactivities hereunder and effectuate the purposes herein set forth.\n  5. The advisory council shall, from time to time, but not less\nfrequently than on December first of each year, submit a report to the\nindustrial commissioner, and shall submit a final report on or before\nMarch thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-two. Such reports may\ninclude such recommendations as the council finds appropriate on the\nbasis of its studies and investigations.\n  6. The appointed members of the advisory council shall receive no\ncompensation for their services but shall receive in lieu of...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>