<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-166"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-166"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="166"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-166/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-166/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-166/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-166/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_166">
        <num>166</num>
        <heading>Signalmen</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 166. Signalmen. 1. When used in this section "signalman" means:\n  a. A telegraph or telephone operator reporting trains to another\noffice or to a train dispatcher;\n  b. A telegraph or telephone leverman who manipulates interlocking\nmachines in railroad yards or on main tracks on the lines;\n  c. A train dispatcher whose duties pertain to the movement of cars,\nengines or trains, by telegraph or telephone in dispatching or reporting\ntrains or receiving or transmitting train orders.\n  2. When used in this section "railroad" means: any portion of a\nsurface, subway or elevated railroad situated wholly or partly in this\nstate and operated by a corporation or receiver on which portion at\nleast twenty freight trains on the average or nine regular passenger\ntrains pass each way in every twenty-four hours.\n  3. No signalman shall be employed on any railroad for more than eight\nhours in any day except in cases of extraordinary emergency caused by\naccident, fire, flood or danger to life or property and he shall be paid\nfor each hour of such overtime at least one-eighth of his daily\ncompensation.\n  4. Every signalman and every towerman or gateman performing duties\nsimilar to those of a signalman, who is employed for eight hours or more\nevery day shall be allowed at least two days of rest of twenty-four\nhours each in every calendar month with the regular compensation, except\nin cases of extraordinary emergency caused by accident, fire, flood, or\ndanger to life or property, when in addition to his regular compensation\nhe shall be paid for every hour so employed at least one-eighth of his\ndaily compensation.\n  5. The provisions of this section shall not apply to employees engaged\nin interstate commerce.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>