<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="202"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_202">
        <num>202</num>
        <heading>Protection of the public and of persons engaged at window cleaning and cleaning of exterior surfaces of buildings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 202. Protection of the public and of persons engaged at window\ncleaning and cleaning of exterior surfaces of buildings. The owner,\nlessee, agent and manager of every public building and every contractor\ninvolved shall provide such safe means for the cleaning of the windows\nand of exterior surfaces of such building as may be required and\napproved by the board of standards and appeals. The owner, lessee,\nagent, manager or superintendent of any such public building and every\ncontractor involved shall not require, permit, suffer or allow any\nwindow or exterior surface of such building to be cleaned unless such\nmeans are provided to enable such work to be done in a safe manner for\nthe prevention of accidents and for the protection of the public and of\npersons engaged in such work in conformity with the requirements of this\nchapter and the rules of the board of standards and appeals. A person\nengaged at cleaning windows or exterior surfaces of a public building\nshall use the safety devices provided for his protection. Every employer\nand contractor involved shall comply with this section and the rules of\nthe board and shall require his employee, while engaged in cleaning any\nwindow or exterior surface of a public building, to use the equipment\nand safety devices required by this chapter and rules of the board of\nstandards and appeals.\n  The provisions of this section shall not apply to (1) multiple\ndwellings six stories or less in height located anywhere in this state;\nnor to (2) any building three stories or less in height in cities, towns\nor villages having a population of less than forty thousand; nor to (3)\nthe windows or exterior surfaces of any building which may be exempted\nunder any rule adopted by the board of standards and appeals.\n  The board of standards and appeals may grant variations pursuant to\nthe provisions of section thirty of this chapter. All existing\nvariations heretofore made by the board relating to the cleaning of\nwindows are hereby validated and continued in full force and effect\nuntil amended or terminated by the board.\n  The board of standards and appeals may make rules to effectuate the\npurposes of this section.\n  Notwithstanding any other law or regulation, local or general, the\nprovisions of this section and the rules issued thereunder shall be\napplicable exclusively throughout the state and the commissioner shall\nhave exclusive authority to enforce this section and the rules issued\nthereunder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>