<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="204"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_204">
        <num>204</num>
        <heading>Inspection of boilers; enforcement; fees; identification; exceptions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_204__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a heat input of two hundred thousand BTU's\nper hour; (ii) a water temperature of two hundred ten degrees\nfahrenheit; (iii) a nominal water containing capacity of one hundred\ntwenty gallons;\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>pressure vessels under federal control or regulation;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>pressure vessels containing water under pressure, including those\ncontaining air, the compression of which serves only as a cushion, when\nnone of the following limitations are exceeded:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_204__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a design pressure of\nthirty pounds per square inch; (ii) a design temperature of two hundred\nten degrees fahrenheit; and\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>pressure vessels used for agricultural purposes.\n  7. Cities. a. A city which qualifies under the provisions of this\nsubdivision shall enforce the provisions of this section and the rules\nof the board promulgated hereunder and for such purpose shall have the\npowers of the commissioner prescribed in subdivision two of this\nsection. In order to so qualify, a city shall have enacted a local law\nor ordinance requiring an inspection of all boilers required to be\ninspected by the provisions of this section located in such city, which\ninspection shall be conducted with at least the same frequency as is\nrequired by this section, but in no case more often than once a year.\nSuch boilers shall be inspected by competent inspectors employed by the\ncity except boilers inspected and insured by a duly authorized insurance\ncompany in accordance with the provisions of subdivision eight of this\nsection and with the rules of the commissioner.\n  b. The fee schedule contained in subdivision th...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that inspections by the insurance company are made with\nthe same frequency as is required by this section except that, for all\nsuch boilers located within a city which qualifies under the provisions\nof subdivision seven of this section, inspections are made with the same\nfrequency as is required by such city;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the insurance company\ncomplies with the rules of the commissioner;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the inspectors of\nthe insurance company hold certificates of competency;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the\ninsurance company gives notice to the owner or lessee of each boiler\ninspected listing all violations of any provision of the rules of the\ncommissioner;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_204__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that a certified copy of the report of each inspection\nis filed with the commissioner or the inspecting agency of such city, as\nthe case may be, within twenty-one days of the inspection, on such forms\nand in such manner as required by the commissioner or the inspecting\nagency of such city, as the case may be. A copy filed with the\ncommissioner shall be accompanied by a non-refundable fee of one hundred\ndollars paid for each boiler inspected. If insurance is refused,\ncancelled or discontinued for the boiler inspected the report shall so\nstate, together with the reasons therefor; the report shall also list\nany instances of the failure of an owner or lessee of the boiler to\ncomply with the rules of the commissioner.\n  b. In order to satisfy the inspection requirements of this section,\nall inspections which are made by duly authorized insurance companies\nshall be made by inspectors whose competency has been certified by the\ncommissioner in accordance with the rules of the boa...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>