<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-206-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-206-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-06-21" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="206-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-206-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-206-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-206-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-206-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_206_C">
        <num>206-C</num>
        <heading>Right of nursing employees to express breast milk</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon request of an employee who chooses to express breast milk\nin the workplace, an employer shall designate a room or other location\nwhich shall be made available for use by such employee to express breast\nmilk. Such room or other location shall be a place that is:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in close\nproximity to the work area; (ii) well lit; (iii) shielded from view; and\n(iv) free from intrusion from other persons in the workplace or the\npublic. Such room or other location shall provide, at minimum, a chair,\na working surface, nearby access to clean running water and, if the\nworkplace is supplied with electricity, an electrical outlet. The room\nor location provided by the employer for this purpose shall not be a\nrestroom or toilet stall.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the sole purpose or function of such room or other location is\nnot dedicated for use by employees to express breast milk, such room or\nother location shall be made available to such an employee when needed\nand shall not be used for any other purpose or function while in use by\nsuch employee. Employers shall provide notice to all employees as soon\nas practicable when such room or other location has been designated for\nuse by employees to express breast milk.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where compliance with the requirements of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision is impracticable because it would impose an undue\nhardship on the employer by causing significant difficulty or expense\nwhen considered in relation to the size, financial resources, nature, or\nstructure of the employer's business, such employer shall make\nreasonable efforts to provide a room or other location, other than a\nrestroom or toilet stall, that is in close proximity to the work area\nwhere an employee can express breast milk in privacy. Provided, however,\nnothing in this subdivision shall otherwise exempt an employer from the\nrequirements of subdivision one of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the workplace has access to refrigeration, the employer shall\nextend such access to refrigeration for the purposes of storing the\nexpressed milk.\n  3. The commissioner shall develop and implement a written policy\nregarding the rights of nursing employees to express breast milk in the\nworkplace pursuant to the provisions of this section. Employers shall\nprovide such written policy to each employee upon hire and annually\nthereafter, and to employees upon returning to work following the birth\nof a child. Such policy shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Inform employees of their rights pursuant to this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Specify the means by which a request may be submitted to the\nemployer for a room or other location for use by employees to express\nbreast milk; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_206_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Require the employer to respond to such request within a\nreasonable timeframe, but not to exceed five business days.\n  4. No employer or their agent, or the officer or agent of any\ncorporation, partnership, or limited liability company, or any other\nperson, shall discharge, threaten, penalize, or in any other manner\ndiscriminate or retaliate against any employee because such employee has\nexercised their rights afforded under this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>