<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-21/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21">
        <num>21</num>
        <heading>General powers and duties of commissioner</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_21__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name of the funding program and the agency administering the\nfunding program;\n  (ii) a description of the purpose of the funding program;\n  (iii) a specific program Uniform Resource Locator ("URL"), if any;\n  (iv) the year the program was established;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a catalog of federal domestic assistance numbers, if any;\n  (vi) the legal authority, including statute and regulation citations;\n  (vii) the program and fiscal contact information including agency\nname, telephone number, and email address;\n  (viii) all eligibility requirements;\n  (ix) any program and special restrictions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any action or actions required to receive aid; and\n  (xi) a description of aid which shall include, but not be limited to,\nthe flow of funds between entities, the type of aid formula used, any\nmatching requirements and any maintenance of effort.\n  16. Beginning on December first, two thousand twenty-four, and every\nDecember first thereafter, the department shall prepare a report of the\ncatalogue of workforce development funding programs established pursuant\nto subdivision fifteen of this section comprised of analysis conducted\nby the agency or entity responsible for each workforce development\nfunding program on the outcomes and effectiveness of such funding\nprograms and the number of persons served by such funding. Such analysis\nmust be submitted to the department by a date specified by the\ndepartment each year. Such report shall be submitted to the governor,\nthe temporary president of the senate, the speaker of the assembly, the\nminority leader of the senate and the minority leader of the assembly\nand shall be made publicly available on the department's website.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>