<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-212-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-212-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="212-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-212-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-212-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-212-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-212-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_212_D">
        <num>212-D</num>
        <heading>Field sanitation for farm hand workers, farm field workers and farm food processing workers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 212-d. Field sanitation for farm hand workers, farm field workers\nand farm food processing workers. 1. Every grower or processor who\nemploys or uses paid farm hand workers, farm field workers or farm food\nprocessing workers, whether or not he or she uses the services of a farm\nlabor contractor, shall, at his or her own expense, provide or make\navailable to such workers toilet and handwashing facilities, including\ntransportation to such facilities.\n  2. Where five or more paid farm handworkers, farm field workers or\nfarm food processing workers are employed in one location at the same\ntime, at least one toilet and handwashing facility shall be provided at\nsuch location for every twenty workers or fraction thereof. Toilet and\nhandwashing units shall be located together. Such facilities shall be\nlocated within a one-quarter mile walk of most hand-laborers or at the\nclosest point that may be accessible by motor vehicle.\n  3. Where more than twenty paid farm hand workers, farm field workers\nor farm food processing workers are employed in one location at the same\ntime and fifty or more percent of such workers are women, one toilet\nshall be designated with appropriate signs for men and one toilet\ndesignated with appropriate signs for women. Toilet and handwashing\nunits shall be located together. Such facilities shall be located within\na one-quarter mile walk of most hand-laborers.\n  4. When compliance with the provisions of subdivisions one, two and\nthree of this section is not practicable because of physical or terrain\nconditions, such toilet and handwashing facilities shall be located at\nthe closest point that may be accessible by motor vehicle.\n  5. Any violation of this section, shall be a misdemeanor punishable by\na fine of not less than five hundred dollars, nor more than one thousand\ndollars, or up to thirty days imprisonment, or both such fine and\nimprisonment. Any second or subsequent offense shall be a misdemeanor\npunishable by a fine of not less than one thousand dollars, nor more\nthan three thousand dollars, or up to sixty days imprisonment, or both\nsuch fine and imprisonment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>