<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220">
        <num>220</num>
        <heading>Hours, wages and supplements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The wages to be paid for a legal day's work, as hereinbefore\ndefined, to laborers, workmen or mechanics upon such public works, shall\nbe not less than the prevailing rate of wages as hereinafter defined.\nServing laborers, helpers, assistants and apprentices shall not be\nclassified as common labor and shall be paid not less than the\nprevailing rate of wages as hereinafter defined. No employee shall be\ndeemed to be an apprentice unless he is individually registered in an\napprenticeship program which is duly registered with the commissioner of\nlabor in conformity with the provisions of article twenty-three of this\nchapter. The wages to be paid for a legal day's work, as hereinbefore\ndefined, to laborers, workmen or mechanics upon any material to be used\nupon or in connection therewith, shall be not less than the prevailing\nrate for a day's work in the same trade or occupation in the locality\nwithin the state where such public work on, about or in connection with\nwhich such labor is performed in its final or completed form is to be\nsituated, erected or used. Such contracts shall contain a provision that\neach laborer, workman or mechanic, employed by such contractor,\nsubcontractor or other person about or upon such public work, shall be\npaid the wages herein provided.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The supplements, as hereinafter defined, to be provided to\nlaborers, workmen or mechanics upon such public works, shall be in\naccordance with the prevailing practices in the locality, as hereinafter\ndefined.  Serving laborers, helpers, assistants and apprentices shall\nnot be classified as common labor and shall be provided supplements in\naccordance with the prevailing practices as hereinafter defined. No\nemployee shall be deemed to be an apprentice unless he is individually\nregistered in an apprenticeship program which is duly registered with\nthe industrial commissioner in conformity with the provisions of article\ntwenty-three of this chapter. The supplements, as hereinafter defined,\nto be provided to laborers, workmen or mechanics upon any material to be\nused upon or in connection therewith, shall be in accordance with the\nprevailing practices in the same trade or occupation in the locality\nwithin the state where such public work on, about or in connection with\nwhich such labor is performed in its final or completed form is to be\nsituated, erected or used. Such contracts shall contain a provision that\neach laborer, workman or mechanic, employed by such contractor,\nsubcontractor or other person about or upon such public work, shall be\nprovided the supplements as required in this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the duty of the fiscal officer, as defined in this\nsection, to ascertain and determine the schedules of supplements to be\nprovided and wages to be paid workers, laborers and mechanics on such\npublic work, prior to the time of the advertisement for bids, and such\nschedules shall be annexed to and form a part of the specifications for\nthe work. Such fiscal officer shall file with the department having\njurisdiction such schedules prior to the time of the commencement of the\nadvertisement for bids on all public works proposed to be constructed.\nThe term "contract" as used in this article also shall include\nreconstruction and repair of any such public work, and any public work\nperformed under a lease, permit or other agreement pursuant to which the\ndepartment of jurisdiction grants the responsibility of contracting for\nsuch public work to any third party proposing to perform such work to\nwhich the provisions of this article would apply had the department of\njurisdiction contracted directly for its performance, or where there is\nno lease, permit or other agreement and ownership of a public work is\nintended to be assumed by such public entity at any time subsequent to\ncompletion of the public work.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person that participates in a public works project in the\ncapacity of a contractor or subcontractor and who wilfully fails to pay\nor provide the prevailing rate of wage or supplements and:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_220__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such failure results in underpayments, which in the aggregate\namount to all workers employed by such person, results in an amount less\nthan twenty-five thousand dollars, shall be guilty of a class A\nmisdemeanor;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_220__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such failure results in underpayments, which in the aggregate\namount to all workers employed by such person, result in an amount\ngreater than twenty-five thousand dollars, that person shall be guilty\nof a class E felony;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_220__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such failure results in underpayments, which in the aggregate\namount to all workers employed by such person, result in an amount\ngreater than one hundred thousand dollars, that person shall be guilty\nof a class D felony; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_220__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such failure results in underpayments, which in the aggregate\namount to all workers employed by such person, result in an amount\ngreater than five hundred thousand dollars, that person shall be guilty\nof a class C felony.\n  (ii) Disposition for violations of this section shall be in accordance\nwith the penal law. Fines upon conviction for any violation of this\nsection shall be in accordance with the penal law.\n  (iii) In addition to the penalties set forth above, any such person\nconvicted of a second offense under subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph\nwithin five years shall disgorge profits and shall not be entitled to\nreceive any monies due and owing on the contract or subcontract; nor\nshall any officer, agent or employee of the department of jurisdiction\nor its financial officer pay to such person any such monies.\nNotwithstanding the foregoing, the department of jurisdiction may\nrelease monies due and owing on the contract or subcontract which have\nnot been withheld pursuant to section two hundred twenty-b of this\narticle for the sole purpose of satisfying the contractor's or\nsubcontractor's obligations under the contract or subcontract to third\nparties who were not themselves involved in the violations giving rise\nto the subsequent offense. For the purposes of this subdivision, third\nparties shall include, but not be limited to, contractors,\nsubcontractors, materialmen, and funds, plans, and programs providing\npension, health, and welfare benefits to workmen, laborers, and\nmechanics employed pursuant to such contract or subcontract. The\ndepartment of jurisdiction may release such monies upon the application\nof the contractor provided that no monies shall be released without the\nwritten approval of the fiscal officer or by order of a court of\ncompetent jurisdiction.\n  (iv) In addition to the penalties set forth above, every contract for\na public work project shall contain a term stating that the filing of\npayrolls in a manner consistent with subdivision three-a of this section\nis a condition precedent to payment of any sums due and owing to any\nperson for work done upon the project.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall ensure that all supplements due under this\narticle shall be paid to or on behalf of an employee. The commissioner\nshall require proof that the pension plan for which any supplement has\nbeen paid is qualified as a bona fide plan by the United States internal\nrevenue service. Acceptable proof shall be shown by submission of a\ndetermination letter issued by the United States internal revenue\nservice.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this subdivision contractors or\nsubcontractors engaged in custom fabrication shall not be regarded as\nmaterial suppliers. For the purposes of this subdivision, a legal day's\nwork for which the prevailing rate of wages for the New York county in\nwhich the public works project is situated shall be paid to laborers,\nworkers and mechanics shall include custom fabrication regardless of\nwhether the custom fabrication occurs on-site, off-site, or in another\njurisdiction outside the state where the custom fabrication constitutes\na significant portion of the building or work, it shall be a condition\nof the contract concerning all such custom fabrication work that the\ncontractor or employer awarded the public work contract, except where\nthe project includes federal funding that triggers federal rules for\nwage requirements, and any subcontractor thereto shall pay the on-site\nprevailing wage required for workers at the site of the public work\nproject to those workers performing the custom fabrication. To perform a\npublic works contract each contractor or subcontractor who employs\nworkers off-site for the custom fabrication work related to a public\nwork project shall maintain certified payrolls for those workers and\nprovide such payrolls, with original certifications, to the department\nat least annually and upon request, and shall comply with section two\nhundred twenty-i of this article, as applicable. For the purposes of\nthis subdivision the term "custom fabrication" shall include, but not be\nlimited to, the fabrication of exterior or interior wall panel systems,\nwoodwork, electrical, plumbing, heating, cooling, ventilation or exhaust\nduct systems, rebar cages, and mechanical insulation solely and\nspecifically designed and engineered for installation in the\nconstruction, repair or renovation of a building which is the subject of\na contract to which the state, a department of the state, a board or\nofficer in the state, a municipal ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall be the duty of the department of jurisdiction as\ndefined in this section to ascertain from the plans and specifications\nthe classification of workers, mechanics and laborers to be employed on\nsuch project. Such department shall file with the fiscal officer, as\ndefined in this section, the classification of workers, mechanics and\nlaborers to be employed upon such public works project, together with a\nstatement of the work to be performed by each such classification. From\nsuch statement it shall be the duty of the fiscal officer to make a\nproper classification of such workers, mechanics and laborers taking\ninto account whether the work is heavy and highway, building, sewer and\nwater, tunnel work or residential and to make a determination of the\nschedules of wages and supplements to be paid or provided, as the case\nmay be, therefor.\n  (ii) The contractor and every sub-contractor on public works contracts\nshall post in a prominent and accessible place on the site where the\nwork is performed a legible statement of all wage rates and supplements\nas specified in the contract to be paid or provided, as the case may be,\nfor the various classes of mechanics, workers, or laborers employed on\nthe work. Such posted statement shall be written in plain English and\ntitled, in lettering no smaller than two inches in height and two inches\nin width, with the phrase "Prevailing Rate of Wages". Such posted\nstatement shall be constructed of materials capable of withstanding\nadverse weather conditions. The contractor and every sub-contractor\nshall notify all laborers, workers or mechanics in their employ in\nwriting of the prevailing rates of wages and supplements for their\nparticular job classification. Such notification shall be given to every\nlaborer, worker or mechanic upon hire, with their first pay stub and\nevery pay stub thereafter At the beginning of performance of every\npublic works contract, and with the first paycheck after July first of\neac...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_220__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>failed to post the statement\nrequired under this subparagraph,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_220__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>failed to provide any notification\nto laborers, workers and mechanics as required under this subparagraph,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_220__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>willfully posted the incorrect prevailing wages and supplements, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_220__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>willfully set forth the incorrect prevailing wage or supplement with\nevery pay stub, the fiscal officer shall, by an order which shall\ndescribe particularly the nature of the alleged violation, assess the\ncontractor or sub-contractor a civil penalty of not more than fifty\ndollars upon the first finding of a violation, two hundred fifty dollars\nupon the second finding of a violation, and five hundred dollars for\neach subsequent violation. In assessing the amount of the penalty, the\nfiscal officer shall give due consideration to the size of the\nemployer's business, the good faith of the employer, and the gravity of\nthe violation.\n  The fiscal officer shall prepare templates that comply with the\nnotification requirements of this subparagraph. Each such template shall\nbe dual-language, including English and one additional language. The\nfiscal officer shall determine, in his or her discretion, which\nlanguages to provide in addition to English, based on the size of the\nNew Yor...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name and address of the contractor engaged by said department of\njurisdiction;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the date when the contract was let;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\napproximate consideration stipulated for in said contract.\n  c. The fiscal officer may require any person or corporation performing\nsuch public work to file with the fiscal officer within ten days of\nreceipt of said request, payroll records, sworn to as to their validity\nand accuracy, requested by the fiscal officer, for said public work or\nfor any public or private work performed by said person or corporation\nduring the same period of time as said public work. Such payroll records\nshall include a copy of each notice required under subdivision one or\ntwo of section one hundred ninety-five of this chapter for every\nlaborer, worker or mechanic, which shall be subscribed and sworn to or\naffirmed as true under penalties of perjury. In addition, the fiscal\nofficer may require such person or corporation to furnish proof of any\nsupplements provided or amount paid to or on behalf of laborers, workers\nor mechanics in satisfaction of the obligation to provide supplements\npursuant to this section. In the event said person or corporation fails\nto provide the requested information within the allotted ten days, the\nfiscal officer shall, within fifteen days, order the department of\njurisdiction to immediately withhold from payment to said person or\ncorporation up to twenty-five percent of the amount, not to exceed one\nhundred thousand dollars, to be paid to said person or corporation under\nthe terms of the contract pursuant to which said public work is being\nperformed. Said amount withheld shall be immediately released upon\nreceipt by the department of jurisdiction of a notice from the fiscal\nofficer indicating that the request for records had been satisfied.\n  d. Any person who wilfully fails to file the requested payroll records\nwithin ninety days of a demand by the fiscal officer shall be guilty of\na class A misdemeanor, provided, however, that a person who violates\nthis subdivision after having previously been convicted of violating\nthis subdiv...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Utility companies who, under local law or ordinance, are\nrequired, as a condition of issuance of a permit to use or open a\nstreet, to agree that none but competent workers, skilled in the work\nrequired of them shall be employed thereon and that prevailing scale of\nunion wages shall be the prevailing wage for the similar titles as\nestablished by the fiscal officer pursuant to this section, paid to\nthose so employed, shall be required to keep original payrolls or\ntranscripts thereof, subscribed and sworn to or affirmed by him or her\nas true under the penalties of perjury, setting forth the names and\naddresses and showing for each workman, laborer, or mechanic the hours\nand days worked, the occupations worked, the hourly wage rates paid and\nthe supplements paid or provided as, and in the manner required by\nparagraphs a, b and c of this subdivision.\n  (ii) Utility company contractors and subcontractors to whom a permit\nmay be issued, to use or open a street, shall be required to comply with\nsection two hundred twenty-four-f of this article, as a condition of the\nissuance of a permit to use or open a street, to agree that none but\ncompetent workers, skilled in the work required of them shall be\nemployed thereon and that prevailing scale of union wages shall be the\nprevailing wage for the similar titles as established by the fiscal\nofficer pursuant to this section, paid to those so employed, shall be\nrequired to keep original payrolls or transcripts thereof, subscribed\nand sworn to or affirmed by him or her as true under the penalties of\nperjury, setting forth the names and addresses and showing for each\nworkman, laborer, or mechanic the hours and days worked, the occupations\nworked, the hourly wage rates paid and the supplements paid or provided\nas, and in the manner required by paragraphs a, b and c of this\nsubdivision.\n  f. Prevailing wage shall be paid for work performed on a public works\nworksite pursuant to this section for any work invo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the person and employee organization, if any,\nwho or which initiated the complaint, (ii) to the person or corporation,\nif any, against whom the complaint was brought, and (iii) where a\ncompliance investigation is made without the filing of a complaint, to\nthe person who or which was the subject of the compliance investigation.\n  7-a. The fiscal officer must make an inquiry as to the willfulness of\nthe alleged violation which is the subject of a compliance investigation\npursuant to subdivision seven of this section. In the event a formal\nhearing is held pursuant to subdivision eight of this section, the\nfiscal officer, upon a review of the entire record and a finding of\ncredible evidence, must make a determination, as to the willfulness of\nsaid violation. No finding of willfulness made pursuant to the\nprovisions of this subdivision shall be dispositive in a criminal\nprosecution initiated pursuant to section one hundred ninety-eight-a of\nthis chapter, or paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of this section, or\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three-a of this section or any other\nprovision of law.\n  8. Hearings. Before issuing an order or determination as provided in\nsubdivision seven of this section, the fiscal officer shall order a\nhearing thereon at a time and place to be specified, and shall give\nnotice thereof, together with a copy of such complaint or the purpose\nthereof, or a statement of the facts disclosed upon such investigation,\nwhich notice shall be served personally or by mail on any person\naffected thereby; such person shall have an opportunity to be heard in\nrespect to the matters complained of at the time and place specified in\nsuch notice, which time shall be not less than five days from the\nservice of the notice personally or by mail. The fiscal officer in such\nhearing shall be deemed to be acting in a judicial capacity, and shall\nhave the right to issue subpoenas, administer oaths and examine\nwitnesses. The enforcement of a subpoena issued under this section shall\nbe regulated by the civil practice law and rules. Such hearing shall be\nexpeditiously conducted and upon such hearing the fiscal officer shall\ndetermine the issues raised thereon and shall make and file an order in\nthe office of the fiscal officer stating such determination, and\nforthwith serve a copy of such order, with a notice of the filing\nthereof, upon the parties to such proceeding, personally or by mail.\nSuch order shall direct payment of wages or supplements found to be due,\nincluding interest at the rate of interest then in effect as prescribed\nby the superintendent of financial services pursuant to section\nfourteen-a of the banking law per annum from the date of the\nunderpayment to the date of the payment, provided, however, that such\ninterest rate shall not apply to subdivision eight-c of this section.\n  In addition to directing payment of wages or supplements including\ninterest found to be due, such order may direct payment of a further sum\nas a civil penalty in an amount...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>