<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="224"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_224">
        <num>224</num>
        <heading>Contracting for public work; enforcement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 224. Contracting for public work; enforcement. 1. The commissioner\nshall have the power to enforce any provision of law requiring the\npreparation of separate specifications for public work contracts.\nWhenever the commissioner determines that an agency, board, department,\ncommission or officer of the state of New York, or of any political\nsubdivision thereof as defined in section one hundred of the general\nmunicipal law, municipal corporation as defined in section sixty-six of\nthe general construction law, public benefit corporation, or local or\nstate authority as defined in section two of the public authorities law\nhaving jurisdiction over a public work contract for which the\npreparation of separate specifications is required has failed to prepare\nsuch separate specifications, the commissioner may issue a stop-bid\norder, which shall take effect as to such public work bid or contract\nwhen served upon such agency, board, department, commission or officer\nof the state of New York, political subdivision, municipal corporation,\npublic benefit corporation or local or state authority. Such stop-bid\norder shall be served by regular mail, and a second copy may be served\nby telefacsimile or by electronic mail, with service effective upon\nreceipt of any of such notices. The order shall remain in effect until\nthe commissioner directs that the stop-bid order be removed, upon a\ndetermination that the agency, board, department, commission or officer\nof the state of New York, political subdivision, municipal corporation,\npublic benefit corporation or local or state authority has complied with\nthe separate specifications requirement. The agency, board, department,\ncommission or officer of the state of New York, political subdivision,\nmunicipal corporation, public benefit corporation or local or state\nauthority may within thirty days after notice of the stop-bid order make\nan application in affidavit form for a redetermination review of such\norder. The commissioner shall make a decision in writing on the issues\nraised in such application within thirty days of receipt of such\napplication.\n  2. The commissioner may file a complaint in the supreme court of any\ncounty where venue is proper to enjoin any agency, board, department,\ncommission or officer of the state of New York, political subdivision,\nmunicipal corporation, public benefit corporation or local or state\nauthority from violating a stop-bid order. In any action brought by the\ncommissioner pursuant to this section in which it prevails, the court\nmay award costs, including the reasonable costs of investigation and\nreasonable attorneys' fees.\n  3. In any court proceedings under this section, the commissioner shall\nbe represented by the attorney general.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>