<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-233"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-233"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-04-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="233"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-233/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-233/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-233/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-233/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_233">
        <num>233</num>
        <heading>Record keeping</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 233. Record keeping. 1. In all cases where service work is being\nperformed pursuant to a contract therefor the contractor shall keep\noriginal payrolls or transcripts thereof, subscribed and confirmed by\nhim as true, under penalties of perjury, showing the hours and days\nworked by each employee, the craft, trade or occupation at which he was\nemployed, and the wages paid.\n  2. Where the wages paid include sums which are not paid directly to\nthe workmen weekly and which are expended for supplements, the records\nrequired to be maintained shall include a record of such hourly payment\non behalf of such employees, the supplement for which such payment has\nbeen made, and the name and address of the person to whom such payment\nhas been made. In all such cases, the contractor shall keep a true and\ninscribed copy of the agreement under which such payments are made, a\nrecord of all net payments made thereunder, and a list of all persons\nfor whom such payments are made.\n  3. The records required to be maintained shall be kept on the site of\nthe work during all of the time that work under the contract is being\nperformed.\n  4. All records required to be maintained shall be preserved for a\nperiod of three years after the completion of work.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>