<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-02-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-27-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_A">
        <num>27-A</num>
        <heading>Safety and health standards for public employees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof the United States Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (Public\nLaw 91-596) which provides: "</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any State which, at any time, desires\nto assume responsibility for development and enforcement therein of\noccupational safety and health standards relating to any occupational\nsafety or health issue with respect to which a Federal standard has been\npromulgated under section 6 shall submit a State plan for the\ndevelopment of such standards and their enforcement."\n  4. Safety and health standards. a. The commissioner shall by rule\nadopt all safety and health standards promulgated under the United\nStates Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (Public Law, 91-596)\nwhich are in effect on the effective date of this section, in order to\nprovide reasonable and adequate protection to the lives, safety and\nhealth of public employees and shall promulgate and repeal such rules\nand regulations as may be necessary to conform to the standards\nestablished pursuant to such act or pursuant to paragraph b of this\nsubdivision.\n  b. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph a of this subdivision,\nthe commissioner, in consultation with the state occupational safety and\nhealth hazard abatement board, shall promulgate rules and regulations\nrecommended to him by such board which establish standards whenever such\nboard finds</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that no federal standard exists for the particular\ncondition being addressed and that such a standard is necessary for the\nprotection of the public employees at risk, or (ii) a federal standard\nexists, but conditions in public workplaces in this state require a\ndifferent standard, and such state standard will be at least as\neffective in providing safe and healthful places of employment as the\nfederal standard.\n  c. Except for an employer located in a city with a population of over\none million, any employer who employs a firefighter determined to be at\nrisk of entrapment at elevations pursuant to regulations promulgated by\nthe commissioner, shall provide emergency escape systems for use by such\nfirefighter. The commissioner shall by rule identify the codes,\nstandards and recommended practices of the National Fire Protection\nAssociation and other appropriate standards approved by the commissioner\nas are appropriate to the nature of the risk to which the firefighter\nshall be exposed and shall, at a minimum, include in such rule language\nrequiring employers to</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>identify whether firefighters employed by\nthem would be exposed to the hazard of entrapment at elevated surfaces;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>identify those firefighters who would be exposed to the hazard; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>determine the appropriate emergency escape systems to address the\nhazard. Such emergency escape systems shall be adequate to protect the\nhealth and safety of the firefighter. The employer shall ensure that the\nfirefighter is instructed in the proper use of the emergency escape\nsystems. As used in this subdivision, the term "entrapment at\nelevations" shall mean a situation where a fire or other emergency\nconditions require a firefighter inside a structure to immediately exit\nthe structure but where such conditions make the normal route of exit\nunusable, thereby requiring the firefighter to exit the structure from\nan opening that is not designed as an exit and is above the ground floor\nor at an elevation above the surrounding terrain that would reasonably\nbe expected to cause injury to a firefighter exiting by means of this\nopening without any emergency escape systems. As used in this\nsubdivision, the term "emergency escape system" shall mean safety ropes\nand system compone...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is compliant with\nthe codes, standards and recommended practices of the National Fire\nProtection Association or other appropriate standard identified by the\ncommissioner through regulation, as a means of emergency self-rescue\nfrom an above grade, immediately hazardous environment,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>has been\ncertified by a nationally recognized safety testing and certification\norganization, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the commissioner has recognized through\nregulation.\n  In order to ensure the adequacy of the emergency escape systems, the\nemployer must routinely inspect and ensure that:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Existing emergency escape systems meet the codes, standards and\nrecommended practices adopted by the commissioner.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Existing emergency escape systems still perform their function and\nto identify any of their limitations such as but not limited to:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Checking the labels or stamps on the equipment; and\n  (ii) Checking any documentation or equipment specifications; and\n  (iii) Contacting the supplier or the approval agency;\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Firefighters are informed of the limitations of emergency escape\nsystems;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Firefighters are not allowed or required to use any emergency\nescape systems beyond their limitations;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Existing and new emergency escape systems have no visible defects\nthat limit their safe use;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Emergency escape systems are used, cleaned, maintained and stored\naccording to manufacturer's instructions;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The firefighter is instructed in identifying to the employer any\ndefects that the firefighter may find in emergency escape systems; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any identified defects are corrected or immediate action is taken\nby the employer to eliminate the use of this equipment.\n  d. Any person who may be adversely affected by a standard issued under\nthis section may, within thirty days after the effective date of such\nstandard, commence a proceeding for judicial review pursuant to article\nseventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules.\n  5. Inspections. a. Any employee or representative of employees who\nbelieves that a violation of a safety or health standard exists, or that\nan imminent danger exists, may request an inspection by giving notice to\nthe commissioner of such violation or danger. Such notice and request\nshall be in writing, shall set forth with reasonable particularity the\ngrounds for the notice, shall be signed by such employee or\nrepresentative of employees, and a copy shall be provided by the\ncommissioner to the employer or the person in charge no later than the\ntime of inspection, except that on the request...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the United States\nOccupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (Public Law, 91-596), a\nserious violation shall be deemed to exist in a place of employment if\nthere is a substantial probability that death or serious physical harm\ncould result from a condition which exists, or from one or more\npractices, means, methods, operations, or processes which have been\nadopted or are in use, in such place of employment unless the employer\ndid not, and could not with the exercise of reasonable diligence, know\nof the presence of the violation. A non-serious violation shall be\ndefined as any violation that does not fall under the definition of\nserious violation. The commissioner shall not assess a penalty against\nan employer for failure to correct a violation of a standard which is\nthe subject of an application for a temporary order granting a variance\nor a violation which is the subject of a petition to modify an order to\ncomply, provided however, that upon issuance by the commissioner of a\ndetermination denying such variance or petition to modify, or upon\nexpiration of a temporary variance or modified compliance period, the\ntime fixed for compliance shall recommence and the employer become\nliable for the penalties provided herein.\n  b. Where the commissioner issues to an employer an order to comply,\nthe employer shall post such order or a copy thereof in a conspicuous\nplace at or near each place of violation cited in the order, where it is\nclearly visible to affected employees. The commissioner shall make such\norder available to employee representatives.\n  c. Any employer, or other party affected by a determination of the\nindustrial commissioner issued pursuant to this section may petition the\nindustrial board of appeals for review of such determination in\naccordance with section one hundred one of this chapter. Judicial review\nof the decision of the industrial board of appeals may be obtained by\nany party affected by such decision by commencing a ...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nhe is unable to comply with a standard by its effective date because of\nunavailability of professional or technical personnel or of materials\nand equipment needed to come into compliance with the standard or\nbecause necessary construction or alteration of facilities cannot be\ncompleted by the effective date,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>he is taking all available steps to\nsafeguard employees against the hazards covered by the standard, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nhe has an effective program for coming into compliance with the standard\nas quickly as practicable. Any temporary order issued under this\nsubdivision shall prescribe the practices, means, methods, operations\nand processes which the employer must adopt and use while the order is\nin effect and state in detail his program for coming into compliance\nwith the standard. Such a temporary order may be granted only after\nnotice to employees and an opportunity for a hearing, provided the\ncommissioner may issue one interim order to be effective until a\ndecision is made on the basis of the hearing. No temporary order may be\nin effect for longer than the period needed by the employer to achieve\ncompliance with the standard or one year, whichever is shorter, except\nthat such an order may be renewed not more than twice so long as the\nrequirements of this subdivision are met and if an application for\nrenewal is filed at least ninety days prior to the expiration date of\nthe order. No in...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a\nspecification of the standard or portion thereof from which the employer\nor owner seeks a variance;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a representation by the employer,\nsupported by representations from qualified persons who have firsthand\nknowledge of the facts represented, that he is unable to comply with the\nstandard or portion thereof and a detailed statement of the reasons\ntherefor;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a statement of the steps he has taken and will take, with\nspecific dates, to protect employees against the hazard covered by the\nstandard;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a statement of when he expects to be able to comply with\nthe standard and what steps he has taken and what steps he will take,\nwith dates specified, to come into compliance with the standard; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\na certification that he has informed his employees of the application by\ngiving a copy thereof to their authorized representative, posting a\nstatement giving a summary of the application and specifying where a\ncopy may be examined at the place or places where notices to employees\nare normally posted, and by other appropriate means. A description of\nhow employees have been informed shall be contained in the\ncertification. The information to employees shall also inform them of\ntheir right to petition the commissioner for a hearing. The commissioner\nis also authorized to grant a variance from any standard or portion\nthereof whenever he determines that such variance is necessary to permit\nan employer to participate in an experiment approved by him designed to\ndemonstrate or validate new and improved techniques to safeguard the\nhealth or safety of workers.\n  c. Any affected employer may apply to the commissioner for a rule or\norder for a variance from a standard promulgated ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the degree of possible physical harm which the hazard to be abated\ncould inflict on the public employees and other citizens at risk;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the imminent nature of the possible infliction of harm;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_A__subsec_k__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the number of public employees and other citizens at risk;\n  (B) a. The board shall have the power, and it shall be its duty to\nreceive, review, and act upon applications for funding for programs\ndesigned to provide occupational safety and health training and\neducation for employees pursuant to the provisions of article\ntwenty-nine of this chapter.\n  b. The board shall, by the promulgation of rules and regulations,\nestablish procedures and criteria that are necessary and appropriate to\ncarry out the provisions of article twenty-nine of this chapter, which\nshall include criteria for the evaluation and selection of applications\nfor grants and the auditing of performance thereunder.\n  (C) a. The board may require as part of such applications made\npursuant to the provisions of this subdivision such information as it\ndeems necessary and shall act upon such applications within a reasonable\ntime.  The board shall furnish the state budget director, state\nindustrial commissioner,...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>