<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-299"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-299"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="299"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-299/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-299/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-299/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-299/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_299">
        <num>299</num>
        <heading>Ventilation, heating and humidity</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 299. Ventilation, heating and humidity. 1. Every work room in a\nfactory shall be provided with proper and sufficient means of\nventilation, natural or mechanical or both, as may be necessary, and\nthere shall be maintained therein proper and sufficient ventilation and\nproper degrees of temperature and humidity at all times during the\nworking hours. If owing to the nature of the manufacturing process\ncarried on in the factory work room excessive heat be created therein,\nthere shall be provided, maintained and operated such special means or\nappliances as may be required to reduce such excessive heat.\n  2. All machinery creating dust or impurities in quantities tending to\ninjure the health of employees shall be equipped with proper hoods and\npipes connected to an exhaust fan of sufficient capacity and power to\nremove such dusts or impurities; such fan shall be kept running\nconstantly while such machinery is in use. If the board decides that\nsuch apparatus is unnecessary for the health and welfare of the\nemployees, or that other means of protection may be provided to\nsafeguard the health and welfare of the employees against such injurious\ndusts or impurities, it may adopt rules excepting such machinery from\nthe operation of this subdivision, or prescribing such requirements as\nwill effectuate the intent of this subdivision.\n  3. If dust, gases, fumes, vapors, fibers or other impurities are\ngenerated or released in the course of the business carried on in any\nworkroom of a factory, in quantities tending to injure the health of the\nemployees, suction devices shall be provided which shall remove such\nimpurities from the workroom, at their point of origin where\npracticable, by means of proper hoods connected to conduits and exhaust\nfans. Such fans shall be kept running constantly while the impurities\nare being generated or released.\n  4. The board shall make rules for and fix standards of ventilation,\ntemperature and humidity in factories and shall prescribe the special\nmeans, if any, required for removing impurities or for reducing\nexcessive heat, and the machinery, apparatus or appliances to be used\nfor any of said purposes, and the construction, equipment, maintenance\nand operation thereof.\n  5. If any requirement of this section or any rule adopted thereunder\nbe not complied with, the commissioner shall issue an order directing\ncompliance therewith within thirty days after the service thereof.  He\nmay in such order require plans and specifications to be filed. In such\ncase, before providing or making any change or alteration in any\nmachinery or apparatus for any of the purposes specified in this\nsection, the person upon whom such order is served shall file with the\ncommissioner plans and specifications therefor and shall obtain his\napproval of the same.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>