<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-33"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-33"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="33"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-33/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-33/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-33/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-33/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33">
        <num>33</num>
        <heading>Service of notice</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 33. Service of notice. 1. Notwithstanding any other law, rule, or\nregulation, whenever the commissioner or board or any person affected by\nthe provisions of this chapter is required to give notice in writing to\nany person, such notice may be given by mailing it in a letter addressed\nto the last known place of business of such person, by delivering it to\nthe person personally, or by electronic communication with the consent\nof the person in accordance with subdivision two of this section. Notice\nto a partnership may be given to any of the partners, notice to a\ncorporation may be given to any officer or agent thereof, and notice to\na limited liability company may be given to any member or agent thereof,\nupon whom a summons may be served as provided by the civil practice law\nand rules, or by electronic communication with the consent of the entity\nin accordance with subdivision two of this section. Consent for any\nentity may be provided by a partner, officer, agent, member, owner, or\nother similar individual. Whenever an order or demand of the department\nis required to be served it shall be served in the manner hereinbefore\nprovided for the service of a notice, by delivering it to any person of\nsuitable age and discretion in charge of the premises affected by such\norder or demand, or by electronic communication with the consent of the\nperson in accordance with subdivision two of this section, or if no\nperson is found in charge by affixing a copy thereof conspicuously upon\nthe premises.\n  2. For the purposes of this section, a person or entity shall be\ndeemed to have consented to electronic communication if, having been\nadvised conspicuously that enrollment or registration is voluntary and\nthat they may continue to receive notices by mail or personal service as\nprovided in this section, they instead affirmatively choose to receive\nnotices by electronic communications only.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>