<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-341"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-341"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="341"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_341">
        <num>341</num>
        <heading>Registration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 341. Registration. 1. No manufacturer or contractor shall engage in\nthe apparel industry unless he or she registers with the commissioner,\nin writing, on a form provided by the commissioner, which shall contain\nthe following information: whether it is a sole proprietorship,\npartnership or corporation, its name, address and number of production\nemployees, the name, home address and social security number of each\nowner or partner, or if the registrant is a corporation, no shares of\nwhich are listed on a national securities exchange or regularly quoted\nin an over-the-counter market by one or more members of a national or an\naffiliated securities association, of each officer and of each of the\nten largest shareholders thereof, how long it has been in business, its\ntax identification number, whether it is a manufacturer or contractor,\nthe name and address of each person with a financial interest in the\nmanufacturer's or contractor's business and the amount of that interest,\nexcept that if the manufacturer or contractor is a publicly-traded\ncorporation, only the names and addresses of the corporation officers\nshall be required, whether it is in contractual relations with a labor\norganization and, if so, the name and address of such labor\norganization, a statement as to whether the registrant or any owner of\nor partner in, or if the registrant is a corporation, no shares of which\nare listed on a national securities exchange or regularly quoted in an\nover-the-counter market by one or more members of a national or an\naffiliated securities association, any officer or any of the ten largest\nshareholders thereof has, within the last three years, been found by any\ncourt or administrative body to have violated this chapter and, if so,\nthe nature and date of such violation and, if the registrant is a\ncontractor, whether that contractor subcontracts the cutting or sewing\nof apparel or sections or components thereof. Such registration form\nshall also require that each owner or partner, or if the registrant is a\ncorporation, then each officer, submit photographic proof of identity.\nDivisions, subsidiary corporations or related companies may, at the\noption of the manufacturer or contractor, be named and included under\none omnibus registration. Such registration shall be filed on or before\nJanuary fifteenth of each year. The commissioner shall issue a\ncertificate of registration, which shall be effective for a period of\ntwelve months, upon receipt of a completed registration form accompanied\nby the requisite photographic proof of identity and documentation that\nsuch manufacturer or contractor has paid any surety bond required\npursuant to subdivision eight of section three hundred forty-five of\nthis article and that a workers' compensation insurance policy is in\neffect for the registrant's production employees working in New York\nstate. The initial registration fee shall be two hundred dollars and\neach subsequent annual renewal registration fee shall be one hundred\nfifty dollars. With respect to new employers, such registration shall be\nfiled upon the commencement of manufacturing or contracting in the\napparel industry and shall be effective until the following January\nfifteenth. The commissioner may pro rate the initial annual registration\nfee in such instances.\n  2. Proof of registration shall be by an official department\nregistration certificate which shall be posted where it may be read by\nemployees during the workday.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>