<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-342"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-342"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="342"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-342/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-342/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-342/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-342/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_342">
        <num>342</num>
        <heading>Establishment of a special task force</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 342. Establishment of a special task force. The commissioner is\nauthorized to establish a special task force for the purpose of\nconcentrating enforcement of the labor law affecting production\nemployees in the apparel industry in New York state and otherwise\nexercising the duties and powers set forth in sections three hundred\nforty-three and three hundred forty-four of this article. Such special\ntask force shall be empowered to investigate and conduct inspections at\nlocations where an apparel industry contractor is operating.\n  The commissioner is further authorized to publish on the internet\nlistings of those persons and entities investigated by the department or\nthe special task force on the apparel industry and found not to be in\ncompliance with the law. The listing shall include all relevant\ninformation concerning the violators included in the registration\nprocess in accordance with section three hundred forty-one of this\narticle. The listing shall be updated regularly, not less than monthly,\namended to be adjusted for new instances of non-compliance. Any retailer\nor manufacturer or contractor requesting verification of the\nregistration status of a manufacturer or contractor shall be provided\nwith a reference to this internet web site listing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>