<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-351"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-351"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="351"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-351/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-351/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-351/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-351/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_351">
        <num>351</num>
        <heading>Powers of the industrial commissioner and exceptions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 351. Powers of the industrial commissioner and exceptions. 1.  The\nindustrial commissioner shall, after proper study and consideration,\ndetermine within what industries conditions may permit of industrial\nhomework as hereinbefore defined without unduly jeopardizing the factory\nworkers in such industries as to both wages and working conditions and\nwithout unduly injuring the health and welfare of the industrial\nhomeworker himself. The commissioner may then restrict the granting of\npermits and licenses for industrial homework as herein defined to such\nindustries and may further issue rules and regulations designed to\ncontrol and regulate industrial homework in the said permitted\nindustries. In all other industries industrial homework is forbidden\nunless expressly permitted in writing by the industrial commissioner.\n  2. a. Exception to this article shall be made by the industrial\ncommissioner in respect of clerical work done in a home. "Clerical work"\nshall mean typing, stenciling, transcribing, copying, bookkeeping and\nstenographic work. Clerical work shall not mean inserting, collating,\nlabeling, nesting, sorting, stamping or similar work.\n  b. Exception to this article may be made by the industrial\ncommissioner in respect of such other provisions consonant with the\ngeneral purpose of this article as the commissioner may on study\ndetermine to be warranted by conditions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>