<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-426"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-426"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="426"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-426/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-426/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-426/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-426/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_426">
        <num>426</num>
        <heading>Equipment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 426. Equipment. Every employer of persons for work in compressed air\nshall:\n  1. Connect at least two air pipes with the working chamber and keep\nsuch pipes in perfect working condition;\n  2. Attach to the working chamber in accessible positions all\ninstruments necessary to show its pressure and keep such instruments in\ncharge of competent persons, with a period of duty for each such person\nnot exceeding eight hours in any twenty-four;\n  3. Place in each shaft a safe ladder extending its entire length;\n  4. Light properly and keep clear each passageway;\n  5. Provide independent lighting systems for the working chamber and\nshaft leading to it, when electricity is used for lighting;\n  6. Guard lights other than electric lights;\n  7. Protect workmen by a shield erected in the working chamber when\nsuch chamber is less than ten feet long and is suspended with more than\nnine feet space between its deck and the bottom of the excavation;\n  8. Provide for and keep accessible to employees working in compressed\nair a dressing room heated, lighted and ventilated properly and supplied\nwith benches, lockers, sanitary waterclosets, bathing facilities and hot\nand cold water;\n  9. Establish and maintain a medical lock properly heated, lighted,\nventilated and supplied with medicines and surgical implements, when the\nmaximum air pressure exceeds seventeen pounds.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>