<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-44"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-44"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-12-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="44"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-44/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-44/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-44/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-44/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44">
        <num>44</num>
        <heading>Workplace fatality registry; construction</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name of the worker;\n  (ii) the age of the worker;\n  (iii) the cause of death;\n  (iv) the manner of death;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the location of death;\n  (vi) the name of the contractor;\n  (vii) the business address of the contractor;\n  (viii) the name of the official or medical personnel making the\ndeclaration of death;\n  (ix) the name of the person or persons charged with making the\ndetermination of the cause and manner of death; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contact information for the office making notification to the\ndepartment, including contact information for the person or persons\nmaking the declaration of death, the person or persons determining the\ncause of death, and the person or persons determining the manner of\ndeath.\n  4. Ninety-day reports. a. Upon receiving a report pursuant to\nsubdivision three of this section, the department shall notify the\ncontractor that such death was determined to be the result of a\nwork-related fatal injury in the workplace and shall require the\ncontractor to submit additional information regarding such workplace\nfatality. The contractor shall provide such information to the\ndepartment no later than ninety days after receiving such notification.\n  b. Information to be reported within ninety days shall include, but\nnot be limited to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name of the contractor;\n  (ii) the business address of the contractor;\n  (iii) the stated business purpose or industry of the contractor;\n  (iv) the name and age of the worker;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the ethnicity of the worker, if known;\n  (vi) the nationality of the worker, if known;\n  (vii) the immigration status of the worker, if known;\n  (viii) the craft, trade or occupation of the worker; and\n  (ix) the union status of the worker.\n  5. Investigation. The department in its sole discretion may also:\n  a. conduct an investigation into any work-related fatal injury in the\nworkplace involving a worker performing construction work;\n  b. request additional information from a contractor in relation to\nsuch worker or such workplace fatality; and\n  c. request information as to whether criminal or civil charges have\nbeen filed against the contractor in the death of the worker, including:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_44__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the details of such criminal or civil charges including the\ncharging officer or agency; and\n  (ii) the actual criminal or civil charge or charges.\n  6. Reporting system. The department shall establish a reporting system\nfor the information required to be reported pursuant to subdivisions\nthree and four of this section.\n  7. Failure to report. Failure by any contractor to report the\ninformation required pursuant to subdivision four of this section within\nninety days of notification by the department that such death was the\nresult of a work-related fatal injury in the workplace shall be subject\nto a fine of not less than one thousand dollars nor more than two\nthousand five hundred dollars per failure to make such report.\n  8. Accessibility of registry. The department shall establish and\nmaintain an online database to make available all information and data\nregarding all workplace fatalities in the construction industry reported\nto the registry pursuant to this section. Such information shall be\nprovided in the aggregate and shall be electronically accessible and\nsearchable to the public, provided however, that in no event shall a\nworker's name or other personal identifying information be included in\nsuch database. The department shall update the database with the\ninformation reported to the registry pursuant to this section within\nfive business days of the receipt of such reports by the department.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>