<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-455"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-455"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="455"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-455/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-455/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-455/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-455/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_455">
        <num>455</num>
        <heading>Magazine precautions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 455. Magazine precautions. 1. No individual shall unlock, open the\ndoors of, or access the contents of, explosive magazines, except for the\nlawful storage or removal of explosives and in accordance with\nregulations of the commissioner. No employer shall allow any individual\naccess to the explosive magazines or explosives of the employer unless a\nlicense has been issued to the individual by the commissioner as\nprovided in this article, or the individual is under the direct\nsupervision of the license holder.\n  No person shall have matches or fire of any kind in any magazine. No\nperson shall store or keep blasting caps, detonating or fulminating\ncaps, or detonators in a magazine in which any other type of explosive\nis stored or kept. No person shall open any package of explosives within\nfifty feet of any magazine, nor shall any explosives be kept in a\nmagazine except in the original containers, or as otherwise provided by\nregulations promulgated under this article. No person shall discharge\nfirearms within five hundred feet of a magazine or explosives factory,\nor at or against any such building or magazine. Any theft or loss of\nexplosives from a storage magazine or otherwise, shall immediately be\nreported to the commissioner and the state or local police or county\nsheriff.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>