<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-457"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-457"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="457"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-457/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-457/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-457/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-457/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_457">
        <num>457</num>
        <heading>Relocation of magazines</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 457. Relocation of magazines. 1. When any magazine is moved from the\nlocation for which it was certified according to section four hundred\nfifty-six of this article, and the magazine is or is intended to be used\nfor the storage of explosives and will be in the new location for more\nthan twenty-four hours, the commissioner shall be notified as to the new\nlocation of the magazine. Such notification shall be made no later than\none business day prior to the move. The notification shall contain all\nof the information required by the commissioner.\n  2. The provisions of subdivision one of this section shall not apply\nwhere the relocation has been ordered by police, fire or other\nauthorized emergency personnel, or where the continued storage in the\ncurrent location would constitute a threat to life or property. In such\ncases the commissioner shall be notified as soon as practicable after\nthe relocation but in no case more than two business days following such\nrelocation.\n  3. When a magazine is abandoned, sold or removed from service, the\ncertificate holder shall notify the commissioner no later than three\nbusiness days from the date of such action and shall surrender the\ncertificate to the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>