<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-458"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-458"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="458"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-458/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-458/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-458/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-458/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_458">
        <num>458</num>
        <heading>Licenses and certificates</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_458__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The investigation prescribed in subdivision five of this\nsection may include, but is not limited to the following:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_458__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a personal interview of the applicant by a designated agent of the\ncommissioner if the commissioner is unable to make a determination on\nthe basis of the factors contained in the application;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_458__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>an examination as to the applicant's knowledge and ability with\nrespect to basic safety precautions in the possession, handling,\nstorage, manufacture and transportation of explosives, and for such\npurpose the commissioner may prescribe tests which the applicant shall\nbe required to pass as a prerequisite to the issuance of the license or\ncertificate. The test may be administered by any person or agency\ndesignated by the commissioner.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_458__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The investigation prescribed in subdivision five of this section\nshall include a report from the New York state identification and\nintelligence system, and such other identification services of the state\nor federal government as may be necessary or appropriate for this\npurpose.\n  7. The commissioner may waive any of the procedures set forth in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_458__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision six of this section with respect to any\napplicant for whom criminal history or other information has been\nobtained from any federal bureau or agency.\n  8. Except for the provisions of subdivision eleven of this section,\nthis section shall not apply to smokeless powder.\n  9. Within thirty days after the issuance of a license or certificate\nunder this section, the commissioner shall notify the chief executive\nofficer of the municipality where the licensee resides or where the\ncertificate holder has his or her place of business of the issuance of\nsuch license or certificate, and provide such officer with such other\ninformation pertaining thereto as the commissioner may prescribe.\n  10. Agencies of the United States, the state and its political and\ncivil subdivisions which are subject to the requirements of this article\nand which, in the exercise of their functions, are required to purchase,\nown, store, use or transport explosives shall not be liable for the\npayment of any fee required by this section.\n  11. No explosives shall be sold, given or delivered to any individual\nunder eighteen years of age, whether such individual is acting for\nhimself, herself or for another person, nor shall any such individual be\neligible to obtain any license or certificate required under this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>