<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-461"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-461"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="461"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-461/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-461/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-461/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-461/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_461">
        <num>461</num>
        <heading>Record and notice of sales, deliveries or gifts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 461. Record and notice of sales, deliveries or gifts. 1. Every\nperson selling, delivering, giving away or otherwise transferring or\ndisposing of explosives shall keep at his or her principal office or\nplace of business within the state, a record of the transaction,\nincluding the name or type and quantity of the explosive, such\nidentification of the explosive as may be required by the regulations\npromulgated pursuant to this article, the date of each sale, delivery,\ngift, transfer or disposition, the name and business address of the\npurchaser, donee, recipient or person to whom delivered, the number of\nthe license, if such license is required by section four hundred\nfifty-eight of this article, and the name and address of the person\ntaking the explosives away. A report of all such transactions, when\nrequested, shall be submitted to the commissioner. Such record shall be\nopen to inspection by the commissioner or by federal, state and local\nenforcement officers at all times. No person shall have in his or her\npossession any explosives unless he or she has a bill of sale or other\nevidence of title thereto.\n  2. Any provision in this article to the contrary notwithstanding, no\nperson in a city having more than one million inhabitants shall ship or\ntransport or cause to be shipped or transported explosives from such\ncity to any other place within the state, unless such person shall, at\nleast twenty-four hours prior to such shipment, transmit to the\ncommissioner a statement in writing giving the weight, name or brand and\ntype of explosives, the name and address of the person to whom such\nexplosives are to be sold, shipped, transported or delivered and the\ndate thereof. Upon receipt of such statement, the commissioner shall\nprovide immediate written notice of such shipment or transportation of\nexplosives to the mayor of a city having more than one million\ninhabitants, or to the designee of the mayor. No person shall make any\nsuch shipment except to a holder of a license issued hereunder.\n  3. No person within the state shall purchase, receive or accept\ndelivery of explosives from any place outside the state, and no person\nshall bring explosives into the state from any place outside the state,\nunless, he or she is in possession of a valid license issued by the\ncommissioner. The licensee receiving the explosives shall maintain a\nrecord including the weight, name or brand and type of the explosives,\nthe name and address of the shipper and the date of shipment, for a\nperiod of three years from the date of receipt or two years from the\ndate of final disposition of the explosives whichever occurs last.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>