<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-530"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-530"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="530"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-530/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-530/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_530">
        <num>530</num>
        <heading>Industrial commissioner's powers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 530. Industrial commissioner's powers. 1. General powers.  The\ncommissioner shall administer this article and for such purpose he shall\nhave power to make all rules and regulations and, subject to the\nregulations of the civil service, to appoint such officers and employees\nas may be necessary in the administration of this article.\n  2. Powers and duties in respect to the national employment service.\nThe state of New York accepts the provisions of an act of the congress\nof the United States effective June sixth, nineteen hundred\nthirty-three, entitled "An act to provide for the establishment of a\nnational employment system and for cooperation with the states in the\npromotion of such system, and for other purposes." Such act is in this\narticle otherwise referred to as "Wagner-Peyser Act".\n  The commissioner is hereby designated as the agent of the state as\nrequired by such act of congress and as such agent is hereby authorized,\nempowered and directed to cooperate with the United States employment\nservice under and pursuant to the terms, conditions, provisions and\nrequirements of such act and he shall have and exercise all powers\nnecessary therefor. The commissioner is hereby further authorized,\nempowered and directed to take such steps and to formulate such plans\nand to execute such projects as may be necessary or appropriate to\nobtain for and on behalf of the state the full benefits, advantages and\nprivileges derivable under and pursuant to such act of congress.\n  3. Acceptance of moneys. The commissioner is authorized to accept\nmoneys to be used in carrying out any of the purposes of this article.\n  4. Claims for damages to personal property. The commissioner is\nauthorized to approve, for payment out of the unemployment\nadministration fund, notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of the\ncourt of claims act, any claim for damage to personal property made by\nan employee of the department whose salary is paid out of that fund\nresulting from the deliberate act of any claimant for benefits,\napplicant for placement, employer, or other person acting on behalf of a\nclaimant, applicant, or employer arising out of official business of the\ndepartment. Payment of such claim shall be limited to the sum of one\nhundred fifty dollars and shall be subject to the prior approval of the\ncomptroller and the attorney general.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>