<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-531"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-531"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="531"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-531/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-531/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-531/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-531/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_531">
        <num>531</num>
        <heading>Regularization of employment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 531. Regularization of employment.  One of the purposes of this\narticle is to promote the regularization of employment in enterprises,\nindustries, localities, and the state. The commissioner shall take such\nsteps as are within his means for the reduction and prevention of\nunemployment and to promote the reemployment of all unemployed workers.\nTo this end the commissioner may employ experts and may carry on and\npublish the results of any investigations and research which he deems\nrelevant, whether or not directly related to the other purposes and\nspecific provisions of this article. Also to this end, the commissioner\nshall undertake investigations of technological developments in industry\nin order to obtain information necessary for evaluating the effects of\nsuch developments on the geographical, industrial, and occupational\nemployment patterns of the state. The commissioner shall also undertake\ninvestigations of occupational training needs of workers unemployed\nbecause of technological developments, the availability of facilities\nfor this purpose, and ways and means for establishing required\nfacilities where this step is needed, and shall co-operate to this end\nwith appropriate education authorities.  The commissioner shall bring\nthe findings of such investigations to the attention of education\nauthorities, labor organizations, employers and other appropriate\nbodies, public and private, in order that educational and training\nefforts shall be appropriate to the changing occupational needs of\nindustry and shall be channeled in the direction of expanding\noccupational opportunities for the labor force. The commissioner shall\nalso utilize such findings in connection with his responsibilities for\nthe development and encouragement of, and recruitment for,\napprenticeship training activities. The commissioner shall by these and\nother appropriate means assist labor and management in the development\nof higher occupational skills commensurate with the changing\nrequirements of industry in the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>