<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-532"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-532"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="532"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-532/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-532/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-532/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-532/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_532">
        <num>532</num>
        <heading>Employment districts and offices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 532. Employment districts and offices.  1. Establishment and\nmaintenance. The commissioner may divide the state into such number of\nemployment districts as he finds necessary to carry out the provisions\nof this article and maintain a district office in each of said\ndistricts. The commissioner shall establish such number of local\nemployment offices as he finds necessary, which offices, in addition to\nthe other duties prescribed herein and by the commissioner, shall act as\nfree public employment exchanges.\n  Such exchanges shall provide and maintain special services for\nunskilled workers and public assistance recipients, which services shall\ninclude but not be limited to:  maintenance of current registers of all\nopportunities for employment in which such workers and recipients would\nbe able to engage which are brought to the attention of such exchanges;\nspecial activities to seek out and develop employment opportunities for\nsuch workers and recipients; employment preparation services; and\ncontinued counseling before and after referral of such workers and\nrecipients to employment opportunities.\n  2. Cooperation with other agencies. The commissioner is authorized to\ncooperate with or to enter into agreements with the federal railroad\nretirement board or any other agency of the United States charged with\nthe administration of an unemployment compensation law, with any\npolitical subdivision of this state, or with any private non-profit\norganization, with respect to the establishment, maintenance, and use of\nfree employment service facilities and free public employment offices,\nand as a part of any such agreement the commissioner may accept moneys,\nservices, or quarters as a contribution to the special "employment\nservice account" in the unemployment administration fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>