<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-539"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-539"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="539"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-539/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-539/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-539/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-539/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_539">
        <num>539</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of land and buildings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 539. Acquisition of land and buildings. The commissioner of general\nservices, on the recommendation of the industrial commissioner and with\nthe approval of the director of the budget and on behalf of the state,\nis hereby authorized\n  (1) to purchase land with or without buildings;\n  (2) to erect buildings thereon;\n  (3) to enter into contracts with any person, firm or corporation which\nshall agree to erect on land owned by such person, firm or corporation,\nsuitable buildings at locations acceptable to the commissioner of\ngeneral services and the industrial commissioner, and to agree on behalf\nof the state to lease such land and buildings for a period of not more\nthan fifteen years from the time of the completion of said buildings at\nsuch rentals and subject to such terms and conditions as may be agreed\nupon; such contract shall contain the plans and specifications for the\nproposed buildings, which must be approved by the industrial\ncommissioner and the commissioner of general services; each such\ncontract and lease shall provide that upon the termination of said\nlease, or upon the earlier payment in full of the total amount specified\ntherein the lessor shall convey to the state title in fee simple to the\nland and buildings covered under said lease;\n  (4) to enter into lease-purchase contracts as specified under (3)\nabove with respect to buildings already in existence:\n  (5) to purchase and to provide for fixtures, equipment and facilities\nin connection with the said buildings or premises and to make necessary\nalterations and improvements thereof.\n  The provisions of section one hundred sixty-one-a of the state finance\nlaw limiting the period for which the commissioner of general services\nis authorized to lease premises to a term not exceeding five years shall\nnot be applicable to leases executed in accordance with this section.\n  Space in each of such buildings shall be primarily utilized by the\ncommissioner for the administration of this article, but space in any\nsuch building in excess of such requirements, as determined by the\nindustrial commissioner, may be rented or sub-leased under an agreement\nentered into by the commissioner of general services only to the state\nof New York, or any agency or authority of the state of New York. Rents\nreceived under such agreement shall be paid into the unemployment\nadministration fund. However, if, in connection with such building,\nmoneys were advanced by the special fund to carry out the purposes of\nthis section, the rents received under such agreement shall be paid into\nthe said fund until such time as it shall be fully reimbursed for such\nadvances. In addition, under such circumstances, an agreement shall be\nentered into between the commissioner and the commissioner of general\nservices pursuant to which the fair rental value of all space in such\nbuilding utilized by the commissioner shall be determined and a transfer\nof amounts equal to such rental value out of the unemployment\nadministration fund to the special fund is hereby authorized until the\nspecial fund shall be fully reimbursed for such advances. The fair\nrental value of space utilized by the commissioner shall not exceed the\nprevailing rental rate for suitable space in privately owned buildings\nin the same locality.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>