<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-552-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-552-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="552-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-552-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-552-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-552-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-552-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_552_B">
        <num>552-B</num>
        <heading>Unemployment insurance control fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_552_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\ntwo of section five hundred eighty-one of this article, the department's\nshare of all penalties imposed and collected pursuant to paragraph one\nof subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_552_B__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section six hundred eighty-five of the tax law, and\nall other moneys credited or transferred thereto from any other fund or\nsources pursuant to law.\n  3. Moneys in the unemployment insurance control fund shall be kept\nseparate from and shall not be commingled with any other moneys in the\ncustody of the commissioner of taxation and finance and the state\ncomptroller. All deposits of such moneys shall, if required by the state\ncomptroller, be secured by obligations of the United States or of this\nstate of market value equal at all times to the amount of the deposit\nand all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such securities\nfor such deposits.\n  4. Moneys of the unemployment insurance control fund shall be used for\nthe location and prevention of fraud and abuse, collection and\nenforcement activities, benefit payment control activities and other\nquality control activities related to the unemployment insurance\nprogram. The moneys shall be paid out of the unemployment insurance\ncontrol fund on the audit and warrant of the state comptroller on\nvouchers certified or approved by the commissioner or his or her duly\ndesignated officer. Any balance in such fund shall not lapse at any time\nbut shall remain continuously available for such purposes.\n  5. The unemployment insurance control fund shall not be used in whole\nor in part for any purpose or in any manner which</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_552_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>would permit its\nsubstitution for, or a corresponding reduction in, federal funds that\nwould be available in its absence to finance expenditures for the\nadministration of this article; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_552_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>would cause the appropriate\nagency of the United States government to withhold any part of an\nadministrative grant which would otherwise be made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>