<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-581-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-581-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="581-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-581-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-581-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-581-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-581-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_581_C">
        <num>581-C</num>
        <heading>Amnesty program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fifty percent or more of the\namount due as computed by such employer is paid with such application or\nwithin the time stated on a bill issued by the commissioner, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nbalance due, including interest, is paid, in no more than two\ninstallments on or before May fifteenth, nineteen hundred ninety-eight\nor the date prescribed therefor on a bill issued by the commissioner.\n  6. Amnesty shall not be granted to any contributor who is a party to\nany criminal investigation being conducted by an agency of the state or\nany political subdivision thereof or is a party to any civil or criminal\nlitigation which is pending on the date of the employer's application in\nany court of this state or the United States relating to any action or\nfailure to act which is the basis for the penalty with respect to which\namnesty is sought. A civil litigation shall be deemed not to be pending\non the date of the application if the employer withdraws from such\nlitigation prior to the granting of amnesty.\n  7. Amnesty contribution return forms shall be in a form prescribed by\nthe commissioner and shall provide for specifications by the applicant\nof the contribution liability with the respect to which amnesty is\nsought. The applicant shall also provide such additional information as\nrequired by the commissioner. Amnesty shall be granted only with respect\nto contribution liabilities specified by the employer on such forms. Any\nreturn or report filed under the amnesty program established in this\nsection is subject to verification and assessment as provided by law. If\nthe applicant files a false or fraudulent contribution return or report,\nor attempts in any manner to defeat or evade a contribution under the\namnesty program, amnesty may be denied or rescinded.\n  8. No refund shall be granted or credit allowed with respect to any\npenalty paid prior to the time the employer applies for amnesty pursuant\nto subdivision four of this section.\n  9. Unless the commissioner on his or her own motion redetermines the\namount of contribution due, including applicable interest, no refund\nshall be granted or credit allowed with respect to any contrib...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of cases in which requests for penalty and interest\npenalty waivers were made;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the number of cases in which requests for penalty plus interest\nwaivers were approved;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of contribution and interest due in all approved and\nunapproved cases;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of penalty and interest penalty waived in all approved\ncases;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the gross revenue collected and the year or other applicable\nperiod for or during which the liability incurred;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of money spent on advertising, notification and\noutreach activities, by each activity;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount paid by the department for services and expenses\nrelated to the establishment of the amnesty program;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an estimate of the amount of revenue foregone as a result of\ndiverting staff of the department from regular work responsibilities to\nwork on the amnesty program;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an estimate of the amount of revenue received during the period of\namnesty program provided for in this section which would have otherwise\nbeen received at a later date; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_581_C__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an estimate of the set revenue generated from the amnesty program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>