<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-622"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-622"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="622"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-622/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-622/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-622/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-622/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_622">
        <num>622</num>
        <heading>Rules governing hearings and appeals</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 622. Rules governing hearings and appeals. 1. Rules and regulations.\nThe manner in which disputes and appeals shall be presented before\nreferees and the appeal board, respectively, and the conduct of hearings\nbefore referees and the board shall be governed by suitable rules and\nregulations established by the board.\n  2. Evidence and procedure. At any hearing held as herein provided,\nevidence may be offered to support a determination, rule, or order or to\nprove that it is incorrect. The appeal board and the referees, in\nhearings and appeals under any provision of this article, shall not be\nbound by common law or statutory rules of evidence or by technical or\nformal rules of procedure but may conduct the hearings and appeals in\nsuch manner as to ascertain the substantial rights of the parties.\nHearings governed by this article may be closed and hearing transcripts\nmay be redacted in accordance with applicable federal or state statutory\nand regulatory requirements governing information confidentiality and\npersonal privacy, including, but not limited to, article six and article\nsix-A of the public officers law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>