<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-656"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-656"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="656"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-656/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-656/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-656/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-656/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_656">
        <num>656</num>
        <heading>Action by commissioner upon wage board report</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 656. Action by commissioner upon wage board report.  When the wage\nboard submits its report and recommendations to the commissioner, the\ncommissioner shall forthwith file them with the secretary of the\ndepartment. Within five days of their receipt, the commissioner shall\npublish a notice of such filing in at least ten newspapers of general\ncirculation in the state. Any objections to the report and\nrecommendations shall be filed with the commissioner within fifteen days\nafter such publication. The commissioner may, if he deems it\nappropriate, order oral argument, which shall be scheduled before the\ncommissioner, or such representative as he may designate, on five days'\nnotice to the persons who have filed objections to the report and\nrecommendations. Whether or not oral argument is scheduled, the\ncommissioner shall by order accept or reject the board's report and\nrecommendations within forty-five days after filing with the secretary\nof the department. The commissioner may by such order modify the\nregulations recommended by the board. Such order of the commissioner\nshall become effective thirty days after publication, in the manner\nprescribed in this section, of a notice of such order. The commissioner\nmay, within such forty-five days, confer with the wage board, which may\nmake such changes in its report or recommendations as it may deem fit.\nThe commissioner also may, within such forty-five days, remand the\nmatter to the board for such further proceeding as he may direct.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>