<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-659"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-659"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="659"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-659/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-659/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-659/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-659/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_659">
        <num>659</num>
        <heading>Reconsideration of wage orders and regulations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 659. Reconsideration of wage orders and regulations.  1. By wage\nboard. At any time after a minimum wage order has been in effect for six\nmonths or more, the commissioner, on his own motion or on a petition of\nfifty or more residents of the state engaged in or affected by the\noccupation or occupations to which an order is applicable, may reconvene\nthe same wage board or appoint a new wage board to recommend whether or\nnot the minimum wage and regulations prescribed by such order should be\nmodified, and the provisions of section six hundred fifty-five through\nsix hundred fifty-seven shall thereafter apply.\n  2. By commissioner. The commissioner, without referral to the wage\nboard, may, at any time after public hearing, by order propose such\nmodifications of or additions to any regulations as he may deem\nappropriate to effectuate the purposes of this article. Notice of\nhearing and promulgation of any such order shall be published in\naccordance with the provisions contained in section six hundred\nfifty-six.  Such order shall be effective thirty days after such\npublication and section six hundred fifty-seven shall thereafter apply.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>