<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-674"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-674"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="674"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-674/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-674/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-674/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-674/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_674">
        <num>674</num>
        <heading>Regulations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 674. Regulations. 1. The commissioner may promulgate such\nregulations as he deems appropriate to carry out the purposes of this\narticle and to safeguard minimum wage standards. Such regulations may\ninclude, but are not limited to, the defining of the circumstances or\nconditions for the acceptance of non-hourly rates and piece rates as\nequivalent to the minimum hourly rates established by this article. Such\nregulations also may include, but are not limited to, waiting time and\ncall-in pay rates; wage provisions governing guaranteed earnings during\nspecified periods of work; allowances for meals, lodging, and other\nitems, services and facilities when furnished by the employer; or by\nphysical or mental deficiency or injury, under special certificates\nissued by the commissioner, at such wages lower than the minimum wage\nestablished by this article and for such period as shall be prescribed\nin such regulations.\n  2. Such regulations may vary with localities if in the judgment of the\ncommissioner conditions make such variation appropriate.\n  3. Such regulations shall be promulgated by the commissioner after a\npublic hearing held after due notice.\n  A notice of the public hearing and a notice of the promulgation of any\nsuch regulation shall be published in the state bulletin. The notice of\nthe promulgation of any such regulation shall be published at least\ntwenty days before the effective date of the regulation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>