<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-691"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-691"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="691"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-691/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-691/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-691/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-691/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_691">
        <num>691</num>
        <heading>Statement of employee rights and employer obligations under state and federal law</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 691. Statement of employee rights and employer obligations under\nstate and federal law. 1. Every licensed employment agency under the\njurisdiction of the commissioner and engaged in the job placement of\ndomestic workers or household employees shall provide to each applicant\nfor employment as a domestic worker or household employee and his or her\nprospective employer, before job placement is arranged, a written\nstatement indicating the rights of such worker and employee and the\nobligations of his or her employer under state and federal law. In the\nevent any such licensed employment agency maintains a website, the text\nof such written statement shall also be provided on the agency's\nwebsite. The department shall promulgate rules and regulations detailing\nwhat information should be included in such written statement. Such\nrules and regulations shall require that such statement of rights and\nobligations embody provisions of state and federal laws that pertain to\ndomestic workers or household employees, both in their capacity as\nworkers and employees in New York state and the United States and in\ntheir capacity specifically as domestic workers or household employees\nin New York state and the United States. Such statement of rights and\nobligations shall include, but not be limited to, a general description\nof employee rights and employer obligations pursuant to laws regarding\nminimum wage, overtime and hours of work, record keeping, social\nsecurity payments, unemployment insurance coverage, disability insurance\ncoverage and workers' compensation. Every licensed employment agency\nunder the jurisdiction of the commissioner and to which this article\napplies shall certify that the written statement required by this\nsubdivision conforms to rules and regulations promulgated by the\ndepartment and shall file a copy of such written statement with the\ndepartment.\n  2. Every employment agency engaged in the job placement of domestic\nworkers or household employees shall keep on file in its principal place\nof business for a period of three years a statement, signed by the\nemployer of a domestic worker or household employee whom the employment\nagency has placed with such employer, indicating that the employer has\nread and understands the statement of rights and obligations he or she\nreceived pursuant to subdivision one of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>