<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-695-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-695-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="695-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-695-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-695-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-695-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-695-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_695_F">
        <num>695-F</num>
        <heading>Application of this article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 695-f. Application of this article. 1. The office of children and\nfamily services shall meet with the designated representative of those\nunits of child care providers, either jointly or separately, for the\npurpose of entering into a written agreement to the extent feasible. The\nagreement may address the stability, funding and operation of child care\nprograms, expansion of quality child care, improvement of working\nconditions, salaries and benefits and payment for child care providers.\nIf issues under discussion require the participation and/or approval of\nother state agencies, those agencies shall participate in the\ndiscussions. Nothing herein shall require that an agreement be reached\non any matters described above.\n  2. In the event an agreement is reached, it shall be embodied in\nwriting between the office of children and family services and other\naffected agencies and the designated representative. The agreement shall\nbe binding on the state, contingent upon any regulatory or legislative\naction that may be required.\n  3. If legislative or regulatory action or appropriation of funds is\nrequired the parties will jointly seek such action.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>