<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-696-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-696-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="696-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-696-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-696-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-696-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-696-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_696_I">
        <num>696-I</num>
        <heading>Savings clause</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_696_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An hourly supplement of four dollars and fifty-four cents\nfurnished to an employee by providing at least four dollars and\nfifty-four cents per hour beginning on July first, two thousand\ntwenty-one in one of the following ways:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_696_I__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the form of health\nand/or other benefits, not including paid leave, that cost the employer\nthe entire required hourly supplemental amount; (ii) by providing a\nportion of the required hourly supplement in the form of health and/or\nother benefits, not including paid leave, and the balance in cash; or\n(iii) by providing the entire supplement in cash.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_696_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The value of such supplement shall be no less than four dollars\nand fifty-four cents per hour.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_696_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The standard benefits supplement rate shall apply only to the\nfirst forty hours worked by each covered airport worker in each week and\nshall not apply to any overtime hours worked by any covered airport\nworker.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_696_I__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The standard benefits supplement rate shall apply to any paid\nleave taken by a covered airport worker that does not exceed forty hours\nin a week.\n  4. If section six hundred ninety-six-a, section six hundred\nninety-six-b, or section six hundred ninety-six-c of this article or any\nportion thereof shall be adjudged by any preliminary relief, including a\ntemporary restraining order or a preliminary injunction, by any court of\ncompetent jurisdiction to be preempted by federal law but is later\nadjudged by the same court not to be preempted by federal law in a final\njudgment, then the definition of "standard benefits supplement rate"\nshall immediately revert to the definition stated in subdivision six of\nsection six hundred ninety-six-a of this article.\n  * NB Effective until January 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>