<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-700"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-700"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="700"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-700/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-700/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-700/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-700/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_700">
        <num>700</num>
        <heading>Findings and policy</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 700. Findings and policy. In the interpretation and application of\nthis article, and otherwise, it is hereby declared to be the public\npolicy of the state to encourage the practice and procedure of\ncollective bargaining, and to protect employees in the exercise of full\nfreedom of association, self-organization and designation of\nrepresentatives of their own choosing for the purposes of collective\nbargaining, or other mutual aid and protection, free from the\ninterference, restraint or coercion of their employers.\n  It is also hereby declared as the public policy of this state that the\nbest interests of the people of the state are served by the prevention\nor prompt settlement of labor disputes and that the voluntary resolution\nof such disputes will tend to promote permanent industrial peace and the\nhealth, welfare, comfort and safety of the people of the state.\nRepresentatives of employers and employees engaged in such disputes are\nencouraged voluntarily to submit them to the agency created by this\narticle prior to engaging in a strike, lock-out or other cessation of\nemployment; and should participate fully and promptly in any meetings\nwhich may be arranged by the agency for the purpose of resolving the\ndispute.\n  To carry out such policy, the necessity for the enactment of the\nprovisions of this article is hereby declared as a matter of legislative\ndetermination.\n  All the provisions of this article shall be liberally construed for\nthe accomplishment of this purpose.\n  This article shall be deemed an exercise of the police power of the\nstate for the protection of the public welfare, prosperity, health and\npeace of the people of the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>