<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-717"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-717"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="717"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-717/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-717/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-717/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-717/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_717">
        <num>717</num>
        <heading>State mediation board, state labor relations board, and state employment relations board abolished</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 717. State mediation board, state labor relations board, and state\nemployment relations board abolished. The state mediation board created\nby chapter five hundred sixty-nine of the laws of nineteen hundred\nsixty-eight, the New York state labor relations board created by chapter\nfour hundred forty-three of the laws of nineteen hundred thirty-seven,\nand the state employment relations board created by chapter one hundred\nsixty-six of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-one are hereby\nabolished. All the functions, powers and duties of such boards are\nhereby assigned to and shall hereafter be exercised and performed by and\nthrough the board. Any controversy, proceeding or other matter pending\nbefore the New York state board of mediation, the state labor relations\nboard or the state employment relations board at the time this section\ntakes effect, may be conducted and completed by the board and for such\npurposes the board shall be deemed to be a continuation of the\nfunctions, powers and duties of the New York state board of mediation,\nthe state labor relations board or the state employment relations board,\nrespectively, and not a new entity. Upon the transfer of functions to\nthe board pursuant to this section, all appropriations and\nreappropriations heretofore or hereafter made to the department of labor\nrelating to the state board of mediation or the state labor relations\nboard or segregated pursuant to law, to the extent of remaining\nunexpended or unencumbered balances thereof, whether allocated or\nunallocated and whether obligated or unobligated are hereby made\navailable for use and expenditure by the board for the same purposes for\nwhich originally appropriated or reappropriated. Whenever the state\nboard of mediation or the state labor relations board or the chairman of\nthe state board of mediation or of the state labor relations board or\nthe state employment relations board is referred to or designated in any\ngeneral, special or local law or in any rule, regulation, contract or\nother document, such reference or designation shall be deemed to refer\nto the board and the chairman thereof, respectively.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>