<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-814"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-814"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="814"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-814/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-814/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-814/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-814/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_814">
        <num>814</num>
        <heading>Local, regional and state joint apprenticeship committees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 814. Local, regional and state joint apprenticeship committees.\nLocal and state joint apprenticeship committees may be approved, in any\ntrade or group of trades, in cities, regions of the state or trade\nareas, by the industrial commissioner, whenever the apprentice training\nneeds of such trade or group of trades or such regions justify such\nestablishment. Such local, regional or state joint apprenticeship\ncommittees shall be composed of an equal number of employer and employee\nrepresentatives chosen from names submitted by the respective local or\nstate employer and employee organizations in such trade or group of\ntrades; also such additional members representing local boards of\neducation or other educational agencies as may be deemed advisable.  In\na trade or group of trades in which there is no bona fide employer or\nemployee organization, the joint committee shall be composed of persons\nknown to represent the interests of employers and of employees\nrespectively or a state joint apprenticeship committee may be approved\nas, or the state apprenticeship council may act itself as, the joint\ncommittee in such trade or group of trades. Subject to the review of the\nindustrial commissioner and in accordance with the standards established\nby the industrial commissioner, such committees may devise standards for\napprenticeship agreements and give such aid as may be necessary in their\noperation, in their respective trades and localities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>