<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-856"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-856"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="856"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-856/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-856/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-856/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-856/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_856">
        <num>856</num>
        <heading>Declaration of legislative finding</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 856. Declaration of legislative finding. The legislature finds\nthat due to the state's continuing loss of business and industry,\ndeclining economy and its resultant excessively high net job loss it is\nnecessary and appropriate to take new and aggressive steps to promote\nand keep business, industry and jobs within the state of New York and it\nis therefore in the public interest of the state of New York to create a\nmechanism to permit the governor of the state of New York, under\nextraordinary circumstances, subject to provisions of this article, to\naward a state contract to a New York state resident business bidder over\na non-resident New York state bidder with a lower submitted bid upon a\nfinding that such award is in the public interest of the state of New\nYork. The legislature also finds that increased costs incurred by the\nstate from the award of the state contract to other than the lowest\nbidder will be offset by the benefits of continued and/or additional\nstate and local government tax revenues generated by continued and/or\nincreased employment within the state, and continued and/or additional\ntax revenues from such additional business being generated within this\nstate.\n  It is therefore the intent of this article to create and provide the\ngovernor of the state of New York with a mechanism for granting a\npreference in the letting of state contracts to New York state resident\nbidders, who have substantial economic ties with New York state, and who\ncontribute to the state's economy where sufficient offsetting benefits\nwould be realized by New York state in terms of state employment and\ngeneration of state and local tax revenues, through the exercise of this\nmechanism.\n  * NB Expired July 1, 1979\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>