<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-857"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-857"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="857"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-857/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-857/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-857/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-857/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_857">
        <num>857</num>
        <heading>New York state job retention board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 857. New York state job retention board. 1. There is hereby\nestablished a board, to be hereinafter designated as the New York state\njob retention board, to be comprised of the following voting members:\nthe governor of the state of New York, the comptroller of the state of\nNew York, the attorney general of the state of New York, the industrial\ncommissioner, the commissioner of commerce, the president of the state\ntax commission, and the commissioner of the office of general services.\nThe executive director of the New York state economic development board\nshall be a non-voting ex-officio member.\n  2. The governor of the state of New York may direct and order the\ncommissioner of the office of general services or other contracting\noffices to award a contract to a bidder, other than the lowest\nresponsible bidder, whenever such bid substitution in the board's\njudgment would best promote the public interest of the state of New\nYork, pursuant to the provisions of section one hundred seventy-four of\nthe state finance law, providing such substituting is consistent with\nthe intent of section eight hundred fifty-six of this chapter and\nsection one hundred seventy-four of the state finance law.\n  3. The New York state job retention board may request any bidder on a\nstate contract to prepare and submit a preferential bidding form.\n  4. The New York state job retention board shall meet upon the request\nof the governor of the state of New York.\n  * NB Expired July 1, 1979\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>