<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-860-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-860-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="860-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-860-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-860-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-860-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-860-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_860_F">
        <num>860-F</num>
        <heading>Powers of the commissioner</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_860_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be confidential; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_860_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>not be published or open to\npublic inspection. Prior to public disclosure of any such information in\nconnection with any court action or proceeding, the employer shall be\ngiven a reasonable opportunity to make application to protect the\ninformation's confidentiality.\n  4. No decision or order issued pursuant to this article shall be\nadmissible or used in evidence in any subsequent court proceeding except\nin an action by the commissioner or the employer to implement, enforce,\nor challenge a determination made by the commissioner pursuant to this\narticle.\n  5. Any officer or employer of the state, any officer or employee of\nany entity authorized to obtain information pursuant to this section,\nand any agent to this state or of such entity who, except with authority\nof the commissioner under this section, discloses information is guilty\nof a misdemeanor.\n  6. If, after an administrative hearing, the commissioner shall\ndetermine that an employer has violated any of the requirements of this\narticle or any rules or regulations promulgated hereunder, the\ncommissioner shall issue an order which shall include any penalties\nassessed by the commissioner under sections eight hundred sixty-g and\neight hundred sixty-h of this article. Upon the entry of such order, any\nparty aggrieved thereby may commence a proceeding for the review thereof\npursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules\nwithin thirty days from the notice of the filing of the said order in\nthe office of the commissioner. Such proceeding shall be commenced\ndirectly in the appellate division of the supreme court. If such order\nis not reviewed, or is so reviewed and the final decision is in favor of\nthe commissioner, the commissioner may file with the county clerk of the\ncounty where the employer resides or has a place of business the order\nof the commissioner containing the amount found to be due. The filing of\nsuch order shall have the full force and effect of a ju...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>