<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-861-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-861-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="861-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-861-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-861-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-861-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-861-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_861_C">
        <num>861-C</num>
        <heading>Presumption of employment in the construction industry</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the individual is free from control and direction in performing\nthe job, both under his or her contract and in fact;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the service must be performed outside the usual course of business\nfor which the service is performed; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the individual is customarily engaged in an independently\nestablished trade, occupation, profession, or business that is similar\nto the service at issue.\n  2. A business entity, including any sole proprietor, partnership,\ncorporation or entity that may be a contractor under this section shall\nbe considered a separate business entity from the contractor where all\nthe following criteria are met:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity is performing the service free from the\ndirection or control over the means and manner of providing the service,\nsubject only to the right of the contractor for whom the service is\nprovided to specify the desired result;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity is not subject to cancellation or destruction\nupon severance of the relationship with the contractor;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity has a substantial investment of capital in the\nbusiness entity beyond ordinary tools and equipment and a personal\nvehicle;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity owns the capital goods and gains the profits\nand bears the losses of the business entity;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity makes its services available to the general\npublic or the business community on a continuing basis;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity includes services rendered on a Federal Income\nTax Schedule as an independent business or profession;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity performs services for the contractor under the\nbusiness entity's name;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>when the services being provided require a license or permit, the\nbusiness entity obtains and pays for the license or permit in the\nbusiness entity's name;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity furnishes the tools and equipment necessary to\nprovide the service;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if necessary, the business entity hires its own employees without\ncontractor approval, pays the employees without reimbursement from the\ncontractor and reports the employees' income to the Internal Revenue\nService;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the contractor does not represent the business entity as an\nemployee of the contractor to its customers; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the business entity has the right to perform similar services for\nothers on whatever basis and whenever it chooses.\n  3. The failure to withhold federal or state income taxes or to pay\nunemployment compensation contributions or workers' compensation\npremiums with respect to an individual's wages shall not be considered\nin making a determination under this section, except as set forth in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_861_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section.\n  4. An individual's act of securing workers' compensation insurance\nwith a carrier as a sole proprietor, partnership or otherwise shall not\nbe binding on any determination under this section.\n  5. When a business entity meets the definition of a separate business\nentity pursuant to subdivision two of this section, the separate\nbusiness entity will be considered a contractor subject to all the\nprovisions of this article in regard to the classification of\nindividuals performing services for it.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>