<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-870-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-870-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="870-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-870-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-870-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-870-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-870-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_870_N">
        <num>870-N</num>
        <heading>Carnival, fair and amusement park safety advisory board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 870-n. Carnival, fair and amusement park safety advisory board. 1.\nTo advise the commissioner in relation to industry standards for\ncarnivals, fairs, amusement parks, amusement devices, tents and viewing\nstands, and his or her duties and powers pursuant to this article, there\nshall be established in the department an advisory board, to be known as\nthe "carnival, fair and amusement park safety advisory board",\nconsisting of eleven members to be appointed as follows: five members\nshall be appointed by the governor, two members shall be appointed by\nthe temporary president of the senate, two members shall be appointed by\nthe speaker of the assembly, one member shall be appointed by the\nminority leader of the senate, and one member shall be appointed by the\nminority leader of the assembly. The members of such advisory board\nshall each be a representative of amusement parks; operators of\ntemporary amusement devices; businesses engaged in the rental of\ntemporary amusement devices; manufacturers and suppliers of amusement\ndevices, tents or viewing stands; or the general public. The governor\nshall appoint the chair of the board from amongst the members appointed\nby him or her.\n  2. Each member of the advisory board shall serve a term of five years,\nor until his or her successor is appointed; provided that of the members\ninitially appointed to the advisory board: one member appointed by the\ngovernor and the member appointed by the minority leader of the assembly\nshall serve terms of one year; one member appointed by the governor and\none member appointed by the temporary president of the senate shall\nserve terms of two years; one member appointed by the governor and one\nmember appointed by the speaker of the assembly shall be appointed for\nterms of three years; one member appointed by the governor and one\nmember appointed by the minority leader of the senate shall be appointed\nfor terms of four years; and one member appointed by the governor, one\nmember appointed by the temporary president of the senate and one member\nappointed by the speaker of the assembly shall be appointed for terms of\nfive years. Any member of the board chosen to fill a vacancy occurring\notherwise than by expiration of term shall be appointed for the\nunexpired term of the member who he or she is to succeed.\n  3. Each member of the advisory board shall serve without salary or\nother compensation, but shall be allowed necessary and actual\ntransportation expenses incurred in the performance of his or her\nduties.\n  4. The advisory board shall consider all matters relating to the\nimplementation of the provisions of this article and advise the\ncommissioner with respect thereto, and on its own initiative may make\nrecommendations to the commissioner as to any rules, regulations and\nstatutes necessary to assure amusement park, carnival and fair safety.\n  5. The commissioner shall designate an officer or employee of the\ndepartment to act as secretary to the advisory board, who shall not be a\nmember of such board and who shall not receive any additional\ncompensation therefor.\n  6. The advisory board may adopt by-laws to govern its own proceedings.\nThe secretary of the board shall keep a complete record of all\nproceedings of the advisory board which shows the names of the members\npresent at each meeting and every matter considered by the advisory\nboard and the action taken thereon. Such records shall be filed in the\noffice of the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>