<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-877"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-877"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="877"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-877/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-877/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-877/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-877/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_877">
        <num>877</num>
        <heading>Trade secrets</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 877. Trade secrets. 1. When a manufacturer, producer, formulator or\nemployer considers the identity of or other information concerning a\ntoxic chemical substance to be a protectable trade secret or a\nproprietary process whose disclosure would compromise his competitive\nadvantage and when other applicable provisions of the health law are\nsatisfied, he may register this information as secret with the\ncommissioner of health.\n  2. Manufacturers, producers, formulators and employers who so register\na substance, process or product with the commissioner of health must\ninform in writing, employers who request information relating to such\nsubstance, and employees and their representatives, that such substance\nor process constitutes a registered trade secret or proprietary process\nand that information regarding the toxic effects of such substance is\nonly available without identifying information and must provide such\ninformation without identifying data.\n  3. No officer, employee or agent of any state or municipal department,\nagency, commission or authority shall disclose to anyone in any manner\nany record or portions thereof protected pursuant to this article and\nwhich are within his custody or knowledge for so long as such record or\nportions thereof shall be so exempted or until a final judicial denial\nof such exemption is rendered. Any person who violates any provision of\nthis subdivision may be fined, suspended or removed from office or\nemployment in the manner provided by law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>