<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-884"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-884"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="884"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-884/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-884/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-884/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-884/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_884">
        <num>884</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and intent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 884. Legislative findings and intent. The workers of New York state,\nboth public and private, pursuant to state and federal laws, have the\nright to a safe and healthy workplace, including, pursuant to the\nprovisions of article twenty-eight of this chapter, the right to\ntraining and education about the toxic substances in their workplace.\n  It is the public policy of this state to promote safe and healthy\nconditions in the workplace. Further, it is the public policy of this\nstate to encourage voluntary compliance with safety and health\nregulations and the prevention of illness and injury through training\nand education programs.\n  Therefore, it is the intent of this legislature to achieve the full\nbenefits of such preventive measures by creating a training and\neducational program on occupational safety and health, which will\noperate through a program of grants to employers (public or private),\nlabor organizations or their federations, trade associations, nonprofit\norganizations and educational institutions, for conducting training,\neducation, and other proven preventive programs. Furthermore, it is the\nlegislature's intention to foster voluntary preventive activities on the\npart of employers and employees by the utilization of the training and\neducation program on occupational safety and health.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>