<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="LAB">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-952"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-952"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-01-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="952"/>
          <FRBRname value="LAB"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-952/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-952/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-952/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/lab/section-952/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_952">
        <num>952</num>
        <heading>Licensing and compliance requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_952__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to engage in the business of elevator and conveyance work, or\naccessibility lift work, or hold themselves out as an elevator\ncontractor, or both, unless such person or business has a valid elevator\ncontractor's license; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_952__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to engage in the business of elevator and conveyance inspections,\nor hold themselves out as an elevator inspection contractor, or both\nunless such person or business has a valid elevator inspection\ncontractor's license; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_952__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any combination of the above.\n  2. Except as otherwise provided for in subdivisions three, four, and\nfive of section nine hundred fifty of this article, it shall be unlawful\nfor any person:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_952__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to engage in elevator and conveyance work, or to hold themselves\nout as an elevator mechanic, or both, unless such person has a valid\nelevator mechanic's license and works for a licensed elevator contractor\nor a public entity; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_952__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to engage in accessibility lift work, or to hold themselves out as\naccessibility lift technicians, or both, unless such person has a valid\naccessibility lift technician's license and works for a licensed\nelevator contractor or a public entity; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_952__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to engage in elevator and conveyance inspections, or to hold\nthemselves out as an elevator inspector, or both, unless such person\nholds an elevator inspector's license and works for a licensed elevator\ninspection contractor or a public entity; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_952__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any combination of the above, provided, however, that the\ninstallation of branch circuits and wiring terminations for machine room\nand pit lighting, receptacles and HVAC as described in the NFPA National\nElectric Code 620.23 and 620.24 as well as fire and heat detectors and\nalarms, may be performed by a licensed electrical contractor.\n  3. It shall be the responsibility of licensees to ensure that any\nelevator and conveyance work or elevator and conveyance inspections that\nthey perform is in compliance with existing state and local building and\nmaintenance codes.\n  4. It shall be the responsibility of holders of business licenses to\nensure that the licensing requirements of subdivisions one and two of\nthis section are complied with by their employees and by businesses that\nthey contract with, and to immediately report to the commissioner any\nfailures to comply with the licensing requirements of subdivisions one\nand two of this section by other businesses or persons that they become\naware of.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>