<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1186"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1186"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1186"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1186/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1186/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1186/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1186/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1186">
        <num>1186</num>
        <heading>Deposit and disposition of revenue</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1186. Deposit and disposition of revenue. The taxes, interest, and\npenalties imposed by this article and collected or received by the\ncommissioner shall be deposited daily with such responsible banks,\nbanking houses or trust companies, as may be designated by the\ncomptroller, to the credit of the comptroller in trust for the tobacco\ncontrol and insurance initiatives pool established by section\nninety-two-dd of the state finance law and distributed by the\ncommissioner of health in accordance with section twenty-eight hundred\nseven-v of the public health law. Such deposits will be kept separate\nand apart from all other money in the possession of the comptroller. The\ncomptroller shall require adequate security from all such depositories.\nOf the total revenue collected or received under this article, the\ncomptroller shall retain such amount as the commissioner may determine\nto be necessary for refunds under this article. Provided, however that\nthe commissioner is authorized and directed to deduct from the amounts\nhe or she receives from the registration fees under section eleven\nhundred eighty-three of this article, before deposit into the tobacco\ncontrol and insurance initiatives pool, a reasonable amount necessary to\neffectuate refunds of appropriations of the department to reimburse the\ndepartment for the costs incurred to administer, collect and distribute\nthe taxes imposed by this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>