<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-L*4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-L*4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1202-L*4"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-L*4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-L*4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-L*4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1202-L*4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1202_L*4">
        <num>1202-L*4</num>
        <heading>Hotel or motel taxes in Niagara Falls</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of any tax sought to be reviewed, with\nsuch interest and penalties thereon as may be provided for by local law\nor regulation, shall be first deposited and there is filed an\nundertaking, issued by a surety company authorized to transmit business\nin this state and approved by the superintendent of financial services\nof this state as to solvency and responsibility, in such amount as a\njustice of the supreme court shall approve to the effect that if such\nproceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed the petitioner will pay all\ncosts and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of such proceeding\nor</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at the option of the petitioner such undertaking may be in a sum\nsufficient to cover the taxes, interest and penalties stated in such\ndetermination plus the costs and charges which may accrue against it in\nthe prosecution of the proceedings in which event the petitioner shall\nnot be required to pay such taxes, interest or penalties as a condition\nprecedent to the application.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_b__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Where any tax imposed hereunder shall have been erroneously,\nillegally or unconstitutionally collected and application for the refund\nthereof duly made to the proper fiscal officer or officers, and such\nofficer or officers shall have made a determination denying such refund,\nsuch determination shall be reviewable by a proceeding under article\nseventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules, provided, however,\nthat such proceeding is instituted within thirty days after the giving\nof the notice of such denial, that a final determination of tax due was\nnot previously made, and that an undertaking is filed with the proper\nfiscal officer or officers in such amount and with such sureties as a\njustice of the supreme court shall approve to the effect that if such\nproceeding be dismissed or the tax confirmed, the petitioner will pay\nall costs and charges which may accrue in the prosecution of such\nproceeding.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_b__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except in the case of a wilfully false or fraudulent return with\nintent to evade the tax, no assessment of additional tax shall be made\nafter the expiration of more than three years from the date of the\nfiling of a return, provided, however, that where no return has been\nfiled as provided by law the tax may be assessed at any time.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_b__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Revenues resulting from the imposition of tax authorized by this\nact shall be paid into the treasury of the city of Niagara Falls and\nshall be credited to and deposited in the general fund account of such\ncity and shall be used only for the promotion of convention activities\nand tourism as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>from the first four per centum (4%), eighty\npercent of such revenue from this tax shall be allocated and paid to a\nnot-for-profit corporation under contract with the county for the\npromotion of tourism in the county; fifteen percent of such revenue\nshall be retained by the city of Niagara Falls for any city purpose; and\nthe remaining five percent of said first four per centum (4%) of revenue\nshall be retained by the city of Niagara Falls for administration and\ncollection costs;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the additional one percentum (1%) of such revenue\nfrom this tax first authorized pursuant to chapter two hundred\nforty-seven of the laws of two thousand six shall be dedicated to the\ncontinuation of a trolley service for the purpose of transporting guests\nof hotels and motels to area tourism attractions; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an additional\none per centum (1%) of revenue shall be dedicated to the operation of\nthe Discover Niagara shuttle. The terms "convention activities" and\n"tourism" may be defined by a resolution of the city council of the city\nof Niagara Falls.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1202_L*4__subsec_c__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any provision of this section or the application thereof to\nany person or circumstance shall be held invalid, the remainder of this\nsection and the application of such provision to other persons or\ncircumstances shall not be affected thereby.\n  * NB There are 4 ยง 1202-l's\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>