<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1216"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1216"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1216"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1216/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1216/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1216">
        <num>1216</num>
        <heading>Special transitional provisions for utility services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1216. Special transitional provisions for utility services.\nNotwithstanding sections three and five of chapter ninety-three of the\nlaws of nineteen hundred sixty-five, as amended, the sale, consumption\nor use of gas, electricity, refrigeration and steam, and gas, electric,\nrefrigeration and steam service of whatever nature, for which a bill is\nrendered based on meters read on or after August first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-five, where one-half or less of the number of days included in the\nmonth or other period billed are days subsequent to July thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-five, shall continue to be subject to the\napplicable tax on such sales, consumption or use as imposed pursuant to\nthe authority of chapter eight hundred seventy-three of the laws of\nnineteen hundred thirty-four, as amended, or the applicable tax on such\nsales, consumption or use as imposed pursuant to the authority of\nsections one, two or three-a of chapter two hundred seventy-eight of the\nlaws of nineteen hundred forty-seven, as amended.  Notwithstanding\nsections three and five of chapter ninety-three of the laws of nineteen\nhundred sixty-five, as amended, such taxes shall also apply to sales,\nconsumption or use of telephone or telegraph service shown on all bills\ndated before August first, nineteen hundred sixty-five covering periods\nsubsequent to July thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-five.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>