<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1254"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1254"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1254"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1254/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1254/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1254/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1254/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1254">
        <num>1254</num>
        <heading>Duty to collect taxes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1254__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every person required to collect\ntax, as defined in section eleven hundred thirty-one, who is required to\ncollect any state tax imposed under sections eleven hundred five, eleven\nhundred six or eleven hundred ten, shall at the same time collect any\napplicable tax imposed by a city, county or school district under the\nauthority of sections twelve hundred ten, twelve hundred eleven, twelve\nhundred twelve or twelve hundred twelve-A, and where the state tax is a\nretail sales tax, shall also collect any compensating use tax which may\nbe applicable as provided in sections twelve hundred thirteen or twelve\nhundred fourteen.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1254__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where the state of New York, any of its agencies,\ninstrumentalities, public corporations (including a public corporation\ncreated pursuant to agreement or compact with another state or Canada)\nor political subdivisions sells services or property of a kind\nordinarily sold by private persons it shall be considered a vendor for\npurposes of the taxes imposed under the authority of sections twelve\nhundred ten, twelve hundred eleven, twelve hundred twelve and twelve\nhundred twelve-A and shall be required to collect the taxes imposed by\ncities, counties and school districts under the authority of such\nsections.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>