<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1262-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1262_M">
        <num>1262-M</num>
        <heading>Allocation of net collections from the additional one percent rate of sales and compensating use taxes in the county of Chenango</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1262-m. Allocation of net collections from the additional one\npercent rate of sales and compensating use taxes in the county of\nChenango.  Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, all net\ncollections received by the county of Chenango from the one percent\nsales and compensating use taxes in addition to the three percent rate,\neach as authorized by section twelve hundred ten of this article, shall\nbe used, in the first instance, to pay the cost of constructing and\nrepaying any debts incurred in the construction of the Chenango county\npublic safety building project, and any operational costs related to the\nChenango county public safety building. Any and all revenue derived from\nsuch additional one percent tax, after the construction and debt\nfinancing costs of the Chenango county public safety building project\nannex, and any operational costs related to the Chenango county public\nsafety building are paid, shall be deposited by the county of Chenango\nin a capital reserves fund. Disbursements from such capital reserves\nfund shall solely be made for the purposes of capital projects and\nrepaying any debts incurred for such capital projects in the county of\nChenango.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1262-m's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>