<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1262-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1262_P">
        <num>1262-P</num>
        <heading>Disposition of net collections from the additional one percent rate of sales and compensating use taxes in the county of Livingston</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1262-p. Disposition of net collections from the additional one\npercent rate of sales and compensating use taxes in the county of\nLivingston.  Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, if the\ncounty of Livingston imposes the additional one percent rate of sales\nand compensating use taxes authorized by section twelve hundred ten of\nthis article for all or any portion of the period beginning June first,\ntwo thousand three and ending November thirtieth, two thousand\ntwenty-seven, the county shall use all net collections from such\nadditional one percent rate to pay the county's expenses for Medicaid.\nThe net collections from the additional one percent rate imposed\npursuant to this section shall be deposited in a special fund to be\ncreated by such county separate and apart from any other funds and\naccounts of the county. Any and all remaining net collections from such\nadditional one percent tax, after the Medicaid expenses are paid, shall\nbe deposited by the county of Livingston in the general fund of such\ncounty for any county purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>