<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1262-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1262-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1262_N">
        <num>1262-N</num>
        <heading>Disposition of net collections from the additional one percent rate of sales and compensating use taxes in the county of Niagara</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1262-n. Disposition of net collections from the additional one\npercent rate of sales and compensating use taxes in the county of\nNiagara.  Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, if the county\nof Niagara imposes the additional one percent rate of sales and\ncompensating use taxes authorized by section twelve hundred ten of this\narticle for all or any portion of the period beginning March first, two\nthousand three and ending November thirtieth, two thousand twenty-three,\nthe county shall use all net collections from such additional one\npercent rate to pay the county's expenses for Medicaid. The net\ncollections from the additional one percent rate imposed pursuant to\nthis section shall be deposited in a special fund to be created by such\ncounty separate and apart from any other funds and accounts of the\ncounty. Any and all remaining net collections from such additional one\npercent tax, after the Medicaid expenses are paid, shall be deposited by\nthe county of Niagara in the general fund of such county for any county\npurpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>