<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1304-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1304-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-08-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1304-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1304-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1304-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1304-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1304-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1304_B">
        <num>1304-B</num>
        <heading>Additional tax</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1304_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304_B__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In addition to any other taxes\nauthorized by this article, any city imposing such taxes is hereby\nauthorized and empowered to adopt and amend local laws imposing in any\nsuch city for each taxable year beginning after nineteen hundred ninety\nbut before two thousand twenty-seven, an additional tax on the city\ntaxable income of every city resident individual, estate and trust, to\nbe calculated for each taxable year as follows:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1304_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for each taxable\nyear beginning after nineteen hundred ninety but before nineteen hundred\nninety-nine, at the rate of fourteen percent of the sum of the taxes for\neach such taxable year determined pursuant to section thirteen hundred\nfour and section thirteen hundred four-A of this article; and (ii) for\neach taxable year beginning after nineteen hundred ninety-eight, at the\nrate of fourteen percent of the tax for such taxable year determined\npursuant to such section thirteen hundred four.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304_B__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding paragraph one of this subsection, for each taxable\nyear beginning after nineteen hundred ninety-nine but before two\nthousand twenty-seven, any city imposing such additional tax may by\nlocal law impose such tax at a rate that is less than fourteen percent\nand may impose such tax at more than one rate depending upon the filing\nstatus and city taxable income of such city resident individual, estate\nor trust.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1304_B__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A local law enacted pursuant to paragraph two of this subsection\nshall be applicable with respect to any taxable year only if it has been\nenacted on or before July thirty-first of such year. A certified copy of\nsuch local law shall be mailed by registered mail to the department at\nits office in Albany within fifteen days of its enactment. However, the\ndepartment may allow additional time for such certified copy to be\nmailed if it deems such action to be consistent with its duties under\nthis article.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1304_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The additional tax imposed pursuant to the authority of this\nsection shall be administered, collected and distributed by the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance in the same manner as the other\ntaxes imposed pursuant to the authority of this article, and all of the\nprovisions of this article, including section thirteen hundred ten of\nthis article, shall apply to the additional tax authorized by this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>