<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1333"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1333"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1333"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1333/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1333/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1333/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1333/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1333">
        <num>1333</num>
        <heading>Deposit and disposition of revenues</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1333__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision six of section one hundred seventy-one-f of this chapter,\nprovided, however, he shall credit to the special offset fiduciary\naccount, pursuant to section ninety-one-c of the state finance law, any\nsuch amount creditable as a liability as set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1333__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision six of section one hundred seventy-one-f of this chapter and\nexcept that he shall pay to the city of New York that amount of\noverpayments of tax imposed pursuant to the authority of this article or\narticle thirty-B of this chapter and the interest on such amount which\nis certified to him by the commissioner of taxation and finance as the\namount to be credited against city of New York tax warrant judgment debt\npursuant to section one hundred seventy-one-l of this chapter, and\nexcept further that he/she shall pay to a non-obligated spouse that\namount of overpayment of tax imposed by such city pursuant to the\nauthority of this article or article thirty-B of this chapter and the\ninterest on such amount which has been credited pursuant to section one\nhundred seventy-one-c, one hundred seventy-one-d, one hundred\nseventy-one-e, one hundred seventy-one-f or one hundred seventy-one-l of\nthis chapter and which is certified to him by the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance as the amount due such non-obligated spouse\npursuant to paragraph six of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1333__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section six hundred\nfifty-one of this chapter, and he shall deduct a like amount which he\nshall pay into the treasury to the credit of the general fund from\namounts subsequently payable to the department of social services, the\nstate university of New York, the city university of New York, or the\nhigher education services corporation or to the revenue arrearage\naccount or special offset fiduciary account pursuant to section\nninety-one-a or ninety-one-c of the state finance law, as the case may\nbe, whichever had been credited the amount originally withheld from such\noverpayment. The amount deducted for administering, collecting and\ndistributing such taxes during such monthly period shall be paid by the\ncomptroller into the general fund of the state treasury to the credit of\nthe state purposes account therein. The first payment to such chief\nfiscal officer shall be made on or before March fifteenth, nineteen\nhundred eighty-five, which payment shall represent the balance of\nrevenue after provision for refund and such reasonable costs, with\nrespect to taxes collected in nineteen hundred eighty-four. Subsequent\npayments shall be made on or before April fifteenth, nineteen hundred\neighty-five, and on or before the fifteenth day of each succeeding month\nthereafter, and shall represent the balance of revenue with respect to\ntaxes collected the preceding calendar months. The amounts so payable\nshall be certified to the comptroller by the commissioner of taxation\nand finance or his delegate, either of whom shall not be held liable for\nany inaccuracy in such certificate. Where the amount so paid over to\nsuch chief fiscal officer is more or less than the amount then due such\ncity, the amount of overpayment or underpayment shall be certified to\nthe comptroller by the commissioner of taxation and finance or his\ndelegate, either of whom shall not be held liable for any inaccuracy in\nsuch certificate. The amount of overpayment or underpayment shall be...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>