<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1405-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1405-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1405-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1405-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1405-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1405-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1405-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1405_B">
        <num>1405-B</num>
        <heading>Cooperative housing corporation transfers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1405_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nNotwithstanding the definition of "controlling interest" contained in\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1405_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen hundred one of this article or\nanything to the contrary contained in subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1405_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nfourteen hundred one of this article, the tax imposed by this article\nshall apply to</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1405_B__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the original conveyance of shares of stock in a\ncooperative housing corporation in connection with the grant or transfer\nof a proprietary leasehold by the cooperative corporation or cooperative\nplan sponsor, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1405_B__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the subsequent conveyance of such stock in a\ncooperative housing corporation in connection with the grant or transfer\nof a proprietary leasehold by the owner thereof. With respect to any\nsuch subsequent conveyance where the property is an individual\nresidential unit, the consideration for the interest conveyed shall\nexclude the value of any liens on certificates of stock or other\nevidences of an ownership interest in and a proprietary lease from a\ncorporation or partnership formed for the purpose of cooperative\nownership of residential interest in real estate remaining thereon at\nthe time of conveyance. In determining the tax on a conveyance described\nin paragraph one of this subdivision, a credit shall be allowed for a\nproportionate part of the amount of any tax paid upon the conveyance to\nthe cooperative housing corporation of the real property comprising the\ncooperative dwelling or dwellings to the extent that such conveyance\neffectuated a mere change of identity or fo...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1405_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every cooperative housing corporation shall be required to file an\ninformation return with the commissioner of taxation and finance by July\nfifteenth of each year covering the preceding period of January first\nthrough June thirty-first and by January fifteenth of each year covering\nthe preceding period of July first through December thirty-first. The\nreturn shall contain such information regarding the conveyance of shares\nof stock in the cooperative housing corporation as the commissioner may\ndeem necessary, including but not limited to, the names, addresses and\nemployee identification numbers or social security numbers of the\ngrantor and the grantee, the number of shares conveyed, the date of the\nconveyance and the consideration paid for such conveyance. The\ncommissioner of taxation and finance may enter into an agreement with\nthe chief fiscal officer of the city of New York to provide that a\nsingle information return may be filed for purposes of the tax imposed\nby this article and the real property transfer tax imposed by such city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1405_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The information contained within information returns filed under\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1405_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section may be provided by the commissioner to\nlocal assessors for use in real property tax administration, and such\ninformation shall not be subject to the secrecy provisions set forth in\nsection fourteen hundred eighteen of this chapter, provided, however,\nthat the commissioner shall not disclose social security numbers or\nemployer identification numbers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>