<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1406"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1406"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1406"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1406/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1406/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1406/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1406/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1406">
        <num>1406</num>
        <heading>Preparation and sale of stamps</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1406__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The tax commission shall\nprepare adhesive documentary stamps for purposes of the real estate\ntransfer tax of such design, in such form, in such denominations and in\nsuch quantities as it may from time to time deem advisable. The tax\ncommission shall make provision for the sale of such stamps by its duly\nauthorized agent or agents in such places, at such times and subject to\nsuch terms and conditions as in its judgment may be necessary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1406__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The tax commission may from time to time and as often as it deems\nadvisable provide for the issuance and exclusive use of stamps of a new\ndesign and forbid the use of stamps of any other design.  In order to\nmake such a change and discontinue the use of stamps of a former design,\nthe tax commission shall publish once in each week for each of three\nmonths immediately preceding the time when such change shall take\neffect, in one or more daily newspapers published in each of the first\nand second class cities of the state, a notice to the effect that after\na certain date, which shall be at least three months after the first\npublication of such notice, only the new issue or design of stamps shall\nbe accepted or used to pay the real estate transfer tax. After such\ndate, it shall be unlawful for any person to make use of any other than\nthe new issue or design of stamps in payment of such tax.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1406__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any person lawfully in possession of unused stamps of an old or\nsuperseded issue or design may, within ninety days from the time when\nsuch change becomes effective, surrender the unused stamps to the tax\ncommission together with a sworn statement setting forth the name and\naddress of the owner and party surrendering the stamps, how, when and\nfrom whom they were acquired and such other information as the tax\ncommission may require. The tax commission shall redeem such unused and\nsurrendered stamps by exchanging stamps of a like denomination of the\nnew issue or design for them.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1406__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of sections seven and eight of the\nstate printing law, the tax commission is hereby directed to make, enter\ninto and execute for and on behalf of the state such contract or\ncontracts for dyes, plates and printing necessary for the manufacture of\nthe stamps provided for by this article. The tax commission shall be the\ncustodian of all stamps, dyes, plates or other material or thing\nfurnished by it and used in the manufacture of such state tax stamps.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1406__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This section shall not apply to the extent the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance chooses not to use documentary stamps for purposes\nof this tax.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>