<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1419"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1419"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1419"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1419/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1419/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1419/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1419/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1419">
        <num>1419</num>
        <heading>Notices</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1419__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any notice authorized or required under the\nprovisions of this article may be given by mailing the same to the\nperson for whom it is intended in a postpaid envelope addressed to such\nperson at the address given in the last return filed by him pursuant to\nthe provisions of this article, in any application made by him, or in\nany instrument evidencing the conveyance which is the subject of the\nnotice, or, if no return has been filed or application made or address\nstated in the instrument, then to such address as may be obtainable. A\nnotice of determination shall be mailed promptly by registered or\ncertified mail.  The mailing of such notice shall be presumptive\nevidence of the receipt of the same by the person to whom addressed.\nAny period of time which is determined according to the provisions of\nthis title by the giving of notice shall commence to run from the date\nof mailing of such notice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1419__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1419__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If any return, claim, statement, notice, application, or other\ndocument required to be filed, or any payment required to be made,\nwithin a prescribed period or on or before a prescribed date under\nauthority of any provision of this article is, after such period or such\ndate, delivered by United States mail to the commissioner of taxation\nand finance, bureau, office, officer or person with which or with whom\nsuch document is required to be filed, or to which or to whom such\npayment is required to be made, the date of the United States postmark\nstamped on the envelope shall be deemed to be the date of delivery.\nThis subdivision shall apply only if the postmark date falls within the\nprescribed period or on or before the prescribed date for the filing of\nsuch document, or for making the payment, including any extension\ngranted for such filing or payment, and only if such document or payment\nwas deposited in the mail, postage prepaid, properly addressed to the\ncommissioner of ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1419__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A)  Any reference in paragraph one of this subdivision to the\nUnited States mail shall be treated as including a reference to any\ndelivery service designated by the secretary of the treasury of the\nUnited States pursuant to section seventy-five hundred two of the\ninternal revenue code and any reference in paragraph one of this\nsubdivision  to a postmark by the United States mail shall be treated as\nincluding a reference to any date recorded or marked in the manner\ndescribed in section seventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue\ncode by a designated delivery service.  If the commissioner finds that\nany delivery service designated by such secretary is inadequate for the\nneeds of the state, the commissioner may withdraw such designation for\npurposes of this article.  The commissioner may also designate\nadditional delivery services meeting the criteria of section\nseventy-five hundred two of the internal revenue code for purposes of\nthis article, or may withdraw any such...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1419__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the last day prescribed under authority of this article\n(including any extension of time) for performing any act falls on\nSaturday, Sunday or a legal holiday in the state of New York, the\nperformance of such act shall be considered timely if it is performed on\nthe next succeeding day which is not a Saturday, Sunday or a legal\nholiday.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>