<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1513"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1513"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1513"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1513">
        <num>1513</num>
        <heading>Declarations of estimated tax</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Requirements of\ndeclaration.--Every taxpayer subject to the taxes imposed under this\narticle shall make a declaration of its estimated tax for the current\ntaxable year, containing such information as the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance may prescribe by regulations or instructions, if\nsuch estimated tax can reasonably be expected to exceed one thousand\ndollars. If a taxpayer is subject to the tax surcharge imposed by\nsection fifteen hundred five-a and such taxpayer's estimated tax under\nthis article can (without regard to section fifteen hundred five-a\nthereof) reasonably be expected to exceed one thousand dollars, such\ntaxpayer shall also make a declaration of its estimated tax surcharge\nfor the current taxable year.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Definition of estimated tax and estimated tax surcharge. The terms\n"estimated tax" and "estimated tax surcharge" mean the amounts which the\ntaxpayer estimates to be the taxes imposed by sections fifteen hundred\none, fifteen hundred two-a and fifteen hundred ten of this article or\nthe tax surcharge imposed by section fifteen hundred five-a of this\narticle, respectively, for the current taxable year, less the sum of any\ncredits which it estimates to be allowable against such taxes or tax\nsurcharge, respectively.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Time of filing declaration.--A declaration of estimated tax and a\ndeclaration of estimated tax surcharge shall be filed on or before June\nfifteenth of the current taxable year in the case of a taxpayer which\nreports on the basis of a calendar year, except that if the requirements\nof subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section are first met:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1513__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>after May thirty-first and before September first of such current\ntaxable year the declaration shall be filed on or before September\nfifteenth, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1513__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>after August thirty-first and before December first of such\ncurrent taxable year, the declaration shall be filed on or before\nDecember fifteenth.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Amendments of declaration.--A taxpayer may amend a declaration of\nestimated tax or a declaration of estimated tax surcharge under\nregulations prescribed by the commissioner of taxation and finance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Return as declaration. If, on or before February fifteenth of the\nsucceeding year in the case of a taxpayer whose taxable year is a\ncalendar year, a taxpayer files its return for the year for which the\ndeclaration is required, and pays therewith the balance, if any, of the\nfull amount of the tax or tax surcharge shown to be due on the return\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1513__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such return shall be considered as its declaration if no\ndeclaration was required to be filed during the taxable year for which\nthe tax or tax surcharge was imposed, but is otherwise required to be\nfiled on or before December fifteenth pursuant to paragraph two of\nsubdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section, and\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1513__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>such return shall be considered as the amendment permitted by\nsubdivision</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section to be filed on or before December\nfifteenth if the tax or tax surcharge shown on the return is greater\nthan the estimated tax or estimated tax surcharge, as the case may be,\nshown on a declaration previously made.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Short taxable period. If the taxable period for which a tax or tax\nsurcharge is imposed under this article is less than twelve months,\nevery taxpayer required to make a declaration of estimated tax or a\ndeclaration of estimated tax surcharge for such taxable period shall\nmake such declaration in accordance with rules of the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Fiscal year. The provisions of this section shall apply to taxable\nyears of twelve months other than a calendar year by the substitution of\nthe months of such fiscal year for the corresponding months specified in\nsuch provisions.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1513__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Extension of time. The tax commission may grant a reasonable\nextension of time, not to exceed three months, for the filing of any\ndeclaration required pursuant to this section, on such terms and\nconditions as it may require.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>