<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-170"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-170"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="170"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-170/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-170/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-170/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-170/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_170">
        <num>170</num>
        <heading>Department of taxation and finance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There shall be in the division of taxation a bureau of\nconciliation and mediation services which shall be responsible for\nproviding conciliation conferences. Such conference shall be provided,\nat the option of any taxpayer or any other person subject to the\nprovisions of this chapter or any other provision of law relating to\nadministration of taxes, where such taxpayer or any other such person\nhas received any written notice of a determination of tax due, a tax\ndeficiency, a denial of a refund or credit application, a cancellation,\nrevocation or suspension of a license, permit or registration, a denial\nof an application for a license, permit or registration or any other\nnotice which gives rise to a right to a hearing under this chapter if\nthe time to petition for such a hearing has not elapsed. Such notice\nshall contain information advising the recipient of the right to have a\nconciliation conference.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A request for a conciliation conference shall be applied for in\nthe manner as set forth by regulation of the commissioner and,\nnotwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, shall suspend the\nrunning of the period of limitations for the filing of a petition\nprotesting such notice and requesting a hearing. To discontinue the\nconciliation proceeding, the recipient of the notice shall make a\nrequest in writing and such person shall have ninety days from the time\nsuch request of discontinuance is made to petition the division of tax\nappeals for a hearing, except that the recipient of a written notice\ndescribed in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision will have thirty days\nfrom the time such request of discontinuance is made to petition the\ndivision of tax appeals for a hearing. The commissioner shall notify the\ndivision of tax appeals when any person requests a conference or\nrequests to discontinue such conference.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A conciliation conferee, all of whom, unless otherwise provided by\nlaw, shall be in the classified civil service, shall conduct the\nconciliation conference in an informal manner and shall hear or receive\ntestimony and evidence deemed necessary or desirable for a just and\nequitable result. The commissioner of taxation and finance shall have\nthe power to delegate authority to a conferee to waive or modify\npenalty, interest and additions to tax to the same extent as such\ncommissioner is permitted under this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The person who requests the conference may appear and represent\nhimself, including a member of a partnership, in any conciliation\nconference, or may designate the person's spouse, parent or child, or an\nattorney admitted to practice in the courts of record of this state, a\ncertified public accountant licensed in this state, an enrolled agent\nenrolled to practice before the internal revenue service, or a public\naccountant licensed in this state to appear and represent him. In\naddition the commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations to\npermit a corporation to be represented by one of its officers or an\nemployee. The department may also allow an attorney, certified public\naccountant or licensed public accountant authorized to practice or\nlicensed in any other jurisdiction of the United States to appear and\nrepresent such person in a conciliation conference proceeding and, on\nthe written request of such person, may allow any other individual to\nrepresent him. An employee of the department of taxation and finance\nfamiliar with the controversy shall also be present at such proceedings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A conciliation order shall be rendered within thirty days after\nthe proceeding is concluded and such order shall, in the absence of a\nshowing of fraud, malfeasance or misrepresentation of a material fact,\nbe binding upon the department and the person who requested the\nconference, except such order shall not be binding on such person if\nsuch person petitions for the hearing provided for under this chapter\nwithin ninety days after the conciliation order is issued, or, for a\nconciliation order affirming a written notice described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision, within thirty days after the conciliation order is\nissued, notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conciliation conference orders shall not be required to be\npublished and such orders shall not be considered as precedent or be\ngiven any force or effect in any subsequent administrative proceeding\nwith respect to the person who requested the conference or in any other\nproceeding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of taxation and finance shall collect, compile\nand prepare for publication statistics and other data with respect to\nthe operations of the bureau of conciliation and mediation services, and\nto submit annually to the governor, the temporary president of the\nsenate and the speaker of the assembly a report on such operations,\nincluding but not limited to, the number of conferences held, the\ndispositions made and the number of conferences pending.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, any person\nwho seeks review by the bureau of conciliation and mediation services of\na written notice that advises that person of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the proposed\ncancellation, revocation, or suspension of a license, permit,\nregistration, or other credential issued under the authority of this\nchapter excluding a certificate of registration of a retail dealer under\nsection four hundred eighty-a of this chapter, (ii) the denial of an\napplication for a license, permit, registration, or other credential\nissued under the authority of this chapter excluding an application for\nregistration as a retail dealer under section four hundred eighty-a of\nthis chapter and an application to renew a certificate of authority\nfiled pursuant to paragraph five of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section one\nthousand one hundred thirty-four of this chapter and any other law, or,\n(iii) the imposition of a fraud penalty under this chapter, must request\na conciliation conference within thirty days of the mailing of that\nnotice.\n  4. The commissioner of taxation and finance may appoint and remove\nsuch officers, assistants and other employees as he may deem necessary\nfor the exercise of the powers and duties of the department, all of whom\nshall be in the classified civil service unless otherwise provided by\nlaw; and he may prescribe their duties, and fix their compensation\nwithin the amounts appropriated therefor. The commissioner of taxation\nand finance may transfer officers or employees from their positions to\nother positions in the department, or abolish or consolidate such\npositions. He shall have all powers necessary to perform the duties\nconferred upon him regarding the state lottery authorized by article\nthirty-four of this chapter. However, the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance shall have no power to appoint or remove any personnel of the\ndivision of tax appeals nor shall such commissioner have any power or\nauthority with regard to the operation and administration of such\ndivision including any power or authority over such division's budget.\nThe commissioner shall furnish to the director of the division of the\nbudget the itemized estimates of the financial needs of the division of\ntax appeals prepared by the tax appeals tribunal. Such itemized\nestimates may not be revised or altered in any manner by the\ncommissioner.\n  5. The head of the division of taxation shall be the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance who shall be appointed by the governor as provided\nin subdivision one of this section. No person shall be appointed as\ncommissioner of taxation and finance unless at the time of his\nappointment he is a resident of the state and known to have knowledge on\nthe subject of taxation and skill in matters pertaining thereto...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>