<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1700"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1700"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1700"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1700/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1700/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1700/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-1700/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1700">
        <num>1700</num>
        <heading>Voluntary disclosure and compliance program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1700__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the taxpayer and the tax liability are eligible under the\nvoluntary disclosure and compliance program, the commissioner is\nauthorized to enter into a voluntary disclosure and compliance agreement\nwith the taxpayer. A voluntary disclosure and compliance agreement will\nbe in a form to be established by the commissioner and include such\nterms as the commissioner may reasonably require to satisfy the\ntaxpayer's disclosed tax obligations and enable and require the taxpayer\nto comply with the tax law in the future. The taxpayer must pay the tax\nand the related interest that are the subject of the voluntary\ndisclosure and compliance agreement when the agreement is executed or\nwithin the time stated on a bill issued to the taxpayer by the\ncommissioner. In the event the commissioner is satisfied that the\ntaxpayer cannot make immediate full payment of the disclosed tax\nliability, the commissioner may enter into an installment payment\nprogram with the taxpayer for the payment of the tax and interest due.\nThe commissioner may require a financial disclosure statement setting\nforth information concerning the taxpayer's current assets, liabilities,\nearnings, and other financial information before entering into an\ninstallment payment plan with the taxpayer. In addition to any other\ninformation and terms that the commissioner determines are appropriate,\nthe voluntary disclosure and compliance agreement shall provide that, if\nthe taxpayer complies with the terms of the compliance agreement, the\ntaxpayer will not be subject to any criminal tax prosecution in New York\nstate for the conduct disclosed by the taxpayer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1700__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the taxpayer intentionally provides false material information\nor omits material information in his or her submissions to the\ncommissioner, or attempts to intentionally defeat or evade a tax due\npursuant to the agreement executed under this article, or intentionally\nfails to comply with the terms of the compliance agreement, such\nagreement shall be deemed rescinded.\n  6. Unless the commissioner on his or her own motion redetermines the\namount of tax due, including applicable interest, no refund shall be\ngranted or credit allowed with respect to any taxes, including\napplicable interest, paid under this program.\n  7. The commissioner may promulgate regulations, issue forms and\ninstructions, and take any and all other actions necessary to implement\nthe provisions of the program established under this section. The\ncommissioner shall publicize the program provided for in this section so\nas to maximize public awareness of and participation in such program.\n  8. For purposes of this section, the term "taxpayer" includes any\nperson required to collect any of the taxes specified in subdivision one\nof this section.\n  9. The voluntary disclosure and compliance application, the disclosure\nstatement, the voluntary disclosure and compliance agreement, and other\ndocuments filed by an eligible taxpayer pursuant to the program\nestablished by this section are deemed to be reports and returns:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1700__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>subject to the secrecy provisions of this chapter in the same\nmanner and to the same extent as if such documents were referred to in\nany of the secrecy provisions of this chapter; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1700__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for purposes of the criminal provisions of article thirty-seven of\nthis chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>