<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="171"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-171/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_171">
        <num>171</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of commissioner of taxation and finance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the various methods by which the\ndepartment communicates tax policy and interpretations to taxpayers, tax\npractitioners, personnel of the department and the general public and\n(ii) the legal force and effect, precedential value and binding nature\nof each such method of communication.\n  Second. Assess, determine, revise, readjust and impose the corporation\ntaxes under articles nine and nine-A of this chapter, and on and after\nJuly first, nineteen hundred twenty-one, have the power and perform the\nduties of the state comptroller in the collection of such taxes and the\ncrediting of such taxes erroneously paid, as jurisdiction thereof is\nvested in such commissioner by section one hundred seventy-six of this\nchapter.\n  Third. On and after July first, nineteen hundred twenty-one, have the\npowers and perform the duties of the state comptroller in relation to\nthe assessment, determination and collection of the tax on transfers of\nproperty, as jurisdiction thereof is vested in such commissioner by\nsection one hundred seventy-six of this chapter.\n  Fourth. On and after July first, nineteen hundred twenty-one, have the\npowers and perform the duties of the state comptroller in the collection\nof the tax on transfers of stock under article twelve of this chapter,\nas jurisdiction thereof is vested in such commissioner by section one\nhundred seventy-six of this chapter.\n  Fifth. On and after July first, nineteen hundred twenty-one, have the\npower and perform the duties of the state comptroller in the assessment,\ndetermination, review, readjustment and collection of taxes upon and\nwith respect to personal income, as jurisdiction thereof is vested in\nsuch commissioner by section one hundred seventy-six of this chapter.\n  Sixth. Administer, supervise and enforce the tax on mortgages as\nprovided in article eleven of this chapter.\n  Eighth. Take testimony and proofs, under oath, with reference to any\nmatter within the line of his official duty. A deputy tax...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe commissioner may grant the relief described in paragraph (iii) of\nthis subdivision to a limited partner of a limited partnership (but not\na partner of a limited liability partnership) or a member of a limited\nliability company if such limited partner or member demonstrates to the\nsatisfaction of the commissioner that such limited partner's or member's\nownership interest and the percentage of their distributive share of the\nprofits and losses of such limited partnership or limited liability\ncompany are each less than fifty percent, and such limited partner or\nmember was not under a duty to act, and did not act, for such limited\npartnership or limited liability company in complying with any\nrequirement of the taxes imposed under article twenty-eight of this\nchapter and pursuant to the authority of article twenty-nine of this\nchapter. Provided, however, the commissioner shall deny an application\nfor relief if: (A) such limited partner or member had a duty to act or\nhas acted on behalf of such limited partnership or limited liability\ncompany in complying with any requirement of the taxes imposed under\narticle twenty-eight of this chapter and pursuant to the authority of\narticle twenty-nine of this chapter; (B) such limited partner or member\nhas been convicted of a crime provided in this chapter; (C) such limited\npartner or member has a past-due tax liability, as such term is defined\nin section one hundred seventy-one-v of this article; (D) approval of\nsuch application would undermine compliance with the taxes or other\nimpositions administered by the commissioner; or (E) approval of such\napplication would be adverse to the best interests of the state.\n  (ii) The relief described in paragraph (iii) of this subdivision shall\nnot be provided unless a limited partner or member submits a properly\ncompleted application for relief on a form prescribed by the\ncommissioner. The information provided in such application must be true\nand complete in...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any payment made by a limited partner or member in excess of such\nlimited partner's or member's percentage of ownership or distributive\nshare, whichever is higher, shall be deemed a payment by the respective\nlimited partnership or limited liability company, and such limited\npartner or member shall not be entitled to a refund of such amount.\n  Sixteenth. Have authority to compromise any taxes or any warrant or\njudgment for taxes imposed by this chapter and the penalties and\ninterest in connection therewith of a tax debtor which is a domestic\nrailroad corporation, or its trustee or trustees in bankruptcy,</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in\nconnection with its qualification as a railroad redevelopment\ncorporation or the acquisition of its facilities by a railroad\nredevelopment corporation or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if said domestic railroad corporation\nis principally engaged in the transportation of passengers and at the\ntime of said compromise it is the debtor in a reorganization proceeding\npursuant to the United States bankruptcy act and said compromise is\napproved by the bankruptcy court.\n  Seventeenth. Have authority to release any real and personal property\nfrom the lien of any warrant for unpaid taxes, additions to tax,\npenalties and interest, or vacate such warrant, upon such conditions as\nhe or she may require, if he or she finds that the interests of the\nstate will not thereby be jeopardized. Such release or vacating of the\nwarrant may be recorded in the office of any recording officer\n(including the department of state) in which such warrant has been\nfiled. When the warrant is vacated, the recording officer (including the\ndepartment of state) shall thereupon cancel and discharge as of the\noriginal date of docketing the vacated warrant.\n  Eighteenth. Have authority to ente...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the case shall not be reopened as to the matters\nagreed upon or the agreement modified, by any officer, employee, or\nagent of this state, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in any suit, action, or proceeding, such\nagreement, or any determination, assessment, collection, payment,\ncancellation, abatement, refund or credit made in accordance therewith,\nshall not be annulled, modified, set aside or disregarded. As used in\nthis paragraph the term "person" includes an individual, trust, estate,\npartnership and corporation.\n  Eighteenth-a. Have authority to compromise civil liability, with such\nqualifications and limitations as may be established pursuant to such\nrules and regulations as the commissioner may prescribe, where such\nliability arises under a tax or other imposition which is administered\nby the commissioner, at any time prior to the time the tax, other\nimposition or administrative action becomes finally and irrevocably\nfixed and no longer subject to administrative review. Upon acceptance of\nan offer in compromise by the commissioner, the matter may not be\nreopened except upon a showing of fraud, malfeasance or\nmisrepresentation of a material fact. The attorney general may\ncompromise any such liability after reference to the department of law\nfor prosecution or defense at any time prior to the time the tax, other\nimposition or administrative action taken by the commissioner is no\nlonger subject to judicial review. Whenever a compromise is made by the\ncommissioner of any such liability, there shall be placed on file in the\noffice of the commissioner the opinion of the counsel for such\ndepartment, with his or her reasons therefor, with a statement of:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe amount of tax or other imposition and any other issues which may be\nthe subject of such compromise,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of interest, additions to\nthe tax, or penalty imposed by law on the taxpayer or other persons\nagainst whom the administrative action was taken by the department, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount actually paid in accordance with the terms of the\ncompromise. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, no such opinion\nshall be required with respect to the compromise of any civil liability\nin which the unpaid amount of tax or other imposition which was the\nsubject of the administrative action (including any interest, additions\nto tax, or penalty) is less than fifty thousand dollars.\n  Eighteenth-b. Where the filing requirement arises under article\ntwenty-two of this chapter or under a law enacted pursuant to the\nauthority of article thirty or thirty-A of this chapter, have authority\nto require a husband and wife whose federal income tax liabilities are\ndetermined on a joint federal return and who have not filed a joint New\nYork income tax return to file separate income tax returns, in which\ncase their income tax liabilities shall be separate. Such authority\nshall be exercised only where one of such persons demonstrates, to the\nsatisfaction of the commissioner, that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the address or whereabouts of\nhis or her spouse is unknown to him or her,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reasonable efforts have\nbeen made by him or her to locate such spouse, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>good cause\nexisted for the failure to file a joint New York income tax return.\n  Eighteenth-c. Where the filing requirement arises under article\ntwenty-two of this chapter or under a law enacted pursuant to the\nauthority of article thirty or thirty-A of this chapter, have authority\nto require a husband and wife whose federal income tax liabilities are\ndetermined on a joint federal return and who have not filed a joint New\nYork income tax return to file separate income tax returns, in which\ncase their income tax liabilities shall be separate. Such authority\nshall be exercised only where one of such persons demonstrates, to the\nsatisfaction of the commissioner, that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>his or her spouse has refused\nto sign a joint New York income tax return,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reasonable efforts have\nbeen made by him or her to have such spouse sign a joint New York income\ntax return,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>there exists objective evidence of alienation of such\nperson from his or her spouse such as a judicial order of protection,\nlegal separation under a decree of divorce or separate maintenance,\nseparation under a written separation agreement or judicial decree of\nseparation, living apart at all times during the twelve months\nimmediately preceding the application for exercise of authority under\nthis provision, the commencement of an action for divorce, or the\ncommencement of proceedings in family court which evidence such\nalienation, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>good cause existed for the failure to file a joint\nNew York income tax return.\n  Eighteenth-d.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Have authority to compromise civil liability, with\nsuch qualifications and limitations as may be established pursuant to\nsuch rules and regulations as the commissioner may prescribe, for a\ntaxpayer's spousal share of liability arising from a joint income tax\nreturn, filed under article twenty-two of this chapter or under a law\nenacted pursuant to the authority of article thirty or thirty-A of this\nchapter, where the following conditions are met:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the taxpayer and spouse filing the joint return are, at the time\nof the offer in compromise, separated under a decree of divorce or\nseparate maintenance, or a written separation agreement, or a judicial\ndecree of separation, or the taxpayer at the time of the offer in\ncompromise is not considered as married within the meaning of section\n7703</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the internal revenue code (relating to certain married\nindividuals living apart), and\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>it is demonstrated to the satisfaction of the commissioner that\nthe collection of the spousal share of liability from the taxpayer\ncannot be accomplished within a reasonable period of time without\nimposing substantial economic hardship on the taxpayer.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon acceptance of an offer in compromise under this subdivision\nby the commissioner, the matter may not be reopened except upon a\nshowing of fraud, malfeasance or misrepresentation of a material fact.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a compromise is made by the department of any such\nliability, there shall be placed on file in the office of the\ncommissioner the opinion of the counsel for the department, with his\nreasons therefor with a statement of:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount of tax assessed,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount of interest, additions to the tax, or penalty imposed\nby law on the taxpayer and spouse against whom the tax is assessed, and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the amount actually paid in accordance with the terms of the\ncompromise.\nNotwithstanding the preceding sentence, no such opinion shall be\nrequired with respect to the compromise of any civil liability in which\nthe unpaid amount of tax assessed (including any interest, additions to\ntax, or penalty) is less than twenty-five thousand dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Spousal share of liability. For purposes of this subdivision, the\nspousal share of liability shall be determined by multiplying the joint\nand several liability arising from the joint return by a fraction, the\nnumerator of which is the tax for the taxable year at issue determined\nseparately for the spouse, and the denominator of which is the sum of\nthe taxes for such taxable year determined separately for the spouse and\nfor the taxpayer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A compromise under this subdivision as to a taxpayer's spousal\nshare of liability arising from a joint income tax return shall not\ncompromise the joint and several liability of the spouse with respect to\nthat return.\n  Nineteenth. Have authority to provide by regulation</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that in any\ndetermination, assessment, collection, refund or credit under this\nchapter, a fractional part of a dollar may be disregarded unless it\namounts to fifty cents or more, in which case it shall be increased to\none dollar, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_171__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that any person making a return, report or other\nstatement required to be filed with it under this chapter, may elect\nwith respect to any amount required to be shown thereon, if such amount\nis other than a whole dollar amount, either to disregard the fractional\npart of a dollar or to disregard the fractional part of a dollar unless\nit amounts to fifty cents or more, in which case the amount (determined\nwithout regard to the fractional part of a dollar) shall be increased by\none dollar; provided, however, that such election shall not be\napplicable to items which must be taken into account in making the\ncomputations necessary to determine the amount required to be shown on\nany such return, report or other statement but shall be applicable only\nto the final amount required to be shown thereon.\n  Twentieth. Have authority, of his own motion, to abate any small\nunpaid balance of an assessment of tax, or any liability in respect\nthereof, under articles twelve-A, eighteen, twent...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nprocedures to improve the accuracy of school district income data, in a\nmanner which gives appropriate recognition to computerized processing\ncapabilities, administrative feasibility of manual processes and\nconfidentiality implications; (ii) procedures to verify the school\ndistrict codes reported by taxpayers; (iii) procedures to correct\nidentified inaccuracies; (iv) procedures to assign school district codes\nbased on the permanent residence addresses of taxpayers who failed to\ncomplete the school district code;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the schedule for the transmittal\nof electronic data between the agencies, as necessary, to implement such\nsystem; and (vi) beginning in the nineteen hundred ninety-six state\nfiscal year, procedures for the review process provided for in paragraph\nc of this subdivision. All state departments and agencies, and school\ndistricts and other local governments and agencies, shall cooperate with\nthe parties to such agreement in its implementation.\n  b. 1. Any correction, pursuant to this paragraph, of verified\ninaccuracies of income data shall only result in the removal of such\nreturns from the identified school district.\n  2. All state departments and agencies, and school districts and other\nlocal governments and agencies, shall cooperate with the parties to such\nagreement in the implementation of the review process provided pursuant\nto this paragraph.\n  c. 1. With respect to income used in the computation of school aid\npayable in the school years nineteen hundred ninety-eight--ninety-nine\nand thereafter, be required to design, develop and implement a process\nwhereby school districts may request a review of the assignment of\ntaxpayer addresses to their school district. Procedures for such a\nreview process shall be included in the cooperative agreement entered\ninto pursuant to paragraph a of this subdivision.\n  2. School districts requesting a review in accordance with the\nprovisions of this paragraph shall be required, in consultation with the\ndistrict superintendent of schools for the supervisory district in which\nthe school district is located, appointed pursuant to section nineteen\nhundred fifty of the education law, to submit to the commissioner of\neducation evidence in support of a contention that the assignment of tax\nreturns to their district is inaccurate. Identified school districts may\nbe required to review ordered listings, prepared by the department or an\nauthorized vendor contracted by the department, of the permanent\nresident addr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\none thousand ninety-six of this chapter, but the underpayment rate shall\nnot be less than seven and one-half percent per annum. Any such rates\nset by such commissioner shall apply to taxes, or any portion thereof,\nwhich remain or become due or overpaid (other than overpayments under\nsuch article twenty and not including reimbursements, if any, under any\nof such articles) on or after the date on which such rates become\neffective and shall apply only with respect to interest computed or\ncomputable for periods or portions of periods occurring in the period\nduring which such rates are in effect. In computing the amount of any\ninterest required to be paid under such articles by such commissioner or\nby the taxpayer, or any other amount determined by reference to such\namount of interest, such interest and such amount shall be compounded\ndaily.\n  b. Cross-reference. For provisions relating to the power of the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance to abate small amounts of interest,\nsee subdivision twentieth of this section.\n  Twenty-seventh. Have authority, upon agreement with the state\ncomptroller, to act as an agent for the state comptroller for the\npurposes of crediting the payment of state money to any claimant against\nthe amount of a past-due legally enforceable debt, as defined in section\none hundred seventy-one-f of this article, owed by such claimant to a\nstate agency, as defined in section one hundred seventy-one-f of this\narticle. All the provisions of section one hundred seventy-one-f of this\narticle shall be applicable to the crediting of the payments of state\nmoney made in accordance with the authority granted in this subdivision,\nwith such modifications as may be necessary to adapt such language to\nsuch crediting and shall apply with the same force and effect as if\nthose provisions had been set forth in full in this section and had\nexpressly referred to such crediting, except to the extent any provision\nthereof is either...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section six hundred ninety-six of the tax law in relation to the\npersonal income tax (or any comparable acts with respect to taxes under\nthis chapter other than the personal income tax) were performed within\nthe time prescribed therefor, and\n  2. The amount of any credit or refund.\n  b. Special rule for overpayments. 1. Paragraph a of this subdivision\nshall not apply for purposes of determining the amount of interest on\nany overpayment of tax.\n  2. If a taxpayer is entitled to the benefits of paragraph a of this\nsubdivision with respect to any return, amended return, or claim for\ncredit or refund, and such return, amended return or claim is timely\nfiled (determined after the application of this subdivision), paragraph\nthree of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section six hundred\neighty-eight and paragraph three of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_171__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection one thousand eighty-eight of this chapter shall not apply.\n  c. Definitions. 1. Presidentially declared disaster. For purposes of\nthis subdivision, the term "presidentially declared disaster" means any\ndisaster which, with respect to an area, resulted in a subsequent\ndetermination by the president of the United States that such area\nwarrants assistance by the federal government under the disaster relief\nand emergency assistance act.\n  2. Taxpayer. For purposes of this subdivision, the term "taxpayer"\nmeans any person or entity required to file a return or remit any tax to\nthe commissioner pursuant to this chapter.\n  d. Where a taxpayer who, pursuant to section seven thousand five\nhundred eight-a of the internal revenue code, is determined for federal\ntax purposes to be affected by a presidentially declared disaster, or\nwho is determined to be affected by a disaster emergency declared by the\ngovernor, but the commissioner has not postponed a tax deadline pursuant\nto the authority in paragraph a of this subdivision due to such\ndisaster, the commissioner may abate any amount of interest from the\nunderpayment of any tax administered by the commissioner under this\nchapter that accrued for the period during which the taxpayer was unable\nto meet such deadline due to direct impacts of the disaster.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>