<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-01-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="187-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-187-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_187_A">
        <num>187-A</num>
        <heading>Credit for employment of persons with disabilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_187_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>who is certified by the education department, or in the case of an\nindividual who is blind or visually handicapped, by the state agency\nresponsible for provision of vocational rehabilitation services to the\nblind and visually handicapped:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_187_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as a person with a disability which\nconstitutes or results in a substantial handicap to employment and (ii)\nas having completed or as receiving services under an individualized\nwritten rehabilitation plan approved by the education department or\nother state agency responsible for providing vocational rehabilitation\nservices to such individual; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_187_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>who has worked on a full-time basis for the employer who is\nclaiming the credit for at least one hundred eighty days or four hundred\nhours.\n  3. Amount of credit. Except as provided in subdivision four of this\nsection, the amount of credit under this section shall be thirty-five\npercent of the first six thousand dollars in qualified first-year wages\nearned by each qualified employee. "Qualified first-year wages" means\nwages paid or incurred by the taxpayer during the taxable year to\nqualified employees which are attributable, with respect to any such\nemployee, to services rendered during the one-year period beginning with\nthe day the employee begins work for the taxpayer.\n  4. Credit where federal work opportunity tax credit applies.  With\nrespect to any qualified employee whose qualified first-year wages under\nsubdivision three of this section also constitute qualified first-year\nwages for purposes of the work opportunity tax credit for vocational\nrehabilitation referrals under section fifty-one of the internal revenue\ncode, the amount of credit under this section shall be thirty-five\npercent of the first six thousand dollars in qualified second-year wages\nearned by each such employee. "Qualified second-year wages" means wages\npaid or incurred by the taxpayer during the taxable year to qualified\nemployees which are attributable, with respect to any such employee, to\nservices rendered during the one-year period beginning one year after\nthe employee begins work for the taxpayer.\n  5. Carryover. In no event shall the credit under this section be\nallowed in an amount which will reduce the tax payable to less than the\napplicable minimum tax fixed by section one hundred eighty-three or\nformer section one hundred eighty-six of this article. If, however, the\namount of credit allowable under this section for any taxable year\nreduces the tax to such amount, any amount of credit not deductible in\nsuch taxable year may be carried over to the follow...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>