<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-197-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-197-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="197-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-197-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-197-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-197-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-197-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_197_A">
        <num>197-A</num>
        <heading>Declaration of estimated tax</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_197_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>after May thirty-first and before September first of such current\ntaxable year, the declaration shall be filed on or before September\nfifteenth, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_197_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>after August thirty-first and before December first of such\ncurrent taxable year, the declaration shall be filed on or before\nDecember fifteenth.\n  4. A taxpayer may amend a declaration of estimated tax or a\ndeclaration of estimated tax surcharge under regulations prescribed by\nthe commissioner of taxation and finance.\n  5. If, on or before February fifteenth of the succeeding year in the\ncase of a taxpayer whose taxable year is a calendar year, a taxpayer\nfiles its return for the year for which the declaration is required, and\npays therewith the balance, if any, of the full amount of the tax or tax\nsurcharge shown to be due on the return:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_197_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such return shall be considered as its declaration if no\ndeclaration was required to be filed during the taxable year for which\nthe tax or tax surcharge was imposed, but is otherwise required to be\nfiled on or before December fifteenth pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_197_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of this section, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_197_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such return shall be considered as the amendment permitted by\nsubdivision four of this section to be filed on or before December\nfifteenth if the tax or tax surcharge shown on the return is greater\nthan the estimated tax or estimated tax surcharge, as the case may be,\nshown on a declaration previously made.\n  6. If the taxable period for which a tax or tax surcharge is imposed\nunder any of the sections enumerated in subdivision one hereof is other\nthan twelve months, every taxpayer required to make a declaration of\nestimated tax or a declaration of estimated tax surcharge for such\ntaxable period shall make such declaration in accordance with rules of\nthe commissioner.\n  7. This section shall apply to taxable periods of twelve months other\nthan a calendar year by the substitution of the months of such fiscal\nyear for the corresponding months specified in this section.\n  8. The tax commission may grant a reasonable extension of time, not to\nexceed three months, for the filing of any declaration required pursuant\nto this section, on such terms and conditions as it may require.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>