<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-2006"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-2006"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2006"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-2006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-2006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-2006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-2006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2006">
        <num>2006</num>
        <heading>Tax appeals tribunal; functions, powers and duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2006__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section five hundred twenty-eight of this chapter, a\ndetermination relating to the tax imposed by article twenty-one-A of\nthis chapter shall finally and irrevocably fix such tax unless the\nperson against whom it is assessed shall petition the division of tax\nappeals for a hearing within thirty days after the giving of notice of\nsuch determination.\n  5. To provide that any party, pursuant to such rules and regulations\nas the tribunal may prescribe, after a petition requesting a hearing has\nbeen filed with the division, may file a motion with the tribunal to\ndismiss the petition on the following grounds:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2006__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a defense is founded upon documentary evidence; or\n  (ii) the tribunal lacks jurisdiction of the subject matter of the\npetition; or\n  (iii) the petitioner lacks legal capacity to petition; or\n  (iv) there is an action pending between the same parties on the same\ncontroversy in a court of any state or the United States; an\nadministrative law judge need not dismiss upon this ground but may make\nsuch determination as justice requires; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2006__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the petition may not be maintained because of discharge in\nbankruptcy, infancy or other disability of the moving party, payment,\nrelease, or statute of limitation; or\n  (vi) the pleading fails to state a cause for relief; or\n  (vii) the tibunal lacks jurisdiction over the taxpayer; or\n  (viii) the tribunal should not proceed in the absence of a person who\nshould be a party.\n  Such motion to dismiss and all supporting documents shall be reviewed\nby an administrative law judge who shall issue a determination granting\nor denying the motion. Such a determination denying the motion shall not\nbe subject to review by the tribunal. The tribunal of its own motion\nmay, upon notice to the parties, issue a decision dismissing the\npetition on the grounds set forth in paragraphs (ii) and (vii) of this\nsubdivision.  Where not otherwise inconsistent with the provisions of\nthis chapter, a motion filed pursuant to this subdivision shall be\nsubject to the same provisions as motions filed pursuant to section\nthree thousand two hundred eleven of the civil practice law and rules.\n  6. To provide that any party, pursuant to such rules and regulations\nas the tribunal may prescribe, after a petition requesting a hearing has\nbeen filed with the division and after issue is joined, may file a\nmotion with the tribunal for summary determination. Such motion shall be\nsupported by an affidavit, by a copy of the pleadings and by other\navailable proof. The affidavit, made by a person having knowledge of the\nfacts, shall recite all the material facts and show that there is no\nmaterial issue of fact, and that the facts mandate judgment in the\nmoving party's favor. The motion and all supporting documents shall be\nreviewed by an administrative law judge. The motion shall be granted if,\nupon all the papers and proof submitted, the administrative law judge\nfinds that it has been established sufficiently that no material and\ntriable issue of fact is presented and that the admin...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>