<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="253-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-253-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_253_G">
        <num>253-G</num>
        <heading>Recording tax imposed by the county of Westchester</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_253_G__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision one of section two hundred fifty-five of this article.\nExcept as otherwise provided in this section, all the provisions of this\narticle relating to or applicable to the administration and collection\nof the taxes imposed by such subdivisions shall apply to the taxes\nimposed under the authority of this section with such modifications as\nmay be necessary to adapt such language to the tax so authorized. Such\nprovisions shall apply with the same force and effect as if those\nprovisions had been set forth in full in this section except to the\nextent that any provision is either inconsistent with a provision of\nthis section or not relevant to the tax authorized by this section. For\npurposes of this section, any reference in this article to the tax or\ntaxes imposed by this article shall be deemed to refer to a tax imposed\npursuant to this section, and any reference to the phrase "within this\nstate" shall be read as "within Westchester county", unless a different\nmeaning is clearly required.\n  3. Where the real property covered by the mortgage subject to the tax\nimposed pursuant to the authority of this section is situated in this\nstate but within and without the county imposing such tax, the amount of\nsuch tax due and payable to such county shall be determined in a manner\nsimilar to that prescribed in the first paragraph of section two hundred\nsixty of this article which concerns real property situated in two or\nmore counties. Where such property is situated both within such county\nand without the state, the amount due and payable to such county shall\nbe determined in the manner prescribed in the second paragraph of such\nsection two hundred sixty which concerns property situated within and\nwithout the state. Where real property is situated within and without\nthe county imposing such tax, the recording officer of the jurisdiction\nin which the mortgage is first recorded shall be required to collect the\ntaxes imposed pursuant to this ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>