<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-270-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-270-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="270-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-270-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-270-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-270-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-270-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_270_C">
        <num>270-C</num>
        <heading>Transfers by operation of law; special exemptions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_270_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the trading with the enemy act (40 Stat. 415), as\namended by the first war powers act (55 Stat. 838);\n  9. From trustees to surviving, substitute, succeeding or additional\ntrustees of the same trust;\n  10. Upon the death of a joint tenant or tenant by the entirety, to the\nsurvivor or survivors.\n  11. Made in obedience to an order of the Federal Securities and\nExchange Commission which has become or becomes final in accordance with\nlaw, provided that such order recites that the delivery or transfer is\nnecessary or appropriate to effectuate the provisions of section eleven\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_270_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Public Utility Holding Company Act of Nineteen Hundred\nThirty-five and specifies and itemizes the securities which are ordered\nto be delivered or transferred;\n  12. Made to effectuate any plan of reorganization or adjustment</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_270_C__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nconfirmed under the act entitled "An act to establish a uniform system\nof bankruptcy throughout the United States," approved July first,\neighteen hundred ninety-eight, as amended,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_270_C__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>approved in an equity\nreceivership proceeding in court involving a corporation, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_270_C__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>under\nsections one hundred nineteen to one hundred twenty-three of the real\nproperty law or article nine of the stock corporation law.\n  13. Made to effectuate any plan of reorganization or adjustment\nrequired by a decree of the court under the anti-trust laws of the\nUnited States or any territory thereof, or of any state or the District\nof Columbia.\n  14. Of the capital stock of no more than one corporation organized\nunder or subject to either articles three or seven of the banking law,\ndelivered or transferred, as provided in section one hundred\nforty-three-a of the banking law, in exchange for shares or other\nsecurities of a company substantially all of the assets of which will\nconsist of said capital stock immediately after such exchange.\n  The tax commission may require that each such delivery or transfer be\naccompanied by a certificate setting forth the facts.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>