<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-471"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-471"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-09-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="471"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-471/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-471/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-471/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-471/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_471">
        <num>471</num>
        <heading>Imposition of cigarette tax</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_471__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of this section. Such tax on\ncigarettes shall be at the rate of five dollars and thirty-five cents\nfor each twenty cigarettes or fraction thereof, provided, however, that\nif a package of cigarettes contains more than twenty cigarettes, the\nrate of tax on the cigarettes in such package in excess of twenty shall\nbe one dollar and thirty-three and three-quarters cents for each five\ncigarettes or fraction thereof. Such tax is intended to be imposed upon\nonly one sale of the same package of cigarettes. It shall be presumed\nthat all cigarettes within the state are subject to tax until the\ncontrary is established, and the burden of proof that any cigarettes are\nnot taxable hereunder shall be upon the person in possession thereof.\n  2. It is intended that the ultimate incidence of and liability for the\ntax shall be upon the consumer, and that any agent or dealer who shall\npay the tax to the commissioner shall collect the tax from the purchaser\nor consumer. Except as hereinafter provided, the tax shall be advanced\nand paid by the agent. The agent shall be liable for the collection and\npayment of the tax on cigarettes imposed by this article and shall pay\nthe tax to the commissioner by purchasing, under such regulations as he\nor she shall prescribe, adhesive stamps of such designs and\ndenominations as he or she shall prescribe. The tax on cigarettes may\nalso be paid by or through the use of metering machines if the\ncommissioner so prescribes. Agents, located within or without the state,\nshall purchase stamps and affix such stamps in the manner prescribed to\npackages of cigarettes to be sold within the state, in which case any\ndealer subsequently receiving such stamped packages of cigarettes will\nnot be required to purchase and affix stamps on such packages of\ncigarettes. All cigarettes sold by agents and wholesalers to Indian\nnations or tribes or reservation cigarette sellers located on an Indian\nreservation must bear a tax stam...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_471__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, no\nperson, including but not limited to a tobacco product manufacturer,\nshall sell unstamped packages of cigarettes to any agent, if such person\nhas not been provided with a certification by the agent as required in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_471__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_471__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any agent who purchases unstamped packages of cigarettes from any\nperson, which are intended for resale in or into the state, shall\nprovide such person and the department with a certification under\npenalty of perjury that such cigarettes will not be resold by the agent\nin violation of the terms of this article. Such certification shall be\nprovided to such person and the department prior to the first sale of\nsuch cigarettes by such person to the agent following the effective date\nof this subdivision, and annually thereafter, on such form as shall be\nprescribed by the commissioner.\n  5. Prior approval system.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_471__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For any year that the recognized\ngoverning body of an Indian nation or tribe has not elected to\nparticipate in the Indian tax exemption coupon system established in\nsection four hundred seventy-one-e of this article, paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_471__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision provides for the prior approval system to be the\nmechanism as to how Indian nations or tribes or reservation cigarette\nsellers can purchase adequate quantities of tax-exempt cigarettes for\nthe personal use and consumption of qualified members of the Indian\nnation or tribe on their nations' or tribes' qualified reservation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_471__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If an Indian nation or tribe does not elect to participate in the\nIndian tax exemption coupon system, Indian nations or tribes or\nreservation cigarette sellers may purchase from New York state licensed\ncigarette stamping agents and wholesalers an adequate quantity of\ntax-exempt cigarettes based on probable demand on their nations' or\ntribes' qualified reservation for official nation or tribal or qualified\nIndian use or consumption from agents and wholesalers who have received\nprior approval from the department. All such pre-approved tax exempt\ncigarettes shall nonetheless bear a tax stamp. The department shall\ngrant agents and wholesalers prior approval in a manner and form to be\ndetermined by the department and as may be prescribed by regulation. The\ndepartment shall issue expedited refunds or credits to agents whenever\nthe department grants such prior approvals. Probable demand shall be\ndetermined as provided by subdivision two of section four hundred\nseventy-one-e of this article and as may be prescribed by regulation.\n  6. Tax agreements with Indian nations or tribes. If an Indian nation\nor tribe enters into an agreement with the state and the legislature\napproves such agreement or if an Indian nation or tribe enters into an\nagreement with the state that is part of a stipulation and order\napproved by a federal court of competent jurisdiction regarding the sale\nand distribution of cigarettes on the nation's or tribe's qualified\nreservation, the terms of such agreement shall take precedence over the\nprovisions of this article and exempt sales to non-members of the tribe\nor nation and non-Indians by such nation from such taxes to the extent\nthat such taxes are specifically referred to in the agreement, and the\nsale or distribution, including transportation, of any cigarettes to the\nnation's or tribe's qualified reservation shall be in accordance with\nthe provisions of such agreement.\n  7. The taxes imposed under this section shall not ap...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>