<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-472"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-472"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="472"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-472/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-472/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-472/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-472/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_472">
        <num>472</num>
        <heading>Preparation and sale of stamps; commissions; distributors</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_472__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_472__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of such section, shall be applicable to\nagents' licenses applied for or granted pursuant to this section, as if\nsuch provisions had been set forth in full in this subdivision and had\nexpressly referred to the applicant for, or the holder of, an agent's\nlicense. Whenever the commissioner shall sell and deliver to any such\nagent any such stamps, such agent shall be entitled to receive as\ncompensation for his services and expenses as such agent in selling or\naffixing such stamps, and to retain out of the moneys to be paid by him\nfor such stamps, a commission on the par value thereof. The commissioner\nis hereby authorized to prescribe a schedule of commissions, not\nexceeding five per centum, allowable to such agent for buying and\naffixing such stamps. Such schedule shall be uniform with respect to the\ndifferent types of stamps used, and may be on a graduated scale with\nrespect to the number of stamps purchased. The commissioner may, in his\ndiscretion, permit an agent to pay for such stamps within thirty days\nafter the date of purchase and may require any such agent to file with\nthe department of taxation and finance a bond issued by a surety company\napproved by the superintendent of financial services as to solvency and\nresponsibility and authorized to transact business in the state or other\nsecurity acceptable to the commissioner, in such amount as the\ncommissioner may fix, to secure the payment of any sums due from such\nagent pursuant to this article. If securities are deposited as security\nunder this subdivision, such securities shall be kept in the custody of\nthe commissioner and may be sold by the commissioner if it becomes\nnecessary so to do in order to recover any sums due from such agent\npursuant to this article, but no such sale shall be had until after such\nagent shall have had opportunity to litigate the validity of any tax if\nit elects so to do. Upon any such sale, the surplus, if any, above the\nsums due under t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>