<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-5-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-5-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-5-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-5-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-5-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-5-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_A">
        <num>5-A</num>
        <heading>Certification of registration to collect sales and compensating use taxes by certain contractors, affiliates and subcontractors</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Affiliate" means a person which directly, indirectly or\nconstructively\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>controls another person;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is controlled by another person; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>is, along with another person, under the control of a common\nparent.\n  "Control" means possession of the power to direct, or cause the\ndirection of, the management and policies of another person.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Commodities" means commodities as defined in article eleven of\nthe state finance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Contract" means an agreement between a contractor and a\ncovered agency for the purchase by the covered agency, pursuant to\narticle eleven of the state finance law, of commodities or services\nhaving a value in excess of one hundred thousand dollars.\n  The term "contract" shall also include a centralized contract, as\ndefined in article eleven of the state finance law, with a value in\nexcess of one hundred thousand dollars.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The term "contract" shall not include:\n  (A) a purchase by a covered agency of commodities or services with a\nvalue in excess of one hundred thousand dollars based upon a formal\nmini-bid solicitation pursuant to a centralized contract;\n  (B) a grant or an intergovernmental agreement; or\n  (C) a purchase of commodities or services from a "preferred source,"\nas such term is defined in article eleven of the state finance law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Multiple purchases of commodities or services by a covered agency\nfrom the same contractor during a state fiscal year shall not be\naggregated for purposes of determining whether the greater than one\nhundred thousand dollar threshold described in this subdivision has been\nmet.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Contractor" means a person awarded a contract.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Covered agency" means a "state agency" for purposes of article\neleven of the state finance law, the legislature, the judiciary, or a\npublic authority or public benefit corporation at least one of whose\nmembers is appointed by the governor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Department" means the department of taxation and finance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Person" means an individual, partnership, limited liability\ncompany, society, association, joint stock company, or corporation;\nprovided, however, that a "person" shall not include a "public\ncorporation" or an "education corporation," as such terms are defined in\nsection sixty-six of the general construction law, a not-for-profit\ncorporation whose contracts are subject to approval in accordance with\narticle eleven-B of the state finance law, a board of cooperative\neducational services created pursuant to article forty of the education\nlaw, or a soil and water conservation district created pursuant to\nsection five of the soil and water conservation districts law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Sales and compensating use taxes" means state and local sales and\ncompensating use taxes imposed by article twenty-eight and pursuant to\nthe authority of article twenty-nine of this chapter, which are\nadministered by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Sales tax quarter" means a quarterly period ending on the last\nday of February, May, August or November.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Services" means services as defined in article eleven of the\nstate finance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Subcontractor" means a person engaged by a contractor or another\nsubcontractor to perform a portion of the contractor's obligations under\na contract.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"State" means the state of New York.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Taxable services" means services, the receipts from the sale of\nwhich are taxable by article twenty-eight or article twenty-nine of this\nchapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The terms "receipts," "sale," "tangible personal property" and\n"vendor" have the meanings given in article twenty-eight of this\nchapter.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, before a\ncontract may take effect, the contractor must comply with the\nrequirements of subparagraphs one and two of this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The contractor must file a written certification with the\ndepartment, made under penalty of perjury, stating that:\n  (A) if the contractor made sales delivered by any means to locations\nwithin the state of tangible personal property or taxable services\nhaving a value in excess of three hundred thousand dollars during the\nimmediately preceding consecutive four sales tax quarters, the\ncontractor is registered for sales and compensating use tax purposes\nwith the department under sections eleven hundred thirty-four and twelve\nhundred fifty-three of this chapter. If the contractor did not make\nsales delivered by any means to locations within the state of tangible\npersonal property or taxable services having a value in excess of three\nhundred thousand dollars during such four sales tax quarters, then the\ncontractor shall so certify;\n  (B) if any affiliate of the contractor made sales delivered by any\nmeans to locations within the state of tangible personal property or\ntaxable ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The contractor shall also provide the procuring covered agency\nwith a written certification, made under penalty of perjury, stating\nthat:\n  (A) the contractor has filed the certification prescribed by this\nsection with the department, and that such certification is correct and\ncomplete, or\n  (B) such certification is not required to be filed with the\ndepartment, and explaining the reasons for such determination.\n  (C) the certification required by this subparagraph shall be included\nin the procurement record (as such term is defined in article eleven of\nthe state finance law), or similar documentation if the state\ncomptroller is not required by law to approve the contract.\n  (D) any question as to the accuracy of the contractor certification\ndescribed in clause (B) of this subparagraph shall be resolved by the\ncontracting covered agency, in consultation, as necessary, with the\nstate comptroller and the department.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A contractor, affiliate of the contractor, or subcontractor which\nregisters for sales and compensating use tax purposes under sections\neleven hundred thirty-four and twelve hundred fifty-three of this\nchapter in order to comply with the provisions of this subdivision shall\nbe a vendor and shall comply with and be subject to the provisions of\narticles twenty-eight and twenty-nine of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The certification requirements prescribed by this subdivision in\norder for a contract to take effect shall be in addition to any other\nrequirements prescribed by law relating to the formation of contracts to\nwhich a covered agency is a party.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a contract has taken effect, and the terms of such contract\nprovide that it may be renewed upon expiration of an initial or\nsubsequent term, then the contractor shall, no later than the day prior\nto the commencement date of the applicable renewal term, certify to the\ncontracting covered agency in writing, and under penalty of perjury,\nthat:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the contractor has filed the certification prescribed by this\nsection with the department, and that such certification is correct and\ncomplete, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that such certification is not required to be filed with the\ndepartment, and explains the reasons for such determination.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any question as to the accuracy of the contractor certification\ndescribed in subparagraph two of this paragraph shall be resolved by the\ncontracting covered agency, in consultation, as necessary, with the\nstate comptroller and the department.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The certification required by paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision\nshall be made a part of the procurement record (as such term is defined\nin article eleven of the state finance law), or similar documentation if\nthe state comptroller is not required by law to approve the contract.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the contractor fails to make the certification required by\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, or if, during the term of the\ncontract, the department or the covered agency discovers that such\ncertification is false, then such failure or false certification shall\nbe a material breach of the contract, and the contract shall be subject\nto termination if the covered agency determines that such action is in\nthe best interests of the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A contractor, affiliate of the contractor, or subcontractor which\nregisters for sales and compensating use tax purposes under sections\neleven hundred thirty-four and twelve hundred fifty-three of this\nchapter in order to comply with the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision shall be a vendor and shall comply with and be subject to\nthe provisions of articles twenty-eight and twenty-nine of this chapter.\n  4. The provisions of this section shall not apply to a contract if the\nprocuring covered agency and the state comptroller, or other approving\nauthority if the state comptroller is not required to approve the\ncontract, find in writing that the contract is necessary to address an\n"emergency," within the meaning of article eleven of the state finance\nlaw, or to ensure the public health, safety or welfare. Such written\nfinding shall explain the reasons supporting such determination.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>