<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-526"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-526"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="526"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-526/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-526/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-526/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-526/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_526">
        <num>526</num>
        <heading>Returns and payment of tax</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_526__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Returns. Every carrier subject\nto this article and every carrier to whom a  license  was  issued  shall\nfile a return quarterly, on or before the last day of the calendar month\nimmediately  following  the  close  of  each  of  the calendar quarters:\nJanuary through March, April through June, July  through  September  and\nOctober  through  December.  Provided, however, the commissioner may, if\nthe commissioner deems it necessary in order to insure  the  payment  of\nthe  taxes  imposed  by  this  article  or  to comply with a cooperative\nagreement with other jurisdictions  pursuant  to  section  five  hundred\ntwenty-eight  of  this article, require returns to be made at such times\nand covering such  periods  as  the  commissioner  may  deem  necessary.\nReturns  shall  be  filed on forms required by the commissioner for such\npurpose and shall contain such  information  and  certification  as  the\ncommissioner may require, including any information required pursuant to\na  cooperative  agreement five hundred twenty-eight of this article. The\nfact that an individual's name is signed to  a  filed  return  shall  be\nprima  facie  evidence  for  all  purposes  that the return was actually\nsigned by such individual and that such individual is authorized to sign\non behalf of the carrier.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_526__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Payment of tax. At the time of filing a return, as required by\nthis article, each carrier shall pay the tax imposed by this article for\nthe period covered by such return. Such tax shall be due and payable at\nthe time of filing the return or, if a return is not filed when due, on\nthe last day on which the return is required to be filed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_526__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Extensions. The commissioner may grant a reasonable extension of\ntime for filing returns or paying the tax whenever good cause exists and\nmay waive the filing of returns if a carrier is not subject to the tax\nimposed by this article for the period covered by the return.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_526__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Leases. In those instances where the carrier is not the owner of\nthe qualified motor vehicle, the owner may be licensed and file returns\nand maintain records pursuant to this article as prescribed by the\ncommissioner or, if the commissioner enters into a cooperative agreement\nunder section five hundred twenty-eight of this article, as prescribed\nin such agreement. In any event, where the carrier is not the owner of a\nqualified motor vehicle, the owner shall be jointly and severally liable\nwith the carrier for payment of tax under this article with respect to\nsuch qualified motor vehicle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>