<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-659"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-659"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="659"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-659/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-659/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-659/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-659/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_659">
        <num>659</num>
        <heading>Report of federal changes, corrections or disallowances</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_659__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "taxpayer" shall include a partnership\nhaving a resident partner or having any income derived from New York\nsources, and a corporation with respect to which the taxable year of\nsuch change, correction, disallowance or amendment is a year with\nrespect to which the election provided for in subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_659__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nsix hundred sixty of this article is in effect, and (ii) the term\n"federal income tax return" shall include the returns of income required\nunder sections six thousand thirty-one and six thousand thirty-seven of\nthe internal revenue code. In the case of such a corporation, such\nreport shall also include any change or correction of the taxes\ndescribed in paragraphs two and three of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_659__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nthirteen hundred sixty-six of the internal revenue code. Reports made\nunder this section by a partnership or corporation shall indicate the\nportion of the change in each item of income, gain, loss or deduction\n(and, in the case of a corporation, of each change in, or disallowance\nof a claim for credit or refund of, a tax referred to in the preceding\nsentence) allocable to each partner or shareholder and shall set forth\nsuch identifying information with respect to such partner or shareholder\nas may be prescribed by the commissioner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>