<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-961"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-961"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="961"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-961/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-961/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-961/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-961/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_961">
        <num>961</num>
        <heading>Effect of federal determination</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_961__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>General.-- A final federal\ndetermination as to\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_961__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the inclusion in the federal gross estate of any item of property\nor interest in property,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_961__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the allowance of any item claimed as a deduction from the federal\ngross estate, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_961__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the value or amount of any such item, shall also determine the\nsame issue for purposes of the tax under this article unless such final\nfederal determination is shown by a preponderance of the evidence to be\nerroneous.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_961__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Definition.-- For the purpose of this section a final federal\ndetermination means:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_961__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A decision by the tax court or a judgment, decree or other order\nby any court of competent jurisdiction which has become final.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_961__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A final disposition by the secretary of the treasury or his\ndelegate of a claim for refund. Such disposition shall be deemed to have\noccurred--\n  (A) as to items of the claim which are allowed, upon allowance of\nrefund or upon disallowance of the claim by reason of offsetting items;\nand\n  (B) as to items of the claim which are disallowed, or as to items\napplied by the secretary of the treasury or his delegate as an offset\nagainst the claim,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_961__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon expiration of the time for instituting suit\nfor refund with respect to such items, unless suit is instituted before\nthe expiration of such time, or (ii) upon filing with the surrogate or\nappraiser a written statement, in such form as may be required by the\ntax commission, that suit for refund will not be instituted.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_961__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A closing agreement made under section seven thousand one hundred\ntwenty-one of the internal revenue code.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_961__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An assessment pursuant to a waiver of restrictions on assessment,\nor a notification in writing issued by the secretary of the treasury or\nhis delegate that the federal estate tax return has been accepted as\nfiled where such notification is issued after an audit of such return,\nunless the executor shall have filed with the commissioner of taxation\nand finance a written statement, in such form as may be required by the\ncommissioner, that a claim for refund of federal estate taxes has been\nor will be filed.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_961__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Items determined.-- If there has been a final federal\ndetermination with respect to a decedent's federal estate tax, any item\nentering into the computation of such tax shall be deemed to have been\nthe subject of the final federal determination, whether or not\nspecifically adjusted thereby.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>