<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="TAX">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-977"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-977"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="977"/>
          <FRBRname value="TAX"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-977/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-977/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-977/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/tax/section-977/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_977">
        <num>977</num>
        <heading>Requirements concerning returns, notices, records and statements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_977__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>General. The commissioner of taxation and finance may\nprescribe regulations as to the keeping of records, the content and form\nof returns, statements or other documents, and the filing of copies of\nfederal estate tax returns and determinations. The commissioner may\nrequire any executor or other person, by regulation, instruction or\nnotice served upon such person, to make such returns or documents,\nrender such statements, or keep such records as the commissioner may\ndeem sufficient to show whether or not such executor or other person is\nliable under this article for tax.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_977__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Federal return.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_977__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a federal estate tax return is required for\nfederal estate tax purposes, a copy thereof, together with such summary\nand additional information as the commissioner of taxation and finance\nmay prescribe, shall be filed with the return of tax under this article.\n  For the purposes of this article, the phrase "return, statement or\nother document" shall include a copy of the federal estate tax return,\ndocument or statement.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_977__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a federal estate tax return is not required for federal estate\ntax purposes, the return of tax under this article shall include such\nschedules and information as the commissioner of taxation and finance\nshall prescribe.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_977__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Identifying numbers.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_977__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When required by the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance:\n  (A) Inclusion in returns. Any person required under the authority of\nthis article to make a return, statement, or other document, or copies\nthereof, shall include in such return, statement, or other document, or\ncopies thereof, such identifying number as may be prescribed for\nsecuring proper identification of such person, or of the decedent.\n  (B) Furnishing number to other persons. Any person with respect to\nwhom a return, statement, or other document, or copy thereof, is\nrequired under the authority of this article to be made by another\nperson shall furnish to such other person such identifying number as may\nbe prescribed for securing his proper identification.\n  (C) Furnishing number of another person. Any person required under the\nauthority of this article to make a return, statement, or other\ndocument, or copy thereof, with respect to another person, shall request\nfrom such other person, and shall include ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_977__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Limitation. For purposes of subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_977__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of this subsection, a return, statement, or other document, or\ncopies thereof, of an estate, with respect to its liability for tax,\nshall be considered as a return, statement, or other document, or copies\nthereof, with respect to each beneficiary of such estate under this\narticle.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_977__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Requirement of information. For purposes of this subsection, the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance is authorized to require such\ninformation as may be necessary to assign an identifying number to any\nperson or estate.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_977__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Use of social security account number. The social security account\nnumber issued to an individual may, except as otherwise specified by the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance, be used as the identifying number\nfor such individual for purposes of this title.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_977__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notice of qualification as executor. Every executor shall give\nnotice of his qualifications as such to the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance in such manner and at such time as may be required by the\ncommissioner. The commissioner may provide such exemptions from the\nrequirements of this section as he deems proper.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>