<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0522"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0522"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0522"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0522/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0522/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0522/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0522/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0522">
        <num>11-0522</num>
        <heading>Urban deer management pilot program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>* ยง 11-0522. Urban deer management pilot program.\n  1. For the purposes of this section, " nuisance wildlife specialist"\nshall mean an employee of or a contractor for the federal or state\ngovernment responsible for wildlife management acting pursuant to a deer\nmanagement plan and deer cull permit. A nuisance wildlife specialist\nmust be in compliance with criteria established by the department that\nat a minimum shall require:\n  a. a minimum level of marksmanship qualifications appropriate to the\nfirearm or hunting implement to be used;\n  b. liability insurance coverage or other financial arrangements\nidentified by the department;\n  c. a copy of the cull permit and a copy of the log of nuisance\nwildlife specialists using the permit, be on the nuisance wildlife\nspecialist's person when exercising any privilege of such permit; and\n  d. reporting requirements.\n  2. The department may, after reviewing the city of Syracuse's cull\npermit application and site-specific deer management plan, and upon a\nfinding by the city of Syracuse that deer have become a nuisance,\ndestructive to public or private property or a threat to public health\nor welfare, issue a deer cull permit for use within the boundaries of\nthe city of Syracuse, authorizing use of a nuisance wildlife specialist\nto take deer pursuant to the terms of the deer cull permit.\n  3. Each cull permit application shall at a minimum include\nrequirements for: the timeframe during which the permit must be used, a\nsite-specific deer management plan, a geographic description of the area\nfor which the permit is being requested, a written contract with the\ncity of Syracuse, a list which identifies participating nuisance\nwildlife specialists and eligibility based on the criteria established\nby the department, provided by the city of Syracuse, requests for any\nauthorization pursuant to subdivisions three and nine of section 11-0505\nof this title, subdivision two of section 11-0901 of this article, and\nsubdivisions two and four of section 11-0931 of this article, provided\nthat any such authorization subsequently granted shall be explicitly\nincluded on any cull permit, and details regarding expected local law\nenforcement consultation.\n  4. Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring or\nobligating the department to issue a permit to take deer when in its\nopinion the nuisance, destruction of property or threat to public health\nand welfare will not be effectively abated thereby.\n  * NB Repealed January 1, 2027\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>