<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0307"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0307">
        <num>11-0307</num>
        <heading>Migratory game birds; regulation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0307. Migratory game birds; regulation.\n  * 1. The department may adopt rules and regulations in relation to\nmigratory game birds, provided such regulations are no less restrictive\nthan federal regulations made under authority of the Migratory Bird\nTreaty Act of July 3, 1918, (16 U.S.C. secs. 703-711), as may be amended\nfrom time to time.\n  * NB Effective until December 31, 2027\n  * 1. The department shall adopt rules and regulations in relation to\nmigratory game birds consistent with federal regulations made under\nauthority of the Migratory Bird Treaty Act of July 3, 1918, (16 U.S.C.\nsecs. 703-711), as presently constituted or as hereafter amended.\n  * NB Effective December 31, 2027\n  2. The department shall, by rule and regulation, establish the means\nor method for creation of both voluntary migratory bird stamps and\nmigratory bird art prints, their administration, sale and distribution\nand other matters relating to such voluntary stamps and art prints. The\ndepartment shall select appropriate works of art that will reflect\nmigratory bird species and/or aquatic ecosystem scenes. The department\nmay prepare or cause to be prepared voluntary migratory bird stamps and\nprints for any year in excess of the number otherwise to be issued for\nsale to collectors or other persons desiring to purchase such voluntary\nstamps or prints.\n  3. The department shall prepare or cause to be prepared voluntary\nmigratory bird stamps and shall furnish such migratory bird stamps\nannually to license issuing agents and officers for issuance or sale in\nthe same manner as other types of licenses. The department shall, by\nrule and regulation, establish the fee for such voluntary stamps which\nshall not exceed five dollars as a fee and fifty cents for the issuing\nagent or officer for a stamp sold in the year in which it was issued.\nThe purchase of a stamp is voluntary and need not be possessed in order\nto hunt migratory waterfowl.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>