<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0113"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0113"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0113"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0113">
        <num>11-0113</num>
        <heading>Manner of reference to and amendment of provisions contained in tables</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0113. Manner of reference to and amendment of provisions contained\n             in tables.\n  1. Any portion of any table contained in a section of the Fish and\nWildlife Law, which portion is capable of identification by reference as\nprovided in this section or otherwise may be quoted, cited, amended or\nrepealed, as if the portion so quoted, cited, amended or repealed,\nconstituted a complete numbered paragraph.\n  2. In the tables in sections 11-0905 and 11-0907 each letter of the\nalphabet in column one identifies and furnishes the citation for the\nmatter in column one following such letter and also identifies and\nfurnishes the citation for the matter appearing in column two and column\nthree opposite the matter so identified in column one.\n  3. All matter identified by a letter of the alphabet printed in\nlower-case print and enclosed in parentheses may be referred to as an\n"item"; all matter identified by a figure printed in arabic numerals and\nenclosed in parentheses may be referred to as a "sub-item".\n  4. The headings appearing at the top of the columns are not part of\nthe identification and citation of any part of the table, but the\nportion of any item or sub-item appearing in a column may be referred to\nas the portion of that item appearing in that column and "relating to"\nspecies, open season, bag limit, area, game and open season, manner of\ntaking, specified waters of the state, or open season, size limits and\nlimits of catch, as the case may be.\n  5. This section does not make ineffective or affect the construction\nor operation of any other form or manner of reference used in any act\nenacted by the legislature.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>