<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0539"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0539"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0539"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0539/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0539/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0539/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0539/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0539">
        <num>11-0539</num>
        <heading>New York natural heritage program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0539__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provides habitat for "endangered species" or "threatened species"\nas defined in section 11-0535 of this title for animals and 9-1503 of\nthis chapter for plants;\n  (ii) provides habitat for rare species where rare means species ranked\nas S1, S2 or S3 under criteria developed pursuant to paragraph b of\nsubdivision one of this section; or\n  (iii) contains "significant ecological communities" where such term\nmeans all rare ecological communities as well as the best examples of\ncommon communities.\n  b. Any property designated as a natural heritage area shall be\ndescribed and depicted upon a map. The description shall include a\nnarrative setting forth the plants, animals or ecological communities\npresent on the property. The department shall make maps depicting\nnatural heritage areas available for public inspection except as\nprovided in subdivision four of this section.\n  c. Designation may be accomplished by the head of any state agency or\nentity having jurisdiction over state lands or waters for such\nappropriate properties as may exist within their respective\njurisdictions and consistent with their respective missions, provided\nthe commissioner is consulted, and approves, prior to such designation.\n  d. A designating state agency or entity shall publish notice\nconcerning the designation of a natural heritage area in the\nenvironmental notice bulletin prior to such designation. Such notice\nshall provide for a thirty day public comment period following\npublication of the notice.\n  e. The head of any state agency or entity having jurisdiction over\nstate lands or waters previously designated as natural heritage areas\nmay seek to remove all or a portion of such lands or waters from such\ndesignation provided, however, that prior to such removal the\ncommissioner publishes a finding that the designated area or portion of\nsuch area no longer meets the criteria in paragraph a of this\nsubdivision. Such finding shall be published in the environmental n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>