<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0913"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0913"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0913"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0913/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0913/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0913/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0913/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0913">
        <num>11-0913</num>
        <heading>Deer management permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0913. Deer management permits.\n  1. a. Until December thirty-first, two thousand twenty-seven, whenever\nin its opinion the population of deer in any area of the state except in\nthe northern zone is such that additional harvest of deer is reasonably\nnecessary to properly manage the deer herd in the state in balance with\nthe available deer range and natural food supply, the department may\nprovide by regulation for issuance of deer management permits,\npermitting the taking of one deer for the permit, in addition to the\nlimit of one deer that may otherwise be taken by one person in a license\nyear.\n  b. In the issuance of permits, the department may give preference to\nresident license holders and may give preference to service-connected\ndisabled veterans having 40 percent or greater service-connected\ndisability as evidenced by a compensation rating from the United States\nDepartment of Veterans Affairs or the United States Department of\nDefense who shall only have to provide proof of service-connected\ndisability at the time of initial issuance of the permit, and to the\napplications of groups which include a person or the spouse of a person,\nprovided that such spouse lives in the same household, who owns at least\n50 acres of land in one parcel in the specified area.\n  c. "Owner" as used in this section shall include the owner or spouse\nof the owner of record of such parcel, provided that such spouse lives\nin the same household as the owner, or a purchaser or spouse of such\npurchaser of such parcel, provided that such spouse lives in the same\nhousehold as such purchaser, under an executory contract duly recorded\nin the office of the recording officer in the county in which real\nproperty to which it relates is situate, who actually occupy and\ncultivate such parcel.\n  2. Each such regulation shall specify, with respect to the permits to\nwhich it relates:\n  a. The open season or part thereof and the day or days of such season\nin which such permits may be used;\n  b. The specific area in which they are valid;\n  c. The manner of taking for which such permits are valid, which shall\nconform with the specifications as to the manner of taking deer in the\nopen season for which the permits may be used;\n  d. The method of application for and issuance of such permits,\nincluding eligibility and allocation among applicants;\n  e. The number of persons, no fewer than one nor more than six, who\nmust join in the application; and\n  f. Such other regulations as the department may determine.\n  3. Each member of a group issued a permit pursuant to this section\nshall possess a license which authorizes the holder to hunt deer before\nthe permit may be validated.\n  4. During a license year, no person shall use more than one license\nwhich authorizes the holder to hunt deer during the regular open season\nin making application for a deer management permit.\n  5. The provisions of paragraph a of subdivision 1 of section 11-0911\nshall not apply when a deer is taken pursuant to a deer management\npermit, but the department may by regulation provide an alternative\nmethod of identifying and reporting the deer so taken.\n  6. With each deer management permit there shall be issued a tag or\nseal and a reporting form as the department shall determine to be\nappropriate, and the additional deer may be taken only by the group\nmember who, at the time, is in physical possession of the permit and any\ntag, seal and reporting form issued with it.\n  7. The department shall charge and receive a fee of ten dollars for\nthe application and the processing of such permit or permits. Applicants\nwho are successful in the computerized selection shall receive the\npermit or permits free of any additional charge. The application fee\nshall be non-refundable. The department may waive the application fee\nfor holders of a lifetime sportsman license existing as of October\nfirst, two thousand nine and holders of a hunting license less than\nsixteen years of age.\n  8. Except with respect to deer management unit thirty-four the\nprovision of this section shall not apply to the "Northern Zone" of the\nstate as defined in subdivision sixteen of section 11-0103 of this\nchapter.\n  9. Nothing set forth in this section shall prevent the department from\npermitting the issuance of deer management permits in those portions of\nFranklin, St. Lawrence, Jefferson and Lewis counties and Northern Zone\nportions of Oneida and Oswego counties which are situated in the area\ngenerally described as the Lake Ontario Plain, St. Lawrence Valley and\nperipheral Adirondacks/peripheral Tug Hill region. The department is\nauthorized and directed to promulgate any rules or regulations necessary\nto more particularly describe the region of land set forth in this\nsubdivision.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>