<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0927"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0927"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0927"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0927/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0927/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0927/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0927/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0927">
        <num>11-0927</num>
        <heading>Field trials</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0927. Field trials.\n  1. No person shall hold a field trial except as provided in this\nsection or take part in a field trial not conducted in accordance with\nthe provisions of this section.\n  2. a. A field trial may be held on liberated game, liberated\nartificially propagated game, led or confined game legally possessed, or\non wild game on a licensed dog training area at any time without\nlicense, provided such game is not taken by shooting or otherwise\nkilled; and, on areas other than a licensed dog training area, such\nfield trials may be held on wild game from August 16 to April 15 without\nlicense, or at such other times when licensed by the department from\nApril 16 to August 15.\n  b. A permit from the department is required for liberation of any\nwildlife.\n  3. Wild game shall not be taken by shooting or otherwise killed in the\ncourse of a field trial. Other game on which a field trial may be held\nas provided in this section may be taken by shooting in the course of a\nfield trial, except a field trial held on a licensed dog training area,\nprovided a license for such shooting has been procured from the\ndepartment. Game so taken shall be immediately identified on forms\nprovided by the department until the game is finally prepared for\nconsumption.\n  4. Game so identified may be possessed, transported, bought and sold\nat any time, without limitation by section 11-0917 of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>