<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0103">
        <num>11-0103</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>game birds;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>big game;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>small\ngame.\n  a. "Game birds" are classified as</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>migratory game birds and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nupland game birds.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Migratory game birds" means the Anatidae or waterfowl, commonly\nknown as geese, brant, swans and river and sea ducks; the Rallidae,\ncommonly known as rails, American coots, mud hens and gallinules; the\nLimicolae or shorebirds, commonly known as woodcock, snipe, plover,\nsurfbirds, sandpipers, tattlers and curlews; the Corvidae, commonly\nknown as jays, crows and magpies.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Upland game birds" (Gallinae) means wild turkeys, grouse,\npheasant, Hungarian or European gray-legged partridge and quail. Grouse\nmeans ruffed grouse and every member of the grouse family. Pheasant\nmeans the ring-necked, dark-necked and mutant pheasants and all species\nand subspecies of the genus Phasianus representing the true or game\npheasants.\n  b. "Big game" means deer, bear, moose, elk, except captive bred and\nraised North American elk (Cervus elaphus), caribou and antelope.\n  c. "Small game" means black, gray and fox squirrels, European hares,\nvarying hares, cottontail rabbits, native frogs, native salamanders,\nnative turtles, native lizards, native snakes, coyotes, red fox (Vulpes\nvulpes) and gray fox (Urocyon cinereoargenteus) except captive bred red\nfox or gray fox, raccoon, opossum, or weasel, skunk, bobcat, lynx,\nmuskrat, mink, except mink born in captivity, fisher, otter, beaver,\nsable and marten but does not include coydogs.\n  3. "Wild game" means all game,...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>domestic game bird and\ndomestic game animal as defined in subdivision 4;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>carcasses of\nforeign game as defined in section 11-1717, imported from outside the\nUnited States;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>game propagated or kept alive in captivity as\nprovided in section 11-1907 of this article;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>game imported alive\npursuant to license of the department, or artificially propagated, until\nsuch game is liberated; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>game so imported or propagated when\nliberated for the purpose of a field trial and taken during the field\ntrial for which it was liberated.\n  4. a. "Domestic game bird" means ducks, geese, brant, swans,\npheasants, quail, wild turkey, ruffed grouse, Chukar partridge and\nHungarian or European gray-legged partridge, propagated under a domestic\ngame bird breeder's license pursuant to section 11-1901 or a shooting\npreserve license pursuant to section 11-1903, or propagated on a\npreserve or island outside the state under a law similar in principle to\ntitle 19 of this article.\n  b. "Domestic game animal" means white-tailed deer propagated under a\ndomestic game animal breeder's license pursuant to section 11-1905 or\npropagated on a preserve or island outside the state under a law similar\nin principle to title 19 of this article.\n  c. To qualify as such domestic game bird or domestic game animal,</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nlive game must be held in private ownership, on such licensed premises,\nand in the case of deer must be held on a preserve which is fenced, or\nis an island, as provided in section 11-1905, or must be held in\nconfinement in course of transportation, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the carcasses or flesh\nof such game coming from outside the state must originate on premises\noperated by the holder of a domestic game certificate as provided in\nsection 11-1715.\n  5. a. "Unprotected wild birds" means the English sparrow and starling,\nand also includes pigeons and psittacine birds existing in a wild state,\nnot domesticated.\n  b. "Protected birds" means all wild birds except those named in\nparagraph a of this subdivision.\n  6. a. "Wildlife" means wild game and all other animal life existing in\na wild state, except fish, shellfish and crustacea.\n  b. "Wild bird" means birds which are "wildlife".\n  c. "Protected wildlife" means wild game, protected wild birds,\nprotected insects, species of special concern and endangered and\nthreatened species of wildlife designated by the department pursuant to\nsection 11-0535 of this article, species listed in section 11-0536 of\nthis article and species protected pursuant to section 11-0311 of this\narticle.\n  d. "Unprot...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Nonhuman primates and prosimians,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Felidae and all hybrids thereof, with the exception of the species\nFelis catus (domesticated and feral cats, which shall mean domesticated\ncats that were formerly owned and that have been abandoned and that are\nno longer socialized, as well as offspring of such cats) and hybrids of\nFelis catus that are registered by the American Cat Fanciers Association\nor the International Cat Association provided that such cats be without\nany wild felid parentage for a minimum of five generations,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Canidae (with the exception of domesticated dogs and captive bred\nfennec foxes (vulpes zerda)),\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Ursidae,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All reptiles that are venomous by nature, pursuant to department\nregulation, and the following species and orders: Burmese Python (Python\nm. bivittatus), Reticulated Python (Python reticulatus), African Rock\nPython (Python sabae), Green Anaconda (Eunectes maurinus), Yellow\nAnaconda (Eunectes notaeus), Australian Amethystine Python (Morelia\namethistina and Morelia kinghorni), Indian Python (Python molurus),\nAsiatic (water) Monitor (Varanus salvator), Nile Monitor (Varanus\nnilocitus), White Throat Monitor (Varanus albigularis), Black Throat\nMonitor (Varanus albigularis ionides) and Crocodile Monitor (Varanus\nsalvadori), Komodo Dragon (Varanus komodensis) and any hybrid thereof,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Crocodylia.\n  7. "Protected insect" means any insect with respect to the taking of\nwhich restrictions are imposed by the Fish and Wildlife Law or\nregulations of the department pursuant thereto.\n  8. "Plumage" is defined in section 11-1729.\n  9. "Shellfish" means oysters, scallops, and all kinds of clams and\nmussels.\n  10. "Hunting" means pursuing, shooting, killing or capturing (other\nthan trapping as defined in subdivision 11) wildlife, except wildlife\nwhich has been lawfully trapped or otherwise reduced to possession, and\nincludes all lesser acts such as disturbing, harrying or worrying,\nwhether they result in taking or not, and every attempt to take and\nevery act of assistance to any other person in taking or attempting to\ntake wildlife.\n  11. "Trapping" means taking, killing and capturing wildlife with\ntraps, deadfalls and other devices commonly used to take wildlife, and\nthe shooting or killing of wildlife lawfully trapped, and includes all\nlesser acts such as pla...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the operator must be present and in immediate\nattendance when lines are in the water;\n  *</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>one person may operate not more than two lines, with or without\nrod, except that one person may operate up to three lines in freshwater;\n  * NB Effective until December 31, 2027\n  *</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>one person may operate not more than two lines, with or without\nrod;\n  * NB Effective December 31, 2027\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_e__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>each line shall have not more than five lures or baits, or a\ncombination of both, and in addition each line shall have not exceeding\nfifteen single hooks, or seven double hooks, or five triple hooks, or\nany combination of such hooks, provided the total number of hook points\nthereof does not exceed fifteen. Angling does not include snatching or\nhooking or the use of tip-ups.\n  c. "Hooking", "snatching" or "snagging" means taking fish that have\nnot taken or attempted to take a bait or artificial lure into their\nmouth, by impaling fish with one or more hooks or similar devices,\nwhether or not baited, into any part of their body.\n  d. "Net" means a non-metallic fabric wrought or woven into meshes and\nincludes the types known as seine, gill, pound, trap, scap, fyke, dip,\nscoop and stake net.\n  e. "Spear" means a hand-propelled single or multiple pronged pike,\nblade or harpoon, and does not include the mechanically propelled device\ncommonly called a spear gun or under-water gu...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_11_0103__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A)(vi) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and that is in\ncompliance with all applicable provisions of the Animal Welfare Act, 7\nUSC Sec. 2131 et seq. and operates a place of refuge where abused,\nneglected, unwanted, impounded, abandoned, orphaned, or displaced wild\nanimals are provided care for their lifetime or rehabilitated and\nreleased back to their natural habitat, and, with respect to any animal\nowned by the organization, does not:\n  a. Use the animal for any type of entertainment, recreational or\ncommercial purpose except for the purpose of exhibition as defined by\nthe department;\n  b. Sell, trade, lend or barter the animal or the animal's body parts;\nor\n  c. Breed the animal.\n  33. "Long bow" includes longbows, recurve bows, compound bows, and\ncrossbows.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>