<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0507"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0507"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0507"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0507">
        <num>11-0507</num>
        <heading>Liberation of fish, shellfish and wildlife</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0507. Liberation of fish, shellfish and wildlife.\n  1. Fish or fish eggs shall not be placed in any waters of the state\nunless a permit is first obtained from the department; but no permit\nshall be required to place fish or fish eggs in an aquarium.\n  2. No person shall liberate or import or cause to be imported for the\npurpose of liberation within the state any European hare (Lepus\neuropaeus), European or San Juan rabbit (Oryctolagus cuniculus), Texas\nor jack rabbit (Lepus californicus), gray fox (Urocyon\ncinereoargenteus), including captive bred gray fox, red fox (Vulpes\nvuples), including captive bred red fox or nutria (Myocastor coypus),\nwhether taken from within or without the state. Nutria may be imported\nonly by permit of the department for scientific, exhibition or for\nbreeding purposes.\n  3. No person shall willfully liberate within the state any wildlife\nexcept under permit from the department. The department may issue such\npermit in its discretion, fix the terms thereof and revoke it at\npleasure. These provisions do not apply to migratory game birds,\nimportation of which is governed by regulation of the department.\n  4. No person shall intentionally liberate zebra mussels (Dreissena\npolymorpha) into any waters of the state. No person shall buy, sell, or\noffer to buy or sell, or intentionally possess or transport zebra\nmussels except under a license or permit issued pursuant to section\n11-0515. Zebra mussels, except those lawfully held pursuant to a license\nor permit, may be destroyed by any person at any time.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>