<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0923"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0923"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0923"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0923/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0923/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0923/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0923/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0923">
        <num>11-0923</num>
        <heading>Dogs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0923. Dogs.\n  1. No owner or trainer of a dog shall:\n  a. allow it to hunt deer, or to run at large on enclosed lands on\nwhich wildlife or domestic game is possessed under license issued\npursuant to the Fish and Wildlife Law or in any state park, state park\nreservation, state-owned game farm or wildlife refuge or state-owned or\nleased wildlife management area;\n  b. allow it to run at large in fields or woods inhabited by deer\noutside the limits of any city or village, except on lands actually\nfarmed or cultivated by the owner or trainer of the dog or a tenant of\nsuch owner or trainer.\n  2. No owner or trainer of a dog shall take it afield for training on\nwild game except from August 16 to April 15 or as otherwise permitted by\ndepartment order.\n  3. Dogs may be trained on artificially propagated game which is\nshackled, or led or confined game, legally possessed, or on training\ndummies or other artificial devices at any time on lands owned or leased\nby the owner or trainer of the dog or on lands for which he has written\npermission of the owner or lessee, provided such training is done in a\nmanner to preclude any disturbances injurious to wildlife.\n  4. During the training of a dog, the trainer and any person in his\ncompany shall not possess afield a firearm loaded with ammunition other\nthan blank shells or blank cartridges, or inflict any injury to animals\nor game birds contrary to law.\n  5. Dogs hunting deer, or hunting any wildlife or domestic game on\nenclosed lands described in paragraph a of subdivision 1 or on a state\ngame farm or wildlife refuge or wildlife management area, may be killed\nas provided in section 11-0529.\n  6. Wildlife, except skunk, deer and bear, may be taken with the aid of\na dog, provided, however, that the department is authorized to establish\na training season during which only persons licensed by the department\npursuant to section 11-0928 of this article may train tracking dogs on\nbear. Such season shall not begin before July first and shall end at\nleast eight days in advance of any open hunting season for bear and no\nperson participating in such training shall possess a firearm of any\nkind or a longbow. Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to\ninvalidate or otherwise affect a permit to track or take bear issued\npursuant to subdivision one of section 11-0521 of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>