<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0909"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0909"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0909"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0909/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0909/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0909/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0909/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0909">
        <num>11-0909</num>
        <heading>Hunting hours</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0909. Hunting hours.\n  1. Bobcat, mink, muskrat, raccoon, coyote, fox and skunk may be taken\nat any hour, day or night.\n  2. Migratory game birds shall be taken only during the hours specified\nin regulations adopted by the department pursuant to section 11-0307.\n  3. a. Wild deer and bear, wild upland game birds, and small game other\nthan bobcat, mink, muskrat, raccoon, coyote, fox and skunk, taken in any\nopen season, shall be taken only between the hours of sunrise and\nsunset, unless otherwise provided in regulations of the department.\n  b. The department shall have the authority to establish by regulation\nhours of hunting wild deer and bear, wild upland game birds, and small\ngame, other than bobcat, mink, muskrat, raccoon, coyote, fox and skunk,\nduring the open season provided therefor.\n  c. Such regulations shall provide for uniform hunting hours for all\nspecies of game for which an open season is provided, during all or any\npart of the period covered by such regulations, other than bobcat, mink,\nmuskrat, raccoon, coyote, fox and skunk.\n  d. The department shall have the authority to provide in such\nregulations for different hours of hunting in different areas as set\nforth in such regulations, and shall have the authority in such\nregulations to provide for different hours of hunting for a part or\nparts of any open season.\n  e. A summary of regulations adopted pursuant to this subdivision shall\nbe published each year in the hunting and fishing syllabus of the\ndepartment issued pursuant to section 11-0323.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>