<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0524"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0524"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0524"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0524/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0524/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0524/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0524/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0524">
        <num>11-0524</num>
        <heading>Nuisance wildlife control operators</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0524. Nuisance wildlife control operators.\n  1. No person shall charge a fee to take, possess, transport or release\nwildlife whenever it becomes a nuisance pursuant to section 11-0505,\n11-0507, 11-0521, or 11-0523 of this title unless such person has been\nissued a nuisance wildlife control operator license by the department.\n  2. No person shall be issued a license by the department under this\nsection unless he or she provides evidence satisfactory to the\ndepartment, that he or she has completed nuisance wildlife control\ntraining. In addition to any other requirements of the department, such\ntraining shall include training in site evaluation, methods of resolving\ncommon nuisance wildlife problems, including, but not limited to,\nnon-lethal methods; exclusion methods; habitat modification; and capture\nand handling techniques.\n  3. The department may issue a revocable nuisance wildlife control\noperator license and adopt regulations concerning the qualifications for\nsuch license and the terms and conditions of such license provided,\nhowever, that any such regulations, terms and conditions include\ntraining requirements consistent with subdivision two of this section.\n  4. The fee for a nuisance wildlife control operator license shall be\nfifty dollars paid annually to be deposited in the conservation fund\nestablished pursuant to section eighty-three of the state finance law,\nprovided, however, that a municipality shall not be subject to this fee.\n  5. Any person licensed pursuant to this section shall submit annually\na report to the department which specifies each client's name and\naddress, the date work was performed, the species controlled, the\nabatement method used, the disposition of the animal, and any other\ninformation as required by the department. The department shall annually\nupdate a list of nuisance wildlife control operators and make it\navailable to the public in both printed and electronic formats.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>