<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0704"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0704"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0704"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0704">
        <num>11-0704</num>
        <heading>Transfer of a lifetime license</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0704. Transfer of a lifetime license.\n  A lifetime license, as provided in section 11-0702 of this title, is\nnot transferable to any person unless:\n  1. the person to whom such license and permit was issued dies within\none year of the issuance date of such license and permit; and\n  2. the person to whom such license and permit is to be transferred is\na legal resident of this state pursuant to this title; and\n  3. the person to whom such license and permit is to be transferred\nwould otherwise be eligible to purchase such license and permit; and\n  4. the person to whom such license is to be transferred is related to\nthe person to whom such license was issued by the first degree of\nconsanguinity, or legal marriage to such person, or is the adopted child\nor step child or step sibling of such person; and\n  5. designation is made by the personal representative of the\ndecedent's estate; and\n  6. The application for transfer is made within three years of the\nissuance of the license; and\n  7. the person to whom such license and permit is transferred pays the\nfee as set forth in section 11-0702 of this title; and\n  8. such license and permit has not been previously transferred.\n  Provided, however, that subdivisions one, six and seven of this\nsection shall not apply when the person to whom such license was issued\nwas a member of the armed forces of the United States or a member of the\nnational guard or other reserve component of the armed forces of the\nUnited States who died in combat zone or combat zone of operations or\nwhile deployed for active military duty, other than training, on or\nafter the eleventh day of September, two thousand one.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>