<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0306-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0306-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-06-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0306-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0306-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0306-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0306-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0306-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0306_A">
        <num>11-0306-A</num>
        <heading>The Flax Pond tidal wetlands sanctuary</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0306-a. The Flax Pond tidal wetlands sanctuary.\n  1. There is established a Flax Pond tidal wetlands sanctuary for the\npurpose of protecting areas of special ecological significance within\nthe Flax Pond tidal marsh. The sanctuary shall be composed of the tidal\nwetlands located in the village of Old Field, county of Suffolk as\ndesignated on the March tenth, nineteen hundred sixty-six survey filed\nin the Suffolk County Clerk's office as file number 136899 and including\na permanent easement for the State University of New York as designated\non the March ninth, nineteen hundred sixty-six survey filed in the\nSuffolk County Clerk's office as file number 81558, and including\nacreage of 146.162 acres. The sanctuary shall be managed by the\ndepartment in cooperation with the state university at Stony Brook. The\nsanctuary shall be managed as a long-term field laboratory for research\nand education to provide:\n  a. a natural area for academic research across a wide variety of\ndisciplines including, but not limited to, the fields of community\necology, population ecology, predator-prey relationships, food chain and\nweb dynamics, nutrient and energy flow, hydrology, ornithology, botany,\nand forestry management;\n  b. opportunities for instruction between teaching faculty and students\nby using the property as an "outdoor classroom";\n  c. opportunities for students, faculty, and the public to connect with\nthe natural world around them;\n  d. a meaningful contribution toward protection of local and regional\nbiodiversity;\n  e. lawful recreational angling, however no commercial fishing or\nshellfishing, nor the taking of invertebrates for bait shall be\npermitted within the sanctuary;\n  f. lawful waterfowl hunting during the appropriate open season\nfollowing receipt of a tidal wetlands access permit issued pursuant to\ndepartment regulations; and\n  g. boating by sail, human propelled oar or paddle, or mechanically\npropelled vessels having a source of power less than ten horsepower.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>