<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1301"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1301">
        <num>11-1301</num>
        <heading>General provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-1301. General provisions.\n  1. Except as specifically provided in this article or in article 13,\nor any regulation adopted pursuant thereto:\n  a. No fish, other than migratory food fish of the sea in the marine\nand coastal district, shall be taken except by angling.\n  b. Fish named by regulation adopted pursuant to section 11-1303 of\nthis title shall be taken only during the open seasons specified in such\norder and only if they are within the minimum size limits established by\nsuch regulation.\n  * c. Except as otherwise prohibited by law, fish may be taken by spear\nor speargun in the marine and coastal district only for recreational\npurposes. A speargun must be submerged when used to take fish. Provided,\nhowever, that no food fish may be taken by spear or speargun within one\nhundred yards of a public bathing area.\n  * NB Repealed June 1, 2026\n  2. Except when taken pursuant to section 11-0515 or 11-0517 of this\narticle, or when taken in nets as provided by title 15 or article 13,\nfish named by regulation adopted pursuant to section 11-1303 of this\ntitle shall not be taken in excess of the daily or seasonal catch limits\nestablished by such regulation.\n  3. Fish shall not be taken contrary to the restrictions contained in\nany regulation of the department, made pursuant to any provision of the\nFish and Wildlife Law, closing waters to the taking of fish, or\nrestricting the use of nets or other devices, or fixing seasons, size\nlimits or daily or seasonal catch limits, or otherwise restricting the\ntaking of fish.\n  4. Fish unintentionally taken contrary to any provision of the Fish\nand Wildlife Law or regulation of the department shall be returned to\nthe water at once without unnecessary injury.\n  5. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of the Fish and Wildlife\nLaw, the department may adopt regulations for catch and release fishing\nin all waters of the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>