<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1209"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1209">
        <num>11-1209</num>
        <heading>Penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-1209. Penalties.\n  1. Whoever shall hunt while his ability is impaired by the consumption\nof alcohol shall be guilty of a violation of law.\n  2. Whoever shall hunt while in an intoxicated condition or while his\nability to hunt is impaired by the use of a drug shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor, punishable by imprisonment in a penitentiary or county jail\nfor not more than one year, or by a fine of not more than five hundred\ndollars, or by both such fine and imprisonment.\n  3. Notwithstanding any provision in section 11-1205 of this title, the\ndepartment may revoke, for a period not exceeding two years, any or all\nlicenses, bowhunting privileges, muzzle-loading privileges, or permits\nto hunt of any person who violates any subdivision of section 11-1203 of\nthis title. Action by the department resulting in such revocation shall\nbecome effective only after a hearing held by the department upon notice\nto such person, at which proof of facts indicating the violation is\nestablished to the satisfaction of the commissioner, or of the hearing\nofficer and concurred in by the commissioner. A person whose license to\nhunt has been revoked as provided in this subdivision is ineligible for\nsuch license during the period determined by the department as provided\nin this section. No such person shall, during such period, procure any\nlicense for which he is ineligible. No person shall without license hunt\nor trap during any period in which the privilege to do so has been\ndenied him by the department as provided in this section. When the\ndepartment has revoked a license, or has denied to any person the\nability to obtain a license, it shall cause the fact of such revocation\nor denial, or both, as the case may be, and the terms and extent\nthereof, to be entered in the minutes of the department, and shall\nforthwith send a written notice of its action as so entered in the\nminutes to the person affected, at his last known address, either by\nregistered or certified mail or by delivery personally by a\nrepresentative of the department. Within five days after service of such\nnotice, such person shall deliver to the department the license or\nlicenses revoked, together with any bowhunting privileges,\nmuzzle-loading privileges or tags issued in connection with them. If the\nlicense was one entitling the holder to the privilege of several\nlicenses, and the revocation concerned some but not all of such\nprivileges, any license, bowhunting privilege, muzzle-loading privilege\nor tag so delivered shall be returned by the department to the person to\nwhom it was issued, appropriately marked or stamped to show the extent\nto which it is revoked.\n  4. Violation of any subdivision of section 11-1203 of this title shall\nconstitute grounds for forfeiture pursuant to the provisions of and\nunder the procedures prescribed in subdivisions one, two, five, six and\nseven of section 71-0909 of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>