<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-2111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-2111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-2111"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-2111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-2111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-2111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-2111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_2111">
        <num>11-2111</num>
        <heading>Posting; service of notice</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_2111__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>consist of the word "posted", or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_2111__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>warn against entry for\nspecified purposes or all purposes without the consent of the person or\norganization authorized to post the protected area. A statement\nconsisting of the word "Posted" shall have the effect of a warning\nagainst all such acts.  The department may by regulation authorize\nadditional contents of such signs, including but not limited to symbols\nindicating the acts which are prohibited.\n  3. Signs to prohibit the taking of fish may be posted by the\ndepartment up to one thousand feet from a fishway or dam erected by the\nstate in public waters, and shall read substantially: "All persons are\nprohibited by law from fishing in this stream between this point and the\nfishway (or dam)."\n  4. Personal service upon any person, in the name of the owner, lawful\noccupant, or other person or organization authorized to post signs as\nprovided in this section, of a notice in writing containing a\ndescription of the premises and a warning provided by this section for a\nposted sign, shall, after the service, have the same effect with respect\nto the person served as if the premises described in the notice were\nposted with such warning as provided in this section.\n  5. Private lands constituting the bed, banks and shores of waters\nstocked with fish by the department, with the consent of the owner of\nsuch lands, shall not be posted against public fishing within five years\nfrom the date of such stocking, except where an alternate arrangement\nhas been agreed to in writing by the department. Owner shall mean, for\npurposes of this subdivision, the owner, lawful occupant, or other\nperson or organization having authority to post such lands.\n  6. The provisions of this section shall not apply to the posting or\nerection of notices identifying a restricted area pursuant to section\n11-0321.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>