<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0341"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0341"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0341"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0341">
        <num>13-0341</num>
        <heading>Trawls; use prohibited in certain waters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>§ 13-0341. Trawls; use prohibited in certain waters.\n  For the purposes of this chapter, a trawl shall be defined as a net\nwhich is towed or dragged through the water column, capturing fish by\nstraining the water, but shall not include a seine which is used to\nencircle fish. The term trawl shall include but not be limited to the\notter trawl, the beam trawl, the Paranzella or two-boat trawl, the pair\ntrawl, the Danish seine and the Scottish seine. Trawls shall not be set\nor used in the water areas of the marine district described in the\nfollowing subdivisions:\n  1. In the waters of the county of Richmond and in the counties of\nKings or Queens, northerly and westerly of a line from the sea end of\nthe breakwater at Rockaway Point to Romer Shoal lighthouse, including\nJamaica Bay and its adjacent bays, inlets, creeks and basins.\n  2. a. In the Atlantic Ocean within one-half mile of the coastline and\nin all connecting tidal waters inshore of the coastline, from Rockaway\nInlet Jetty at Rockaway Point to the Town of Babylon bathing pavilion at\nCedar Island Beach, and in all tidal waters inshore of a line from the\nTown of Babylon bathing pavilion to the sea buoy (BW S-I, Bell) at the\nentrance of Fire Island Inlet and thence to the seaward end of Fire\nIsland Inlet Jetty at Democrat Point.\n  b. Seaward of Rockaway Inlet within an arc with a radius of one and\none-half miles measured from the point at 40Á32.4' N latitude, 73Á56.5'\nW longitude, which is at or near the most southerly terminus of the\nRockaway Inlet Jetty at Rockaway Point.\n  c. Seaward of East Rockaway Inlet within an arc with a radius of one\nand one-half miles measured from the point at 40Á34.9' N latitude,\n73Á45.3' W longitude, which is at or near the most southerly terminus of\nthe East Rockaway Inlet Jetty at Silver Point.\n  d. Seaward of Jones Inlet within an arc with a radius of two miles\nmeasured from the point at 40Á34.4' N latitude, 73Á34.6' W longitude,\nwhich is at or near the most southerly terminus of the East (Short Beach\nside) Inlet Jetty, during the period January 1 through June 14.\n  e. Seaward of Fire Island Inlet within an arc with a radius of two\nmiles measured from the point at 40Á37.2' N latitude, 73Á18.4' W\nlongitude, which is at or near the most southerly terminus of the Fire\nIsland Inlet Jetty at Democrat Point, during the period January 1\nthrough June 14.\n  3. In Mecox Inlet within one-half mile of the narrowest part of the\nmouth of such inlet and seaward of Moriches and Shinnecock Inlets within\nseparate arcs each with a radius of one and one-half miles measured from\na point for Moriches Inlet at 40Á45.4' N latitude, 72Á45.2' W longitude,\nand for Shinnecock Inlet at 40Á50.2' N latitude, 72Á28.3' W longitude,\nwhich points are midway between the points at the most southerly termini\nof the east and west jetties at the entrance to each inlet.\n  4. In the Harlem River and the East River east of the Robert F.\nKennedy Bridge and in Long Island Sound west of a line drawn from\nHewlett's (King's) Point to the north end of Hart Island, thence to the\nsouth end of Glen Island, and in their adjacent bays, coves, creeks and\nconfluent waters.\n  5. In Flanders Bay, Great Peconic Bay, Little Peconic Bay, Noyac Bay\nand Shelter Island Sound, including all waters forming a part thereof or\ntributary thereto, lying westerly of an imaginary line extending from\nthe most southerly point of Orient State Park to the most easterly point\nof Shelter Island, also known as Ram Head, and from this point in a\ngenerally southerly direction to the most northerly point of Cedar\nPoint, including all of Orient Harbor, Hallock Bay and Northwest Harbor.\n  6. In the county of Suffolk in the waters lying westerly of an\nimaginary line extending in a southerly direction from the most easterly\nend of Plum Island to the most northerly end of Gardiners Island, and\nwesterly of Gardiners Island, and westerly of a line extending in a\nsoutherly direction from the most southerly end of Gardiners Island to\nGoff Point; provided, however, that vessels and motorboats owned and\noperated by citizens who are residents of the state may be used in such\nwaters in connection with the operation of trawls and other types of\nnets towed by such boats and vessels. Nothing in this subdivision shall\nbe construed as legalizing the operation of any trawls in the waters\ndescribed in subdivision 5 of this section.\n  7. In Long Island Sound, including all waters forming a part thereof\nor which are tributary thereto: a. west of an imaginary line from the\nNew York-Connecticut boundary shore line extending easterly and\nsoutherly to Eaton's Point Neck on Long Island from April 1 to November\n1.\n  b. South of a line from Hewlett Point on Great Neck eastward to Sands\nPoint on Manhassett Neck, then to Matinicock Point, then to Oak Neck\nPoint, then to Rocky Point at Centre Island, then to Lloyd Point, then\nto Eaton's Neck Point, buoy 13, then to buoy "1" (privately maintained)\noff the Northport Power Plant, then to buoy "NR" off the north of the\nNissequogue river, then to buoy "1" off Stony Brook Harbor, and then to\nCrane Neck Point.\n  c. In the Nissequogue River.\n  d. Within Stony Brook Harbor.\n  e. Within one-half mile of the shore between an imaginary line\nextending north from Crane Neck Point and an imaginary line extending\nnorth from the shore intersect of the Riverhead-Brookhaven town line\nnear Wading River, including all bays, harbors and tributaries landward\nthereof, including Port Jefferson Harbor, Conscience Bay, Setauket\nHarbor and Mount Sinai Harbor.\n  f. Within one mile of the shore of Fishers Island, or between the\nshore of Fishers Island and the Connecticut-New York State boundary line\nwherever such boundary line is within less than one mile of the shore of\nFishers Island.\n  8. In the waters of the Great South Bay, Moriches Bay and Shinnecock\nBay, including all tidal waters and all waters forming a part thereof or\ntributary thereto.\n  9. The department is authorized to adopt regulations prescribing the\nminimum size net mesh, and the manner in which such nets may be\npossessed and used, in trawl fisheries for summer and winter flounder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>