<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0342"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0342"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0342"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0342/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0342/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0342/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0342/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0342">
        <num>13-0342</num>
        <heading>Marine fisheries data</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 13-0342.  Marine fisheries data.\n  1. a.  The department is authorized to adopt regulations which require\nreporting of catch, effort, area fished, gear used, by-catch, and volume\nand value of product purchased from fishermen, by holders of all\ncategories of commercial food fish, lobster, and crab fishing and\nlanding licenses, marine and coastal district food fish and crustacea\ndealers and shippers licenses, marine and coastal district party and\ncharter boat license, menhaden licenses, shellfish shippers permits and\ndiggers permits.\n  b. Beginning May first, nineteen hundred ninety-nine and every May\nfirst thereafter, the department shall submit a report to the\nlegislature on the data collected pursuant to this section. Such report\nshall include the catch, effort, area fished, gear used, by-catch, and\nvolume and value of product purchased from fishermen, by holders of all\ncategories of commercial food fish, lobster, and crab fishing and\nlicenses, marine and coastal district party and charter boat licenses,\nmenhaden licenses, shellfish shippers permits and diggers permits.\n  2. The department may, by rule and regulation, provide that data\ncollected by the department or available to the department shall be\nconfidential and shall not be disclosed except when required under court\norder. The department may, by rule and regulation, prescribe such\nprocedures as may be necessary to preserve such confidentiality except\nthat the department may release or make public any statistics in an\naggregate or summary form which does not directly or indirectly disclose\nthe identity or business of any person who submits such statistics.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>