<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0329"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0329"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0329"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0329/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0329/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0329/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0329/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0329">
        <num>13-0329</num>
        <heading>Lobsters; permit to take; prohibited acts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0329__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision fifteen of\nsection 13-0343 of this chapter. This permit is to be used for the\npurposes of obtaining bait fish to be used solely by the permittee to\npursue his lobster fishery. Bait so taken shall not be sold.\n  11. In order to reduce mortality of lobster due to lost traps and\npots, the department may adopt regulations requiring escape panels and\nvents in such traps and pots and describing their design, configuration,\ncomposition, size and any other necessary characteristics. Any such\nregulations shall be consistent with the Interstate Management Plan for\nAmerican Lobster prepared by the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries\nCommission.\n  12. Lobsters shall not be transferred from one vessel to another\nvessel on the waters of Long Island Sound or its adjacent bays, harbors\nand estuaries, except that nothing in this section shall prohibit the\nunloading of lobsters, lawfully taken and possessed, in harbor at a\nvessel's permanent mooring to a transfer vessel for the purpose of\ntransporting such lawfully taken and possessed lobsters to land.\n  13. The department may issue a permit, revocable at pleasure, to any\nperson to import, possess, buy or sell lobsters of less than the size\npermitted to be taken and possessed pursuant to this section for\nscientific and educational purposes only.\n  14. Possession of a lobster trap or pot with a volume larger than\ntwenty-two thousand nine hundred fifty cubic inches is prohibited.\n  15.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0329__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department shall adopt regulations to implement and\nadminister a lobster trap tag program. Such regulations shall be\nconsistent with the specific requirements of the lobster fishery\nmanagement plan adopted by the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries\nCommission and any other applicable federal lobster trap tag\nregulations. Lobster trap tags shall be issued by the department or an\nagent authorized by the department. The cost to affected permittees for\neach tag shall not be more than the cost of production and distribution\nof each tag and shall not exceed the sum of twenty cents.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0329__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the department administers a lobster trap tag program, any\nfunds derived from such program and received by the department shall be\ndeposited into the marine resource account established pursuant to\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0329__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph three of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0329__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\neighty-three of the state finance law.\n  16. The department may, until December thirty-first, two thousand\ntwenty-seven, adopt regulations for Atlantic States Marine Fisheries\nCommission Areas One, Two, Three, Four, Five, and Outer Cape Cod, to\nimplement conservation measures that affect landings of lobsters,\npursuant to the recommendations of the respective Area's Lobster\nConservation Management Team as required by the Interstate Fishery\nManagement Plan for American Lobster adopted by the Atlantic States\nMarine Fisheries Commission.\n  * 17. a. No lobster may be taken from Atlantic States Marine Fisheries\nCommission Area Six from September eighth through November twenty-eighth\npursuant to the recommendations of the Area's Lobster Conservation\nManagement Team as required by the Interstate Fishery Plan for Lobsters\nadopted by the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission.\n  b. During the September eighth through November twenty-eighth closure,\nlobster permit holders who use lobster traps or pots shall remove\nlobster traps and pots from the water by September twenty-second.\n  c. No lobster trap or pot may be in the water from September\ntwenty-second until November fourteenth unless the lobster permit holder\nalso holds a permit or license that authorizes them to harvest other\nspecies from their lobster traps or pots.\n  d. Lobster permit holders may set unbaited lobster traps or pots\nbeginning November fourteenth.\n  e. Lobster permit holders may set baited lobster traps or pots\nbeginning November twenty-first.\n  * NB Repealed December 31, 2027\n  18. a. Lobsters greater in length than provided in subdivision 5 of\nthis section may be imported into the state and possessed for\nexportation provided that:\n  i. The lobsters were legally taken in the state or country where the\nlobsters were landed, and, if applicable, the Atlantic States Marine\nFisheries Commission Area where the lobsters were taken;\n  ii. The lobsters were placed in...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>