<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0339"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0339">
        <num>13-0339</num>
        <heading>Marine fish; size limits of marine species; sale of marine species</heading>
        <content>
          <p> ยง 13-0339. Marine fish; size limits of marine species; sale of marine\n              species.\n  1. a. The taking of fish with nets in the marine and coastal district\nis governed by sections 13-0333, 13-0335, 13-0341, 13-0343, 13-0347 and\n11-1521, and regulations adopted pursuant to sections 11-0303, 11-1303,\n13-0338, 13-0339-a, 13-0340, 13-0340-a, 13-0340-b, 13-0340-c, 13-0340-d,\n13-0340-e, 13-0340-f and 13-0340-g of this chapter. The taking of fish\nby other means, in the marine and coastal district, is governed by title\n13 of article 11 of the Fish and Wildlife Law, subject to restrictions\nin section 13-0343 as to certain waters, and to provisions of sections\n13-0347 and 11-1521 and regulations adopted pursuant to section 11-0303\nof this chapter as to striped bass and sections 13-0338, 13-0339-a,\n13-0340, 13-0340-a, 13-0340-b, 13-0340-c, 13-0340-d, 13-0340-e,\n13-0340-f and 13-0340-g as to other species of marine fish. The taking,\nand sale or taking for sale, of certain bait fish are governed by\nsection 11-1315 of this chapter.\n  b. Open seasons, minimum size limits and catch limits for fish other\nthan the marine species named in subdivisions 2 and 3 of this section\nare specified by regulations adopted pursuant to sections 11-0303,\n11-1303, 13-0338, 13-0339-a, 13-0340, 13-0340-a, 13-0340-b, 13-0340-c,\n13-0340-d, 13-0340-e, 13-0340-f and 13-0340-g of this chapter. All\nshortnose sturgeon irrespective of size and all Atlantic sturgeon under\nthe size limits prescribed by regulations adopted pursuant to section\n11-1303 of this chapter taken in gill nets shall be immediately returned\nto the water without unnecessary injury. Other fish named by regulations\nadopted pursuant to sections 11-0303, 11-1303, 13-0338, 13-0339-a,\n13-0340, 13-0340-a, 13-0340-b, 13-0340-c, 13-0340-d, 13-0340-e,\n13-0340-f and 13-0340-g of this chapter and under the size limits\nprescribed in such regulations, shall not be bought, sold or trafficked\nin.\n  c. The sale, possession and transportation of fish, other than the\nmarine species named in subdivisions 2 and 3 of this section are\ngoverned by sections 11-1319, 11-1521 and 13-0347, and regulations\nadopted pursuant to sections 11-0303, 11-1303, 13-0338, 13-0339-a,\n13-0340, 13-0340-a, 13-0340-b, 13-0340-c, 13-0340-d, 13-0340-e,\n13-0340-f and 13-0340-g of this chapter.\n  2. Fluke or summer flounder (Paralichthys dentatus) and southern\nflounder (Paralichthys lethostigma) less than fourteen inches in length,\nweakfish (Cynoscion regalis) less than twelve inches in length, Atlantic\ncod (Gadus morhua) less than nineteen inches in length, porgy or scup\n(Stenotomus chrysops) less than seven inches, black sea bass\n(Centropristis striata) less than nine inches, and winter flounder\n(Pleuorenectes americanus) less than eleven inches in length may not be\ntaken by angling for recreational purposes.\n  3. Fluke or summer flounder (Paralichthys dentatus) and southern\nflounder (Paralichthys lethostigma) less than fourteen inches; blue fish\n(Pomatomus saltatrix) less than nine inches; porgy or scup (Stenotomus\nchrysops) less than nine inches; weakfish (Cynoscion regalis) less than\ntwelve inches; mackerel (Scomber scombrus) less than seven inches; black\nsea bass (Centropristis striata) less than nine inches; Atlantic cod\n(Gadus morhua) less than nineteen inches; winter flounder (Pleuorenectes\namericanus) less than twelve inches, may not be taken or possessed for\ncommercial purposes or transported for commercial purposes nor bought,\nsold or offered for sale. For purposes of this subdivision, commercial\npurposes includes use of any form of net, comb, dredge or hook and line,\nexcept angling.\n  4. All length measurements in this section shall be taken as the total\nlength which is defined as the longest straight-line measurement from\nthe most anterior or forward part of the fish with the jaws closed to\nthe tip of the tail. The tail rays of a fish with a forked tail may be\nsqueezed together to give the longest overall measurement.\n  5. Blue marlin (Makaira nigricans), white marlin (Tetrapturus\nalbidus), sailfish (Istiophorus platypterus), and longbill spearfish\n(Tetrapturus pfluegeri) shall not be bought, sold or offered for sale.\nStriped marlin (Tetrapturus audax), black marlin (Makaira indica),\nshortbill spearfish (Tetrapturus angustirostris) shall not be bought,\nsold or offered for sale unless identified and tagged as such prior to\nentry into the state. Such identification and tag shall include at a\nminimum, the species of billfish and the place of initial landing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>