<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0343"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0343"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0343"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0343/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0343/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0343/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0343/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0343">
        <num>13-0343</num>
        <heading>Nets other than trawls; restrictions on use of nets and trawls</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0343__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as permitted by this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0343__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>landing nets may be used in completing the catch of fish hooked by\nangling; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0343__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>cast nets, not in excess of twenty feet in diameter,\noperated by hand may be used to take Atlantic menhaden (Brevoortia\ntyrannus) and mullets (Mugil spp), except in the waters described in\nsubdivisions four, eight and twelve of this section. The use of cast\nnets shall be limited to one per boat.\n  2. In the waters of the marine district in the county of Richmond\npurse seines may not be used to take menhaden; and nets of not more than\nten feet in length, operated by hand, may be used to take minnows and\nshrimp for bait.\n  3. In the Harlem River and the East River east of the Robert F.\nKennedy Bridge and in Long Island Sound west of a line drawn from\nHewlett's (King's) Point to the north end of Hart Island, thence to the\nsouth end of Glen Island, and in their adjacent bays, coves, creeks and\nconfluent waters, only such nets as are used to take lobsters or crabs\nmay be used.\n  4. In the Nissequogue River fish may be taken by angling only except\nthat nets of not more than twenty feet in length and four feet in depth,\noperated by hand, may be used to take bait fish during daylight hours\nonly.\n  5. a. In the inland tidal waters within the town of Hempstead, no\nperson shall at any time engage in eel dredging by the use of nets\naccompanied by cutting boards, chains or other similar devices.\n  b. In the inland tidal waters within the town of Hempstead westerly of\nthe Wantagh State Parkway causeway, nets shall not be used except nets,\nnot over forty feet long and four feet deep, may be used to take minnows\nor shrimp for bait.\n  6. In Jamaica Bay and its adjacent creeks, inlets and basins, nets\nshall not be used inshore of a line from the beacon at Rockaway Point\njetty to the municipal bath houses on Coney Island, except that minnows\nand shrimp may be taken by hand nets not over forty feet long and four\nfeet deep and except that nets other than trawls may be used from\nOctober 10 to December 31 in that part of such area southerly of a line\nfrom t...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_13_0343__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>haul seines shall not be used measuring over one hundred fifty\nfathoms in length, attached to which may be two wings, each measuring\nnot more than one hundred fifty fathoms in length with a stretched mesh\nsize including knot of not less than three and one-quarter inches in one\nwing and three and one-half inches in the other wing;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_13_0343__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the use of haul seines is prohibited from midnight Thursday to\n6:00 P.M. Sunday.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_13_0343__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>when permitted by the commissioner, pound or trap nets may be used\nin the waters described in paragraph a of this subdivision provided they\ndo not interfere with or obstruct navigation or the carrying out of\nshellfish culture as provided in this chapter. Any such pound or trap\nnets shall be marked in accordance with requirements prescribed by the\ncommissioner.\n  b. Waste fish shall not be left on shore or within the waters five\nhundred feet from shore.\n  15. a. Nets shall not be used in Long Island sound west of an\nimaginary line from the New York-Connecticut boundary shore line\nextending easterly and southerly to Eaton's Point Neck on Long Island\nfrom April 1 to November 1, nor at any time in the waters of Huntington\nBay, Lloyd Harbor, Northport Bay or Coldspring Harbor; provided,\nhowever, that hand nets not more than forty feet long and four feet in\nwidth may be used to take minnows and shrimp for bait, at any time.\n  b. Gill nets shall not be used in Long Island Sound...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>