<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0805"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0805"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-0805"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0805/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0805/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0805/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0805/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_0805">
        <num>15-0805</num>
        <heading>Regulation of reservoir releases</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-0805. Regulation of reservoir releases.\n  1. The commissioner is authorized and directed to promulgate rules and\nregulations as expeditiously as possible but in no event later than the\nfirst day of April, nineteen hundred seventy-seven for releases from\nSchoharie reservoir through the Shandaken tunnel and for releases from\nNeversink, Pepacton and Cannonsville reservoirs, nor later than the\nfirst day of October, nineteen hundred seventy-eight for releases from\nthe remaining impounding reservoirs, to carry out the policy set out in\nthis title consistent with the findings and policies set out in this\narticle.\n  2. Without limiting the foregoing, such rules and regulations may\ninclude provisions respecting the volume, timing and rate of change in\nvolume of releases of water, monitoring, maintenance of records,\ninspection of records and premises, reporting and investigations by\nrepresentatives of the department, may vary from time to time, on a\nseasonal basis and from reservoir to reservoir and shall include\nprovisions to insure that an adequate supply of water for power\nproduction and for any municipality which uses water from such reservoir\nfor drinking and other purposes will not be impaired, to provide for the\npublic health and safety in the event of drought or other emergency\nconditions and shall be promulgated only after affected municipalities\nare provided an opportunity for consultation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>