<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0801"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0801"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-0801"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_0801">
        <num>15-0801</num>
        <heading>Statement of legislative findings and policy</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-0801. Statement of legislative findings and policy.\n  1. In addition to the statements of policy and legislative findings as\nherein otherwise provided in this article, the legislature hereby finds\nthat the volume and abrupt changes in the volume of releases of water\nfrom impounding reservoirs of water having a capacity of more than one\nbillion gallons and located in the counties of Delaware, Greene, Putnam,\nSchoharie, Sullivan, Ulster and Westchester have damaged the\nrecreational uses, such as trout fishing and canoeing, of waters\naffected by such releases, that such waters are a recreational resource\nfor residents from all parts of the state of New York and elsewhere,\nthat such recreational resource benefits the economy and welfare of this\nstate and that the volume and rate of change of volume of such releases\ncan be regulated to protect and enhance the recreational use of waters\naffected by such releases while ensuring and without impairing an\nadequate supply of water for power production or for any municipality\nwhich uses water from such reservoirs for drinking and other purposes.\n  2. It is hereby declared to be the policy of this state that the\nvolume and rate of change of volume of releases of water from such\nreservoirs should be regulated to protect and enhance the recreational\nuse of waters affected by such releases while ensuring and without\nimpairing an adequate supply of water for power production or for any\nmunicipality which uses water from such reservoirs for drinking and\nother purposes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>