<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-0301"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_0301">
        <num>15-0301</num>
        <heading>Investigations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-0301. Investigations.\n  1. The department may, of its own motion, make or cause to be made\nsuch surveys and investigations as it may deem advisable and necessary\nfor the discharge of its duties under this article.\n  2. The department, upon its own motion, or upon a petition presented\nto it by a person or public corporation pursuant to provisions of this\narticle, may in its discretion, extend the scope of such proceeding to\nany improvements or developments of natural resources which may be done\nunder any provisions of this article, and if any part of the procedure\ngoverning the matters concerning which the petition is presented cannot\nbe made applicable in all respects to the subject matter of the\nproceedings as thus extended, then the procedure peculiar to such\nadditional matter as provided for in this article may be adopted to the\nextent necessary.\n  3. The department shall make or cause to be made continuing\ninvestigations of the water resources of the state so as to accumulate\ncomprehensive data as a basis of providing for their proper\nconservation, development, regulation and use.\n  4. The department shall conduct systematic gauging of rainfall and\nstream flow throughout the state when moneys shall have been\nappropriated therefor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>