<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-0111"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_0111">
        <num>15-0111</num>
        <heading>Public Authorities Law and Administrative Code of the City of New York are not affected</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-0111. Public Authorities Law and Administrative Code of the City of\n             New York are not affected.\n  Nothing contained in this article shall be deemed or construed as\namending, repealing, altering or otherwise modifying in whole or in part\nany provision of Title 1, Article 5 of the Public Authorities Law, as\namended, with respect to Power Authority of the State of New York, or\nany provision of Title K of Chapter fifty-one and Title D of Chapter 15\nof the Administrative Code of the City of New York, as amended, with\nrespect to the City of New York, and such acts shall remain in full\nforce and effect, except that notwithstanding the provisions of this\nsection and title 3 of article 1 of this chapter, section 15-0103 and\ntitle 8 of this article shall apply to the city of New York, its\nagencies and departments. Nothing in this article shall be deemed or\nconstrued as adding to, diminishing or otherwise modifying the rights,\npowers, duties and obligations granted to and imposed upon Power\nAuthority of the State of New York and the City of New York, its or\ntheir agencies and departments by such statutes or any other statutes,\nexcept that notwithstanding the provisions of this section and title 3\nof article 1 of this chapter, section 15-0103 and of title 8 of this\narticle shall apply to the city of New York, its agencies and\ndepartments.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>