<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1709"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1709"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1709"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1709/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1709/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1709/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1709/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1709">
        <num>15-1709</num>
        <heading>Preliminary permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1709. Preliminary permits.\n  1. The department may issue preliminary permits for the purpose of\nenabling applicants for a license hereunder to secure the data and to\nperform the acts required by section 15-1707, provided, however, that\nupon the filing of any application for a preliminary permit by any\nperson or public corporation, the department before granting such\napplication shall at once give notice of such application in writing to\nany municipality which, in its judgment, is likely to be interested in\nor affected by such application. Each such permit shall be for the sole\npurpose of maintaining priority of application for a license under the\nterms of title 17 of this article for such period or periods, not\nexceeding a total of three years, as in the discretion of the department\nmay be necessary for making examinations and surveys, preparing maps,\nplans, specifications and estimates, and making financial arrangements.\n  2. The permit shall set forth the conditions under which priority\nshall be maintained and the license issued, and may prescribe any\ncondition of issuing the license for the protection of the interests of\nthe state. Only one preliminary permit at a time shall be issued and\noutstanding for the same project. The same preference shall be accorded\nby the department in considering applications for a preliminary permit\nas is accorded in considering applications for a license. Each\npreliminary permit shall require the permittee to proceed diligently and\nimmediately to secure the data and to perform the acts required by\nsection 15-1707.\n  3. All investigation work in connection with any operations carried on\nunder the preliminary permit shall be subject to the inspection of the\ndepartment, its agents and employees, and, from time to time upon the\nrequest of the department, the permittee shall make full reports to the\ndepartment of the progress of the work carried on under the preliminary\npermit, but such reports shall be confidential until final application\nis made for the license, unless the department takes proceedings to\nrevoke the preliminary permit.\n  4. Permits shall not be transferable and may be cancelled by the\ndepartment upon failure of the permittee to comply with the conditions\nthereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>