<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1111"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1111">
        <num>15-1111</num>
        <heading>Duties of county; county charge; counties included within a city</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1111. Duties of county; county charge; counties included within a\n             city.\n  1. The county legislative body or bodies shall comply promptly with\nthe departments request for lists of nominations for membership on the\nboard. The county or counties shall cooperate with and assist, so far as\nis reasonable and practicable, the board in carrying out its functions.\n  2. Of the total costs and expenses incurred by the department,\ntwenty-five per cent shall be a county charge and shall be audited and\npaid as such in the manner prescribed by the county legislative body or\nbodies. If more than one county is included within the region of the\nproject, the county charge of twenty-five per cent shall be equitably\napportioned among them, consideration being given to, but not limited\nto, prospective benefits to accrue to each in the event that the project\nis undertaken. If the counties fail to agree within sixty days after the\nstatement of costs and expenses from the department upon an equitable\napportionment of the county charge, the department after hearing the\ncounties, shall make such apportionment.\n  3. With respect to any or all of the counties within the city of New\nYork, except as provided and limited by subdivision 7 of section\n15-1103:\n  a. All rights, powers and privileges granted to, and all duties,\nobligations and charges imposed upon any county by the provisions of\ntitle 11 of this article, are granted to or imposed upon such city; and\n  b. All rights, powers and privileges granted to the county legislative\nbody of any county by the provisions of title 11 of this article\n(including, but not limited to the power to approve a petition for a\nsurvey and study and establishment of a regional planning board) and all\nduties and obligations imposed upon any such county legislative body by\ntitle 11 of this article, are granted to or imposed upon the board of\nestimate of such city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>