<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1109"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1109"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1109"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1109">
        <num>15-1109</num>
        <heading>Additional powers and duties of the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1109. Additional powers and duties of the department.\n  1. The department shall, if appropriations are available therefor,\nprovide the board with such office space and equipment, clerical,\ntechnical, scientific, engineering, legal and other personnel and\nservices as are reasonably necessary to assist the board in carrying out\nits functions, and shall fix the compensation, within appropriations\navailable therefor, of such personnel. The department may enter into and\nexecute contracts in the manner and form prescribed by law for\ntechnical, scientific, engineering and legal services to be made\navailable for the board's functions, and may enter into cooperative\nagreements with federal agencies for research, the investigation,\ncollection, compilation, study and analysis of information and data on\nthe water resources and the hydrology of the state, and for the\npreparation and publication of reports thereon.\n  2. The department shall cooperate with the board and render to it\nadvisory and consultant services whenever practicable.\n  3. The department shall endeavor to coordinate the activities of\nexisting agencies and departments of the state charged with functions\ninvolving waters and to secure their cooperation with and assistance for\nthe board in carrying out its functions, and provide the means for\ncoordination of the studies and development plans of all regional\nboards;\n  4. The department shall keep a true and accurate account of all\nexpenditures incurred on behalf of the board including, but not limited\nto, those incurred for all proceedings, hearings (except the hearing\nrequired by section 15-1103), notifications, clerical, technical,\nengineering, legal and other services and expenses;\n  5. The department shall, within a reasonable time after the plan has\nbeen approved or disapproved, submit an itemized statement of the costs\nand expenses so incurred and expended to the county legislative body.\nNotice shall be attached to such statement that, under title 11 of this\narticle, twenty-five per cent of the cost and expenses is a county\ncharge which, if more than one county is involved, is to be equitably\napportioned among them; that the counties may by agreement determine\nsuch equitable apportionment within sixty days from the date of such\nnotice, and, that in the failure of the counties so to agree, the\ndepartment, on a specified date after such sixty day period has expired,\nwill hear the counties at its office and proceed to make an equitable\napportionment of the county charge;\n  6. The department shall recommend legislation to accomplish and\nfurther the planning and development program of the water resources of\nthe state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>