<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1945"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1945"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1945"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1945/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1945/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1945/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1945/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1945">
        <num>15-1945</num>
        <heading>Minor repairs in existing drainage ditches</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1945. Minor repairs in existing drainage ditches.\n  1. Repairs of a minor nature may be made to ditches heretofore\nconstructed by assessment under the former drainage law, or the laws\nfrom which it was derived or under the provisions of this or any other\ngeneral or special law by following the procedure set forth in section\n15-1943 so far as it is applicable. The total cost of such repairs shall\nnot exceed the sum of five thousand dollars on any one ditch for work\ndone under one proceeding. The cost of such work shall be paid for out\nof the drainage fund provided by section 15-1957 hereof.\n  2. When such repairs or enlargements shall be finished, it shall be\nthe duty of the department to make up an itemized account of the cost\nincurred in the making of such repairs or enlargements and to file the\nsame as provided in section 15-1955 and such cost shall thereafter be\nassessed and collected within not to exceed three years as therein\nprovided and as further provided herein. The expenses of such repairs\nand enlargements shall be apportioned among the premises to which were\noriginally apportioned the cost of construction of such ditch or\nditches, as shown by the apportionment made for such original\nconstruction and filed in the county clerk's office or elsewhere\naccording to the valuation thereof on the last completed assessment roll\nor the drainage enhancements thereof, if such have been determined.\n  3. In case any public corporations have contributed to the\nconstruction of such ditch or ditches, such public corporations shall be\nliable for the repair or enlargement of the ditch or ditches, in the\nsame proportion that they were originally assessed for the construction\nof the same, which shall also be levied and collected out of the taxable\ninhabitants of such public corporation in the same manner that other\ntaxes are levied and collected in the corporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>