<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1981"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1981"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1981"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1981/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1981/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1981/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1981/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1981">
        <num>15-1981</num>
        <heading>Powers of association; limitations; voluntary dissolution</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1981. Powers of association; limitations; voluntary dissolution.\n  1. The association shall have:\n  a. Power to construct, maintain and keep in repair the drainage\nproject described in the articles of association;\n  b. Power to sue and be sued and to enter into contracts to carry out\nits purposes;\n  c. Power to make application, pursuant to section 15-1983, to acquire\nthe right to construct, maintain and keep in repair, on the lands of\nothers, that part of the drainage project as so described in the\narticles of association; and\n  d. No power to issue bonds or other evidences of indebtedness.\n  2. All actions of the association shall be taken by a majority vote,\nexcept as hereinafter provided, of those members present at a duly\ncalled meeting at which a quorum is present. Each member shall have but\none vote regardless of the number of parcels of drainable acreage owned\nby him and included within the drainage section. If there be more than\none owner of a parcel or parcels of drainable acreage, such owners shall\nbe entitled collectively to but one vote.\n  3. No drainage section association shall be formed in an area within a\npresently existing drainage improvement district. The formation of such\nan association shall not prevent the inclusion of the aggregate drained\nacreage within a drainage improvement district hereafter created, in\nwhich event the association shall be deemed to be dissolved, except for\nthe purpose of meeting and paying its existing liabilities for debts,\ncosts, expenses and fees.\n  4. A voluntary petition to dissolve the association may be made to the\nSupreme Court upon petition of the president of the association when\nauthorized to do so by the affirmative votes of three-fourths of the\nmembers present at a special meeting called for that sole purpose and at\nwhich a quorum is present. Ten days' notice, in writing of the time and\nplace of the presentation of such a petition shall be given to all\nmembers and to non-members, if any, upon whose lands drainage works\nshall have been constructed in accordance with the articles of\nassociation. Public notice of the presentation of the petition shall\nalso be given by a notice stating the time and place of such\npresentation, published once in two consecutive weeks prior to such time\nin a paper published in the county in which the articles of association\nhave been recorded. The court, after hearing all interested persons, may\ngrant an order dissolving the association, upon such terms and\nconditions as in its discretion are merited. The court shall not grant\nsuch order in the absence of proof that the association has no\noutstanding indebtedness. An order dissolving the association shall be\nrecorded in the office of the county clerk in which the articles of\nassociation have been recorded and shall direct the county clerk to\nindex it under the name of the association in the index of grantors of\nreal property.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>