<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2109"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2109"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2109"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2109">
        <num>15-2109</num>
        <heading>General powers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2109. General powers.\n  1. The board shall have power to make all necessary rules and\nregulations which shall be effective when approved by the department.\n  2. The board and its authorized agents may enter upon any lands as in\nits judgment may be necessary for the purpose of making surveys and\nexaminations to accomplish any purpose authorized by title 21 of this\narticle, being liable only for actual damage done.\n  3. The board on behalf of such district shall have and may exercise\nall of the powers enumerated in subdivision 1 of section 15-2103 and in\naddition thereto all such other powers as are necessary and proper to\ncarry into execution the powers expressly granted to it, including power\nto make such channel improvements as may be necessary to prevent damage\nto downstream properties by the waters released from reservoirs.  The\nboard shall have charge of the operation of all reservoirs now in\nexistence, or hereafter constructed for the regulation of the flow of\nthe river and its tributaries of the district which it represents, not\nincluding, however, any reservoirs which are or may be maintained\nprimarily to provide water for the canal system of the state. No\nreservoirs for the regulation of the flow of streams or for any other\npurpose except for municipal water supply shall be hereafter constructed\nin Hamilton or Herkimer counties on the south branch of the Moose River\nby any river regulating board.\n  4. The board shall have the right to establish and maintain stream\ngauges and rain gauges, and may make such surveys and examinations of\nrainfall, stream flow and flood conditions, and of other scientific and\nengineering subjects as may be necessary and proper for the purposes of\nthe district and shall preserve a record thereof.\n  5. The board, on behalf of such district, subject to the limitations\nof title 21 of this article, shall have a dominant right of eminent\ndomain over the right of eminent domain of public corporations, except\ncities. In exercise of this right, due care shall be taken to do no\nunnecessary damage to other public utilities, and in case of failure to\nagree upon the mode and terms of interference, not to interfere with\ntheir operation and usefulness beyond the actual necessities of the\ncase, due regard being paid to the other public interests involved.\n  6. The board on behalf of such district shall have power to consent to\nthe transfer of jurisdiction over lands under its jurisdiction to any\nstate department or a bureau, division or agency thereof, or to any\nstate agency, upon such terms and conditions and under such regulations\nand restrictions as said board shall deem just and proper, providing,\nhowever, that the use of such lands will not interfere with the purposes\nfor which they were acquired.\n  7. The board of the Hudson river-Black river regulating district shall\nhave the power to contract to sell water, upon such terms and conditions\nas it deems advisable to any or all of the counties of Albany, Columbia,\nEssex, Fulton, Green, Hamilton, Rensselaer, Saratoga, Schenectady,\nWarren or Washington, which counties are contained within such district.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>