<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2714"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2714"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2714"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2714">
        <num>15-2714</num>
        <heading>Additional designations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2714. Additional designations.\n  In addition to the rivers designated in section 15-2713 of this\nchapter, the following rivers are included in the system, being\nclassified by the criteria stated in section 15-2707:\n  1. Wild rivers\n  a. Cedar river - Approximately seven and three-tenths miles from the\noutlet of Cedar lakes to a point where a road crosses the river\napproximately one and one-half miles upstream of Cedar river flow.\n  b. Kunjamuk river - Approximately eight miles from the outlet of South\npond to a fish barrier dam near the southwest boundary of lot 9,\ntownship 31, Gorton Tract.\n  c. Main branch of the Oswegatchie river - Approximately eighteen and\none-half miles from the Partlow Mill dam to the southernmost boundary\nbetween private and state land at Inlet.\n  d. Middle branch of the Oswegatchie river - Approximately fourteen and\none-half miles from the north boundary of lot 27, Watson's East Triangle\nto a point one mile downstream of the confluence with Wolf creek.\n  e. Piseco outlet - Approximately four and one-fifth miles from a point\none-half mile east of the route 10 bridge crossing to the confluence\nwith the West Branch of the Sacandaga river.\n  f. West branch of the Sacandaga river - Approximately nine miles from\nthe source near Silver lake mountain to the Silver lake wilderness\nboundary near route 10 and approximately two and seven-tenths miles from\nthe confluence with Cow creek to the confluence with Piseco outlet.\n  g. South branch of West Canada creek - Approximately five and\nnine-tenths miles from the headwaters near T-Lake falls to a footbridge\ncrossing located approximately one mile upstream of the Floe.\n  2. Scenic rivers\n  a. Black river - Approximately seven and eight-tenths miles from the\npoint where Farr road crosses the river to the point where the river\nintersects the Adirondack park boundary.\n  b. Bog river - Approximately seven and three-tenths miles from the dam\nbelow Hitchins pond to Big Tupper lake.\n  c. Blue Mountain stream - Approximately nine miles from the outlet of\nClear pond to the confluence with Pleasant lake stream.\n  d. Carmens river - Approximately two and one-quarter miles from its\nheadwaters at the north boundary of Cathedral Pines Park (formerly Camp\nWilderness), Suffolk county, southerly to its intersection with the\nsouthern boundary of Camp Sobaco (Girl Scout Camp).\n  e. Carmens river--Approximately two and one-half miles from Yaphank\navenue, Suffolk county, southerly to the Concrete Wing dam in Southhaven\npark.\n  f. Carmens river--Approximately two and one-half miles from the south\nside of Sunrise highway, Suffolk county, southerly to the mouth of the\nriver (a line between Long Point and Sandy Point) at its confluence with\nGreat South Bay.\n  g. Cedar river - Approximately ten miles from a point where a road\ncrosses the river one and one-half miles upstream of Cedar river flow to\na point where a southerly extension of the northeast state land boundary\nof lot 96, township 33, Totten and Crossfield's Purchase, would\nintersect the river.\n  h. Deer river - Approximately six and two-tenths miles from the outlet\nof Deer river flow to a point where the river intersects the Adirondack\npark boundary.\n  i. East Canada creek - Approximately twenty and nine-tenths miles from\nPowley Place to a point at which the creek intersects the Adirondack\npark boundary near Sprite creek at the southwest corner of lot 45, town\nof Oppenheim, Lott and Low's Patent.\n  i-1. The Genesee river within Letchworth State Park.\n  j. Middle branch of the Grasse river - Approximately fourteen and\none-half miles from the confluence of Blue Mountain stream and Pleasant\nlake stream to the confluence of the South Branch of the Grasse river.\n  k. North branch of the Grasse river - Approximately twenty-five and\nfour-tenths miles from the outlet of Church pond to a point where the\nNorth Branch intersects the Adirondack park boundary.\n  l. South Branch of the Grasse river - Approximately thirty-five and\ntwo-tenths miles from the outlet of Center pond to the confluence with\nthe outlet of Allen pond, and approximately three and seven-tenths miles\nfrom the most southerly point where the South Branch of the Grasse river\nintersects the Adirondack park boundary, north to the confluence with\nthe Middle Branch of the Grasse river.\n  m. Independence river - Approximately twenty-six miles from the outlet\nof Little Independence pond to the point where the Sperryville bridge\ncrosses the river.\n  n. Jordan river - Approximately eighteen miles from the outlet of\nMarsh pond to Carry Falls reservoir.\n  o. Kunjamuk river - Approximately ten and four-tenths miles from a\nfish barrier dam near the southwest boundary of lot 9, township 31,\nGorton Tract, to the confluence with the Sacandaga river.\n  p. Long Pond outlet - Approximately sixteen miles from the outlet of\nLong pond to the confluence with the West Branch of the St. Regis river.\n  q. Marion river - Approximately five miles from the outlet of Utowana\nlake to Raquette lake.\n  r. Main branch of the Moose river - Approximately fifteen and\nfour-fifths miles from the confluence of the South and Middle Branches\nof the Moose river to a point where the Main Branch intersects the\nAdirondack park boundary.\n  s. South branch of the Moose river - Approximately fourteen and\ntwo-fifths miles from the west boundary of state land near Rock dam to\nthe east boundary of state land north of Woodhull mountain.\n  s-1. North Branch of the Moose river -- Approximately six miles from\nthe outlet of Big Moose lake to the confluence with the outlet of Goose\nPond.\n  s-2. Nissequogue river - Approximately one and four-tenths miles from\nthe dam at the outlet of New Mill Pond to the pedestrian bridge south of\nRoute 25/25A including its tributaries and ponds identified as P288\nPhillips Millpond, P289 Willow Pond, P290 Upper Vail Pond, P291 Webster\nPond, and P291a Lower Vail Pond on a certain map titled "Official\nClassifications - Surface Waters of Western Suffolk County," published\nby the water resources council and prepared by the New York state\ndepartment of health.\n  t. Middle branch of the Oswegatchie river - Approximately nine miles\nfrom the outlet of Walker lake to the north boundary of lot 27, Watson's\nEast Triangle and approximately fourteen and two-fifths miles from a\npoint one mile downstream of the confluence with Wolf Creek to a point\nwhere the Middle Branch intersects the Adirondack park boundary at the\nsoutheast boundary of lot 993, township of Diana, Macomb's Purchase,\ngreat tract 4.\n  u. West branch of the Oswegatchie river - Approximately seven miles\nfrom the outlet of Buck pond to a point approximately one mile upstream\nof Round pond at the point where a foot and snowmobile bridge crosses\nthe West Branch.\n  v. Otter brook - Approximately ten miles from the outlet of Lost pond\nto the confluence with the South Branch of the Moose river.\n  w. Raquette river - Approximately twenty miles from the outlet of Long\nlake to the confluence with a small stream from the northeast, located\napproximately one mile downstream from Trombley Landing, and\napproximately thirteen and eight-tenths miles from the confluence with\nDead creek to a point where the river intersects the north boundary of\nlot 1, township 5, Tannery Lot near Carry Falls reservoir.\n  x. Red river - Approximately nine and seven-tenths miles from the\nheadwaters of the river to the confluence with the South Branch of the\nMoose river.\n  y. Rock river - Approximately six and nine-tenths miles from the\nO'Neil flow road crossing to the confluence with the Cedar river.\n  z. Round lake outlet - Approximately two and seven-tenths miles from\nthe outlet of Round lake to the confluence with the Bog river.\n  aa. East branch of the St. Regis river - Approximately fourteen and\none-half miles from a point where route 30 crosses the East Branch near\nMeacham lake, to a point one-half mile upstream from Everton falls.\n  bb. Main branch of the St. Regis river - Approximately fifteen and\nfive-tenths miles from a point where a private road to Bay pond crosses\nthe Main Branch in lot 16, township 17, Macomb's Purchase, great tract\n1, to the confluence with Balsam brook.\n  cc. West branch of the St. Regis river - Approximately thirty-five\nmiles from the outlet of Little Fish pond to a point one-half mile\ndownstream from the confluence with Fenner Meadow brook.\n  dd. West Canada creek - Approximately seventeen miles from a point\nwhere the creek intersects the state land boundary approximately two\nmiles upstream of the Old Mitchell Dam site, to the route 8 bridge\ncrossing near Nobleboro.\n  ee. West Stony creek - Approximately seven and seven-tenths miles from\nthe Tannery road crossing to the confluence with Hatch brook.\n  ff. Peconic river - Approximately ten and one-half miles from the\nwestern boundary of the Red Maple swamp to the Long Island railroad\nbridge between Connecticut and Edwards Avenue and approximately three\nmiles from Middle Country Road (State Route 25) to the confluence with\nthe previously described segment of the Peconic including tributaries\nT112-5, T112-6 and T112-7.\n  3. Recreational rivers\n  a. East branch of the Ausable river - Approximately twenty-eight and\nthree-tenths miles from St. Huberts to the confluence with the West\nBranch.\n  b. Main branch of the Ausable river - Approximately twenty-two miles\nfrom the confluence of the East and West Branches of the Ausable river\nto Lake Champlain.\n  c. West branch of the Ausable river - Approximately twenty-nine and\none-half miles from the headwaters of the West Branch near Heart lake to\nthe confluence with the East Branch.\n  d. Black river - Approximately six and three-fifths miles from the\noutlet of North lake to a point where Farr road crosses the river.\n  e. Bouquet river - Approximately forty-seven and seven-tenths miles\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>