<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2715"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2715"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2715"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2715/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2715/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2715/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2715/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2715">
        <num>15-2715</num>
        <heading>Designation of additions to the system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2715. Designation of additions to the system.\n  1. The commissioner or agency shall study and from time to time submit\nto the governor and to the legislature proposals for the addition to the\nstate wild, scenic and recreational rivers system of river areas which,\nin their judgment, fall within one or more of the descriptive classes\nset out in this title. Each proposal shall specify the class or classes\nof the proposed addition and shall be accompanied by a detailed report\non the factors which, in the judgment of the commissioner or agency,\nmake the area a worthy addition to the system. The report shall show the\narea included within the proposal; the characteristics which make the\narea a worthy addition to the system; the current status of land\nownership and use in the area; the anticipated acquisitions of land and\nscenic or other easements in the area; the potential uses of the land\nand water; and the cost of acquisitions of land and scenic or other\neasements and improvements proposed. The commissioner or agency shall\nsend the report to the legislative authority of each county, town, and\nmunicipal corporation, any part of which is within the area, and to the\ncommissioner of transportation, commissioner of agriculture and markets,\ncommissioner of health, and commissioner of commerce.  Thereafter, each\nproposal shall be submitted to the governor and the legislature for\nadoption or modification. This section is not intended to preclude or\ndiscourage studies and proposals by other agencies or by citizen groups\nworking independently or with the commissioner or the agency, provided\nthat such studies and proposals shall be conducted and made in\naccordance with the criteria and procedures set forth in this\nsubdivision and shall be submitted to the agency or the commissioner as\nappropriate for comment prior to submission of any proposal to the\ngovernor or the legislature. The commissioner and the agency shall\nprovide technical assistance to and cooperate with any such agencies and\ncitizen groups.\n  2. Not later than three years after the effective date upon which each\nof the following rivers shall have been designated for study by\ninclusion in this subdivision, the agency, after consultation and\ncooperation with the commissioner with respect to rivers within the\nAdirondack park, or the commissioner with respect to rivers elsewhere,\nis hereby directed to consider and make proposals to the legislature for\nthe addition of each such river to the state wild, scenic and\nrecreational rivers system :\n  a. The Batten Kill river from the Vermont state line to the dam at\nGreenwich.\n  b. The Delaware river from Port Jervis to the junction of the East and\nWest Branches of the Delaware river, and the East Branch of the Delaware\nriver upstream to the Downsville dam, and the West Branch of the\nDelaware river upstream to the Cannonsville dam.\n  c. The Genesee river from the Pennsylvania state line to Letchworth\nState Park.\n  d. The Susquehanna river from Otsego lake to Bainbridge at the Route\n206 crossing.\n  g. Bouquet river--Approximately twenty-four miles of the North Branch\nfrom Trout pond to the confluence with the Main Branch.\n  h. The Branch--Approximately sixteen miles from Elk lake to the\nconfluence with the Schroon river.\n  i. East Stoney creek--Approximately eighteen miles from Harrisburg\nlake to Great Sacandaga lake.\n  j. Grasse river--Approximately twenty-five miles of the Main Branch\nfrom the confluence with the South Branch to the village of Canton.\n  l. Osgood river--Approximately fourteen miles from Jones pond to\nMeacham lake.\n  m. Oswegatchie river--Approximately eleven miles of the Main Branch\nfrom the Cranberry lake outlet to River road.\n  n. Pleasant Lake stream--Approximately seven miles from Pleasant lake\nto the confluence with the Middle Branch of the Grasse river.\n  o. Saranac river--Approximately seventeen miles of the North Branch\nfrom Mud pond to the confluence with the Main Branch.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>