<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2905"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2905"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2905"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2905">
        <num>15-2905</num>
        <heading>Statewide inventory of existing significant deficiencies in water supply systems</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2905. Statewide inventory of existing significant deficiencies in\n             water supply systems.\n  The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of health and\nutilizing information requested from the responsible local officials as\nwell as relevant information developed through titles eleven and\nthirteen of this article, shall cause to be prepared an inventory of\nexisting significant deficiencies in water supply availability\nthroughout the state, including specific needs for improvement,\nrehabilitation and establishment of water supply, distribution and\ntransmission facilities. Such inventory shall also identify those water\nsupply systems affected or threatened by intrusions of hazardous\nmaterials or wastes and the nature of remediation required. Such\ninventory shall be completed and transmitted to the governor,\nlegislature and the council by July first, nineteen hundred eighty-five.\n  The commissioner in consultation with the secretary of state, shall\nalso cause to be prepared a review and summary of existing statutory and\nconstitutional provisions relating to the provision and financing of\nwater supply facilities by local governments, including such provision\nand financing through inter-local cooperation. Such review and summary\nshall also identify any existing statutory and constitutional\nconstraints against the effective and efficient provision of sound\nfinancing, on a revenue or general obligation basis, of such facilities.\nSuch review and summary shall be completed and transmitted to the\ngovernor, legislature and the council by January first, nineteen hundred\neighty-six. At such time and based upon the above inventory and review\nand summary, the commissioner shall also cause to be prepared a\ncompilation of those instances in which correction of existing\nsignificant deficiencies appears to be beyond the reasonable financial\ncapabilities of the affected communities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>