<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2907"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2907"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2907"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2907">
        <num>15-2907</num>
        <heading>Water resources management strategy; development purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2907. Water resources management strategy; development purpose.\n  Not later than January first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven, the\ndepartment of environmental conservation, with the participation of the\ndepartment of health and whenever possible, regional planning and\ndevelopment boards, shall develop and submit a complete statewide water\nresources management strategy to the water resources planning council\nfor its review and adoption. This strategy shall be composed of substate\nwater resources management strategies which recognize the natural\nboundaries of the water resource basins, watersheds, and aquifers and\nexisting significant deficiencies of water supply, and which organize\nthese in the most practical and manageable manner. Each substate\nmanagement strategy shall analyze the present and future demographic,\nnatural resource, economic development, water quality, and conservation\nrequirements of public and private water systems and develop regional\nmanagement strategies to meet the water resources requirements of\nresidential, agricultural, industrial and commercial users as well as\nassure the highest possible quality and quantity of these resources.\n  Strategies shall analyze the efficiency and capacity of existing water\nsupply sources and facilities and shall contain recommendations for\nappropriate modifications, restoration, and expansion or development of\nnew sources or facilities. Such strategies shall also include\nevaluations and recommendations as to the feasibility of including\nhydroelectric energy generation facilities as part of the modifications,\nrestoration, and expansion or development of new or existing resources\nor facilities. The strategy shall also contain recommendations regarding\nimplementation of these strategies by the department of health, the\ndepartment of environmental conservation, other appropriate state\nagencies, local governments and special districts. In addition, the\ndepartments shall submit to the council substate water resources\nmanagement strategies as soon as such strategies are developed. The\ndepartments shall also report regularly to the council on the\ndevelopment of the strategies and receive the council's recommendations\nand directions. Such substate strategies shall also be available for\npublic inspection as soon as such strategies are developed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>