<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2141"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2141"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2141"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2141/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2141/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2141/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2141/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2141">
        <num>15-2141</num>
        <heading>Hudson River Regulating District and Black River Regulating District: funds of the board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2141. Hudson River Regulating District and Black River Regulating\n             District: funds of the board.\n  1. Notwithstanding the consolidation of the Hudson River Regulating\nDistrict and the Black River Regulating District into a single district,\neffectuated by this title, or any other provision of title 21 of this\narticle, moneys constituting the respective "general fund" or "debt\nservice fund" or other fund or funds of either the Hudson River\nRegulating Board or District or the Black River Regulating Board or\nDistrict, shall remain and be kept separate and apart and shall be\napplied for the cost of maintenance and operation in the area of the\nappropriate district and to pay the debts and obligations of the\nappropriate board or district, on whose account such moneys were\nreceived.\n  2. Notwithstanding any provision of sections 15-2137 and 15-2139 or\nany other provision of title 21 of this article, all moneys hereafter\nreceived by the Hudson River-Black River Regulating District and its\nboard, as consolidated, by reason of assessments or from the sale of\nobligations issued or from other source, all for the purposes of the\nrespective areas heretofore comprising the Hudson River Regulating\nDistrict or the Black River Regulating District, shall be kept separate\nand apart and shall constitute "general funds" and "debt service funds"\nand other fund or funds with the same force and effect as funds\nheretofore constituted by the Hudson River Regulating Board or District\nand by the Black River Regulating Board or District and shall be applied\nsolely for the cost of maintenance and operation in the respective areas\nfrom which the moneys were received and to pay the debts and obligations\naccrued or as they become due in the areas where the debts and\nobligations were incurred, provided, however, that the expenses of the\nboard, as consolidated by this part, and of its officers and employees\nshall be paid from the appropriate "general funds" in the same\nproportion as moneys are annually collected from the respective areas.\nThe provisions of section 15-2129, in so far as the same are applicable\nand not inconsistent herewith, shall apply as they relate to the\n"general fund", "debt service fund", and to the fund or funds of the\ndistrict.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>