<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1743"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1743"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1743"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1743/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1743/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1743/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1743/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1743">
        <num>17-1743</num>
        <heading>Reporting of spills of liquids stored in bulk</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 17-1743. Reporting of spills of liquids stored in bulk.\n  Any person who is the owner of or in actual or constructive possession\nor control of more than one thousand one hundred gallons, in bulk, of\nany liquid, including petroleum, which, if released, discharged or\nspilled would or would be likely to pollute the lands or waters of the\nstate including the groundwaters thereof shall, as soon as he has\nknowledge of the release, discharge or spill of any part of such liquid\nin his possession or control onto the lands or into the waters of the\nstate including the groundwaters thereof immediately notify the\ndepartment. Within forty-eight hours of receipt of notification made\npursuant to this section of a spill of a hazardous substance or acutely\nhazardous substance listed pursuant to article thirty-seven of this\nchapter of a quantity that may threaten the health or safety of the\npublic or environment, the department shall notify the chief executive\nofficer in the village, town, and city in which the spill occurred, and\nany adjoining city or town or village that the department deems\nappropriate. In addition, the department shall provide notification of\nsuch spill to the general public through local news outlets, newspaper\nor any other media available to the department. Notification received\npursuant to this section or information obtained by the exploitation of\nsuch notification shall not be used against any such person in any\ncriminal case, except a prosecution for perjury or for giving a false\nstatement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>