<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1903"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1903">
        <num>17-1903</num>
        <heading>Contracts for construction of sewage treatment works</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the erection, building, acquisition,\nalteration, reconstruction, improvement or extension of which is\ncommenced or is to be commenced between the date on which this act\nbecomes a law and March 31, 1972, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any portion of the erection,\nbuilding, acquisition, alteration, reconstruction, improvement or\nextension of which is undertaken between the date on which this act\nbecomes a law and March 31, 1972.\n  d. "Municipality" means any county, city, town, village, district\ncorporation, county or town improvement district, or sewer authority now\nexisting in a city, the New York State Environmental Facilities\nCorporation acting pursuant to subdivision three of section twelve\nhundred eighty-five of the public authorities law, or any two or more of\nthe foregoing which are acting jointly in connection with an eligible\nproject.\n  e. "Federal pollution abatement assistance" means funds available to a\nmunicipality, either directly or through allocation by the state, from\nthe federal government as grants for construction of sewage treatment\nworks, pursuant to section 6 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act\nas enacted by section 1 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act\namendments of 1956 and acts amendatory thereto.\n  f. "Federal assistance" means funds available, other than by loan,\nfrom the federal government to a municipality, either directly or\nthrough allocation by the state, for construction of sewage treatment\nworks or which are used for such construction, pursuant to the Federal\nWater Pollution Control Act and acts amendatory thereto or pursuant to\nany other federal law or program.\n  2. For the purpose of discharging the state responsibility with\nrespect to the protection and promotion of the health of the inhabitants\nof the state by the provision of sewage treatment works, the\ncommissioner, in the name of the state, may enter into contracts with\nmunicipalities having power to construct, operate and maintain sewage\ntreatment works, and any such municipality may enter into a contract\nwith the commissioner, concerning eligible projects. Any such contract\nmay include such provisions as may be agreed upon by the parties\nthereto, and shall in...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An amount equal to thirty per cent of the actual cost of the\nproject, or an amount equal to thirty per cent of the estimated\nreasonable cost of the project, whichever is lower, provided, however,\nthat the state payment under this subparagraph shall be reduced by the\namount of any federal assistance received or to be received by the\nmunicipality which is in excess of sixty per cent of the cost of the\nproject, together with,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If necessary to limit the municipal share of the cost of the\nproject to forty per cent, an additional amount which when added to the\namount of federal assistance, if any, received or to be received by the\nmunicipality, equals thirty per cent of the actual cost of the project,\nor equals thirty per cent of the estimated reasonable cost of the\nproject, whichever is lower.\n  c. An agreement by the municipality\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To proceed expeditiously with, and complete, the project in\naccordance with plans approved pursuant to section 17-0701;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>To commence operation of the sewage treatment works on completion\nof the project, and not to discontinue operation or dispose of the\nsewage treatment works without the approval of the commissioner;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to operate and maintain the sewage treatment works in accordance\nwith applicable provisions of this article, the state sanitary code and\nrules and regulations of the commissioner;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to apply for and make reasonable efforts to secure federal\nassistance for the project;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to secure the approval of the commissioner before applying for\nfederal pollution abatement assistance, in order to maximize the amounts\nof such assistance received or to be received for all projects in New\nYork state, including amounts for reimbursement of payments made by the\nstate pursuant to subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of paragraph b of this subdivision;\nand\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to provide for the payment of the municipality's share of the cost\nof the project.\n  d. A provision that, in the event that federal assistance which was\nnot included in the calculation of the state payment pursuant to\nparagraph b of this subdivision becomes available to the municipality,\nthe amount of the state payment shall be recalculated with the inclusion\nof such additional federal assistance and the municipality shall either\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>pay to the state the amount by which the state payment actually made\nexceeds the state payment determined by the recalculation or,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if\nsuch additional federal assistance has not been received by the\nmunicipality, authorize the state to receive and retain such amount from\nthe federal government.\n  3. The commissioner may adopt rules and regulations pursuant to\nsubdivision 2 of section 17-0303 governing the making and enforcing of\ncontracts pursuant to this section.\n  4. All contracts entered into pursuant to this section shall be\nsubject to approval by the state comptroller, and by the attorney\ngeneral as to form. All payments by the state pursuant to such contracts\nshall be made after audit by and upon the warrant of the comptroller on\nvouchers approved by the commissioner.\n  5. The commissioner shall prepare and file with the department an\nannual report on the scope and results of construction undertaken\npursuant to this section.\n  6. In connection with each contract concerning an eligible project the\ncommissioner shall keep adequate records of the amount of the payment by\nthe state pursuant to su...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of paragraph b of subdivision 2\nof this section, and of the amount of federal assistance received by the\nmunicipality. Such records shall be retained by the commissioner and\nshall establish the basis for application for federal reimbursement of\nsuch payments made by the state. The commissioner is hereby authorized\nto make such applications in appropriate cases.\n  7. In the event that a project is an eligible project by reason of\nclause</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subparagraph</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of paragraph c of subdivision 1 of this\nsection rather than by reason of clause</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of such subparagraph, then\nthe estimated reasonable cost of the project determined pursuant to\nparagraph a of subdivision 2 of this section and the actual cost of the\nproject for the purpose of subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_17_1903__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of paragraph b of\nsuch subdivision shall be calculated only with respect to that portion\nof the erection, building, acquisition, alteration, reconstruction,\nimprovement or extension of the sewage treatment works which is\nundertaken after the date on which this act becomes a law.\n  8. The commissioner may advance funds to a municipality in accordance\nwith the following provisions:\n  a. Prior to entering into a contract authorized by subdivision 2 of\nthis section, the commissioner may advance funds to a municipality, in\nan amount up to five per cent of the estimated reasonable cost of an\neligible project as determined by the commissioner, for the purpose of\nassisting the municipality in defraying expenses of an eligible project\nincurred in advance of construction. This advance shall be payable, upon\nthe warrant of the comptroller on a voucher approved by the\ncommissioner, after formal acceptance by the municipality of the federal\npollution abatement assistance offered purs...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>