<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0107">
        <num>19-0107</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the Act.\n  12. "Clean fuel vehicle" means a vehicle in a class or category of\nvehicles which has been certified to meet, for any model year, the clean\nfuel vehicle standards for clean fuel vehicles specified in this article\npursuant to section 7583 of the Act.\n  13. "Covered fleet" means ten or more motor vehicles which are owned\nor operated by a single person in an area designated as being a severe\nozone non-attainment area by the administrator pursuant to Title I of\nthe Act. In determining the number of motor vehicles owned or operated\nby a single person for the purposes of this article, all motor vehicles\nowned or operated, leased or otherwise controlled by such person, by any\nperson who controls such person, by any person controlled by such\nperson, and by any person under common control with such person shall be\ntreated as owned by such person. The term "covered fleet" shall not\ninclude motor vehicles held for lease or rental to the general public,\nmotor vehicles ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in\na covered fleet which is centrally fueled or is capable of being\ncentrally fueled and (ii) in a vehicle class for which standards are\napplicable under this article.\n  15. "Emission offset" or "offset" means emission reductions or\nemission reduction credits which are required to be obtained by an air\ncontamination source in order to obtain approval for a permit to\nconstruct a new air contamination source, or modify an existing air\ncontamination source, in a non-attainment area pursuant to Title I of\nthe Act.\n  16. "Emission reduction" or "emission reduction credit" means the\nactual decrease in emissions of a regulated air contaminant in tons per\nyear. Emission reductions may be created by, but not limited to,\nproduct, process, pollution control or housekeeping changes that:\n  a.  reduce emissions beyond that which is required by the Act;\n  b. are real and actually occur;\n  c. are quantifiable;\n  d. are enforceable by the commissioner or the administrator; and\n  e. are assured for the life of a corresponding increase.\n  17. "Fugitive emissions" means those emissions of regulated air\ncontaminants which could not reasonably pass through a stack, chimney,\nvent or other functionally-equivalent openings.\n  18. "Operating permit" means a permit issued pursuant to section\n19-0311 of this article.\n  19. "Major air contamination source" or "major stationary source"\nmeans any stationary source or any group of stationary sources located\nwithin a contiguous area and under common control and belonging to a\nsingle major industrial grouping that:\n  a. emits or has the potential to emit one hundred tons per year of any\nregulated air contaminant; or\n  b. emits or has the potential to emit ten tons per year of any air\ncontaminant or twenty-five tons per year of any combination of air\ncontaminants listed under section 7412</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Act, including fugitive\nemissions of such contaminants, or lesser quantities as the\nadministrator may establish pursuant to the Act; or\n  c. emits or has the potential to emit twenty-five tons per year of\nvolatile organic compounds or oxides of nitrogen, including fugitive\nemissions of such contaminants if located in an area designated a\n"severe non-attainment area" pursuant to section 7511 of the Act; or\n  d. emits or has the potential to emit fifty tons per year of volatile\norganic compounds or one hundred tons of oxides of nitrogen if located\nin an ozone transport region pursuant to section 7511</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Act.\n  Fugitive emissions from a stationary source must be considered in\ndetermining whether such stationary source is a major stationary source\nfor permit requirements if the source belongs to one of the categories\nof stationary sources identified by the administrator in regulation\npursuant to section 7602</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Act.\n  20. "Major industrial grouping" means all activities belonging to the\nsame major group identified in the Standard Industrial Classification\nManual</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_j__subsec_1987">
            <num>(1987)</num>
            <content>
              <p>published by the United States department of commerce.\n  21. "Potential to emit" means the maximum capacity of a stationary\nsource to emit any regulated air contaminant under its physical and\noperational design. Any physical or operational limitation on the\ncapacity of such source to emit a regulated air contaminant, including\nair pollution control equipment and restrictions on hours of operation\nor on the type or amount of material combusted, stored, or processed,\nshall be treated as part of its design if the limitation is enforceable\nby the commissioner and the administrator of the United States\nenvironmental protection agency provided, however, that physical or\noperational limitations enforceable by the commissioner shall be treated\nas part of a source's design, if the commissioner is given such\nauthorization by the administrator.\n  22. "Regulated air contaminant" means the following:\n  a. oxides of nitrogen;\n  b. volatile organic compounds;\n  c. sulfur dioxide;\n  d...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Act and which the commissioner has listed in\nregulation. The department may use emergency rulemaking pursuant to\nsubdivision six of section two hundred two of the state administrative\nprocedure act if necessary, in order to timely list such air\ncontaminants.\n  23. "State implementation plan" or "SIP" means documents prepared by\nthe department, and submitted to the administrator for approval, which\nidentify actions and programs to be undertaken by the state and its\nsubdivisions to implement the Act.\n  24. "Stationary source" means any building, structure, facility or\ninstallation that emits or may emit any regulated air contaminant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>