<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0317"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0317"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0317"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0317/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0317/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0317/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0317/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0317">
        <num>19-0317</num>
        <heading>Air program evaluation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 19-0317. Air program evaluation.\n  Within eighteen months after the effective date of this section, and\nbiennially thereafter, the department shall, in coordination with the\ndepartment of economic development, prepare and submit to the governor\nand the legislature a report evaluating the programs proposed or adopted\nto implement the Act. The evaluation shall include:\n  1. an identification of the specific measures taken to implement the\nAct, and progress made toward meeting emission reductions required by\nthe Act;\n  2. recommendations on any additional measures which must be taken if\nthe state is not meeting emission reductions required by the Act;\n  3. an evaluation of the resources available to implement the programs\nrequired by the Act and whether those resources are sufficient;\n  4. an analysis of the costs of measures taken to implement the Act,\nincluding costs imposed directly and indirectly on mobile sources,\nstationary sources, consumers and businesses. The analysis shall also\nidentify the benefits of compliance with the Act;\n  5. an analysis of the adequacy of measures taken to assist small\nbusiness stationary sources in complying with the Act;\n  6. an identification and status of any non-compliance notifications\nreceived from the United States environmental protection agency;\n  7. a summary of any significant new regulations or guidance prepared\nby the United States environmental protection agency; and\n  8. an identification of any regulation or guidance expected from the\nUnited States environmental protection agency necessary for the state to\nimplement provisions of the Act, and the effect of any past due rule or\nguidance on the state's compliance efforts.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>