<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-1103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-1103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-1103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_1103">
        <num>19-1103</num>
        <heading>Vehicle global warming index labels</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 19-1103. Vehicle global warming index labels.\n  1. No model year two thousand ten or subsequent model year motor\nvehicle shall be sold in this state unless there is securely and\nconspicuously affixed in a clearly visible location, a label on which\nthe manufacturer shall endorse clearly, distinctly, and legibly true and\ncorrect entries disclosing information concerning the emissions of\nglobal warming gases.\n  2. Unless alternative labeling is approved by the commissioner\npursuant to section 19-1105 of this title, the label required by\nsubdivision one of this section shall include:\n  a. a global warming index that contains quantitative information\npresented in a continuous, easy-to-read scale, unless the commissioner\ndetermines, after public hearing, that an alternative graphical\nrepresentation will more effectively convey the information to\nconsumers, and that compares the emissions of global warming gases from\nthe vehicle with the average projected emissions of global warming gases\nfrom all vehicles of the same model year. For reference purposes, the\nindex shall also identify the emissions of global warming gases from the\nvehicle model of that same model year that has the lowest emissions of\nglobal warming gases; and\n  b. the use of at least one color ink, as determined by the\ncommissioner, in addition to black.\n  3. In order to ensure that the label is useful and informative to\nconsumers, the commissioner shall, in designing the label and to the\nextent feasible within its existing resources:\n  a. seek input from the commissioner of motor vehicles, automotive\nconsumers, graphic design professionals, and persons with expertise in\nenvironmental labeling; and\n  b. consider other relevant label formats consistent with paragraph a\nof subdivision two of this section.\n  4. The index included in the label pursuant to paragraph a of\nsubdivision two of this section shall be updated as determined necessary\nby the commissioner to ensure that the differences in emissions among\nvehicles are readily apparent to the consumer.\n  5. Such label and index included in such label shall, to the largest\nextent possible, be consistent with labels and information required by\nother states. A label that complies with the requirements of the\nCalifornia vehicle labeling program shall be deemed to meet the\nrequirements of this title. An automobile manufacturer may apply to the\ncommissioner for approval of an alternative to the labeling requirement\nthat is at least as effective in providing presale notification of the\nvehicle's emissions of global warming gases as is the labeling required\nby this title.\n  6. Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting a\npurchaser from removing the label required by this section, after such\npurchaser has taken possession of the vehicle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>