<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0917"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0917"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-0917"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0917/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0917/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0917/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0917/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_0917">
        <num>21-0917</num>
        <heading>The Great Lakes Basin advisory council</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0917__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>advise the commissioner and the governor on the implementation and\nany modifications to any comprehensive long-term Great Lakes management\nplan developed by the department;\n  (ii) advise the state's members on the board of directors of the Great\nLakes protection fund;\n  (iii) annually identify specific research or program needs for funding\nfrom the New York Great Lakes protection fund, after consultation with\nthe Great Lakes protection fund, other Great Lakes states and other\nconcerned parties. Such annual program, with as much detail on the scope\nand expectations of each project as is practical, shall be submitted to\nthe commissioner, who shall select specific projects from the program,\nrecommended by the council and shall submit such projects to the\ndepartment for implementation; and\n  (iv) evaluate and report to the governor and the legislature on the\nprojects funded by the New York Great Lakes protection fund.\n  b. The governor shall appoint nine members with one representing an\ninstitution that performs research on the issues and the problems of the\nGreat Lakes, one representing a labor union whose members derive their\nlivelihood from the Great Lakes, three representing environmental or\nconservation organizations with interests in the Great Lakes Basin, two\nrepresenting business organizations whose commercial interest lies in\nactivities in or around Lake Ontario, Lake Erie and/or the St.  Lawrence\nRiver, one representing a municipality adjacent to Lake Erie, Lake\nOntario or the St. Lawrence River, and one representing a county having\na population of two hundred and fifty thousand people or less adjacent\nto Lake Erie, Lake Ontario or the St. Lawrence River. The temporary\npresident of the Senate and the speaker of the Assembly shall each\nappoint two members who have a demonstrated knowledge in Great Lakes\nissues. The commissioner, the commissioners of the departments of state,\nhealth, transportation, economic development and the chair...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>