<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-0903"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_0903">
        <num>21-0903</num>
        <heading>Representation on the commission</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 21-0903. Representation on the commission.\n  In pursuance of article four of the compact there shall be five\ncommissioners. One shall be the Commissioner of Environmental\nConservation or, if designated by him, one of his principal deputies.\nThe other four commissioners shall be designated by the Governor to\nserve at his pleasure. Each commissioner shall have three-fifths of one\nvote and is hereby given all of the powers conferred on a commissioner\nby the compact or which shall be necessary or incidental to the\nperformance of his functions as such a commissioner. It is hereby\nspecifically recognized that the interests and activities of the Great\nLakes Commission contemplate many aspects of the great lakes and of\ntheir relation to the member states. Accordingingly, it is declared to\nbe the legislative intent that each of the New York commissioners, and\nsuch commissioners as a group, shall confer and consult with all other\nagencies and officers of the state government whenever appropriate to\ncoordinate or make known the views and policies of such agencies and\nofficers with respect to the work of the commission or the interests of\nthe state in the great lakes basin.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>