<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0901"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0901"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-0901"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_0901">
        <num>21-0901</num>
        <heading>Great Lakes Basin Compact</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 21-0901. Great Lakes Basin Compact.\n  The Great Lakes Basin Compact, as first enacted by chapter 643 of the\nlaws of l960, as reenacted by chapter 473 of the laws of 1961, and as\nrenumbered by chapter 73 of the laws of l962, is hereby continued. The\ncompact is as follows:\n  The party states solemnly agree:\n                                 ARTICLE I\n  The purposes of this compact are, through means of joint or\ncooperative action:\n  1. To promote the orderly, integrated, and comprehensive development,\nuse, and conservation of the water resources of the Great Lakes Basin\n(hereinafter called the Basin).\n  2. To plan for the welfare and development of the water resources of\nthe Basin as a whole as well as for those portions of the Basin which\nmay have problems of special concern.\n  3. To make it possible for the states of the Basin and their people to\nderive the maximum benefit from utilization of public works, in the form\nof navigational aids or otherwise, which may exist or which may be\nconstructed from time to time.\n  4. To advise in securing and maintaining a proper balance among\nindustrial, commercial, agricultural, water supply, residential,\nrecreational, and other legitimate uses of the water resources of the\nBasin.\n  5. To establish and maintain an intergovernmental agency to the end\nthat the purposes of this compact may be accomplished more effectively.\n                                ARTICLE II\n  A. This compact shall enter into force and become effective and\nbinding when it has been enacted by the legislatures of any four of the\nStates of Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, New York, Ohio,\nPennsylvania, and Wisconsin and thereafter shall enter into force and\nbecome effective and binding as to any other of said states when enacted\nby the legislature thereof.\n  B. The Province of Ontario and the Province of Quebec, or either of\nthem, may become states party to this compact by taking such action as\ntheir laws and the laws of the Government of Canada may prescribe for\nadherence thereto. For the purpose of this compact the word "state"\nshall be construed to include a Province of Canada.\n                                ARTICLE III\n  The Great Lakes Commission created by Article IV of this compact shall\nexercise its powers and perform its functions in respect to the Basin\nwhich, for the purposes of this compact, shall consist of so much of the\nfollowing as may be within the party states:\n  1. Lakes Erie, Huron, Michigan, Ontario, St. Clair, Superior, and the\nSt. Lawrence River, together with any and all natural or man-made water\ninterconnections between or among them.\n  2. All rivers, ponds, lakes, streams, and other watercourses which, in\ntheir natural state or in their prevailing condition, are tributary to\nLakes Erie, Huron, Michigan, Ontario, St. Clair, and Superior or any of\nthem or which comprise part of any watershed draining into any of said\nlakes.\n                                ARTICLE IV\n  A. There is hereby created an agency of the party states to be known\nas The Great Lakes Commission, (hereinafter called the Commission). In\nthat name the Commission may sue and be sued, acquire, hold and convey\nreal and personal property and any interest therein. The Commission\nshall have a seal with the words "The Great Lakes Commission" and such\nother design as it may prescribe engraved thereon by which it shall\nauthenticate its proceedings. Transactions involving real or personal\nproperty shall conform to the laws of the state in which the property is\nlocated, and the Commission may by bylaws provide for the execution and\nacknowledgment of all instruments in its behalf.\n  B. The Commission shall be composed of not less than three\ncommissioners nor more than five commissioners from each party state\ndesignated or appointed in accordance with the law of the state which\nthey represent and serving and subject to removal in accordance with\nsuch law.\n  C. Each state delegation shall be entitled to three votes in the\nCommission. The presence of commissioners from a majority of the party\nstates shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business at any\nmeeting of the Commission. Actions of the Commission shall be by a\nmajority of the votes cast except that any recommendations made pursuant\nto Article VI of this compact shall require an affirmative vote of not\nless than a majority of the votes cast from each of a majority of the\nstates present and voting.\n  D. The commissioners of any two or more party states may meet\nseparately to consider problems of particular interest to their states\nbut no action taken at any such meeting shall be deemed an action of the\nCommission unless and until the Commission shall specifically approve\nthe same.\n  E. In the absence of any commissioner, his vote may be cast by another\nrepresentative or commissioner of his state provided that said\ncommissioner or other representative casting said vote shall have a\nwritten proxy in proper form as may be required by the Commission.\n  F. The Commission shall elect annually from among its members a\nchairman and vice-chairman. The Commission shall appoint an Executive\nDirector who shall also act as secretary-treasurer, and who shall be\nbonded in such amount as the Commission may require. The Executive\nDirector shall serve at the pleasure of the Commission and at such\ncompensation and under such terms and conditions as may be fixed by it.\nThe Executive Director shall be custodian of the records of the\nCommission with authority to affix the Commission's official seal and to\nattest to and certify such records or copies thereof.\n  G. The Executive Director, subject to the approval of the Commission\nin such cases as its bylaws may provide, shall appoint and remove or\ndischarge such personnel as may be necessary for the performance of the\nCommission's functions. Subject to the aforesaid approval, the Executive\nDirector may fix their compensation, define their duties, and require\nbonds of such of them as the Commission may designate.\n  H. The Executive Director, on behalf of, as trustee for, and with the\napproval of the Commission, may borrow, accept, or contract for the\nservices of personnel from any state or government or any subdivision or\nagency thereof, from any intergovernmental agency, or from any\ninstitution, person, firm or corporation; and may accept for any of the\nCommission's purposes and functions under this compact any and all\ndonations, gifts, and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials,\nand services from any state or government or any subdivision or agency\nthereof or intergovernmental agency or from any institution, person,\nfirm or corporation and may receive and utilize the same.\n  I. The Commission may establish and maintain one or more offices for\nthe transacting of its business and for such purposes the Executive\nDirector, on behalf of, as trustee for, and with the approval of the\nCommission, may acquire, hold and dispose of real and personal property\nnecessary to the performance of its functions.\n  J. No tax levied or imposed by any party state or any political\nsubdivision thereof shall be deemed to apply to property, transactions,\nor income of the Commission.\n  K. The Commission may adopt, amend and rescind bylaws, rules and\nregulations for the conduct of its business.\n  L. The organization meeting of the Commission shall be held within six\nmonths from the effective date of this compact.\n  M. The Commission and its Executive Director shall make available to\nthe party states any information within its possession and shall always\nprovide free access to its records by duly authorized representatives of\nsuch party states.\n  N. The Commission shall keep a written record of its meetings and\nproceedings and shall annually make a report thereof to be submitted to\nthe duly designated official of each party state.\n  O. The Commission shall make and transmit annually to the legislature\nand Governor of each party state a report covering the activities of the\nCommission for the preceding year and embodying such recommendations as\nmay have been adopted by the Commission. The Commission may issue such\nadditional reports as it may deem desirable.\n                                 ARTICLE V\n  A. The members of the Commission shall serve without compensation, but\nthe expenses of each commissioner shall be met by the state which he\nrepresents in accordance with the law of that state. All other expenses\nincurred by the Commission in the course of exercising the powers\nconferred upon it by this compact, unless met in some other manner\nspecifically provided by this compact, shall be paid by the Commission\nout of its own funds.\n  B. The Commission shall submit to the executive head or designated\nofficer of each party state a budget of its estimated expenditures for\nsuch period as may be required by the laws of that state for\npresentation to the legislature thereof.\n  C. Each of the Commission's budgets of estimated expenditures shall\ncontain specific recommendations of the amount or amounts to be\nappropriated by each of the party states. Detailed commission budgets\nshall be recommended by a majority of the votes cast, and the costs\nshall be allocated equitably among the party states in accordance with\ntheir respective interests.\n  D. The Commission shall not pledge the credit of any party state.  The\nCommission may meet any of its obligations in whole or in part with\nfunds available to it under Article IV (II) of this compact, provided\nthat the Commission takes specific action setting aside such funds prior\nto the incurring of any obligations to be met in whole or in part in\nthis manner. Except where the Commission makes use of funds available to\nit under Article IV (H) hereof, the Commission shall not incur any\nobligations prior to the allotment of funds by the party states adequate\nto </p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>