<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-1103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_1103">
        <num>21-1103</num>
        <heading>State member of the basin panel and representative; planning members</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 21-1103. State member of the basin panel and representative; planning\n             members.\n  1. As provided in the third subdivision of section three of article\nthree of the compact the Governor shall be this state's member on the\nbasin panel established thereby or shall appoint a representative to act\nfor him. He shall appoint four planning members of the commissions to\nserve at his pleasure: a citizen who is a resident of the valley, a\nstate planning official, a state parks official and an officer of the\nDepartment of Environmental Conservation.\n  2. The legislative member shall be elected by a majority vote of the\nlegislators elected from the counties of Clinton, Essex, Warren and\nWashington.\n  3. Any person, member or alternate, serving on the interstate\ncommission on Lake Champlain basin (Incochamp) pursuant to this section\nshall be reimbursed for all necessary expenses incurred as an incident\nof such service, and such reimbursement shall be from the funds of said\nperson's department or office. For this purpose the citizen member shall\nbe considered as a member of the executive department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>