<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0901"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0901"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23-0901"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23_0901">
        <num>23-0901</num>
        <heading>Compulsory integration and unitization in oil and natural gas pools and fields</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_23_0901__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>During the recovery of the actual well costs, 1/16 or 6.25%,\n  (ii) During the recovery of the first 100% of the risk penalty, 3/32\nor 9.38%,\n  (iii) During the recovery of the second 100% of the risk penalty, the\nlowest royalty fraction set forth in an existing lease in the unit, but\nno less than 1/8 or 12.5%.\n  Nothing in this subparagraph relieves any lessee of its obligation to\npay, from the commencement of production, any remaining royalty and\noverriding royalty owed under the terms of its lease.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_23_0901__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Integrated participating owner" or "participating owner" means an\nowner who elects to participate in the initial well in a spacing unit,\npays all costs associated with participation and complies with all of\nthe requirements for participation, including the terms of integration,\nspecified in an order of integration issued pursuant to the compulsory\nintegration provisions of this section.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_23_0901__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Integrated royalty owner" means an owner who has either elected\nto be an integrated royalty owner or who does not elect to become either\na participating owner or a non-participating owner. The integrated\nroyalty owner shall receive a royalty equal to the lowest royalty in an\nexisting lease in the spacing unit, but no less than one-eighth. The\nintegrated royalty owner shall have no obligation to the well operator\nor any other owner for any charges, taxes or fees associated with the\noperation of the oil or gas well and, notwithstanding any other law to\nthe contrary, shall not be liable by reason of the owner's status as an\nintegrated royalty owner for any claims for personal injury or property\ndamage suffered by any person relating to the drilling and operation of\nthe well.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_23_0901__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Risk penalty" means the percentage applied to well costs to\nreimburse the well operator for the risk involved with the exploration\nfor and development of a well or the percentage applied to other costs\nthat are subject to recoupment and a risk penalty, as provided herein.\nAt any time during a risk penalty phase, an owner subject to a risk\npenalty may pay to the well operator the full amount subject to\nrecoupment by the well operator, to terminate the risk penalty phase and\nbe eligible for other opportunities for participation as provided\nherein.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_23_0901__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>"Well costs" means the costs incurred or estimated to be incurred\nby the well operator in relation to the drilling, completion, and the\ninstallation of surface equipment, other than as described in item E of\nclause (ii) of subparagraph 1 of paragraph c of this subdivision,\nincluding, without limitation, surveying, drill site preparation,\nleasing of surface rights and access roads pertinent to the drill site,\nconstruction of access roads, permitting, drilling, stimulation,\ntesting, well logging, drilling insurance, plugging and abandonment of\nthe well, environmental mitigation costs associated with drilling and\nany other costs associated with the foregoing that the operator has\nincurred or anticipates incurring, including a reasonable charge for\nsupervision of the foregoing activities.\n  b. If upon issuance of a well permit by the department, the well\noperator does not control all owners within the spacing unit, either\nthrough lease or voluntary agreement, the department s...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_23_0901__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The notice of hearing to each uncontrolled owner shall be made in\na form prescribed by the department, and shall include:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_23_0901__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An election form, as prescribed by the department, granting the\nuncontrolled owner the right to elect to be integrated into the spacing\nunit as an integrated participating owner, an integrated\nnon-participating owner or an integrated royalty owner. Such form shall\nset forth the well operator's good faith estimate of those well costs\nwhich the owners electing to be integrated as participating owners will\nbe responsible for paying to the well operator prior to conclusion of\nthe integration hearing, based on each owner's proportionate share of\nsuch costs, and confirm that if an uncontrolled owner does not make a\ntimely election and does not timely comply with all of the requirements\nto be either a participating owner or a non-participating owner, that\nsuch uncontrolled owner shall be integrated into the spacing unit as an\nintegrated royalty owner.\n  (ii) A copy of the proposed order of integration, which shall include\nthe proposed terms of integration applicable to integrated participating\nowners and integrated non-participating owners. The proposed order of\nintegration shall include the following terms in addition to any\napplicable risk penalty:\n  A. The owner shall be liable for its proportionate share of all costs\nand expenses, including taxes, and claims of third parties related to\nthe well, operations thereon and in conjunction therewith, and shall be\nentitled to its proportionate share of all benefits therefrom. If an\nowner's share of production is subject to a risk penalty, the well\noperator shall establish a risk penalty account for such owner and all\ncosts, expenses and benefits attributable to such owner shall be\nreflected in the penalty account;\n  B. The well operator shall hold any funds paid by the owner or\nrecouped through the risk penalty attributable to the plugging and\nabandonment costs of the well, as estimated prior to the drilling of the\nwell, in an interest bearing account until such funds are required and\nutilized for...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_23_0901__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within twenty-one days of receiving notice of the integration\nhearing, each uncontrolled owner shall provide to the well operator and\nthe department its election as to whether it chooses to be integrated as\na participating owner, a non-participating owner or an integrated\nroyalty owner. Failure of an uncontrolled owner to elect to be\nintegrated as a participating owner, a non-participating owner or an\nintegrated royalty owner and to pay the amount specified in the notice\nby the date of the hearing, or to make any election, shall result in the\nowner being integrated as an integrated royalty owner. Nothing contained\nin this section shall preclude any person from entering into a lease or\nother voluntary agreement at any time prior to the hearing.\n  d. If substantive and significant issues are raised during the\nintegration hearing, the department shall schedule an adjudicatory\nhearing.\n  e. If no substantive and significant issues are raised at the hearing,\nthe department sh...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>