<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0801"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0801"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="24-0801"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_24_0801">
        <num>24-0801</num>
        <heading>Permits for wetlands in the Adirondack park</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 24-0801. Permits for wetlands in the Adirondack park.\n  1. As used in this title, the term "freshwater wetlands", in addition\nto its meaning under section 24-0107 of this article, shall mean\n"wetlands" as defined in subdivision sixty-eight of section eight\nhundred two of article twenty-seven of the executive law.\n  2. Where the activities otherwise subject to regulation under this\narticle involve freshwater wetlands located within the boundaries of the\nAdirondack park, the inquiries referred to and the applications provided\nfor in section 24-0703 of this article shall be made to and filed with\nthe Adirondack park agency at its headquarters office, under such\nregulations and procedures as the Adirondack park agency may promulgate.\nThe Adirondack park agency shall review the application in place of the\ncommissioner or local government as provided in section 24-0705 of this\narticle, having due regard for the declaration of policy and statement\nof findings set forth in this article and for the considerations set\nforth in subdivision one of section 24-0705 of this article. The agency\nshall in addition determine prior to the granting of any permit that the\nproposed activity will be consistent with the Adirondack park land use\nand development plan and would not have an undue adverse impact upon the\nnatural, scenic, aesthetic, ecological, wildlife, historic, recreational\nor open space resources of the park, taking into account the economic\nand social or other benefits to be derived from the activity. Any person\nmay seek review of a ruling made solely pursuant to the provisions of\nthis article by the Adirondack park agency pursuant to the provisions of\narticle seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>