<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-1301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-1301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="24-1301"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-1301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-1301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-1301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-1301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_24_1301">
        <num>24-1301</num>
        <heading>Miscellaneous provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 24-1301. Miscellaneous provisions.\n  1. The provisions of this article shall not be construed to limit in\nany manner the functions, powers and duties of the commissioner or the\ndepartment of environmental conservation, or of any other state\ndepartment or agency, under this chapter or any other laws.\n  2. The commissioner, his agents or employees and the personnel of the\nAdirondack park agency may enter upon any lands or waters after\nreasonable notice and for good cause shown for the purpose of\nundertaking any investigations, examination, survey, or other activity\nfor the purposes of this article.\n  3. The commissioner may adopt and, from time to time, amend rules and\nregulations consistent with this article to assist him in carrying out\nhis functions, powers and duties hereunder.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a privately\nowned parcel of land or part thereof within the county of Richmond that\ndid not contain a designation as a freshwater wetland on the tentative\nfreshwater wetlands map filed in the office of the clerk of Richmond\ncounty in 1981 shall not be on any tentative freshwater wetlands map if\nthe landowner has any written determination from the department pursuant\nto subdivision five of section 24-0703 of this article that such parcel\nof land or part thereof did not meet the statutory definition of a\nfreshwater wetland. Such representations shall be considered to have\nbeen definitive when made, and such parcel or part thereof shall not be\ndesignated as a freshwater wetland on any final map filed in the office\nof the clerk of Richmond county pursuant to this article. The provisions\nof this subdivision shall not apply to any parcel of land or part\nthereof, purchased after January first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven,\nor to any such parcel or part thereof owned wholly or in part by any\nunit of government or agency or subdivision thereof, any authority or\nagency existing pursuant to governmental action, or subdivision thereof;\nincluding the state and the city of New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>