<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-0305"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_0305">
        <num>27-0305</num>
        <heading>Permits for waste transporters</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_0305__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may, by regulation, exempt from the permit\nrequirements of this title persons engaged in the transportation of:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_0305__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>types of wastes which do not constitute a hazard to human health\nand the environment;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_0305__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>small quantities of waste; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_0305__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>wastes transported by rail, water and air carriers.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_0305__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner may also exempt from the permit requirements of\nthis title persons engaged in the transportation of low-level\nradioactive waste only upon a showing by such person that compliance\nwith such requirements would create a hardship on his own business\nactivities and upon a determination that, based upon the characteristics\nincluding half life, concentration, activity, and toxicity of the\nspecific low-level radioactive waste transported, such transport imposes\nno potential significant adverse impact on public health, safety or\nwelfare, the environment, or natural resources as determined by the\ndepartment in consultation with the department of health. The\ncommissioner shall promulgate guidelines for the purpose of determining\nthe circumstances under which such exemption may be granted. Any person\ngranted such an exemption must comply with such conditions as specified\nby the commissioner. Such exemption shall be reviewed periodically as\nspecified by the commissioner but at least once every two years. Any\nexemption granted hereunder may be revoked after due notice and\nopportunity for hearing for a violation of any provision of this title\nor other applicable laws, rules or regulations relating to the\ntransportation of regulated wastes or upon a showing that the exempted\nperson no longer meets the requisite guidelines for exemption.\n  3. A generator of a waste may obtain a permit pursuant to this title\nto transport his own waste or if he contracts with another person to\nremove, transport or dispose of regulated wastes. If a generator obtains\nsuch a permit, a person engaged in the removal, transportation or\ndisposal of his waste shall not be required to obtain a permit pursuant\nto this title for the transportation of such wastes.\n  4. The department shall make rules and regulations implementing this\nsection promulgated in accordance with the state administrative\nprocedure act in order to carry out and enforce the intent and purposes\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>