<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0909"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0909"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-0909"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0909/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0909/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0909/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0909/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_0909">
        <num>27-0909</num>
        <heading>Standards applicable to transporters of hazardous waste</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-0909. Standards applicable to transporters of hazardous waste.\n  Not later than eighteen months after the effective date of this title,\nand after consultation and coordination with the commissioner of\ntransportation, and after opportunity for public hearings, the\ncommissioner shall promulgate regulations establishing such standards\nwhich shall be applicable to transporters of hazardous waste identified\nor listed under this title, as may be necessary to protect human health\nand the environment. Such standards shall include but need not be\nlimited to requirements respecting:\n  1. Recordkeeping practices that accurately identify the hazardous\nwastes transported, and their sources and delivery points;\n  2. Transportation and storage of such waste only if properly labeled;\n  3. Compliance with the manifest system established under section\n27-0905 of this title;\n  4. Transportation of all such hazardous waste only to the hazardous\nwaste treatment, storage, or disposal facility or facilities which are\ndesignated on the manifest form, a copy of which shall be presented to\nthe generator prior to transportation, and which either hold operation\npermits issued under this article, are a permittee under the Federal\nResource Conservation and Recovery Act of nineteen hundred seventy-six\nor any amendments thereof, or are otherwise duly authorized to accept\nhazardous waste; and\n  5. Requirement of a bond to meet all responsibilities in case of\nrelease of hazardous wastes causing damage as a condition to the\nissuance of a permit to a transporter required by this title.\n  6. No vehicle, vehicle container, holding tank or other equipment used\nto transport hazardous waste shall be used in transporting any item\nintended for human or animal consumption unless such waste and its\nresidue have been completely removed. The commissioner shall promulgate\nregulations establishing such minimum standards and procedures necessary\nto insure proper cleaning and removal of hazardous waste and its residue\nfrom such equipment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>