<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0707"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0707"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-0707"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_0707">
        <num>27-0707</num>
        <heading>Permits for new solid waste management facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_0707__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\nthree of section ninety-seven-m of the state finance law that will\nexpedite compliance with the Ocean Dumping Ban Act of 1988.  For any\nsuch permit application submitted by a municipality prior to April\nfirst, nineteen hundred ninety-one, the department shall, upon issuance\nof a permit, require as a permit condition that the municipality or\nplanning unit of which it is a part have in effect a local solid waste\nmanagement plan which contains all of the elements set forth in\nparagraph b of subdivision one of section 27-0107 of this article by a\ndate certain, which shall be no sooner than April first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-one, unless otherwise agreed by the municipality, and\nwhich shall be no later than April first, nineteen hundred ninety-two.\nFor any such permit application submitted on behalf of a municipality\nprior to April first, nineteen hundred ninety-one, the department shall\nrequire as a permit condition that the proposed solid waste management\nfacility shall be prohibited from accepting waste from such municipality\nby a date certain, which shall be no sooner than April first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-one and no later than April first, nineteen hundred\nninety-two, unless such municipality or the planning unit of which it is\na part has in effect a local solid waste management plan which contains\nall of the elements set forth in paragraph b of subdivision one of\nsection 27-0107 of this article. For purposes of this paragraph,\n"planning unit" shall have the same meaning as set forth in subdivision\none of section 27-0107 of this article.\n  c. that a permit will be issued only if:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_0707__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the proposed facility will be in full compliance with the\napplicable rules and regulations in effect on the date of submission of\nthe permit application; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_0707__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>there has been opportunity for public review and comment at\nrelevant stages of the project planning process; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_0707__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a determination has been made that the proposed facility will not\nresult in unfair competition between municipalities and scrap dealers,\nprocessors and consumers; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_0707__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the applicant has received or will receive the written opinion of\ncounsel to each muncipality or public authority which has entered into a\ncontract, lease or rental agreement with the proposed facility that such\ncontract, lease or rental agreement is in compliance with the applicable\nrequirements of sections one hundred one, one hundred three and one\nhundred twenty-w of the general municipal law.\n  2-a. No exemption from the permit requirements imposed by this title\nshall be allowed for the establishment of a new solid waste management\nfacility for the disposal of nonputrescible construction and demolition\ndebris when such facility will be used for the deposition of\nconstruction and demolition debris from an offsite source when a fee or\nany other form of consideration is required for the privilege of using\nthe facility for the disposal of construction and demolition debris.\n  2-b. The department of environmental conservation shall not issue a\npermit to construct or a perm...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>