<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0712"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0712"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-12-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-0712"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0712/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0712/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0712/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0712/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_0712">
        <num>27-0712</num>
        <heading>Coverage of all vehicles, including barges transporting solid waste</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-0712. Coverage of all vehicles, including barges transporting solid\n             waste.\n  1. Legislative findings and intent. It is the purpose of this section\nto assure that solid waste management is conducted in a safe, sanitary,\nefficient and environmentally sound manner throughout the state. The\nlegislature finds and declares that current law and regulations have not\nalways achieved this purpose. A large percentage of solid waste is\ntransferred and transported over water as well as by container truck.\nSome type of cover is necessary to protect against the spillage of waste\nand emission of odors during its transfer and transportation. The\nlegislature further finds and declares that legislation is necessary to\nremedy this situation by requiring the responsible parties to cover such\nvehicles with devices which will accomplish the intent of this section.\n  2. A municipality or any individual, firm or corporation acting on its\nbehalf or any other individual, firm or corporation shall not cause or\npermit any solid waste to be transported on any vehicle, barge, ship, or\nscow unless the solid waste on the vehicle, barge, ship, or scow is\ncovered provided, however, that putrescible waste transported by rail\nshall be covered with sealing hard lids in a manner not inconsistent\nwith Federal Railroad Administration regulations, and non-putrescible\nwaste shipped by rail shall be covered with hard tarping securely\nfastened over the load, which shall not exceed the height of the side of\nthe rail container, in a manner not inconsistent with Federal Railroad\nAdministration regulations.\n  3. The department shall monitor and inspect such vehicles, barges,\nships and scows transporting solid waste on a regular basis to insure\nthat they are covered and in compliance with the provisions of this\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>