<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0921"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0921"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-0921"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0921/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0921/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0921/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0921/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_0921">
        <num>27-0921</num>
        <heading>Short-term management</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-0921. Short-term management.\n  1. a. The commissioner shall immediately begin preparation of a\nproposal for a short-term hazardous waste management program for the\neffective and safe disposal, treatment and storage of hazardous waste.\nSuch program shall be coordinated with the on-going comprehensive\nprogram for the long-term treatment and disposal of hazardous waste.\n  b. As part of the proposal, a comprehensive study shall be made with\nregard to the short-term needs of New York state generators of hazardous\nwaste consistent with the protection of public health and safety and the\nenvironment and in light of:\n  (1) federal and state laws, rules and regulations designed to ensure\nproper disposition of hazardous waste from generation to final storage\nor treatment which place substantial responsibilities on industry to\nresponsibly and safely dispose of hazardous waste;\n  (2) the identified shortfall in existing available storage, treatment\nand disposal capacity, and the potential economic and environmental\nproblems that may occur as a result of the potential disruption of\noperation of the presently permitted commercial industrial hazardous\nwaste disposal, treatment and storage facilities located in New York;\nand\n  (3) the fact that it will take a period of several years before a\ncomprehensive program for the long-term disposal and treatment of\nhazardous waste is in operation sufficient to replace or reduce present\nmethods of hazardous waste disposal.\n  c. The proposed short-term hazardous waste management program shall\nincorporate the best short-term methods and means available to contain,\nstore and treat hazardous waste. In preparing the program, consideration\nshall be given to the short-term needs of New York state generators of\nhazardous waste, to the siting of secure landfills or other storage\nfacilities on suitable private or state-owned land, to the development\nand construction of such facilities in a manner to safely allow for the\neventual retrieval of hazardous waste for the purpose of ultimate\ndestruction, detoxification, or neutralization by industrial hazardous\nwaste treatment facilities, to the options of public versus private\nownership and operation of such facilities, to the ongoing efforts to\nestablish and maintain a statewide waste exchange system, and to the\nestablishment of incentives to encourage reduction of the amount of\nhazardous waste generated.\n  2. Not later than January first, nineteen hundred eighty-two, the\ncommissioner shall submit to the legislature the study and the proposal\nfor a short-term hazardous waste management program required pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section, including any proposed implementing\nlegislation and rules and regulations where appropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>