<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0704"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0704"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-0704"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_0704">
        <num>27-0704</num>
        <heading>Land burial and disposal in the counties of Nassau and Suffolk; special provisions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_0704__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no resource recovery facility is available to\naccept such waste; (ii) the owner of the landfill is making all\nreasonable efforts to implement a resource recovery system acceptable to\nthe commissioner; and (iii) that the landfilling of such wastes will not\nhave significant adverse environmental impacts. In granting any such\napproval, the commissioner shall impose conditions necessary to mitigate\nany adverse environmental impacts to the maximum extent practicable and\nshall impose a schedule under which the municipality shall implement an\nacceptable resource recovery system.\n  5. Within seven years of the effective date of this section, no person\nshall operate a landfill existing on the effective date of this section\nin the counties of Nassau and Suffolk unless:\n  a. The owner or operator of the landfill has posted a financial\nguarantee such as, but not limited to, pollution liability insurance,\nsureties, performance bonds and/or trust funds acceptable to the\ncommissioner securing the cost of corrective treatment, or the\ndevelopment of alternative water sources, should such landfill become a\nsource of groundwater, surface water or air pollution. The size of the\nfinancial guarantee, the financial stability of the surety, and the\nterms of posting shall be determined by the commissioner. Financial\nsurety shall also be arranged to ensure the proper operation and\nmaintenance of leachate and other collection and treatment systems for a\nperiod of time, as determined by the commissioner, after a landfill is\nclosed; and\n  b. The landfill is underlain by two or more natural and/or synthetic\nliners each with provisions for leachate collection, and has a treatment\nand disposal system, all of which are approved by the commissioner. Any\nnatural clay liners shall have a minimum compacted thickness of two feet\nand all liners shall have a maximum hydraulic conductivity not to exceed\none times ten to the minus seven centimeters per second. If the landfill\nu...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_0704__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nno resource recovery facility is available to accept such waste; (ii)\nthe owner of the landfill is making all reasonable efforts to implement\na resource recovery system acceptable to the commissioner; and (iii)\nthat the landfilling of such wastes will not have significant adverse\nenvironmental impacts. In granting any such approval, the commissioner\nshall impose conditions necessary to mitigate any adverse environmental\nimpacts to the maximum extent practicable and shall impose a schedule\nunder which the municipality shall implement an acceptable resource\nrecovery system.\n  6. Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, the\ncommissioner may allow, by permit, the disposal of clean fill material\nin the counties of Nassau and Suffolk. Such material shall not be\ncontaminated with hazardous wastes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>