<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1012"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1012"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-04-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1012"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1012/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1012/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1012/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1012/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1012">
        <num>27-1012</num>
        <heading>Deposit and disposition of refund values; registration; reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1012. Deposit and disposition of refund values; registration;\n             reports.\n  1. Each deposit initiator shall deposit in a refund value account an\namount equal to the refund value initiated under section 27-1005 of this\ntitle which is received with respect to each beverage container sold by\nsuch deposit initiator. Such deposit initiator shall hold the amounts in\nthe refund value account in trust for the state. A refund value account\nshall be an interest-bearing account established in a banking\ninstitution located in this state, the deposits in which are insured by\nan agency of the federal government. Deposits of such amounts into the\nrefund value account shall be made not less frequently than every five\nbusiness days. All interest, dividends and returns earned on the refund\nvalue account shall be paid directly into said account. The monies in\nsuch accounts shall be kept separate and apart from all other monies in\nthe possession of the deposit initiator. The commissioner of taxation\nand finance may specify a system of accounts and records to be\nmaintained with respect to accounts established under this subdivision.\n  2. Payments of refund values pursuant to section 27-1007 of this title\nshall be paid from each deposit initiator's refund value account. No\nother payment or withdrawal from such account may be made except as\nprescribed by this section.\n  3. Each deposit initiator shall file quarterly reports with the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance on a form and in the manner\nprescribed by such commissioner. The commissioner of taxation and\nfinance may require such reports to be filed electronically. The\nquarterly reports required by this subdivision shall be filed for the\nquarterly periods ending on the last day of May, August, November and\nFebruary of each year, and each such report shall be filed within twenty\ndays after the end of the quarterly period covered thereby. Each such\nreport shall include all information such commissioner shall determine\nappropriate including but not limited to the following information:\n  a. the balance in the refund value account at the beginning of the\nquarter for which the report is prepared;\n  b. all such deposits credited to the refund value account and all\ninterest, dividends or returns received on such account, during such\nquarter;\n  c. all withdrawals from the refund value account during such quarter,\nincluding all reimbursements paid pursuant to subdivision two of this\nsection, all service charges on the account, and all payments made\npursuant to subdivision four of this section; and\n  d. the balance in the refund value account at the close of such\nquarter.\n  4. a. Quarterly payments. An amount equal to eighty percent of the\nbalance outstanding in the refund value account at the close of each\nquarter shall be paid to the commissioner of taxation and finance at the\ntime the report provided for in subdivision three of this section is\nrequired to be filed. The commissioner of taxation and finance may\nrequire that the payments be made electronically. The remaining twenty\npercent of the balance outstanding at the close of each quarter shall be\nthe monies of the deposit initiator and may be withdrawn from such\naccount by the deposit initiator. If the provisions of this section with\nrespect to such account have not been fully complied with, each deposit\ninitiator shall pay to such commissioner at such time, in lieu of the\namount described in the preceding sentence, an amount equal to the\nbalance which would have been outstanding on such date had such\nprovisions been fully complied with. The commissioner of taxation and\nfinance may require that the payments be made electronically.\n  b. Refund value account shortfall. In the event a deposit initiator\npays out more in refund values than it collects in deposits of refund\nvalues during the course of a quarterly period as described in\nsubdivision three of this section, the deposit initiator may apply to\nthe commissioner of taxation and finance for a refund of the amount of\nsuch excess payment of refund values from sources other than the refund\nvalue account, in the manner as provided by the commissioner of taxation\nand finance. A deposit initiator must apply for a refund no later than\ntwelve months after the due date for filing the quarterly report for the\nquarterly period for which the refund claim is made. No interest shall\nbe payable for any refund paid pursuant to this paragraph.\n  c. Final report. A deposit initiator who ceases to do business in this\nstate as a deposit initiator shall file a final report and remit payment\nof eighty percent of all amounts remaining in the refund value account\nas of the close of the deposit initiator's last day of business. The\ncommissioner of taxation and finance may require that the payments be\nmade electronically. The deposit initiator shall indicate on the report\nthat it is a "final report". The final report is due to be filed with\npayment twenty days after the close of the quarterly period in which the\ndeposit initiator ceases to do business. In the event the deposit\ninitiator pays out more in refund values than it collects in such final\nquarterly period, the deposit initiator may apply to the commissioner of\ntaxation and finance for a refund of the amount of such excess payment\nof refund values from sources other than the refund value account, in\nthe manner as provided by the commissioner of taxation and finance.\n  5. All moneys collected or received by the department of taxation and\nfinance pursuant to this title shall be deposited to the credit of the\ncomptroller with such responsible banks, banking houses or trust\ncompanies as may be designated by the comptroller. Such deposits shall\nbe kept separate and apart from all other moneys in the possession of\nthe comptroller. The comptroller shall require adequate security from\nall such depositories. Of the total revenue collected, the comptroller\nshall retain the amount determined by the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance to be necessary for refunds out of which the comptroller must\npay any refunds to which a deposit initiator may be entitled. After\nreserving the amount to pay refunds, the comptroller must, by the tenth\nday of each month, pay into the state treasury to the credit of the\ngeneral fund the revenue deposited under this subdivision during the\npreceding calendar month and remaining to the comptroller's credit on\nthe last day of that preceding month; provided, however, that, beginning\nApril first, two thousand thirteen, nineteen million dollars, and all\nfiscal years thereafter, twenty-three million dollars plus all funds\nreceived from the payments due each fiscal year pursuant to subdivision\nfour of this section in excess of the greater of the amount received\nfrom April first, two thousand twelve through March thirty-first, two\nthousand thirteen or one hundred twenty-two million two hundred thousand\ndollars, shall be deposited to the credit of the environmental\nprotection fund established pursuant to section ninety-two-s of the\nstate finance law.\n  6. The commissioner and the commissioner of taxation and finance shall\npromulgate, and shall consult each other in promulgating, such rules and\nregulations as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this\ntitle. The commissioner and the commissioner of taxation and finance\nshall provide all necessary aid and assistance to each other, including\nthe sharing of any information that is necessary to their respective\nadministration and enforcement responsibilities pursuant to the\nprovisions of this title.\n  7. a. Any person who is a deposit initiator under this title before\nApril first, two thousand nine, must apply by June first, two thousand\nnine to the commissioner of taxation and finance for registration as a\ndeposit initiator. Any person who becomes a deposit initiator on or\nafter April first, two thousand nine shall apply for registration prior\nto collecting any deposits as such a deposit initiator. Such application\nshall be in a form prescribed by the commissioner of taxation and\nfinance and shall require such information deemed to be necessary for\nproper administration of this title. The commissioner of taxation and\nfinance may require that applications for registration must be submitted\nelectronically. The commissioner of taxation and finance shall\nelectronically issue a deposit initiator registration certificate in a\nform prescribed by the commissioner of taxation and finance within\nfifteen days of receipt of such application or may take an additional\nten days if the commissioner of taxation and finance deems it necessary\nto consult with the commissioner before issuing such registration\ncertificate. A registration certificate issued pursuant to this\nsubdivision may be issued for a specified term of not less than three\nyears and shall be subject to renewal in accordance with procedures\nspecified by the commissioner of taxation and finance. The commissioner\nof taxation and finance shall furnish to the commissioner a complete\nlist of registered deposit initiators and shall continually update such\nlist as warranted. The commissioner shall share any information with the\ncommissioner of taxation and finance that is necessary for the\nadministration of this subdivision.\n  b. The commissioner of taxation and finance shall have the authority\nto revoke or refuse to renew any registration issued pursuant to this\nsubdivision when he or she has determined or has been informed by the\ncommissioner that any of the provisions of this title or rules and\nregulations promulgated thereunder have been violated. Such violations\nshall include, but not be limited to, the failure to file quarterly\nreports, the failure to make payments pursuant to this subdivision, the\nproviding of false or fraudulent information to either the department of\ntaxati</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>