<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1507"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1507"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-09-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1507"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1507">
        <num>27-1507</num>
        <heading>Treatment and disposal of regulated medical waste</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1507. Treatment and disposal of regulated medical waste.\n  1. Treatment or disposal of regulated medical waste shall be by one of\nthe following methods:\n  a. By incineration in a regulated medical waste incineration facility\napproved and under permit pursuant to article nineteen of this chapter\nwhich provides complete combustion of the waste to carbonized or\nmineralized ash. Regulated medical waste so combusted shall be\ndisposable as nonhazardous waste provided it is not an otherwise\nhazardous waste as defined in the regulations promulgated under section\n27-0903 of this article.\n  b. By discharge to sewerage system if the waste is liquid or\nsemi-liquid except as specifically prohibited by the commissioner or the\ncommissioner of health.\n  c. By decontamination by autoclaving, or by other technique approved\nby the department of health. Regulated medical waste so treated shall be\ndisposed of as solid waste provided it is not otherwise a hazardous\nwaste as defined in section 27-0903 of this article or the regulations\npromulgated thereunder, and is accompanied by a certificate, in a form\nprescribed by the commissioner of health which evidences such treatment.\n  d. By other method approved in writing by the commissioner of health.\n  2. Regulated medical wastes shall not be disposed of by burial at a\nlandfill disposal facility, unless treated in accordance with\nsubdivision one of this section. All sharps must be rendered\nunrecognizable prior to disposal.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>