<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1303"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1303">
        <num>27-1303</num>
        <heading>Identification of sites</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1303. Identification of sites.\n  1. a. For a period of one year after the effective date of the chapter\nof the laws of two thousand three designating and amending this\nparagraph, each county shall, for the purpose of locating inactive\nhazardous waste disposal sites, as that term was defined on January\nfirst, two thousand three, survey its jurisdiction to determine the\nexistence and location of suspected inactive hazardous waste disposal\nsites and shall annually thereafter submit a report to the department\ndescribing the location of each such suspected site and the reasons for\nsuch suspicion.\n  b. Commencing one year after the effective date of this paragraph,\neach county shall, for the purpose of locating inactive hazardous waste\ndisposal sites, survey its jurisdiction to determine the existence and\nlocation of suspected inactive hazardous waste disposal sites and shall,\nafter consultation with all cities, towns, and villages within its\njurisdiction, annually thereafter submit a report to the department\ndescribing the location of each such suspected site and the reasons for\nsuch suspicion.\n  2. Each county, after consultation with all cities, towns, and\nvillages within its jurisdiction, shall review the information\nconcerning such county in the registry established pursuant to section\n27-1305 of this article and shall, on or before September first,\nnineteen hundred eighty, and annually thereafter on the first day of\nSeptember of each succeeding year, provide the department with any\ninformation which might correct or supplement the information in such\nregistry with respect to suspected inactive hazardous waste disposal\nsites within the jurisdiction of such county.\n  3. Counties shall cooperate and coordinate with local jurisdictions,\nregional organizations or state agencies to fulfill its responsibilities\nunder subdivisions one and two of this section. Nothing contained within\nthis section shall reduce the powers or responsibilities of any county,\nother local jurisdiction, regional organization or state agency to\nidentify, investigate, assess or monitor any inactive hazardous waste\ndisposal site.\n  4. For purposes of this section, "county" shall include each city\nincorporating within its boundary one or more counties but shall not\ninclude those counties incorporated within a city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>