<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1305"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1305">
        <num>27-1305</num>
        <heading>Reports by the department; registry of sites</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a general description of the site, which shall include the name,\nif any, of the site, the address of the site, the type and quantity of\nthe hazardous waste disposed of at the site and the name of the current\nowners of the site;\n  (ii) an assessment by the department of any significant environmental\nproblems at and near the site;\n  (iii) an assessment prepared by the department of health of any\nserious health problems in the immediate vicinity of the site and any\nhealth problems deemed by the department of health to be related to\nconditions at the site;\n  (iv) the status of any testing, monitoring or remedial actions in\nprogress or recommended by the department;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the status of any pending legal actions and any federal, state or\nlocal government permits or approvals concerning the site; and\n  (vi) an assessment of the relative priority of the need for action at\neach site to remedy environmental and health problems resulting from the\npresence of wastes at such site;\n  b. Address and site boundaries including tax map parcel numbers or\nsection, block and lot numbers, and if the site is located within a\ndisadvantaged community;\n  c. Time period of use for disposal of hazardous waste;\n  d. Name of the current owner and operator and names of any past and\nreported owners and operators during the time period of use for disposal\nof hazardous waste;\n  e. Names of persons responsible for the generation and transportation\nof hazardous waste disposed of;\n  f. Type and quantity of hazardous waste disposed of;\n  g. Manner of disposal of hazardous waste;\n  h. Nature of soils at the site;\n  i. Depth of water table at the site;\n  j. Location, nature and size of aquifers at the site;\n  k. Direction of present and historic groundwater flows at the site;\n  l. Location, nature and size of all surface waters at and near the\nsite;\n  m. Levels of contaminants, if any, in groundwater, surface water, air\nand soils at and near the site resulting from hazardous wastes disposed\nof at the site or from any other cause and areas known to be directly\naffected or contaminated by wastes from the site;\n  n. As determined by the department of health, current quality of all\ndrinking water drawn from or distributed through the area in which the\nsite is located when the department of health determines that water\nquality may have been affected by the site in question and any known\nchange in the quality of such drinking water over time;\n  o. Proximity of the site to private residences, public buildings or\nproperty, school, daycare, medical, or senior care facilities, places of\nwork or other areas where individuals may be present, or lo...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_v__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Assessment and classification. The department shall, as part of\nthe registry, assess and, based upon new information received, reassess\nby March thirty-first of each year, in cooperation with the department\nof health, the relative need for action at each site to remedy\nenvironmental and health problems resulting from the presence of\nhazardous wastes at such sites including in such assessment whether\nsites shall be prioritized under subdivision five of this section due to\nsite location in an area identified as a disadvantaged community;\nprovided, however, that if at the time of such assessment or\nreassessment, the department has not placed a site in classification 1\nor 2, as described in clauses</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of this subparagraph, and\nsuch site is the subject of negotiations for, or implementation of, a\nbrownfield site cleanup agreement pursuant to title fourteen of this\narticle, obligating the person subject to such agreement to, at a\nminimum, eliminate or mitigate all significant threats to the public\nhealth and environment posed by the hazardous waste pursuant to such\nagreement, the department shall defer its assessment or reassessment\nduring the period such person is engaged in good faith negotiations to\nenter into such an agreement and, following its execution, is in\ncompliance with the terms of such agreement, and shall assess or\nreassess such site upon completion of remediation to the department's\nsatisfaction. In making its assessments, the department shall place\nevery site in one of the following classifications:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Causing or presenting an imminent danger of causing irreversible\nor irreparable damage to the public health or environment--immediate\naction required;\n  (ii) Significant threat to the public health or environment--action\nrequired;\n  (iii) Does not present a significant threat to the public health or\nenvironment--action may be deferred;\n  (iv) Site properly closed--requires continued management;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Site properly closed, no evidence of present or potential adverse\nimpact--no further action required.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_v__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Prioritization. The department shall, in accordance with\nsubdivision five of this section, prioritize remedial programs at sites\nplaced in classification 1 or 2, as described in clauses</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of\nsubparagraph one of this paragraph, that are located in disadvantaged\ncommunities, consistent with the protection of public health and the\nenvironment.\n  c.</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any owner or operator of a site listed pursuant to this section\nmay petition the commissioner for deletion of such site, modification of\nthe site classification, or modification of any information regarding\nsuch site by submitting a written statement in such form as the\ncommissioner may require setting forth the grounds of the petition.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within ninety days after the submittal of such petition, the\ncommissioner may convene an administrative hearing to determine whether\na particular site should be deleted from the registry, receive a\nmodified site classification or whether any information regarding the\nsite should be modified. In any such hearing the burden of proof shall\nbe on the petitioner. No less than thirty days prior to the hearing the\ncommissioner shall cause a notice of hearing to be published in the next\navailable environmental notice bulletin, on the department's website,\nand in a newspaper of general circulation in the county in which the\nsite is located. The commissioner shall also notify in writing any owner\nor operator of the site, as well as the owners of record of adjacent\nproperties, no less than thirty days prior to the hearing. The cost of\nany such hearing, including the cost of any public notification, shall\nbe at the petitioner's expense.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>No later than thirty days following receipt of the complete record\nas that term is defined in the state administrative procedure act, or\nfollowing the decision not to hold a hearing the commissioner shall\nprovide the owner or operator with a written determination accompanied\nby reason therefor regarding the deletion of such site, modification of\nthe site classification or modification of any information regarding\nsuch site. Any final decision rendered by the commissioner shall be\nreviewable under article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and\nrules.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commissioner may not delete any site from the registry without\nproviding public notice no less than sixty days prior to the proposed\ndeletion. Such notice of deletion shall be published in the next\navailable environmental notice bulletin, on the department's website,\nand in a newspaper of general circulation in the county in which the\nsite is located. The commissioner shall also notify in writing any owner\nor operator of the site, if applicable, no less than sixty days prior to\nthe proposed deletion. The commissioner shall provide a thirty-day\nperiod for submission of written comments and an opportunity for\nsubmission of oral comments at a public meeting at or near the site. The\ncommissioner shall summarize any comments received and make the summary\navailable to the public on the department's website. The commissioner\nmay convene an administrative hearing to determine whether a particular\nsite should be deleted from the registry, receive a modified site\nclassification...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department shall notify, as soon as possible and within\navailable resources all public repositories of the registry, including\nupdating its website, of any modifications or deletions to such\nregistry. The department shall also note any such deletions or\nmodifications in the next annual report and publication of the registry.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The department shall, within ten days of any determination notify\nthe local governments of jurisdiction whenever a change is made in the\nregistry pursuant to this subdivision.\n  d.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Within seven months after the effective date of this\nsubdivision the department shall notify by certified mail the owner of\nall or any part of each site or area included in the registry, of the\ninclusion of the site or area by mailing notice to such owner at the\nowner's last known address. Thereafter, fifteen days before any site or\narea is added to the registry, the department shall notify in writing by\ncertified mail the owner of all or any part of such site or area of the\ninclusion of such site or area by mailing notice to each such owner at\nthe owner's last known address.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notice pursuant to paragraph a of this subdivision shall include\nbut not be limited to a description of the duties and restrictions\nimposed by section 27-1317 of this title and by section one thousand\nthree hundred eighty-nine-d of the public health law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Non-receipt of any notice mailed to an owner pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall in no way affect the responsibilities, duties or\nliabilities imposed on any person by this title or title XII-A of\narticle thirteen of the public health law.\n  e. The department shall, in consultation with the department of\nhealth, evaluate existing site evaluation systems and shall develop a\nsystem to select and prioritize sites for remedial action. Such system\nshall incorporate environmental, natural resource and public health\nconcerns, and a site's location within a disadvantaged community.\n  f. The department shall develop a site status reporting system and\nutilize such system to ensure that the registry required by subdivision\none of this section provides a complete and up-to-date listing of all\nsites in each region.\n  3. The department shall, as soon as possible but in no event later\nthan January first, nineteen hundred eighty-four, and annually\nthereafter prepare and submit in writing ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>monies expended or encumbered for the purpose of conducting site\ninvestigations;\n  (ii) monies expended or encumbered for the purpose of conducting\nremedial investigations and feasibility studies;\n  (iii) monies expended or encumbered for the purpose of conducting\nremedial design studies;\n  (iv) monies expended or encumbered for the purpose of conducting\nremedial construction activities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>monies expended or encumbered for operation, maintenance, and\nmonitoring activities;\n  (vi) monies expended or encumbered for interim remedial measures;\n  (vii) monies expended or encumbered for oversight activities,\nincluding personnel and contractor costs, at inactive hazardous waste\ndisposal sites;\n  (viii) monies expended or encumbered in stand-by contracts entered\ninto pursuant to section 3-0309 of this chapter and the purposes for\nwhich these stand-by contracts were entered into;\n  (ix) an accounting of payments received and payments obligated to be\nreceived pursuant to this title, and a report of the department's\nattempts to secure such obligations; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1305__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an accounting of all response costs recovered statewide and\nnatural resource damages recovered at each site, including through\nsettlement or agreement, commissioner order, judicial determination and\naward, a required instrument of financial responsibility, or an\nenvironmental lien.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>