<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1509"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1509"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1509"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1509/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1509/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1509">
        <num>27-1509</num>
        <heading>Transfer of regulated medical waste to off-site treatment and disposal facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1509. Transfer of regulated medical waste to off-site treatment and\n             disposal facilities.\n  1. No person shall transport regulated medical waste unless permitted\nas a regulated medical waste transporter by the department.\n  2. Vehicles transporting more than fifty pounds of regulated medical\nwaste shall be identified on each side and the back of the vehicle with\nthe name or trademark of the transporter and with conspicuously\ndisplayed signs or decals with the word "infectious" or the words\n"regulated medical waste".\n  a. Regulated medical waste shall be transported to an off-site\ntreatment or disposal facility in a leakproof, fully enclosed container\nor vehicle compartment.\n  b. Regulated medical waste shall not be transported in the same\nvehicle with other waste unless the regulated medical waste is\nseparately contained in rigid reusable containers or kept separate by\nbarriers from other waste, or unless all of the waste is to be treated\nor disposed of as regulated medical waste in accordance with the\nrequirements of this title.\n  c. Regulated medical waste shall be delivered for treatment or\ndisposal only to a facility to which delivery of such waste is\nauthorized pursuant to this article.\n  d. Persons manually loading or unloading containers of regulated\nmedical waste on or from transport vehicles shall be provided by their\nemployer with, and shall be required to wear, protective gloves and\nother protective clothing as may be required by the department.\n  e. Surfaces of transport vehicles that have contacted spilled or\nleaked regulated medical waste shall be decontaminated by procedures\napproved by the commissioner of health.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>