<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1437"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1437"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-07-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1437"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1437/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1437/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1437/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1437/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1437">
        <num>27-1437</num>
        <heading>BCP-EZ program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1437__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at the time of the application, the department has determined that\nthe brownfield site does not pose a significant threat pursuant to\nsection 27-1411 of this title;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1437__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant has waived in writing any claim for tax credits\npursuant to section twenty-one of the tax law on a form prescribed by\nthe department; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1437__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the activity is conducted in a manner which satisfies all\nrequirements applicable to like activity conducted pursuant to sections\n27-1415 and 27-1417 of this title, except as provided in subdivision two\nof this section and the time periods specified in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1437__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1437__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof subdivision three of section 27-1417 of this title.\n  2. For any site accepted into the BCP-EZ program pursuant to this\nsection with a remedial work plan identifying a Track 4 remediation, if\na contaminant is identified in soil in excess of the remedial action\nobjectives contained in an applicable generic table developed pursuant\nto subdivision six of section 27-1415 of this title, the applicant may\nuse site-specific data to demonstrate to the department that the\nconcentration of the contaminant in the soils reflects background\nconditions and, in that case, a contaminant-specific action objective\nfor such contaminant equal to such background concentration may be\nestablished provided that such objective is protective of the public\nhealth and the environment and is determined in a manner acceptable to\nthe department.\n  3. Upon the department's acceptance of the certification by the\napplicant that the remediation requirements of this title, pursuant to\nsection 27-1419 of this title, have been achieved for the brownfield\nsite and an environmental easement, if necessary, has been created and\nfiled pursuant to title thirty-six of article seventy-one of this\nchapter, a site in the BCP-EZ program shall be eligible to receive a\ncertificate of completion in accordance with section 27-1419 of this\ntitle; provided, however, that such certificate of completion shall not\nentitle the holder to any tax credits provided by section twenty-one of\nthe tax law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>