<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0105"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0105"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29-0105"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_0105">
        <num>29-0105</num>
        <heading>Certification of site and disposal method selection</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 29-0105. Certification of site and disposal method selection.\n  1. Upon application by the commission, the department shall certify\nthat the commission's selection of the site or sites and disposal method\nor methods pursuant to section 29-0305 of this article is in conformance\nwith the applicable siting criteria promulgated pursuant to section\n29-0103 of this title; shall certify that, with modifications proposed\nby the department, the selection would be in conformance with the\napplicable siting criteria; or shall refuse to certify such selection\nand shall specify the manner in which such selection fails to meet the\napplicable siting criteria. Such certification or refusal to certify\nshall be based upon the record. The department shall hold public\nhearings with respect to the draft environmental impact statement and\nwith respect to the application for certification. Such hearings and\nsuch certification or refusal to certify shall be completed within one\nhundred eighty days of the commission's submission of a complete\napplication for certification.\n  2. The department shall publish in the state register notice of its\ndecision on the application for certification of the site and disposal\nmethod selection.\n  3. The department's decision on the application for certification of\nthe site and disposal method selection and the accompanying final\nenvironmental impact statement shall be submitted by the department to\nthe governor, the legislature, and the chairman of the New York state\nenergy research and development authority. In addition to any other\ninformation otherwise required for a final environmental impact\nstatement, such statement shall include:\n  a. copies of the minutes of the public hearing held on the draft\nenvironmental impact statement on siting and disposal method selection\nand of recommendations from the advisory committee established pursuant\nto section 29-0501 of this article, and the department's responses to\nthe views, comments, information, and recommendations therein; and\n  b. a listing providing a brief description, identification, or\nreference for each report, study, or other document relied upon by the\ndepartment for information supporting its analyses or conclusions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>