<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0703"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0703"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29-0703"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_0703">
        <num>29-0703</num>
        <heading>Closure and post-closure plans</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 29-0703. Closure and post-closure plans.\n  1. Any permits for such facilities for the management of low-level\nradioactive waste issued by the department shall require owners and\noperators of facilities for the permanent disposal of low-level\nradioactive waste to submit to the department for its approval plans for\nthe closure and post-closure monitoring and maintenance of their\nfacilities. The department may promulgate rules and regulations\nconcerning the contents of such plans. Such plans shall be approved\nprior to the effective date of the facilities' operating permit.\n  2. Together with the submission of a plan for closure and post-closure\nmonitoring and maintenance, the owner or operator of such facilities for\nthe permanent disposal of low-level radioactive waste shall submit to\nthe department for approval a written estimate of the costs associated\nwith closure at the estimated point in the facilities' operating life\nwhen the extent and manner of their operation would make closure the\nmost expensive, as indicated by the closure plan.\n  3. The owner or operator shall prepare new closure and post-closure\nmonitoring and maintenance cost estimates whenever a change in the\nclosure and post-closure monitoring and maintenance requirements affects\nthe cost of the closure or post-closure care.\n  4. One year after the approval of the cost estimates as set forth in\nsubdivision two of this section, and annually thereafter until closure\nof the facilities, the operator's closure and post-closure monitoring\nand maintenance estimates shall be adjusted to account for inflation.\n  5. All estimates made pursuant to this section and revision thereto\nshall be subject to the review and approval of the department.\n  6. The methods and instruments of financial assurances for permitted\nfacilities for permanent disposal of low-level radioactive waste shall\nbe periodically reviewed by the department to determine whether they are\nadequate in light of changed circumstances to insure proper closure and\npost-closure monitoring and maintenance of such facilities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>