<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0117"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0117"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-0117"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0117/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0117/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0117/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0117/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_0117">
        <num>3-0117</num>
        <heading>Activities of local governmental agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 3-0117. Activities of local governmental agencies.\n  1. Activities of local health boards, departments and officers and\nother local government agencies pertaining to functions, powers and\nduties which were transferred pursuant to chapter 140 of the Laws of\n1970, from the Department and Commissioner of Health to the Department\nand Commissioner of Environmental Conservation shall be eligible for aid\nunder the provisions of titles 1, 2, and 3 of article 6 of the Public\nHealth Law to the same extent such activities were eligible for such aid\nif conducted immediately prior to the effective date of chapter 140 of\nthe Laws of 1970. The Commissioner of Environmental Conservation shall\nexercise the same powers of approval and supervision with respect to\nsuch activities as were exercised by the Commissioner of Health\nimmediately prior to the effective date of that chapter.\n  2. Counties and cities shall be eligible for aid for other\nenvironmental conservation activities pertaining to functions, powers\nand duties other than those which were so transferred pursuant to\nchapter 140 of the Laws of 1970. Such other activities shall be\ndescribed under rules and regulations adopted pursuant to subdivision\nfour of this section.\n  3. A county or city shall be eligible for aid whenever it shall\nappropriate or otherwise make funds available and expend monies for the\npurpose of defraying expenses incurred in undertaking environmental\nconservation activities under this section. The appropriations made or\nto be made by the legislature for the purpose of carrying out the\nprovisions of this section shall be apportioned and made available by\nthe director of the budget to the Commissioner of Environmental\nConservation. The rate of aid shall be set annually by the Commissioner\nof Environmental Conservation, provided however, that except as\notherwise provided in the public health law, the rate shall not exceed\nfifty percentum of the amount expended annually by a county or city. In\nthe event that the amount appropriated by the legislature is\ninsufficient to make full payment of all state aid to which eligible\ncounties and cities would otherwise be entitled under this section, the\namounts appropriated shall be apportioned in proportion to the amounts\nto which such counties and cities would otherwise be entitled.\n  4. The Department of Environmental Conservation shall adopt rules and\nregulations to implement the provisions of this section, which shall\ninclude, but not be limited to the establishment of the following:\ninformation and reporting requirements; activity, facility,\nconstruction, equipment, service, administration and work eligibility\nrequirements and standards; department inspection, examination and\napproval procedures; qualifications for persons engaged in environmental\nconservation activities; and minimum criteria for the composition of\ncounty and city government bodies that may be authorized to engage in\nactivities for which aid may be sought.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>