<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0315"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0315"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-04-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-0315"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_0315">
        <num>3-0315</num>
        <heading>Geographic information system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 3-0315. Geographic information system.\n  1. The department in conjunction with the commissioner of health shall\ncreate and maintain a geographic information system, and associated data\nstorage and analytical systems for purposes of collecting, streamlining,\nand visualizing integrated data, permits, and relevant sites about\ndrinking water quality including, but not limited to, incorporating\nsupply well and monitoring well data, emerging contaminant data, water\nquality monitoring data, pertinent data from remediation and landfill\nsites, permitted discharge locations and other potential contamination\nrisks to water supplies. Such system shall also incorporate information\nfrom the source water assessment program collected by the department of\nhealth, data from annual water supply statements prepared pursuant to\nsection eleven hundred fifty-one of the public health law, information\nfrom the database pursuant to title fourteen of article twenty-seven of\nthis chapter, and any other existing data regarding soil and groundwater\ncontamination currently gathered by the department, as well as data on\ncontamination that is readily available from the United States\ngeological survey and other sources determined appropriate by the\ndepartment. In addition to facilitating interagency coordination and\npredictive analysis to protect water quality, such system shall provide\nstate agency information to the public through a website, within\nreasonable limitations to ensure confidentiality and security.\n  2. The department shall make reasonable efforts to include additional\ndata, including data from well logs currently required to be filed with\nthe department pursuant to section 15-1525 of this chapter.\n  3. Parties required to submit data pursuant to any reporting\nrequirements set forth in this section shall, upon request of the\ndepartment, submit such data in an electronic format acceptable to the\ndepartment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>