<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-0304"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_0304">
        <num>3-0304</num>
        <heading>The department shall compile and maintain an inventory of educational resources for teaching the principles of environmental conservation...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 3-0304. The department shall compile and maintain an inventory of\n            educational resources for teaching the principles of\n            environmental conservation in New York state.\n  Inventory of educational resources for teaching the principles of\nenvironmental conservation in New York state. l. Legislative findings.\nThe people of the state of New York, through the temporary state\ncommission on youth education in environmental conservation, have\nexpressed the need for resource information assistance if they are to\nimprove their local programs in environmental education.\n  The legislature hereby affirms this need and declares that a\nregionally responsive system for identifying resources through a\nstatewide inventory and for referring inquiries to appropriate sources\nmust be developed if we are to maintain and improve the quality of our\nenvironment.\n  The department, in consultation with the department of education and\nthe office of parks, recreation and historic preservation shall compile\nand maintain an inventory of education resources for teaching the\nprinciples of environmental conservation in New York state.\n  2. This information shall be used as the basis for a clearing house\nfor materials pertaining to environmental conservation education which\nshall be available for public use. A revised and up-to-date inventory\nshall be available to the public and widely distributed on or before\nSeptember 1, 1991. The clearinghouse shall maintain information on, but\nnot limited to, the following:\n  a. Natural resources and facilities which can be used for educational\npurposes.\n  b. Conservation and environmental organizations, both public and\nprivate.\n  c. Resource personnel.\n  d. Curriculum resources.\n  e. A calendar of environmental education activities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>