<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0313"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0313"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-0313"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0313/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0313/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0313/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0313/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_0313">
        <num>3-0313</num>
        <heading>Adopt-a-beach stewardship program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 3-0313. Adopt-a-beach stewardship program.\n  1. The commissioner may enter into stewardship agreements with any\nperson or persons for the purposes of preserving, maintaining, or\nenhancing a state-owned beach, shoreline area or portion thereof in\naccordance with the policies of this chapter.\n  2. The stewardship agreement shall provide that the beach or shoreline\narea be preserved and maintained in its natural state or managed to\nenhance or restore the natural values it provides, consistent with the\nprovisions of this chapter. Activities may include: remediating\nvandalism and storm damage, picking up litter and trash, establishing or\nmaintaining access or nature trails, providing interpretive services for\nschool groups and other citizens, and otherwise providing positive\nbenefits to the beach or shoreline area.\n  3. Stewardship agreement with any person or persons may provide for\nassistance of personnel, facilities and supplies of the department for\nthe purposes of supporting appropriate activities under such stewardship\nagreement, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.\n  4. The department shall establish procedures by which a person or\npersons may apply for a stewardship agreement, and shall be responsible\nfor working with such persons to identify specific sections of a\nstate-owned beach or shoreline area and specific activities deemed\nappropriate for such stewardship agreement. The department may consider\nfactors such as safety, environmental sensitivity, need, cost and other\nfactors deemed relevant in determining which beach or shoreline areas or\nactivities may be eligible or appropriate for a stewardship agreement.\n  5. The department shall provide recognition of the stewardship\nactivities by appropriate signage on or near the adopted beach or\nshoreline area, and may provide recognition by such other measures as it\nmay determine to be appropriate, including but not limited to press\nreleases, certificates, and newsletters.\n  6. The stewardship agreement may be modified in scope or altered in\nany other manner at the sole discretion of the department, not\ninconsistent with the provisions of this section. The person or persons\nshall have the option of renewing the agreement subject to the approval\nof the department and the continuation by the department of the\nadopt-a-beach stewardship program. The department may immediately remove\nthe signs and it may terminate the agreement upon thirty days notice, if\nin its sole judgment it finds and determines that the person or persons\nare not meeting the terms and conditions of the agreement.\n  7. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, the state and\nits employees shall not be liable for damages suffered by any person\nresulting from the actions or activities of such volunteers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>