<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0921"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0921"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="33-0921"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0921/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0921/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0921/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0921/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_0921">
        <num>33-0921</num>
        <heading>Aquatic antifouling paint applicator certification</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 33-0921. Aquatic antifouling paint applicator certification.\n  1. Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation pursuant\nto this title, a person who is certified by the commissioner as an\naquatic antifouling paint applicator may engage in the commercial\napplication of aquatic antifouling paint.\n  2. Application for aquatic antifouling paint applicator certification\nshall be made to the commissioner. The application shall be on a form\nprescribed by the commissioner and shall be accompanied by the fee or\nfees provided in section 33-0911 of this article.\n  3. An applicant for aquatic antifouling paint applicator certification\nshall successfully complete a comprehensive twenty-hour training course\napproved by the department including eight hours of category-specific\ntraining which includes topics related to the safe and proper use,\nhandling, storage and disposal of aquatic antifouling paints and/or\nsatisfy the commissioner as to the applicant's knowledge and experience\nconcerning the proper use and application of aquatic antifouling paint\nand application equipment through examination prior to initial\ncertification. The commissioner may consider appropriate experience of\nthe applicant as specified in regulations when determining eligibility\nfor examination.\n  4. Aquatic antifouling paint applicator certification shall be valid\nfor three years after which every applicator shall recertify.\nRecertification shall require no more than five hours of course work by\ntraining, workbook, or examination as required by the commissioner.\n  5. No certification shall be valid unless the certified person also\nholds a valid identification card issued by the commissioner.\nCertification identification cards shall be valid for three years.\n  6. Certified aquatic antifouling paint applicators shall maintain such\nrecords and shall furnish such reports concerning the application of\naquatic antifouling paints as the commissioner shall require. All\nrecords required to be kept under this section shall be available for\ninspection by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>