<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="34-0106"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_0106">
        <num>34-0106</num>
        <heading>County regulation of coastal erosion hazard areas</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_34_0106__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If approval of a city (other than a city which wholly includes\none or more counties), town or village erosion hazard area ordinance or\nlocal law is revoked by the commissioner pursuant to subdivision four of\nsection 34-0105 of this article, the commissioner may designate the\ncounty in which such city, town or village is located to administer and\nenforce such city, town or village ordinance or local law so as to\ninsure compliance of activities or development in the affected erosion\nhazard area with the minimum standards promulgated pursuant to section\n34-0108 of this article. Such county shall be deemed to possess all\nadministrative and enforcement powers included in such city, town or\nvillage ordinance or local law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_34_0106__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner shall reinstate approval of the city, town or\nvillage ordinance or local law when the commissioner is satisfied that\nthe city, town or village will carry out the purposes and policies of\nthis article, at which time administration and enforcement by the county\npursuant to this subdivision shall cease, and the city, town or village\nshall administer and enforce such ordinance or local law.\n  8. The commissioner shall revoke his approval of a county erosion\nhazard area local law, or shall revoke his designation pursuant to\nsubdivision six of this section of a county to administer and enforce a\ncity, town or village ordinance or local law, if he determines, after\nnotice and hearing relative thereto, that the affected county has failed\nto administer or enforce such ordinance or local law to adequately carry\nout the purposes and policies of this article. In the event of such\nrevocation, the provisions of subdivision three of section 34-0107 of\nthis article shall apply.\n  9. Where an application is made for any permit, variance or other form\nof approval required pursuant to any local law enacted and approved by\nthe commissioner pursuant to this section, for any activity or\ndevelopment within a designated erosion hazard area, the county to which\nsuch application is made shall ascertain what, if any, other permit,\nvariance or hearing procedures or applications are required with regard\nto such activity or development by any governing body of the state or\nits subdivisions pursuant to any federal, state or local law or\nordinance. Such county, at the request of the applicant, shall\nconsolidate and coordinate said application, permit, variance and\nhearing procedures, as required by each such governing authority, into a\nsingle, comprehensive hearing and review procedure with regard to such\nactivity or development. However, nothing contained in this section\nshall be deemed to limit or restrict the state, its subdivisions, or any\nother go...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>