<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-36-0111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-36-0111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="36-0111"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-36-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-36-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-36-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-36-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_36_0111">
        <num>36-0111</num>
        <heading>Flood hazard evaluation of state facilities, lands and programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 36-0111. Flood hazard evaluation of state facilities, lands and\n             programs.\n  1. State agencies shall take affirmative action to minimize flood\nhazards and losses in connection with state-owned and state-financed\nbuildings, roads and other facilities, the disposition of state land and\nproperties, the administration of state and state-assisted planning\nprograms, and the preparation and administration of state building,\nsanitary and other pertinent codes. Such action shall include, but not\nbe limited to, requirements for the evaluation and reduction of flood\nhazards in the siting, planning, construction and maintenance of such\nfacilities and the administration of such programs; needed and\neconomically feasible flood-proofing and other protective measures of\nexisting state facilities; and appropriate flood hazard restrictions\nbinding upon purchasers and persons acquiring state lands and\nproperties, or interests therein, and their successors.\n  2. The commissioner shall assist state agencies in determining and\nevaluating flood hazards and alternative protective measures, and shall\npromulgate regulations, in consultation with the director of the budget,\nto govern the review by the commissioner of potential flood hazards at\nproposed construction sites of state, and state-financed facilities.\nSuch regulations shall ensure that reviews thereunder shall be\ncoordinated with those of appropriate environmental impact statements,\nproject notification and review systems, and state capital construction\nfunding requests.\n  3. The department, pursuant to designation by the governor, shall act\nas the state coordinating agency for the national flood insurance\nprogram in order to assist in its review of state agency activities and\nto serve as a resource for local governments.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>