<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-38-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-38-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="38-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-38-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-38-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-38-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-38-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_38_0103">
        <num>38-0103</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 38-0103. Definitions.\n  The following terms, whenever used or referred to in this article,\nshall have the following meaning unless a different meaning clearly\nappears from the context:\n  1. "Chlorofluorocarbon compounds" shall mean one or more of the\nfollowing substances used alone or in combination with other compounds:\nCFC-11, CFC-12, CFC-113, CFC-114, or CFC-115.\n  2. "Ozone" means an allotropic, triatomic form of oxygen, chemically\ndescribed as O3.\n  3. "Halon compounds" shall mean one or more of the following\nsubstances: halon-1211, halon-1301 and halon-2402.\n  4. "Person" shall mean any person, business enterprise or state\nauthority, locality or municipality.\n  5. "Motor vehicle" shall mean motor vehicle as defined by section one\nhundred twenty-five and omnibus as defined by section one hundred\ntwenty-six of the vehicle and traffic law.\n  6. "Motor vehicle air conditioner" means mechanical vapor compression\nrefrigeration equipment used to cool the drivers or passenger\ncompartment of any motor vehicle.\n  7. "Approved motor vehicle refrigerant recapturing equipment" means\nequipment that is certified by Underwriters Laboratories (or another\nindependent standards testing organization acceptable to the department)\nto meet the Underwriters Laboratories standard applicable to equipment\nfor the removal and storage of used CFC refrigerants from motor vehicle\nair conditioners (Underwriters Laboratories standards 1963, October 2,\n1989) unless such standard is modified by the commissioner through\nregulation. Equipment purchased before the date of such certification\nshall be considered approved if the manufacturer provides proof that the\nmodel is functionally identical to a model which is certified pursuant\nto this section.\n  8. "Approved motor vehicle refrigerant recycling equipment" means\nequipment that is certified by Underwriters Laboratories (or another\nindependent standards testing organization acceptable to the department)\nto meet the society of automotive engineers standard applicable to\nequipment for the extraction and reclamation of refrigerant from motor\nvehicle air conditioners (SAE standard J-1990, October, 1989), unless\nsuch standard is modified by the commissioner through regulation.\nEquipment purchased before the date of such certification shall be\nconsidered approved if the manufacturer provides proof that the model is\nfunctionally identical to the model which is certified pursuant to this\nsection.\n  9. "Properly using" approved motor vehicle refrigerant recycling\nequipment means using such equipment in conformity with the Society of\nAutomotive Engineers standard establishing the recommended service\nprocedure for containment of CFC-12 refrigerant (SAE standard J-1989 or\nrevisions thereof).\n  10. "Recycle" means to decontaminate, reclaim, or reprocess CFC\nrefrigerants captured from a motor vehicle air conditioner or\nrefrigeration system for reuse, or to destroy such compounds by methods\napproved by either the United States Environmental Protection Agency or\nthe commissioner.\n  11. "Refrigeration system" shall mean and shall be limited to:\nrefrigerators used in retail stores, cold storage warehouse\nrefrigeration systems, and air conditioning systems in large buildings,\nincluding but not limited to, those systems commonly referred to as\nchillers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>