<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0125"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0125"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-01-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="43-0125"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_0125">
        <num>43-0125</num>
        <heading>Regulatory and user fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_43_0125__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Dock, wharf and mooring fees. The owner of a dock, wharf or\nmooring within the park used for non-commercial residential purposes\nshall pay an annual fee of fifty dollars. The owner of a dock or wharf\nwithin the park used for commercial purposes shall pay an annual fee of\nfive dollars per linear foot for each such dock. The owner of a mooring\nused for commercial purposes shall pay an annual fee of one hundred\ndollars for each mooring. New docks constructed for commercial use after\nthe effective date of this section shall pay a first time fee of ten\ndollars per linear foot and five dollars per linear foot annually\nthereafter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_43_0125__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Boat fees. In addition to the registration required by the state,\nany mechanically propelled boat or vessel with ten horsepower or more\nused on Lake George shall have an annual permit issued by the\ncommission. The fee therefor for boats twenty feet or less in length\noverall shall be forty dollars; for boats twenty-one to twenty-five feet\nin length overall, fifty dollars; and for boats over twenty-five feet in\nlength overall, fifty dollars plus seven dollars and fifty cents for\neach foot by which the length overall exceeds twenty-five feet; for\nboats over twenty-five feet in length overall outfitted for overnight\nuse, fifty dollars plus thirty dollars for each foot by which the\noverall length exceeds twenty-five feet. The commission may establish a\none week use permit for twenty dollars. The commission may establish a\none day use permit for twelve dollars for any mechanically propelled\nboat or vessel with ten horsepower or more.\n  3. The commission may charge a fee to an applicant for a permit in\norder to recover the costs incurred in reviewing and acting upon an\napplication for such permit.\n  4. Except as otherwise provided by law, all fees collected pursuant to\nthis section shall be deposited to the credit of the Lake George park\ntrust fund pursuant to section ninety-seven-h of the state finance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>