<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="49-0209"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49_0209">
        <num>49-0209</num>
        <heading>Regional advisory committees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_49_0209__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the priority ranking of properties for the region;\n  (ii) the degree to which an acquisition will help to meet a regional\nor statewide need;\n  (iii) the future costs and benefits which may be associated with the\nproject;\n  (iv) the economic impact on adjacent parcels, the community or region\nand the local governments therein; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_49_0209__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the ecological value of the project taking into account the type,\nvariety and relative scarcity of the resources therein.\n  e. advise the commissioners and the state land acquisition advisory\ncouncil annually with respect to plans and priorities for their\nrespective region, and communicate at such other times as may be needed\nto fulfill its responsibilities.\n  f. review the state land acquisition plan prepared by the department\nand office pursuant to section 49-0207 of this title at least biennially\nand make recommendations regarding such plan as it affects the region.\n  g. review any community preservation project plans developed pursuant\nto section six-s of the general municipal law.\n  3. Regional advisory committee members shall be knowledgeable of, and\nconcerned with, the land preservation, conservation, historic, cultural,\nrecreation and acquisition goals of this chapter. No employee of the\ndepartment or office shall serve on a regional committee. At any time\nthat a member of a regional committee has or may have a direct or\nindirect financial interest in or resulting from the acquisition or\ndecision not to acquire an interest in land pursuant to this title, such\nmember shall not participate in any discussion or deliberation of the\ncommittee concerning such acquisition.\n  4. A regional advisory committee shall consist of at least thirteen,\nand not more than twenty-three members. Each county outside the city of\nNew York or the city of New York in the case of a county contained\nwithin the city of New York shall appoint members to its region's\nadvisory committee in a manner designed to provide equal representation\nfor all counties within a region on such committee, provided that the\ntotal number of local government appointees to a regional advisory\ncommittee shall not exceed one-half of the committee's membership. The\ncommissioners shall appoint to each regional advisory committee\nadditional members equal to one more than the total numb...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>