<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0501"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0501"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="49-0501"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49_0501">
        <num>49-0501</num>
        <heading>Designation of geoparks and other sites</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 49-0501. Designation of geoparks and other sites.\n  1. For the purposes of this title, a "geopark" is an area or territory\nof the state encompassing one or more sites of scientific importance,\nfor not only geological reasons but also by virtue of their\narchaeological, ecological and cultural value.\n  2. The commissioner shall study and may designate areas, territories\nand sites within the state which constitute geoparks and other sites\nwhich have geological significance. Such geoparks and sites may include,\nbut not be limited to:\n  a. Cayuga heights, along state route thirty-four in the county of\nTompkins;\n  b. Cascadilla creek, along University avenue in the city of Ithaca,\ncounty of Tompkins;\n  c. Ithaca Falls park Fall creek, along Lincoln street in the city of\nIthaca, county of Tompkins;\n  d. Taughannock Falls state park, in the county of Tompkins;\n  e. Niagara river gorge and Power Plant Haul road, in the county of\nNiagara;\n  f. Whirlpool state park, in the county of Niagara;\n  g. the mouth of Eighteen Mile creek at Lake Erie, in the county of\nErie;\n  h. Buffalo creek at Bullisi road, in the county of Erie;\n  i. Fall brook along state route sixty-three, in the town of Geneseo,\ncounty of Livingston;\n  j. LeRoy quarry, in the town of LeRoy, county of Genesee;\n  k. the Potsdam sandstone at Ausable chasm, in the county of Clinton;\n  l. Ausable falls, in the county of Clinton;\n  m. Whiteface mountain, in the county of Essex;\n  n. the Chattermarks on Bear mountain, in the county of Rockland;\n  o. the erratic and groves in Central park, in the county of New York;\n  p. the glacial channel in Central park, in the county of New York;\n  q. the burrows in sandstone in Watkins Glen, in the county of\nSchuyler;\n  r. the upper devonian shale, siltstone and sandstone in Watkins Glen\ngorge, in the county of Schuyler;\n  s. Watkins Glen state park, in the county of Schuyler;\n  t. Letchworth state park, in the county of Wyoming;\n  u. Penn Dixie fossil park and nature preserve, in the county of Erie;\n  v. Lafarge quarry, in the county of Ulster;\n  w. Seneca stone quarry, in the county of Seneca;\n  x. Taughannock park road in Taughannock Falls state park, in the\ncounty of Tompkins;\n  y. State route four and twenty-two, in the town of Whitehall, county\nof Washington;\n  z. Rondaxe road on Bald mountain, in the town of Webb, county of\nHerkimer;\n  aa. Cannan road, in the towns of East Martinsburg and Knox, county of\nLewis;\n  bb. Barnet garnet mine, in the county of Warren;\n  cc. John Boyd Thacher state park, in the county of Albany;\n  dd. the Petrified Sea Gardens, in the county of Saratoga;\n  ee. Lester park, in the county of Saratoga;\n  ff. Saratoga Springs state park, in the county of Saratoga;\n  gg. Skytop Lane quarry, in the county of Delaware;\n  hh. Sidney Mountain quarry, in the county of Delaware;\n  ii. Sidney Mountain Bluestone quarry, in the county of Delaware;\n  jj. Sidney Center outcrops, in the county of Delaware;\n  kk. Sheetz quarry, in the county of Delaware;\n  ll. Pine Hill road, in the county of Delaware;\n  mm. Chimney Bluffs state park, in the county of Wayne;\n  nn. Wiscory Falls, in the county of Allegany;\n  oo. White creek, in the county of Allegany;\n  pp. Sixtown creek, in the county of Allegany;\n  qq. Rushford Dam park, in the county of Allegany;\n  rr. Caneadea Gorge overlook, in the county of Allegany;\n  ss. Buttermilk Falls state park, in the county of Cayuga;\n  tt. Chittenango Falls state park, in the county of Madison;\n  uu. Cohoes Falls, in the county of Saratoga;\n  vv. Clarksville cave, in the county of Albany;\n  ww. Joralemon town park, in the county of Albany;\n  xx. Normanskill gorge, in the county of Albany;\n  yy. Barton garnet mine, in the county of Warren;\n  zz. Kimberlite dike, in the county of Onondaga;\n  aaa. Howes Cave quarry, in the county of Schoharie;\n  bbb. Howe Caverns, in the county of Schoharie;\n  ccc. Kaaterskill Falls, in the county of Greene;\n  ddd. Knox cave, in the county of Albany;\n  eee. Manorkill Falls, in the county of Schoharie;\n  fff. McFail's Cave nature preserve, in the county of Schoharie;\n  ggg. Montauk Point, in the county of Suffolk;\n  hhh. Montour Falls, in the county of Schuyler;\n  iii. Niagara Falls state park, in the county of Niagara;\n  jjj. Onesquethaw Cave, in the county of Albany;\n  kkk. Stark's Knob, in the county of Saratoga;\n  lll. Cairo Fossil Forest, in the county of Greene;\n  mmm. Gilboa Fossil Forest, in the county of Schoharie; and\n  nnn. Herkimer Diamond Mines, in the county of Herkimer.\n  3. For each area, territory and site designated pursuant to\nsubdivision two of this section, the commissioner, in cooperation with\nthe commissioners of transportation and economic development, may:\n  a. establish a management plan designed to foster socio-economic\ndevelopment that is sustainable;\n  b. establish methods for conserving and enhancing its geological\nheritage; and\n  c. establish best practices for conservation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>