<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="49-0211"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49_0211">
        <num>49-0211</num>
        <heading>State land acquisition advisory council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 49-0211. State land acquisition advisory council.\n  1. The council shall consist of seven members: the commissioner of\nenvironmental conservation and the commissioner of parks, recreation and\nhistoric preservation, and the following officials or their designees:\nthe governor, the majority leader of the senate, the speaker of the\nassembly, the minority leader of the senate and the minority leader of\nthe assembly. The governor shall appoint the chair. Persons serving as a\nmember of the council pursuant to designation shall serve at the\npleasure of the designating authority, without compensation, but shall\nbe entitled to receive reimbursement of reasonable expenses necessarily\nincurred in the performance of their duties pursuant to the provisions\nof this title.\n  2. The provisions of section seventy-four of the public officers law\nshall be applicable to the members of the council in connection with\ntheir duties under this article. At any time that a member of the\ncouncil has or may have a direct or indirect financial interest in or\nresulting from the proposed acquisition or decision not to acquire land\nor an interest in land, such member shall not participate in any\ndiscussion or deliberation of the council concerning such land or\ninterest.\n  3. The advisory council shall:\n  a. advise and make recommendations to the commissioners regarding\nacquisition goals and priorities to ensure a balance of statewide and\nregional interests in acquisition;\n  b. have an opportunity to review and make recommendations regarding\nspecific parcels proposed by the commissioners for acquisition prior to\nthe approval by the department or the office of any parcel for\nacquisition; and\n  c. review the annual reporting of the regional advisory committees,\nany community preservation project plans developed pursuant to section\nsix-s of the general municipal law, the department and the office, and\nthe state land acquisition plan.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of article six of the public\nofficers law, no records of the advisory council shall be available for\npublic inspection. Notwithstanding the provisions of article seven of\nthe public officers law, no meeting or proceeding of the advisory\ncouncil shall be open to the public. All proceedings of the advisory\ncouncil shall be confidential. Members of the advisory council may\nparticipate in a meeting by means of a conference telephone or similar\ncommunications equipment and may exchange information by mail.\n  5. In carrying out its responsibilities pursuant to this article, the\ncouncil shall take into account the regional and state land acquisition\npriorities and policies.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>