<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="51-0303"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_51_0303">
        <num>51-0303</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 51-0303. Definitions.\n  As used in this title, the following terms shall mean and include:\n  2. "Construction". The erection, building, acquisition, alteration,\nreconstruction, improvement or extension of sewage treatment works; the\ninspection and supervision thereof; and the engineering, architectural,\nlegal, fiscal and economic investigations and studies, surveys, designs,\nplans, working drawings, specifications, procedures, and other actions\nnecessary thereto;\n  3. "Eligible project". A water quality improvement project for the\nconstruction of sewage treatment works,\n  a. for which a permit has been issued by the department,\n  b. which is, in the judgment of the commissioner, in accord with\napplicable comprehensive studies and reports,\n  c. which is approved for federal pollution abatement assistance,\n  d. which conforms with applicable law, rules and regulations, and\n  e. which is, in the judgment of the commissioner, necessary for the\naccomplishment of the state water pollution control program;\n  4. "Federal pollution abatement assistance". Funds available to a\nmunicipality, either directly or through allocation by the state, from\nthe federal government as grants for construction of sewage treatment\nworks, pursuant to the federal water pollution control act and acts\namendatory thereto;\n  5. "Municipality". A city, county, town, village, the New York state\nenvironmental facilities corporation, a sewer authority within a city,\nor an improvement district or district corporation within a city,\ncounty, town or village, or Indian tribes residing within New York\nstate, or any combination thereof;\n  6. "Project cost". The actual cost or estimated reasonable cost,\nwhichever is lower, of construction of an eligible project;\n  7. "Water quality improvement project". A sewage treatment works for\nthe purpose of treating, neutralizing or stabilizing sewage, including\ntreatment or disposal plants, the necessary intercepting, outfall and\noutlet sewers, pumping stations integral to such plants or sewers,\nequipment and furnishings thereof and their appurtenances.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>