<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="52-0701"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52_0701">
        <num>52-0701</num>
        <heading>Approval and execution of state projects</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 52-0701. Approval and execution of state projects.\n  1. State environmentally sensitive land projects and forest preserve\nprojects shall be undertaken pursuant to the provisions of this article\nonly with the approval of the commissioner.\n  2. The commissioner shall make an itemized estimate of funds or\nappropriations required annually for inclusion in the executive budget.\n  3. The commissioner shall, after hearings and prior to the approval of\nany environmentally sensitive land projects and forest preserve\nprojects, promulgate rules and regulations which shall include but need\nnot be limited to: eligibility requirements, departmental ranking and\nreview processes, project approval guidelines and criteria, and funding\ndistribution for forest preserve projects and for each type of\nenvironmentally sensitive lands project as defined in subdivision four\nof section 52-0101 of this article.\n  4. Real property acquired with monies provided through this title\nshall not be sold or disposed of, or used for any purpose inconsistent\nwith the natural resource value for which it was acquired, without the\nexpress authority of the legislature. Prior to the implementation of any\nsale, disposal, or change of use authorized by the legislature, the\nagency authorized to sell, dispose of or change the use of any such\nlands shall first provide substitute lands of equal fair market value,\nequivalent natural resource value and similarly suitable location as\napproved by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>