<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="52-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-52-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_52_0107">
        <num>52-0107</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the commissioner for title three of this article</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 52-0107. Powers and duties of the commissioner for title three of this\n             article.\n  In administering the provisions of title three of this article, the\ncommissioner:\n  1. shall make an itemized estimate of funds or appropriations by\nproject required annually for inclusion in the executive budget.\n  2. may, in the name of the state, as further provided within this\narticle, contract to make, within the limitations of appropriations\navailable therefor, a state assistance payment to a municipality\nrepresenting the state share of the cost of a project approved and to be\nundertaken pursuant to title three of this article. Such contracts shall\nbe subject to approval by the state comptroller and, as to form, by the\nattorney general.\n  3. may, in the name of the state, as further provided within this\narticle, enter into contracts, within the limitations of appropriations\navailable therefor, with public benefit corporations and private\ncontractors for services contemplated by this article to be funded\nhereunder.\n  4. shall approve vouchers for the payment of assistance pursuant to an\napproved contract. All such payments shall be paid on the audit and\nwarrant of the state comptroller.\n  5. may perform such other and further acts as may be necessary, proper\nor desirable to carry out the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>