<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-53-0305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-53-0305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="53-0305"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-53-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-53-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-53-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-53-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53_0305">
        <num>53-0305</num>
        <heading>Designation of commissioner</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 53-0305. Designation of commissioner.\n  For the purposes of this title, the commissioner is designated as the\nappropriate state official to coordinate federal funding of urban\nforestry and arboriculture programs and by regulation may provide for\nthe submission and approval of urban forestry and arboriculture plans.\nThe department will also provide technical assistance to urban areas for\nurban forestry and arboriculture, and encourage the participation of\nmunicipal foresters, private agencies, organizations, firms, and\nindividuals to furnish urban forestry and arboricultural services in\norder to carry out the purposes of this title. The commissioner may take\nsteps necessary to facilitate the cooperation of private agencies and\norganizations with municipalities for the purposes of this article,\nincluding long-term contracts with private parties for the use of vacant\npublic lands in or around urban areas, subject to other requirements of\nstate law and the jurisdiction of other public agencies with respect\nthereto, for purposes of urban forestry and arboriculture under this\narticle, and to provide trees and shrubs for planting in accordance with\nan approved urban forestry or arboricultural plan. This program shall be\nadministered in cooperation with the Cornell cooperative extension and\nthe soil and water conservation districts to avoid duplication between\nthese agencies and the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>