<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0507"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0507"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="54-0507"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_54_0507">
        <num>54-0507</num>
        <heading>State assistance application procedure</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 54-0507. State assistance application procedure.\n  1. A municipality, upon the approval of its governing body, may submit\nan application to the commissioner, in such form and containing such\ninformation as the commissioner may require, for state assistance\npayments toward the cost of a project which is within the state of New\nYork and which is eligible for state assistance pursuant to this title.\n  2. The commissioner shall review such project application and may\napprove, disapprove or recommend modifications thereto consistent with\napplicable law, criteria, standards or rules and regulations relative to\nsuch projects. In reviewing applications for projects pursuant to this\nsection, the commissioner shall give due consideration to:\n  a. the urgency of need to provide state assistance payments for the\nproject in relation to the provision of monies for other project needs\nin the state known at the time such application is made;\n  b. any adverse environmental impact resulting from the municipal\nlandfill, including effects on groundwater; and\n  c. the ability of the municipality to pay for the costs of closure.\n  3. No monies shall be expended for non-hazardous municipal landfill\nclosure projects or municipal landfill gas management projects except\npursuant to an appropriation therefor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>