<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="54-0503"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_54_0503">
        <num>54-0503</num>
        <heading>Eligibility to receive state assistance payments for municipal landfill closure projects</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 54-0503. Eligibility to receive state assistance payments for\n             municipal landfill closure projects.\n  Any municipality which is the owner or operator of a landfill may\napply for state assistance payments toward the cost of a municipal\nlandfill closure project upon showing that the following criteria, in\naddition to applicable rules and regulations, have been met:\n  1. The landfill site has not been classified pursuant to subparagraph\none or two of paragraph b of subdivision four of section 27-1305 of this\nchapter. Sites which have been removed from the registry may apply for\nstate assistance payments.\n  2. The municipality has an obligation to close the landfill by a\nspecific date pursuant to an administrative order, court order or permit\nwhich requires the municipality to cease acceptance of waste at the site\nwithin eighteen months of the date the application for state assistance\npayment is approved.\n  3. A closure investigation report which complies with the requirements\nof applicable regulations of the department, including a demonstration\nthat future physical climate risk due to sea level rise, and/or storm\nsurges and/or flooding, based on available data predicting the\nlikelihood of future extreme weather events, including hazard risk\nanalysis data if applicable, has been considered, shall have been\nsubmitted.\n  4. The municipality has agreed, upon project approval, to waive any\nright to state assistance for closure of the site under section 27-1313\nof this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>