<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="54-0101"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-0101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_54_0101">
        <num>54-0101</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 54-0101. Definitions.\n  As used in this article, unless otherwise specified within any title\nof this article, the following terms shall mean and include:\n  1. "Commissioner" means the commissioner of environmental\nconservation; except that within and for the purposes of the projects\nundertaken by the office pursuant to title nine of this article, the\nterm shall mean the commissioner of the office of parks, recreation and\nhistoric preservation.\n  2. "Cost" means the cost of an approved project, which shall include\nengineering and architectural services, plans and specifications,\nconsultant and legal services, and other direct expenses incident to\nsuch project less any federal assistance received or to be received and\nany other assistance from other parties.\n  3. "Department" means the department of environmental conservation.\n  4. "Facility" means any structure or site improvement including paths,\ntrails, roads, bridges, ramps and buildings.\n  5. "Federal assistance" means funds available, other than by loan,\nfrom the federal government, either directly or through allocation by\nthe state for construction or program purposes pursuant to any federal\nlaw or program.\n  6. "Governing body" means:\n  a. in the case of a county outside of the city of New York, the county\nboard of supervisors or other elective governing body;\n  b. in the case of a city or village, the local legislative body\nthereof, as the term is defined in the municipal home rule law;\n  c. in the case of a town, the town board;\n  d. in the case of a public benefit corporation, the board of\ndirectors, members or trustees thereof;\n  e. in the case of a public authority, the governing board of\ndirectors, members, or trustees thereof;\n  f. in the case of a not-for-profit corporation, the board of directors\nthereof or such other body designated in the certificate of\nincorporation to manage the corporation; and\n  g. in the case of an Indian tribe or nation, any governing body\nrecognized by the United States or the state of New York.\n  7. "Municipality" means a local public authority or public benefit\ncorporation, a county, city, town, village, or Indian tribe or nation\nresiding within New York state, or any combination thereof. For the\npurposes of title 5 and title 9 of this article, municipality shall also\ninclude state agencies, state public authorities and state public\nbenefit corporations. For the purposes of title 7 and title 9 of this\narticle, the term municipality shall also include a school district and\na supervisory district.\n  8. "Not-for-profit corporation" means a corporation formed pursuant to\nthe not-for-profit corporation law and qualified for tax-exempt status\nunder the federal internal revenue code.\n  9. "Office" means the office of parks, recreation and historic\npreservation.\n  10. "Solid waste" shall have the definition set forth in title 5 of\narticle 27 of this chapter but shall not include hazardous waste as\ndefined in title 9 of article 27 of this chapter.\n  11. "State assistance payment" means the payment of monies by the\nstate for projects authorized by the environmental protection fund, to\npreserve, enhance, restore and improve the quality of the state's\nenvironment.\n  12. "Secretary" means the secretary of state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>