<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1105"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1105"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-03-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="54-1105"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_54_1105">
        <num>54-1105</num>
        <heading>State assistance payments for coastal rehabilitation projects</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 54-1105. State assistance payments for coastal rehabilitation\n             projects.\n  1. The commissioner is authorized to provide on a competitive basis,\nwithin amounts appropriated, state assistance payments to a municipality\nor a not-for-profit corporation toward the cost of any coastal\nrehabilitation project approved by the commissioner provided that the\ncommissioner determines that future physical climate risk due to sea\nlevel rise, and/or storm surges and/or flooding, based on available data\npredicting the likelihood of future extreme weather events, including\nhazard risk analysis data if applicable, has been considered.\n  2. The commissioner and a municipality or not-for-profit corporation\nmay enter into a contract for the undertaking of a coastal\nrehabilitation project. Such project shall be recommended to the\ncommissioner by the governing body of the municipality or not-for-profit\ncorporation as that term is defined pursuant to subdivision six of\nsection 54-0101, and when approved by the commissioner, undertaken by\nthe municipality or not-for-profit corporation pursuant to this article\nand any other applicable provisions of law.\n  3. State assistance payments shall not exceed fifty percent of the\nproject cost or two million dollars, whichever is less. Such costs are\nsubject to final computation and determination by the commissioner upon\ncompletion of the project, and shall not exceed the maximum eligible\ncost set forth in the contract.\n  4. Prior to processing applications for state assistance payments\ntoward the cost of coastal rehabilitation projects, the commissioner\nshall promulgate rules and regulations which shall include criteria for\ndetermining eligible expenditures and procedures for governing the\ncommitment and disbursement of funds appropriated in accordance with\nthis title. The commissioner shall also promulgate rules and regulations\nwhich shall include application procedures, review processes, and\nproject approval guidelines and criteria consistent with section\n54-1107.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>