<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0113"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0113"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="55-0113"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_55_0113">
        <num>55-0113</num>
        <heading>Special groundwater protection areas; Long Island designation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the North Hills area of the town of North Hempstead, Nassau\ncounty;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the area of the Northeastern villages of the town of Oyster Bay,\nNassau county;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the Woodbury road-West Pulaski road area, town of Huntington,\nSuffolk county;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the West Hills area of the town of Huntington, Suffolk county;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the Oak Brush Plains of the towns of Babylon and Huntington,\nSuffolk county;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the Setauket Pine Barrens, town of Brookhaven, Suffolk county;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the Central Pine Barrens of the towns of Brookhaven, Riverhead and\nSouthampton, Suffolk county;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the South Fork Morainal Forest of the towns of Southampton and\nEast Hampton, Suffolk county; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the Hither Hills area of the town of East Hampton, Suffolk county.\n  2. Such areas identified for Long Island in this section shall be\naddressed concurrently as a single planning project in order to insure\nconsistency and uniformity in the development of a management plan that\nrecognizes the regional importance of the special groundwater protection\nareas.\n  3. The preliminary boundaries of the special groundwater protection\nareas designated in subdivision one of this section shall be those\nidentified in the state groundwater management plan except for said\nareas designated in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this\nsection which shall be the same as those areas adopted by the Nassau\nCounty Board of Health pursuant to article ten of the Nassau County\nPublic Health Ordinance on December twelfth, nineteen hundred\neighty-four. Final boundaries shall be determined on the basis of\ninformation developed in accordance with the requirements of section\n55-0115 of this article.\n  4. Other areas not identified in this section can be petitioned for\naccording to the guidelines set forth in section 55-0109 of this\narticle.\n  5. The Long Island regional planning board is designated as the\nplanning entity for the nine special groundwater protection areas herein\nidentified on Long Island, and is authorized to carry out the planning\nwork specified in this article.\n  6. An advisory group to be known as the "special groundwater\nprotection area advisory council" shall be established. The voting\nmembership shall consist of representatives of the following\norganizations: one member from the Nassau county department of health;\none member from the Nassau county department of public works; one member\nfrom the Nassau county planning commission; two members from the Suffolk\ncounty department of health services; one member from the New York state\ndepartment of environmental conservation; one member from the New York\nstate department of health; two members from the New York state\nlegislative commission on water resource needs of Long Island; two\nmembers from conservation organizations having property or other\ninterests in one or more of the special groundwater protection areas;\nand a member from each town which contains part or all of a special\ngroundwater protection area. The special groundwater protection area\nadvisory council shall serve as an advisory group to the Long Island\nregional planning board and shall assist in the development, review, and\nimplementation of the management plan.\n  7. The Long Island regional planning board shall submit an ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_55_0113__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this section\nshall use public funds to acquire land within such special groundwater\nprotection area being used as a recreational facility or open space at\nthe time of proposed acquisition unless such land is being offered for\nsale or a change of use for such land is proposed by the owner thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>