<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="57-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_57_0103">
        <num>57-0103</num>
        <heading>Legislative declaration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 57-0103. Legislative declaration.\n  The legislature hereby declares it to be in the public interest to\nprotect and manage the Pine Barrens-Peconic Bay system, in the county of\nSuffolk, by establishing a Long Island Pine Barrens maritime reserve. It\nis further in the public interest to establish a council made up of\nrepresentatives of state and local governments and private citizens to\nprepare a comprehensive management plan and make recommendations to\npreserve, protect and enhance the natural, recreational, economic and\neducational values of the region, which the state and local governments\nmay adopt. In addition, it is further in the public interest to\nestablish a commission made up of a governor's appointee, the county\nexecutive of Suffolk county and the supervisors of the towns of\nBrookhaven, Riverhead and Southampton to prepare, oversee and\nparticipate in the implementation of a comprehensive land use plan for\nthe Central Pine Barrens area to guide development therein in a manner\nsuitable to the needs for preservation of the core preservation area and\ncompatible growth and development in the compatible growth area.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>