<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-6-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-6-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-6-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-6-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-6-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-6-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_0103">
        <num>6-0103</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 6-0103. Definitions.\n  As used in this article:\n  1. "Criteria" shall mean the state smart growth public infrastructure\ncriteria provided in section 6-0107 of this article.\n  2. "State infrastructure agency" shall mean the department, the\ndepartment of transportation, the department of education, the\ndepartment of health, the department of state, the New York state\nenvironmental facilities corporation, the New York state housing finance\nagency, the housing trust fund corporation, the dormitory authority, the\nthruway authority, the port authority of New York and New Jersey, the\nempire state development corporation, the New York state urban\ndevelopment corporation and all other New York authorities. Any\nsubsidiary of, or corporation with the same members or directors as, a\npublic benefit corporation identified in this subdivision shall also be\ndeemed to be within the definition of state infrastructure agency under\nthis article.\n  3. "Municipal centers" shall mean areas of concentrated and mixed land\nuses that serve as centers for various activities, including, but not\nlimited to, central business districts, main streets, downtown areas,\nbrownfield opportunity areas, downtown areas of local waterfront\nrevitalization program areas, transit-oriented development,\nenvironmental justice areas, and hardship areas. Municipal centers shall\nalso include: areas adjacent to municipal centers, as defined in this\nsubdivision, which have clearly defined borders, are designated for\nconcentrated development in the future in a municipal or regional\ncomprehensive plan, and exhibit strong land use, transportation,\ninfrastructure and economic connections to a municipal center; and areas\ndesignated in a municipal or comprehensive plan, and appropriately zoned\nin a municipal zoning ordinance, as a future municipal center.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>