<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-0211"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_0211">
        <num>71-0211</num>
        <heading>Disposition of fees and penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 71-0211. Disposition of fees and penalties.\n  1. Notwithstanding any other provisions of law to the contrary, all\nfines and penalties collected pursuant to title nineteen of this\narticle, except amounts required to be paid into the conservation fund\npursuant to subdivision two of section 71-1929 of such title; title\ntwenty-one of this article; title twenty-seven of this article, except\namounts required to be paid into the hazardous waste remedial fund\npursuant to subdivision two of section 71-2725 of such title; and title\nforty-one of this article shall be paid into the general fund to the\ncredit of the state purposes account.\n  2. Unless otherwise provided in this chapter, not later than the tenth\nday of each month, all fines, penalties and forfeitures collected for\nviolations of this chapter or rules, regulations, local laws or\nordinances adopted thereunder under judgment of any town or village\ncourt, shall be paid over by such court to the comptroller of the state,\nwith a statement accompanying the same, setting forth the action or\nproceeding in which such moneys were collected, the name and residence\nof the defendant, the nature of the offense, and the fines and penalty\nimposed. The comptroller shall pay these funds into the general fund of\nthe state.\n  All fines and penalties collected for violations of this chapter by\ncourts operating pursuant to section thirty-nine of the judiciary law\nshall be paid to the state commissioner of taxation and finance on a\nmonthly basis no later than ten days after the last day of each month.\nAll such fines and penalties shall be the property of the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>