<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0907"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0907"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-0907"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_0907">
        <num>71-0907</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of enforcement officers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hunting, fishing or trapping or\ndisturbing wildlife; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>cutting, pulling or digging of trees; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe removal of trees.\n  3. The officers named in subdivision 1 shall enforce the provisions of\nthis chapter listed in section 71-0501 or under titles 5 through 15\ninclusive and title 33 of this article or of judgments obtained for\nviolation thereof, and shall have, particularly, the powers stated in\nsubdivision 4. Peace officers shall have the same powers as conservation\nofficers, and state police under the Fish and Wildlife Law, except the\npower to search without warrant.\n  4. Officers named in subdivision 1 shall have power:\n  a. To execute all warrants and search warrants issued for violation of\nthe Fish and Wildlife Law and to serve subpoenas issued for examination,\ninvestigation or trial of offenses against any of its provisions;\n  b. To search without search warrant any boat or vehicle of any kind,\nany box, locker, basket, creel, crate, game bag, package or any\ncontainer of any nature and the contents of any building other than a\ndwelling whenever they have cause to believe that any provision of this\narticle or of any law for the protection of fish, shellfish, crustacea,\nwildlife, game or protected insects has been or is being violated, and\nto use such force as may be necessary for the purpose of examination and\nsearch;\n  c. To search any dwelling and its contents, provided they have a\nsearch warrant to do so;\n  d. To arrest without warrant any person committing in their presence a\nmisdemeanor under the provisions of this chapter listed in section\n71-0501 or under titles 5 through 15 inclusive and title 33 of this\narticle and to take such person immediately before a magistrate having\njurisdiction for trial;\n  e. To seize as evidence without warrant any fish, shellfish,\ncrustacea, wildlife, game, or parts thereof, protected insects or\nplumage as defined in section 11-1729, whenever they have cause to\nbelieve it is possessed or transported in violation of law, or it bears\nevidence of illegal taking, or it is possessed or transpor...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any net, trap or other device constituting a nuisance as defined\nin section 71-0915;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any net, trap or device other than a boat, a vehicle, or aircraft\nor a firearm when they have cause to believe that its possession or use\nis in violation of any provision of the Fish and Wildlife Law or\nregulation pursuant thereto;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any firearm, when they have cause to believe that it has been used\nin a violation of the Fish and Wildlife Law constituting a misdemeanor\ninvolving the illegal taking or attempting to take wild deer;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any rakes, tongs, dredges, or device other than a boat or vehicle\nused, or in possession for purpose of use, for the taking of shellfish\nin violation of subdivisions 1 or 2 of section 13-0309.  For the\npurposes of this paragraph "device" includes a bird, dog, or other\nanimal used in or as an aid in taking fish or wildlife, any jack light,\nspot light or other artificial light other than a headlight attached in\nproper position to a motor vehicle, any hunting appliance or apparatus\nand any fishing or netting gear or tackle.  This paragraph does not\nlimit any power of seizure pursuant to warrant.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any boat or vehicle, when they have probable cause to believe it\nhas been used for the taking of shellfish in violation of subdivision 2\nor 3 of section 13-0309 of this chapter by a person possessing, at the\ntime of such use, commercial shellfish harvesting gear or shellfish in\nexcess of two pecks. For the purposes of this subparagraph "commercial\nshellfish harvesting gear" shall mean rakes, tongs, dredges and other\ndevices commonly used to harvest shellfish for commercial purposes.\n  5. To retain custody of and provide for the safekeeping of any thing\nseized as provided in paragraph e or f of subdivision 4 of this section,\nor deposit it for safekeeping with any police officer, as he deems\nappropriate, subject to regulations of the department, or of the\nSuperintendent of State Police in the case of a member of the state\npolice, and subject to order of any court having jurisdiction, until\ndetermination of any prosecution, civil or criminal, arising from the\nviolation or al...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>encounters or is forecasted to encounter\nunsafe weather conditions defined as high winds thirty-five knots or\ngreater or waves ten feet or higher or ice or other adverse condition\nthat make the continuation of the voyage unsafe and poses a risk to life\nand property, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>experiences a mechanical problem, that makes the\ncontinuation of the voyage unsafe and poses a risk to life and property\nincluding compromised hull integrity or pump failures or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>experiences\na significant medical emergency which requires immediate medical\nattention necessary to protect the health of any person on board, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nexperiences loss of essential gear such as support systems that renders\nthe vessel unable to remain at sea said commercial fishing vessel may\ndock at a New York port. A sinking vessel or a vessel leaking oil or\nfuel may be otherwise directed when the safety of persons is maintained\nand the vessel poses a significant threat to the waters of New York. The\ncommercial fishing vessel may be required by the department to\nindependently verify the reason for the unscheduled dockage with a\nmechanic deemed qualified by New York state, the National Weather\nService or a medical professional, as appropriate. b. The fishing vessel\nshall immediately notify the department and the permitting state as soon\nas the danger is known and communication signals allow. The commercial\nfishing vessel shall provide the department with:</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>details on the\nvessel including the vessel captain's name;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>identity of the\npermitting state;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the nature of the problem;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>identity of the\nintended docking location, estimated time of arrival, and quantities and\ntypes of fish on board and,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0907__subsec_c__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a call back phone number or other method\nof contact. c. The commercial fishing vessel shall not offload cargo\nwithout the express authorization of and supervision by department\npersonnel. Authorization to offload fish may be granted where the fish\non board the vessel will become unmarketable due to the duration of the\nunscheduled dockage. Authorization may be limited according to the\nwillingness of the permitting state to accept the fish under that\nstate's fish allocation.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>