<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-1707"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-1707"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-1707"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-1707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-1707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-1707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-1707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_1707">
        <num>71-1707</num>
        <heading>Violations of health laws or regulations; penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 71-1707. Violations of health laws or regulations; penalties.\n  1. Any person who violates, disobeys or disregards any term or\nprovision of this chapter listed in section 71-1701, or of titles 17\nthrough 21 inclusive of this article or of any lawful notice, order or\nregulation pursuant thereto for which a civil penalty is not otherwise\nexpressly prescribed by law, shall be liable to the people of the state\nfor a civil penalty of not to exceed one thousand dollars for every such\nviolation.\n  2. The penalty provided for in subdivision one of this section may be\nrecovered by an action brought by the commissioner in any court of\ncompetent jurisdiction.\n  3. Nothing in this section contained shall be construed to alter or\nrepeal any existing provision of law declaring such violations or any of\nthem to be misdemeanors or felonies or prescribing the penalty therefor.\n  4. Such civil penalty may be released or compromised by the\ncommissioner before the matter has been referred to the Attorney\nGeneral, and where such matter has been referred to the Attorney\nGeneral, any such penalty may be released or compromised and any action\ncommenced to recover the same may be settled and discontinued by the\nAttorney General with the consent of the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>