<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-2903"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_2903">
        <num>71-2903</num>
        <heading>Investigations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 71-2903. Investigations.\n  1. The commissioner, or any officer of the department when authorized\nby the commissioner, may investigate and report as to all matters within\nor pertaining to the powers and jurisdiction of the department for the\npurpose of carrying into effect the provisions of article 33 of this\nchapter or this title and the rules of the department made pursuant\nthereto.\n  2. To aid in the administration of article 33, the commissioner or any\nperson designated by him may issue subpoenas in his name requiring the\nattendance and giving of testimony by witnesses and the production of\nbooks, papers and other evidence for any hearing, proceeding or\ninvestigation conducted or to be conducted by or before the department.\nService of such a subpoena, enforcement of obedience thereto, and\npunishment for disobedience thereof shall be had as and in the manner\nprovided by the civil practice law and rules relating to enforcement of\nany subpoena issued by a board or committee except that in the case of\nhearings, proceedings, or investigations before or conducted by the\ndepartment neither any person certified to apply pesticides nor the\nholder of a business registration issued pursuant to article 33, nor an\nemployee of such registration holder or, nor an officer or stockholder\nin a registered corporation, when required to attend as a witness, shall\nbe entitled to any subpoena fee or mileage. Any member of the department\nor any person who may be designated hereunder by the department to hold\nhearings may administer oaths to witnesses. The department also may\nprovide for the taking of depositions of witnesses for the purpose of\nany such hearing. In such case, such officer, employee or other person\nmay administer oaths to the witnesses whose depositions are to be taken.\nEach deposition shall be reduced to writing and subscribed by the\ndeponent.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>