<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-2503"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-2503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_2503">
        <num>71-2503</num>
        <heading>Violation; penalties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_2503__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nactivity taking place requiring a permit under article twenty-five but\nfor which no permit has been granted or (ii) failure on the part of a\npermittee to adhere to permit conditions, the commissioner shall have\npower to direct the violator to cease and desist from violating the act.\nIn such cases the violator shall be provided an opportunity to be heard\nwithin ten days of receipt of the notice to cease and desist.\n  c. Following a hearing held pursuant to section 71-1709 of this\narticle, the commissioner shall have power to direct the violator to\ncease and desist from violating the act and to restore the affected\ntidal wetland or area immediately adjacent thereto to its condition\nprior to the violation, insofar as that is possible within a reasonable\ntime and under the supervision of the commissioner. Any order of the\ncommissioner shall be enforceable in an action brought by the\ncommissioner in any court of competent jurisdiction. Any civil penalty\nor order issued by the commissioner under this subdivision shall be\nreviewable in a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil\npractice law and rules.\n  2. Criminal sanctions. Any person who violates any provision of\narticle twenty-five shall, in addition, for the first offense, be guilty\nof a violation punishable by a fine of not less than five hundred nor\nmore than five thousand dollars; for a second and each subsequent\noffense such person shall be guilty of a misdemeanor punishable by a\nfine of not less than one thousand nor more than ten thousand dollars or\na term of imprisonment of not less than fifteen days nor more than six\nmonths or both. In addition to or instead of these punishments, any\noffender shall be punishable by being ordered by the court to restore\nthe affected tidal wetland or area immediately adjacent thereto to its\ncondition prior to the offense, insofar as that is possible. The court\nshall specify a reasonable time for the completion of the restoration,\nwhich s...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>