<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-3303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-3303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-3303"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-3303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-3303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-3303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-3303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_3303">
        <num>71-3303</num>
        <heading>Civil and administrative sanctions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 71-3303. Civil and administrative sanctions.\n  1. Any person who violates any provision of, or fails to perform any\nduty imposed by article forty-three of this chapter or any rule or\nregulation promulgated pursuant thereto, or any term or condition of any\ncertificate or permit issued pursuant thereto, or any final\ndetermination or order of the Lake George park commission made pursuant\nto article forty-three of this chapter shall be liable for a civil\npenalty not to exceed five hundred dollars for each such violation and\nan additional penalty of five hundred dollars for each day during which\nsuch violation continues, to be assessed by the Lake George park\ncommission after an opportunity to be heard, or by the court in any\naction or proceeding initiated by the attorney general in the name of\nthe Lake George park commission. In addition thereto, such person may,\nby similar process, be enjoined from continuing such violation, and any\npermit or certificate issued to such person may be revoked or suspended,\nor a pending renewal application denied based upon such violation.\n  2. Such civil penalty may be released or compromised by the Lake\nGeorge park commission before the matter has been referred to the\nattorney general; and, where such matter has been referred to the\nattorney general, any such penalty may be released or compromised and\nany action commenced to recover the same may be settled and discontinued\nby the attorney general with the consent of the Lake George park\ncommission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>