<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-0101"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_0101">
        <num>72-0101</num>
        <heading>Declaration of policy</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 72-0101. Declaration of policy.\n  The legislature of the state of New York hereby declares that\ncomprehensive environmental regulatory management programs are essential\nto protect New York state's environmental resources and the public's\nhealth and welfare. It further declares that those regulated entities\nwhich use or have an impact on the state's environmental resources\nshould bear the costs of the regulatory provisions which permit the use\nof these resources in a manner consistent with the environmental,\neconomic and social needs of the state. The legislature further declares\nthat regulatory fees are an appropriate mechanism to pay a portion of\nthe costs of the department's regulatory functions and programs and a\nportion of the costs to fund the cleanup of inactive hazardous waste\ndisposal sites and that such fees should be borne by the state's\nregulated entities in order to further strengthen the state's\ncapabilities to achieve its environmental quality objectives.  The\nlegislature further declares that the department's regulatory programs\nand corresponding costs vary according to certain relevant technical\ncriteria which shall be considered in determining adjustments to fees as\nprovided in this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>