<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-0201"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_0201">
        <num>72-0201</num>
        <heading>Fees and penalties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_72_0201__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fifteen percent in the\nenvironmental protection fund established by section ninety-two-s of the\nstate finance law not to exceed two million one hundred thousand\ndollars; and (ii) seventy-one percent in the industry fee transfer\naccount of the hazardous waste remedial fund established by subdivision\none of section ninety-seven-b of the state finance law.\n  2. All persons subject to regulation under a state environmental\nregulatory program including those persons holding existing permits,\ncertificates or approvals under such programs shall be liable for fees\nauthorized by this article on and after April first, nineteen hundred\neighty-three.\n  3. Liability for fees authorized by this chapter for persons receiving\nnew permits, certificates or approvals shall equal the annual fee\nestablished pursuant to this title and prorated from the date of\nissuance.\n  4. Payment of fees shall be due within thirty days of billing by the\ndepartment.\n  5. If the amount of the fee is not paid within forty-five days of the\nlast date prescribed under subdivision four of this section, a penalty\nshall be imposed on such deficiency. The amount of such penalty shall\nnot exceed five percent of such deficiency per month and the total\npenalty shall not exceed twenty-five percent of the deficiency.\n  Notice of the determination of a penalty, and notice of the right to\nappeal such determination shall be given to the person liable for the\npayment of the fee and any penalty due. The penalty as determined\npursuant to this subdivision shall be finally and irrevocably assessed\nunless a hearing is requested by certified mail to the commissioner\nwithin thirty days after receiving notice of the determination of a\npenalty, or unless the commissioner on his own motion shall redetermine\nsuch penalty. After such hearing the commissioner shall give notice of\nfinal determination to the person against whom the fee and penalty is\nassessed. No such penalty as defined in this subdivisi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_72_0201__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_72_0201__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the United States internal revenue code of\n1986 (Public Law 99-514, 26 U.S.C. section 1 et seq.) from the date the\nfee was required to be paid.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>