<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0105"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0105"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="73-0105"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_73_0105">
        <num>73-0105</num>
        <heading>Task force composition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>* ยง 73-0105. Task force composition.\n  1. The task force shall consist of fourteen members; nine of whom\nshall be the director of the canal corporation, commissioner of the\ndepartment of environmental conservation, the secretary of state, the\ncommissioner of transportation, the director of the state emergency\nmanagement office, the commissioner of parks, recreation and historic\npreservation, the commissioner of agriculture and markets, the chairman\nof the power authority of the state of New York and the commissioner of\neconomic development or designee; and five additional members who shall\nbe from outside the public offices listed in this section and who shall\nhave professional experience in the fields of hydrology, civil\nengineering, climatology, emergency management and soil and water\nconservation. The governor shall appoint three of the five additional\nmembers and the temporary president of the senate and speaker of the\nassembly shall each appoint one of each of the five additional members.\n  2. The task force shall appoint a chairperson from among its members.\n  3. The members of the task force shall receive no compensation for\ntheir services, but shall be allowed their actual and necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of their duties.\n  4. The task force shall consult with the emergency management officer,\nor appropriate county officer, from each county adjacent or intersected\nby the canal system or the Oswego river basin and each such officer\nshall provide to the task force a document listing their concerns and\nrecommendations related to flooding along the canal system. The task\nforce shall consider such concerns and recommendations in its\ndeliberations and in the formulation of its determinations and\nrecommendations.\n  5. The task force shall also solicit the views of persons who reside\nadjacent to the canal system or major bodies within the Oswego river\nbasin to assist it in making its determinations and formulating its\nrecommendations.\n  6. To help ensure the task force's receipt of a comprehensive and\ndiverse array of views, a citizen advisory board to the task force shall\nbe established. The advisory board shall consist of up to thirteen\nmembers appointed for two years, seven members shall be appointed\nfollowing the recommendation of the governor; two members shall be\nappointed following the recommendation of the temporary president of the\nsenate; two members shall be appointed following the recommendation of\nthe speaker of the assembly; one member shall be appointed following the\nrecommendation of the minority leader of the senate; and one member\nshall be appointed following the recommendation of the minority leader\nof the assembly. The advisory board shall represent a diverse array of\ninterests, including property owners residing adjacent to or in close\nproximity to the canal system or major water bodies within the Oswego\nriver basin, recreational and commercial users of the canal system,\nenvironmental groups and hydroelectric power generators that operate\nfacilities within the canal system. No member of the advisory board may\nbe concurrently employed by, or provide goods or services to, any agency\nor public corporation which is represented on the task force. The\ncommissioner shall select a member of the advisory board to serve as\nchairperson.\n  7. The members of the advisory board shall receive no compensation for\ntheir services, but shall be allowed their actual and necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of their duties.\n  8. The advisory board shall advise the task force on relevant\ninformation and issues related to flooding and flood mitigation in the\ncanal system or the Oswego river basin; make recommendations to fulfill\nthe purposes of this article; and provide advice and assistance required\nby the task force.\n  9. The task force shall meet at least six times at the call of the\nchairperson.\n  * NB Repealed 120 days after the New York State canal flood mitigation\ntask force has submitted its completed report (see ch. 456/2007 ยง2)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>