<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0115"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0115"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-10-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75-0115"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75_0115">
        <num>75-0115</num>
        <heading>Community air monitoring program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 75-0115. Community air monitoring program.\n  1. For purposes of this section, the following definitions and related\nprovisions shall apply:\n  a. "Community air monitoring system" means advanced sensing monitoring\nequipment that measures and records air pollutant concentrations in the\nambient air at or near sensitive receptor locations in disadvantaged\ncommunities.\n  b. "Disadvantaged community" means a community identified as\ndisadvantaged pursuant to the criteria set forth in section 75-0111 of\nthis article.\n  c. "Sensitive receptors" includes hospitals, schools and day care\ncenters, and such other locations as the department may determine.\n  2. a. On or before October first, two thousand twenty-two, the\ndepartment shall prepare, in consultation with the climate justice\nworking group, a program demonstrating community air monitoring systems.\n  b. The program shall identify the highest priority locations in\ndisadvantaged communities around the state to deploy community air\nmonitoring systems, which shall be communities with potentially high\nexposure burdens for toxic air contaminants and criteria air pollutants.\nThe program shall be undertaken in no less than four communities\nstatewide with regional consideration.\n  c. The department shall publish the air quality data produced by the\ncommunity air monitoring systems deployed pursuant to this section on\nits website as it becomes available.\n  3. On or before June first, two thousand twenty-four, the department\nshall prepare, in consultation with the climate justice working group, a\nstrategy to reduce emissions of toxic air contaminants and criteria air\npollutants in disadvantaged communities affected by a high cumulative\nexposure burden. The strategy shall include criteria for the development\nof community emission reduction programs. The criteria presented in the\nstrategy shall include, but are not limited to, the following:\n  a. an assessment and identification of communities with high\ncumulative exposure burdens for toxic air contaminants and criteria air\npollutants.\n  b. a methodology for assessing and identifying the contributing\nsources or categories of sources, including, but not limited to,\nstationary and mobile sources, and an estimate of their relative\ncontribution to elevated exposure to air pollution in impacted\ncommunities identified pursuant to paragraph a of this subdivision.\n  c. an assessment of the existing and available measures for reducing\nemissions from the contributing sources or categories of sources\nidentified pursuant to paragraph b of this subdivision.\n  4. a. Based on the assessment and identification of disadvantaged\ncommunities with high cumulative exposure burdens for toxic air\ncontaminants and criteria air pollutants completed pursuant to paragraph\na of subdivision three of this section, the department shall select\ndisadvantaged communities around the state for preparation of community\nemissions reduction programs. The department may select additional\nlocations annually thereafter, as appropriate.\n  b. The department shall have the authority to adopt regulations\nestablishing programs to achieve emissions reductions for the locations\nselected using the most cost-effective measures identified pursuant to\nparagraph c of subdivision three of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>