<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0119"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0119"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75-0119"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0119/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-75-0119/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75_0119">
        <num>75-0119</num>
        <heading>Implementation reporting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 75-0119. Implementation reporting.\n  1. The department in consultation with the council shall, not less\nthan every four years, publish a report which shall include\nrecommendations regarding the implementation of greenhouse gas reduction\nmeasures.\n  2. The report shall, at minimum, include:\n  a. Whether the state is on track to meet the statewide greenhouse gas\nemissions limits established in section 75-0107 of this article.\n  b. An assessment of existing regulations and whether modifications are\nneeded to ensure fulfillment of the statewide greenhouse gas emissions\nlimits.\n  c. An overview of social benefits from the regulations or other\nmeasures, including reductions in greenhouse gas emissions and\ncopollutants, diversification of energy sources, and other benefits to\nthe economy, environment, and public health.\n  d. An overview of compliance costs for regulated entities and for the\ndepartment and other state agencies.\n  e. Whether regulations or other greenhouse gas reduction measures\nundertaken are equitable, minimize costs and maximize the total benefits\nto the state, and encourage early action.\n  f. Whether activities undertaken to comply with state regulations\ndisproportionately burden disadvantaged communities as identified\npursuant to section 75-0111 of this article.\n  g. An assessment of local benefits and impacts of any reductions in\nco-pollutants related to reductions in statewide and local greenhouse\ngas emissions.\n  h. An assessment of disadvantaged communities' access to or community\nownership of the services and commodities identified in section six of\nthe chapter of the laws of two thousand nineteen which added this\narticle.\n  i. Whether entities that have voluntarily reduced their greenhouse gas\nemissions prior to the implementation of this article receive\nappropriate credit for early voluntary reductions.\n  j. Recommendations for future regulatory and policy action.\n  3. In preparing this report, the department shall, at a minimum,\nconsult with the council, and the climate justice working group\nestablished in section 75-0111 of this article.\n  4. The report shall be published and posted on the department's\nwebsite.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>