<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0113"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0113"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0113"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0113">
        <num>9-0113</num>
        <heading>Adopt-a-natural resource stewardship program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0113. Adopt-a-natural resource stewardship program.\n  1. The commissioner may enter into stewardship agreements with any\nperson or persons for the purposes of preserving, maintaining, or\nenhancing a state-owned natural resource or portion thereof in\naccordance with the policies of this article.\n  2. The stewardship agreement shall provide that the natural resource\nbe preserved and maintained in its natural state or managed to enhance\nor restore the natural resource values they provide, consistent with the\nprovisions of this chapter and purposes of this article. Activities may\ninclude: remediating vandalism, picking up litter and trash,\nestablishing or maintaining access or nature trails, providing\ninterpretive services for school groups and other citizens, managing\nfish and wildlife habitat, and otherwise providing positive benefits to\nthe natural resource.\n  3. Stewardship agreement with any person or persons may provide for\nassistance of personnel, facilities and supplies of the department for\nthe purposes of supporting appropriate activities under such stewardship\nagreement, in accordance with the provisions of this article.\n  4. The department shall establish procedures by which a person or\npersons may apply for a stewardship agreement, and shall be responsible\nfor working with such persons to identify specific sections of a\nstate-owned natural resource and specific activities deemed appropriate\nfor such stewardship agreement. The department may consider factors such\nas safety, environmental sensitivity, need, cost and other factors\ndeemed relevant in determining which natural resource or activities may\nbe eligible or appropriate for a stewardship agreement.\n  5. Consistent with other laws of the state and regulations of the\ndepartment, the department shall provide recognition of the stewardship\nactivities by appropriate signage on or near the adopted natural\nresource, and may provide recognition by such other measures as it may\ndetermine to be appropriate, including but not limited to press\nreleases, certificates, newsletters, and articles in the\nconservationist.\n  6. The stewardship agreement may be modified in scope or altered in\nany other manner at the sole discretion of the department, not\ninconsistent with the provisions of this section. The person or persons\nshall have the option of renewing the agreement subject to the approval\nof the department and the continuation by the department of the\nadopt-a-natural resource stewardship program. The department may\nterminate the agreement and remove the signs upon thirty day notice, if\nin its sole judgment it finds and determines that the person or persons\nare not meeting the terms and conditions of the agreement.\n  7. The department shall, to the maximum extent practicable, provide\nassistance to other state agencies that are interested in developing\nstewardship programs for natural resources under their jurisdiction.\n  8. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, the state and\nits employees shall not be liable for damages suffered by any person\nresulting from the actions or activities of such volunteers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>