<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0307"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0307">
        <num>9-0307</num>
        <heading>Forest preserve lands; detached parcels outside Adirondack and Catskill parks</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0307. Forest preserve lands; detached parcels outside Adirondack and\n            Catskill parks.\n  Any lands of the state, now owned or hereafter acquired, constituting\nthe forest preserve, but outside of the Adirondack and Catskill parks as\nnow fixed by law and not acquired or dedicated for the practice of\nforest or wild life conservation, and consisting in any case of not more\nthan 100 contiguous acres entirely separated from any other portion of\nthe forest preserve, may be dedicated, used, sold or exchanged as\nfollows:\n  1. The department may dedicate any of such lands for the practice of\nforest or wild life conservation, or may use any of such lands for\npublic recreational or other state purposes, under the care, custody and\ncontrol of the division of lands and forests. Such dedication or use\nshall be by written order of the commissioner, filed in his office, a\ncertified copy of which shall be forthwith filed by him in the office of\nthe Secretary of State.\n  2. The department may consent to a transfer of jurisdiction over any\nsuch lands by the Office of General Services, and such office may make\nsuch transfer in accordance with the provisions of subdivision 4 of\nsection 3 of the Public Lands Law governing transfers of jurisdiction in\ngeneral, for the purpose of thereby dedicating such lands for the\npractice of forest or wild life conservation or for the use thereof for\npublic recreational or other state purposes.\n  3. The department may consent to a sale or exchange of any of such\nlands in accordance with the provisions of section 24 of the Public\nLands Law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>