<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0717"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0717"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0717"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0717/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0717/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0717/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0717/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0717">
        <num>9-0717</num>
        <heading>Community forests</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0717. Community forests.\n  1. Power and authority. A county, city, town, village, school district\nor any other political subdivision of the state, may acquire by\npurchase, or gift, or take over lands in its possession within the\nboundaries of the state and use the same for forestry purposes. The\ngoverning board of a county, city, town or school district may\nappropriate money for the purchase of lands for the purposes herein\nprovided, to establish forest plantations or for the care and management\nof forests.\n  2. Procedure. Such boards may undertake such work at regular or\nspecial meetings by majority vote of such board after two weeks' public\nnotice setting forth the fact that such plan is contemplated and that\nmoneys are to be appropriated for such purposes.\n  3. Assistance and trees and shrubs. The department may assist and\nadvise such boards in its reforesting and wildlife habitat improvement\nwork, and the department may furnish trees and shrubs for planting such\npublicly owned lands without charge provided they are planted in\naccordance with the instructions of the department.\n  4. Use. Such governing board shall have full power and authority to\nacquire, maintain, manage and operate such forests, and sell the produce\nthereof, for the benefit of the inhabitants of its district.\n  5. Revenue. The net income from such lands shall be paid into the\ngeneral fund of such municipal division and shall be used only upon\norder of its governing board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>