<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0801"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0801"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0801"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0801/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0801/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0801">
        <num>9-0801</num>
        <heading>Legislative purpose and findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0801. Legislative purpose and findings.\n  It is the purpose of this act to provide for the development and\nmaintenance of a forest resources planning program, consistent with\narticle fourteen of the state constitution, in furtherance of the policy\nof the state of New York to conserve, improve and protect its natural\nresources and environment. The legislature recognizes that the needs and\nopportunities which affect the use, management and protection of the\nforest resources of the state are interrelated and require a\ncomprehensive approach to issue resolution and policy development. To\nbest serve the public interest, forest resources programs and efforts\nshould be based upon periodic assessments and analyses of present and\nanticipated use, demand for, and supply of renewable forest resources\nfrom the public and private forest lands of the state. The department\nshall consult and cooperate with the Adirondack park agency in the\npreparation of those parts of the assessment and plan with respect to\nthe forest resources of the Adirondack park. The legislature hereby\ndesignates the department of environmental conservation as the official\nstate agency with the responsibility to plan for present and future\ndemands on the state's forest resources and declares that the department\nshall conduct a program of long range comprehensive forest resource\nplanning which planning program shall include the periodic preparation\nof a forest resources assessment and the periodic development of a\nforest resources plan.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>