<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0807"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0807"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0807"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0807">
        <num>9-0807</num>
        <heading>Committees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0807. Committees.\n  The commissioner shall appoint an advisory committee and a technical\nreview committee to assist directly in carrying out the provisions of\nthis act by promoting a constructive interchange among agencies and\norganizations interested in planning for the use, management and\nprotection of public and private forest resources and to enhance the\nprospect of common acceptance of plan recommendations.\n  1. The advisory committee membership shall be representative of forest\nresources related agencies and organizations in this state. The\ncommittee shall provide interdisciplinary review and analysis of policy\ndevelopment throughout the planning process. The committee shall meet at\nleast annually and shall file a written annual report to the department\nand the legislature which report shall include a statement of progress\nmade toward attaining the goals and objectives stated in the forest\nresource plan, recommendations for amendment of the plan and any other\nmatter the committee deems necessary to be included. The members of the\nadvisory committee shall not receive any remuneration except that the\ndepartment may reimburse members thereof for reasonable expenses\nincurred in attending meetings.\n  2. The technical review committee membership shall be representative\nof the full range of expertise in use, management and protection of\nforest resources. The committee will provide scientific and technical\nreview and analysis in development of the forest resources assessment.\nThe members of the technical review committee shall not receive any\nremuneration except that the department may reimburse members thereof\nfor reasonable expenses incurred in attending meetings.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>