<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0815"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0815"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0815"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0815">
        <num>9-0815</num>
        <heading>Request for comment on local laws or ordinances pertaining to the practice of forestry</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0815. Request for comment on local laws or ordinances pertaining to\n            the practice of forestry.\n  The commissioner upon his or her own initiative, or upon the written\nrequest of a municipality or an owner of forest land within the\nmunicipality, may elect to comment upon a proposed local law or\nordinance which may restrict the practice of forestry. The requesting\nmunicipality or owner of forest land shall provide, at a minimum, the\nfull text of the proposed local law or ordinance to the commissioner\nwith such request.\n  1. Upon receipt of such written request or upon the commissioner's\ndetermination to comment on a local law or ordinance, the commissioner\nshall notify the municipal legislative body, in writing, of the receipt\ndate or the date of such determination.\n  2. An owner of forest land shall provide notice to the municipal\nlegislative body proposing the local law or ordinance of a written\nrequest to the commissioner in the time, manner, and form as may be\nprescribed by the commissioner.\n  3. The commissioner, in preparing his or her comments for\nconsideration by the municipality, may consider factors including, but\nnot limited to, the impact of the proposed local law or ordinance upon\nthe long-term viability of forests in the municipality and any\nmodifications or alternatives which a municipality may undertake to\nminimize the impacts to the practice of forestry in preparing his or her\ncomments.\n  4. The commissioner shall have forty-five days after receipt of an\nordinance to provide his or her comments, if any, to the municipal\nlegislative body proposing the law or ordinance. Any municipal\nlegislative body shall defer the adoption of such local law or ordinance\npending receipt of comments, if any, from the commissioner or the\npassage of forty-five days from the date of receipt of the proposed\nlocal law or ordinance by the commissioner. The commissioner shall have\nthe opportunity to respond only to the original proposal considered by\nthe local governing body.\n  5. For purposes of this section, "forest land" shall mean land that is\nsuitable to forest crop production.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>