<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0903"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0903">
        <num>9-0903</num>
        <heading>Recreation facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0903. Recreation facilities.\n  1. The department shall have care, custody, control and management of\nthe Lake George beach facility in Warren county, the Belleayre mountain\nski center in Ulster and Delaware counties, the Whiteface mountain ski\ncenter and the New York world war veterans memorial highway in Essex\ncounty and the Gore mountain ski center and the Prospect Mountain\nVeteran's Memorial Highway in Warren county. The New York world war\nveterans memorial highway in Essex county and the Prospect Mountain\nVeteran's Memorial Highway in Warren county shall continue to be\nmaintained by the Department of Transportation.\n  2. The commissioner shall have the power and is authorized to impose\nand provide for the collection of such fees or charges as he may deem\nnecessary and for the best interests of the state for the use of all\nfacilities and their appurtenances. All moneys received therefrom shall\nbe deposited in the State Treasury pursuant to the provisions of the\nState Finance Law.\n  3. The department shall have the supervision and jurisdiction over all\nlocks and adjacent state property between the Saranac river and lower\nSaranac lake and between lower Saranac and middle Saranac lake in the\ncounty of Franklin and make such improvements and repairs thereto from\ntime to time as may be necessary.\n  4. The commissioner shall have the power and is authorized to\nencourage investment by the private sector for the provision of\nequipment and capital improvements for concession facilities operated at\nthe Belleayre Mountain ski center and the Gore Mountain ski center by\nentering into concession license agreements for extended periods not to\nexceed ten years in total. Such extended term shall be for the purpose\nof assuring a concessionaire of adequate protection against loss of\ninvestment in structures, fixtures, equipment, supplies and other\nimprovements, and the length of such term shall have a direct\nrelationship to the period required to amortize the investment. The bid\nprospectus submitted to prospective bidders shall contain specific\ninformation concerning the nature of the capital improvements or\nequipment to be provided by the successful bidder.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>