<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1707"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1707"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-1707"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_1707">
        <num>9-1707</num>
        <heading>New York invasive species advisory committee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-1707. New York invasive species advisory committee.\n  1. There shall be established a New York invasive species advisory\ncommittee which shall provide information, advice and guidance to the\ncouncil, including but not limited to providing assistance with the\ndevelopment of the four-tier classification system for nonnative animal\nand plant species.\n  2. The commissioner and the commissioner of agriculture and markets\nshall select up to twenty-five at-large members with at least one member\nfrom each of the following: New York biodiversity research institute,\nNew York state's land grant university, New York sea grant, a statewide\norganization formed to address invasive species, a statewide land\nconservation organization, a statewide agricultural organization, a\nnursery business, a boating organization, the darrin freshwater\ninstitute, the soil and water conservation districts, the natural\nheritage program, a New York state forestry school, a lake association,\nthe New York city department of environmental protection, and a\nstatewide local government organization.\n  3. The members of the advisory council shall serve without\ncompensation, except members shall be allowed their necessary and actual\nexpenses incurred in the performance of their duties under this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>