<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1915"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1915"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-1915"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1915/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1915/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1915/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1915/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_1915">
        <num>9-1915</num>
        <heading>Notarized statement</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_1915__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>:\nMailing address(es):\nTelephone number</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_1915__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>:\nTax parcel number:\nCircle either 1 or 2; if you circle 1, you must also circle a or b:\n  1. I (we) elect to participate in the process to resolve title issues\nregarding the above-referenced parcel as authorized by title nineteen of\narticle nine of the environmental conservation law.\n  a. I (we) intend to reduce my (our) payment by gifting to the state a\nspecified portion of a disputed parcel in fee simple without reservation\nfor inclusion in the forest preserve or a conservation easement to the\ntown restricting development over all or a specified portion of a\ndisputed parcel, with a secondary right of enforcement in the state. The\nintended gift is described in the attached document.\n  b. I (we) do not intend to reduce my (our) payment to the state by\ngifting any portion of the parcel to the state or by gifting a\nconservation easement over any portion of the parcel to the town; or\n  2. I (we) elect to not participate in the special process to resolve\ntitle issues regarding the above-referenced parcel as authorized by\ntitle nineteen of article nine of the environmental conservation law. I\n(we) understand that: within twenty-four months of my (our) filing of\nthis notice, the attorney general shall commence an action in a court of\ncompetent jurisdiction to determine title to such parcel; nothing in\ntitle nineteen of article nine of the environmental conservation law\nshall be applicable to such litigation; and failure by the attorney\ngeneral to commence such action within such twenty-four month time frame\nshall not subsequently prevent the attorney general from commencing such\nan action or create a presumption against the state's claim of title.\nSignature\n(Notarization)\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>