<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1907"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1907"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-1907"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_1907">
        <num>9-1907</num>
        <heading>Process for clearing title</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_1907__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a flat rate of two thousand dollars per\nparcel; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_1907__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an amount equal to the total assessed value of the\nparcel, including structures and improvements situated thereon, as\ndetermined by the two thousand twelve town assessment, less the assessed\nvalue of any portion of such parcel conveyed to the state in fee or any\nconservation easement conveyed to the town, pursuant to paragraph a of\nsubdivision two of this section, divided by the total assessed value of\nall disputed parcels, including structures and improvements situated\nthereon as determined by the two thousand twelve town assessment,\nmultiplied by two hundred thousand dollars. The town shall use all such\npayments to acquire land for inclusion in the forest preserve pursuant\nto subdivision six of this section.\n  6. Within eighteen months of the date of the letters sent by the\ndepartment pursuant to subdivision one of this section, the department\nshall identify lands for the town to acquire for inclusion in the forest\npreserve. Subject to legislative approval, such lands shall provide a\nnet benefit to the forest preserve as compared to the disputed parcels\nto which the state is estopped from asserting a claim pursuant to\nsubdivision seven of this section. The town shall use all payments\nacquired pursuant to subdivision five of this section for the\nacquisition of such lands. Such lands shall be conveyed from the owner\ndirectly to the state. Title to land to be conveyed to the state\npursuant to this title and the deed to the state shall be approved by\nthe attorney general, as to form and manner of execution and\nrecordability, before the deed shall be accepted on behalf of the state.\n  7. The commissioner shall cause to be prepared an accurate survey map\nshowing the boundaries of all disputed land to which the state will be\nreleasing and extinguishing its right, title and interest and record the\nsurvey map in the Hamilton county clerk's office. The commissioner shall\nalso cause legal descriptions of such boundaries to be prepared from the\nma...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_1907__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>facts or actions\nthat occurred prior to the effective date of this title, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_1907__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>deeds,\ntax sales or other documents that predate the effective date of this\ntitle. The commissioner shall also cause to be prepared an accurate\nsurvey map, to be recorded in the county clerk's office, and a legal\ndescription from the survey map, for each individual parcel of land the\nclaimant of which has filed a notice pursuant to paragraph b of\nsubdivision two of this section or has not complied in a timely fashion\nwith the requirements of subdivisions two, four or five of this section.\nThe department shall provide a copy of such survey and legal description\nto the office of the attorney general to assist in the litigation\nrequired by section 9-1909 of this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>