<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-1-102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-1-102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1-102"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-1-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-1-102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-1-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-1-102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1_102">
        <num>1-102</num>
        <heading>Powers of incorporated village The citizens of the state of New York, from time to time inhabitants of the territory comprised within the...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1-102. Powers of incorporated village\n  The citizens of the state of New York, from time to time inhabitants\nof the territory comprised within the boundaries of any village\nheretofore or hereafter incorporated shall continue to be a municipal\ncorporation in perpetuity under its corporate name and the same shall in\nthat name be a body politic and corporate in fact and in law, with power\nof perpetual succession. The village shall have power:\n  1. To take, purchase, hold, lease, sell and convey such real and\npersonal property as the purposes of the corporation may require.\n  2. To take by gift, grant, bequest or devise and hold real and\npersonal estate absolutely or in trust for any purpose of the\ncorporation or for any public use upon such terms or conditions as may\nbe prescribed by the grantor or donor and accepted by said corporation\nand to provide for the proper administration of the same.\n  3. To take unconditionally by gift, grant, bequest or devise for any\nother purpose any real or personal property or estate or interest\ntherein, to hold same for only such time as is reasonably necessary to\nsell, convey or to dispose thereof, and to so sell, convey or dispose\nthereof; notwithstanding that the holding of such property would not be\nfor a purpose of the corporation or for a public use.\n  4. To make, have and use, and from time to time alter, a common seal.\n  5. To contract and be contracted with, to sue and be sued, to complain\nand defend and to institute, prosecute, maintain, defend and intervene\nin, any action or proceeding in any court.\n  6. To have and exercise all the rights, privileges and jurisdiction\nessential to a proper exercise of its corporate function, including all\nthat may be necessarily incident to, or may be fairly implied from the\npowers specifically conferred upon such corporation.\n  7. To have and exercise all the rights, privileges, functions and\npowers prescribed and exercised by it under existing or subsequent laws\nand not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>