<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1010"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1010"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-09-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-1010"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1010/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1010/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1010/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1010/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1010">
        <num>10-1010</num>
        <heading>Election of company officers and delegates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 10-1010 Election of company officers and delegates. Each of the\nseveral companies whose members constitute the fire department of the\nvillage shall hold an annual meeting on the first Tuesday in April in\neach year, except those fire companies constituting the fire department\nof the village of Fishkill, Dutchess county, and the village of\nCroton-on-Hudson, Westchester county, which shall hold such annual\nmeetings on the first Tuesday in December of each year. At such meeting\nthe members of each company shall elect by ballot from their own number\na captain and a lieutenant, and such further officers if any as may be\nprovided for in the by-laws of the company, who must be approved by the\nboard of fire commissioners, one warden and one delegate to the general\nconvention of the fire department. The terms of office of the captain\nand lieutenant and such further officers if any, as are elected as\nherein provided, shall be one year, the wardens two years, and the\ndelegates three years, respectively, and any vacancies occurring in any\nsuch offices shall be filled by election in like manner. At the first\nannual meeting after this act takes effect two wardens and three\ndelegates shall be elected, the wardens to serve for one and two years,\nrespectively, and the delegates for one, two and three years,\nrespectively. Any person who has been convicted of arson in any degree\nshall not be eligible for election to the office of captain, lieutenant,\nwarden, delegate and any other offices provided for in the by-laws of\nthe company. Any captain, lieutenant, warden, delegate or other officer\nof the company who is convicted of arson in any degree during their term\nof office shall be disqualified from completing such term of office.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>