<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1018"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1018"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-1018"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1018/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1018/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1018/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1018/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1018">
        <num>10-1018</num>
        <heading>Duties of chief and assistants</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 10-1018 Duties of chief and assistants. The chief shall be president\nof the council and of the meetings of the fire department.  He shall,\nunder the direction of a separate board of fire commissioners, if any,\nhave exclusive control of the members at all fires, inspections and\nreviews, the supervision of the engines, hose and other apparatus owned\nby the village for the prevention or extinguishment of fires, of all\nproperty owned by the fire department, and of all officers and employees\nthereof elected or employed by the council or by a separate board of\nfire commissioners, if any. He shall, whenever required by the board of\nfire commissioners, report to the board the condition of the property of\nthe department and such other information respecting the department as\nmay be required. He shall hold the members, officers and employees of\nthe department strictly to account for neglect of duty, and may, in a\nvillage in which separate fire commissioners are not appointed, suspend\nor discharge them at any time, subject to the approval of two-thirds of\nthe members of the council at the next meeting.  He shall, upon\napplication, and if authorized by the council, or a separate board of\nfire commissioners, if any, issue through the secretary of the fire\ndepartment a certificate of the time of service of a member of the fire\ndepartment, and shall give to each officer of the department immediately\nafter his election a certificate thereof countersigned by the secretary.\nIn case of the inability or absence of the chief, the first assistant\nand in case of the absence or inability of both the chief and first\nassistant, the second assistant, and in the absence of the second\nassistant, the third assistant, if any, and in the absence of the third\nassistant, if any, the fourth assistant, if any, shall perform the\nduties and have all the powers of the chief.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>