<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1020"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1020"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-1020"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1020/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1020/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1020/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1020/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1020">
        <num>10-1020</num>
        <heading>Abolition of fire department; employment of paid firefighters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 10-1020 Abolition of fire department; employment of paid\nfirefighters.  The board of trustees of any village may, by resolution,\nabolish, in whole or in part, the fire department in such village, which\naction of the board of trustees shall be subject to a permissive\nreferendum as defined in this chapter; if such fire department is\nabolished, all the money and property of such department shall be turned\nover by the officers of such department or by the fire commissioners to\nthe board of trustees within ten days after service of notice on such\nofficers or commissioners of the action of the board of trustees. Or,\nthe board of trustees may, by resolution, determine that one or more\nfirefighters shall be employed to act with such voluntary department and\nmay fix the salary of such firefighters; the board of trustees may also\ndetermine that such paid firefighters shall have charge of all apparatus\nand other equipment and that the voluntary department shall act under\nthe orders of such paid firefighter or firefighters.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>