<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1000"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1000"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="10-1000"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1000/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1000/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1000/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-10-1000/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_10_1000">
        <num>10-1000</num>
        <heading>General powers of the board of fire commissioners</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 10-1000 General powers of the board of fire commissioners. The board\nof fire commissioners of a village, subject to the approval of the board\nof trustees:\n  1. Has the care, custody and control of all village property of the\nfire department.\n  2. May purchase such equipment as is suitable and necessary to prevent\nand extinguish fires within the village, or for the purposes of any\nemergency and first aid squad organized within the fire department, and\nuniforms for all active members of the fire department and keep the same\nin good condition and repair.\n  3. May erect and maintain suitable and necessary buildings for the\nfire department.\n  4. May construct and maintain reservoirs and cisterns and supply them\nwith water for use at fires.\n  5. May adopt rules for the admission, suspension, removal and\ndiscipline of the members, officers and employees of the fire\ndepartment, may prescribe their powers and duties, and fix their\ncompensation not inconsistent with section 10-1018 of this article.\n  6. May adopt rules and regulations governing fire companies and fire\ndepartments, prescribing the duties of the members thereof, and may\nenforce discipline and provide for public drills, parades, funerals,\ninspections and reviews of the village fire department, or any company\nor unit thereof, within the village or at other places within the state,\nany adjoining state or in Canada. Such rules and regulations shall not\nauthorize any member of the board of fire commissioners to interfere\nwith the duties of the fire chief or the assistant fire chief at such\ntimes as the fire department or any company or squad thereof is on duty.\n  7. May appoint persons other than members or officers of the\ndepartment to take charge of village property, and may fix their\ncompensation.\n  8. May employ duty or " persons on call," to serve on a part-time\nbasis when necessary, and fix their duties and compensation. Such\npart-time paid firefighters in the event of injury shall be entitled to\nthe applicable benefits provided for such part-time paid firefighters\nunder section two hundred seven-a of the general municipal law and in\nthe event of injury or death shall be entitled to the applicable\nbenefits, if any, provided for such part-time paid firefighters under\nthe retirement and social security law and the workers' compensation\nlaw.  Persons who are volunteer members of the village fire department\nmay be employed as such part-time paid firefighters, but in the event of\ninjury, death, disease, or infection, resulting from services performed\nin line of duty as such part-time paid firefighters they shall not be\nentitled to any of the benefits provided for volunteer firefighters\nunder the volunteer firefighters' benefit law, or under any policy of\nblanket accident insurance purchased by the village or purchased by the\nfire department to cover only volunteer members of such department.\n  9. May inquire into the cause and origin of fires occurring in the\nvillage and may take testimony in relation thereto.\n  11. Notwithstanding any other provisions of law to the contrary, a\nvillage may include as part of its budget an appropriation to fund an\nannual firefighters' inspection-dinner for each fire company within the\nvillage.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>