<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1114"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1114"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1114"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1114/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1114/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1114">
        <num>11-1114</num>
        <heading>Alternative provision for connections with mains</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-1114 Alternative provision for connections with mains. The board\nof commissioners shall have authority to determine the manner and\nconditions under which said supply pipes shall be installed and shall\nhave authority to install and maintain said supply pipes and to adopt\nsuch uniform service charges as they deem just for each supply pipe so\nconnected with the mains or distributing pipes and extending to the\nstreet or right of way lines, regardless of the location of said water\nmains or distribution pipe within said streets or rights of way lines\nand regardless of the soil, rock or other physical conditions within\nsaid streets or rights of way lines.\n  Such uniform service charge as the board may adopt shall be any\npercentage of the cost up to but not exceeding the average actual cost\nof installing such supply pipes as before described. Such percentage of\nthe average actual cost of installing such supply pipes as may not be\ncharged shall be borne by the village.\n  The said board shall have authority to apply such percentage of the\naverage actual cost of installing such supply pipes as the village might\npay, to such other supply pipe connection for the same property or\nproperties as in the judgment of the board might be advisable.\n  The board of water commissioners may cause a notice to be published in\nthe official newspaper of the village and if so published, shall serve\non the owners or occupants a printed notice notifying such owners and\noccupants of any and all property fronting or abutting on any street,\nright of way or portion thereof, in or upon which any public water main\nor distributing pipe is about to be laid or is being laid or has been\nlaid by said board, that connection pipes to and from the water mains or\ndistribution pipes in said street, right of way or any portion thereof\nin front of each separate piece of property and where directed by said\nboard, shall be installed by said board in such manner and under such\nconditions and at such prices as said board shall prescribe.\n  The said board shall have authority to assess the actual cost of such\nconnection pipes or such service charge as may be determined and the\nactual cost of maintaining the same upon the property so connected.\nShould the owner of said property so connected fail to pay the cost or\ncharge thereof, the said board shall have authority to add such cost or\ncharge to the annual tax on such property and collect the same,\ntherewith, and when so collected, the amount thereof shall be paid into\nthe water fund of the village. Nothing herein contained shall be\nconstrued to prevent the financing, in whole or in part, pursuant to the\nlocal finance law, of any expense incurred by the village pursuant to\nthis section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>