<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1124"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1124"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1124"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1124/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1124/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1124">
        <num>11-1124</num>
        <heading>Contracts for purchase and sale of water</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-1124 Contracts for purchase and sale of water. 1. The board of\nwater commissioners may contract with the town board on behalf of the\ntown or a water supply, fire alarm or fire protection district thereof,\nor with the board of trustees of a village or the board of fire\ncommissioners of a fire district, respectively, to furnish water for the\nextinguishment of fires, including the furnishing, erection,\nmaintenance, care and replacement of fire hydrants, the erection and\nmaintenance of markers therefor, and the removal of snow and ice to\nprovide access thereto, or for sanitary or other public purposes, for\nany period not exceeding ten years. The amount payable each year under\nsuch a contract shall be raised as a part of the expenses of such town\nor water supply, fire alarm or fire protection district thereof, village\nor fire district, and paid to the treasurer of the village owning such\nsystem of water works. Nothing herein contained shall be deemed to alter\nor remove any of the limitations, restrictions or procedural\nrequirements provided in sections one hundred eighty-four-a and one\nhundred eighty-four-b of the town law.\n  2. The board of water commissioners of any village maintaining its own\nwater distribution system may contract in the name of such village with\nany public corporation or improvement district which possesses the power\nto sell a supply of water, for the purpose of purchasing all or any\nportion of the water supply of such village from such public corporation\nor improvement district for such period as may be deemed necessary, but\nnot in excess of forty years. The term "public corporation" as used in\nthis subdivision shall mean a public corporation as defined in the\ngeneral corporations law and also any joint water works corporation\nformed under the provisions of chapter six hundred fifty-four of the\nlaws of nineteen hundred twenty-seven, as amended.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>