<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1106"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1106/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1106/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1106">
        <num>11-1106</num>
        <heading>Establishment of water works</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-1106 Establishment of water works. If a resolution to establish a\nsystem of water works be adopted, the board of water commissioners shall\nproceed to construct such system accordingly. It shall prepare a map and\nplans showing the sources of water supply and a description of the\nlands, streams, water or water rights to be acquired therefor, and the\nmode of constructing the proposed water works and the location thereof,\nincluding reservoirs, mains, distributing pipes and hydrants. The water\ncommissioners, their agents, servants and employees, may enter upon any\nlands for the purpose of preparing such map and plans. The map and plans\nshall be filed with the village clerk, and a certified copy of such map\nshall also be filed in the county clerk's office of each county in which\nany of the lands are situated. The board of water commissioners may\nacquire, in the name of the village, by purchase, if it can agree with\nthe owners, or otherwise by condemnation, any land, streams, water or\nwater rights necessary for such system. The board may amend the map and\nplans at any time and such amended map shall be filed in the office of\nthe village clerk, and of the county clerk, in like manner as the\noriginal. The board may construct such water system by contract or\notherwise, and may appoint, and at pleasure remove, a superintendent to\ntake charge of the system, and may fix his compensation or may, by\nresolution, provide that any other village officer shall also act as the\nsuperintendent of water.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>