<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1126"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1126"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1126"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1126/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1126/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1126/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-11-1126/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1126">
        <num>11-1126</num>
        <heading>Water mains connecting with reservoirs of New York city</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 11-1126 Water mains connecting with reservoirs of New York city.  A\nproposition may be submitted at a village election to authorize any\nincorporated village of the state of New York to contract with the city\nof New York to take and receive from any of the reservoirs, aqueducts,\nconduits, streams or pipes of the city of New York, including any water\nsupply, reservoir, works, et cetera, for the supply of any public\ninstitution of said city, a supply of water for the uses and purposes of\nthe said village, on such terms, conditions and stipulations as such\nvillage and city may deem necessary and to that end such village is\nauthorized and empowered to lay the necessary mains and pipes to the\nsource of supply, valves, hydrants, supply pipes, and other necessary\nappurtenances for the use of said water, including its purification,\nwithout the consent of any board, officer, bureau, or department of the\nstate, or any subdivision thereof, and to issue its bonds to pay\ntherefor. The connections with said reservoirs, aqueducts, conduits,\nstreams or pipes shall be made at the expense of such village, and such\nvillage shall pay to the city of New York water charges or rates in the\nsame amounts as are charged by the city of New York to persons using\nwater in that city. Any such village desiring to take and receive water\nunder the provisions of this section shall make application to the\nproper officer in charge of the water supply of the city of New York in\nwriting, stating the place and manner in which it is proposed to make\nsaid connections, which said officer in charge of the water supply of\nthe city of New York shall have exclusive jurisdiction in the premises,\nto the exclusion of any other board, officer, bureau or department of\nthe state or any subdivision thereof. Provided said city agrees to sell\nand said village agrees to purchase water, it shall be the duty of the\nsaid officer to grant a permit or authorization for the said\nconnections, under reasonable rules and regulations, including the\ninstallation of proper meters, or other devices for ascertaining the\nquantity of water thus taken.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>