<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-12-1204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-12-1204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="12-1204"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-12-1204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-12-1204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-12-1204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-12-1204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_12_1204">
        <num>12-1204</num>
        <heading>Supervision and extension of system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 12-1204 Supervision and extension of system. The lighting system\nacquired or established under this article shall be under the control\nand supervision of the board of light commissioners. The board shall\nkeep it in repair and shall have authority to purchase such supplies and\nmaterials as may be needed for the operation and maintenance of such\nsystem for periods not exceeding one year. Such board may, from time to\ntime extend, alter or reconstruct such system and may use therefor\nsurplus funds it has on hand.  However, nothing contained in this\nsection shall be construed to prevent the village from financing, in\nwhole or in part, expenditures for any such improvements pursuant to the\nlocal finance law. Such system may with the permission and approval of\nthe public service commission be so extended, altered or reconstructed\noutside the village wherever franchises are first obtained from the\nlocal authorities. If such system shall be so extended, altered or\nreconstructed outside of a village into a town or a lighting district\nthereof, the board of light commissioners of the village may contract\nwith the town board of such town for lighting the streets, highways,\npublic grounds and public buildings of such town or lighting district,\nin pursuance of the provisions of article twelve of the town law, which\nshall be applicable to such contract and to the levying of a tax for the\npayment of the amounts which shall be payable thereunder to the\ntreasurer of the village.  Wherever such system shall be so extended,\naltered or reconstructed outside of a village, occupants of premises\nadjacent to such extended, altered or reconstructed system outside of\nthe village shall be entitled to be supplied with light therefrom under\nsuch conditions and at such rates as the board of light commissioners\nshall determine.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>