<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-1404"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_1404">
        <num>14-1404</num>
        <heading>Use by the state, individuals and corporations outside corporate limits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-1404 Use by the state, individuals and corporations outside\ncorporate limits. The board of sewer commissioners may sell to a\ncorporation, or to an individual, the right to make connection with its\nsewerage system for the purpose of discharging sewage or wastewater\ntherein from outside the village limits, and fix the term, consideration\nand conditions therefor.  The board shall not sell nor permit the use of\nits sewerage system under this section if thereby such system will be\nrendered inadequate for the village or its inhabitants. The term\n"corporation" shall mean a corporation as defined in section one hundred\ntwo of the business corporation law. The board of sewer commissioners of\nany village may contract with the state of New York or with the state\nauthority having control and supervision of any state institution, and\nthe state of New York or the state authority having control and\nsupervision of any state institution may contract with the board of\nsewer commissioners of any village, to provide sewerage and sewage\ndisposal facilities for the conveyance, treatment and disposal of the\nsewage or wastewater of such state or state institution either within or\nwithout the corporate limit of said village on such conditions and\nconveying such powers to the state or such state authority and for such\nconsideration and such period of time as said sewer commissioners and\nthe state of New York or such state authority may agree. The board of\nsewer commissioners of any village may contract with the United States\nof America or with the federal agency, administration or authority\nhaving control and supervision of any federal institution or\ninstallation to provide sewerage and sewage disposal facilities for the\nconveyance, treatment and disposal of the sewage or wastewater of such\nfederal institution or installation either within or without the\ncorporate limits of the village on such conditions, for such\nconsideration and for such period of time as said sewer commissioners\nand the United States of America or such federal agency, administration\nor authority may agree.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>