<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1402"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1402"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-1402"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1402/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1402/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_1402">
        <num>14-1402</num>
        <heading>Extension of sewerage systems beyond village limits and acquisition of property therefor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-1402 Extension of sewerage systems beyond village limits and\nacquisition of property therefor. The board of sewer commissioners of a\nvillage may construct or extend the sewerage system without the village\nlimits and may construct a sewage disposal plant without such village\nand acquire land for such purposes. If such commissioners are unable to\nagree with the property owners for the purchase of real property\nnecessary for the construction or extension of the sewerage system, they\nmay acquire the same by condemnation proceedings, whether it be\nnecessary to acquire the fee or an easement for a right of way therein,\nand whether the property and easements necessary to be so acquired are\nwithin or without the village limits. But no such sewerage system or\nsewage disposal plant shall be constructed or extended by a village\nwithout its limits into another town, village or a city without the\nconsent of the board of trustees, town board, common council or other\nsimilar legislative body of such town, village or city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>