<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1432"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1432"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-1432"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1432/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1432/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1432/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1432/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_1432">
        <num>14-1432</num>
        <heading>Levy of taxes and assessments to pay bonds issued for a sewerage system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-1432 Levy of taxes and assessments to pay bonds issued for a\nsewerage system. The board of trustees of any village which shall have\nheretofore issued or may hereafter issue bonds for the purpose of paying\nthe cost of constructing in said village a sewerage system, whether\nincluding or not including trunk lines, outfall sewers, disposal plants\nor lateral sewers, or private on-site wastewater disposal systems may,\nnotwithstanding that any part of the expense of constructing such\nsewerage system or private on-site wastewater disposal system has\ntheretofore been assessed upon lands benefited, determine and order that\nany portion of such cost, not exceeding in amount the aggregate amount\nof such bonds then outstanding, shall be assessed upon the lands\nbenefited by the construction of such sewerage system or private on-site\nwastewater disposal system in the manner provided in this section. Any\nsuch resolution shall determine the aggregate amount of such bonds which\nshall then be outstanding and unpaid and shall fix the portion of each\ninstallment of maturities of said bonds which is thereafter to be\nassessed upon lands benefited, in the manner provided in this section.\nAny such resolution shall be subject to a permissive referendum. Prior\nto the first day of May in each year the board of trustees shall compute\nthe aggregate amount of the portion of the principal of said bonds, to\nbecome due during the ensuing fiscal year which is required by said\nresolution to be assessed upon the lands benefited, and also the\ninterest on such portion of said bonds to become due during such fiscal\nyear, and shall assess such amount on the lands within said village, in\nproportion as nearly as may be to the benefit which each lot or parcel\nwill derive from the construction of said sewerage system. After making\nsuch apportionment, the board of trustees shall serve on the owner of\neach such lot or parcel of land a notice of the completion of such\napportionment and that at a specified time and place a hearing will be\nheld to consider and review the same.\n  The board of trustees shall meet at the time and place specified in\nsuch notice and hear objections to such apportionment, and may modify\nand correct the same. The board of trustees upon the completion and\ncorrection of such apportionment, shall forthwith file the same in the\noffice of the village clerk, and shall give notice of the filing of such\ncompleted and corrected apportionment in the manner provided for by\nsection fourteen hundred ten of the real property tax law as to towns.\nThe apportionment shall then be deemed final and conclusive, unless an\nappeal is taken therefrom as hereinafter provided within fifteen days\nafter the filing thereof. The board of trustees shall, in the annual tax\nlevy for such fiscal year, levy upon each such lot or parcel of land the\nsum so apportioned to such lot or parcel of land, and the amount so\nlevied shall be collected in the same manner as other village taxes. In\nthe event that any such resolution shall become effective, any lot or\nparcel of land assessed by any previous assessment or apportionment of\nany part of the cost of constructing such sewerage systems shall be\nfreed from the lien of such former assessment or apportionment, except\nto the extent that any part of such cost so apportioned to such lot or\nparcel of land shall have been included in the annual tax levies of said\nvillage.  The powers conferred by this section shall be in addition to\nthe powers conferred by any other law, including any general or special\nlaw, and such powers may be exercised without regard to the restrictions\ncontained in any other law other than the village law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>