<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1414"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1414"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-1414"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1414/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1414/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1414/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-14-1414/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_1414">
        <num>14-1414</num>
        <heading>Contracts for construction of system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14-1414 Contracts for construction of system. The board of sewer\ncommissioners of a village authorized to construct the whole or any part\nof a sewerage system shall provide for the construction thereof, either\nunder an entire contract, or in parts or sections, as the board may\ndetermine. All contracts shall be let to the lowest responsible bidder\nafter advertisement for bids where so required by section one hundred\nthree of the general municipal law.  No contract shall be made by which\na greater amount shall be agreed to be paid than the maximum stated in\nthe resolution or in the petition for the construction of such sewerage\nsystem. Nothing herein contained shall make it unlawful for the village\nauthorities to make extensions to sewerage systems or to construct\nadditional sewerage systems through or by the officers or employees of a\nvillage and authority is hereby granted to all villages to extend\nsewerage systems and to construct new sewerage systems by village\nemployees under the direction of the superintendent of public works,\nstreet commissioner or similar officer, when authorized by resolution of\nthe board of trustees and when in accordance with plans approved by the\nstate department of health.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>