<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1703"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1703"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1703"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1703">
        <num>17-1703</num>
        <heading>Filling of village offices, election of officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 17-1703. Filling of village offices, election of officers. 1. Upon\nthe filing of the certificate of incorporation of each village which has\nbeen incorporated to embrace the entire territory of a town in the\noffice of the clerk of the town, the town board of such town shall\nconstitute the interim board of trustees of the village for all purposes\nand the supervisor of such town shall be the interim mayor of such\nvillage for all purposes until the first election in such village of a\nboard of trustees and mayor. Upon the qualification and filing of the\noath of office by the mayor and trustees elected in accordance herewith,\nthe holding of the office, ex officio, of mayor or trustee by any town\nofficer shall terminate.\n  2. A first election of village officers shall be held pursuant to the\nelection law at the same time, date and places, and in substantially the\nsame manner as the first regularly scheduled election of town officers\noccuring not less than thirty days after such filing of the certificate\nof incorporation of such village.\n  3. At such first election, a mayor and two trustees shall be chosen to\nserve as village officers for terms of two years each and two other\ntrustees shall be chosen to serve as village officers for terms of four\nyears each measured from the first day of January next succeeding such\nelection notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one hereof.\n  4. For purposes of electing successors to the village officers elected\nat the first village election as herein provided the terms of office of\ntrustees shall be four years and the term of office of the mayor shall\nbe two years and such terms of office shall commence on the first day of\nJanuary next succeeding the date of election.\n  5. Nothing herein contained shall diminish the power of the board of\ntrustees pursuant to section 3-302 of this chapter or any other\nprovision of law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>