<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1732"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1732"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1732"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1732/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1732/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1732/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1732/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1732">
        <num>17-1732</num>
        <heading>Trees and shrubs and shade tree commission</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 17-1732 Trees and shrubs and shade tree commission. In any such\nvillage the board of trustees may annually raise by taxation and\nappropriate and expend for planting, care and preservation of trees and\nshrubs in and upon the public highways and public places thereof a sum\nnot exceeding twenty-five hundred dollars, except that the village of\nScarsdale may raise by taxation and expend for the purposes of this\nsection such sum as may be necessary and appropriate therefor; and in\nany such village the board of trustees may regulate the planting,\nmaintenance, protection and control of shade trees upon the public\nhighways or public places of such village, and for that purpose shall\nhave power to enact, amend and repeal an ordinance or ordinances,\nproviding for the appointment of a shade tree commission (which may be\nthe village planning commission) and for the planting, care,\npreservation, maintenance, protection and control of shade trees and\nshrubs upon the public highways or public places of such village, and\nfor the enforcement thereof by fines and penalties. Every such ordinance\nshall provide that the members of such shade tree commission serve\nwithout compensation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>