<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1714"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1714"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1714"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1714/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1714/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1714">
        <num>17-1714</num>
        <heading>Establishment and maintenance of hospitals</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 17-1714 Establishment and maintenance of hospitals. 1. For the\npurpose of enabling such villages to procure federal aid under the\nprovisions of the national industrial recovery act in the establishment\nof hospitals, the board of trustees of any village which has been or may\nhereafter be incorporated or which has annexed territory to embrace the\nentire territory of a town, and which is adjacent to a city or town in\nwhich a hospital is maintained by a duly incorporated membership\ncorporation, may acquire by gift or purchase title to lands in such city\nor town in trust for hospital purposes. If such land is to be acquired\nby gift, the acquisition shall be subject to a permissive referendum or\nif such land is to be acquired by purchase, the acquisition shall be\nsubject to a permissive referendum if it is to be paid from taxes levied\nfor the fiscal year in which such expenditure is made. The board may\nconstruct and maintain on such land suitable buildings and equip the\nsame for hospital purposes and, from time to time, enter into one or\nmore agreements with such membership hospital corporation for the\ncontrol and operation thereof, and such board of trustees may accept on\nsuch terms as the president of the United States shall prescribe, any\ngrants made by him pursuant to the provisions of the said national\nindustrial recovery act in aid of the establishment of the said\nhospital.\n  2. There shall be levied and assessed annually upon the taxable\nproperty in the said village in the manner prescribed by law a sum\nsufficient to defray the cost of the operation and maintenance of the\nsaid hospital in each year, as estimated by the board of trustees of\nsuch village.\n  3. Hospital corporations duly incorporated under the provisions of the\nmembership corporation law are hereby empowered to dedicate, grant and\nrelease to any such village lands for said purposes, upon terms and\nconditions to be approved by its board of governors, and to enter into\nagreements with the board of trustees of any such village for the\ncontrol, operation and maintenance of any hospital or hospitals to be\nconstructed as hereinbefore provided.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>