<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1706"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1706"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1706"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1706/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1706/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1706/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-17-1706/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1706">
        <num>17-1706</num>
        <heading>Succession of powers and duties relating to public bridges and highways</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 17-1706 Succession of powers and duties relating to public bridges\nand highways. In every such village all powers and duties granted to or\nimposed upon the town board of a town, or upon any officer of a town, in\nrelation to any public bridge or bridges, street or streets, highway or\nhighways, wholly or partly within such town, are hereby granted to and\nimposed upon the board of trustees of such village. The board of\ntrustees of any such village shall have full power and authority to\nrepair, replace, construct or re-construct any public bridge over any\nboundary of such village. If the project is to be paid from taxes levied\nfor the fiscal year in which the expenditure is to be made, the board of\ntrustees may submit to the voters of the village qualified to vote at\nsuch an election, a proposition for the repair, replacement,\nconstruction or re-construction of any such bridge partly at the expense\nof such village and such board of trustees shall also have power to\ncomplete any proceedings commenced under the town law, or under the\nhighway law, for the repair, replacement, construction or\nre-construction of any such bridge.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>