<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-18-1828"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-18-1828"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="18-1828"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-18-1828/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-18-1828/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-18-1828/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-18-1828/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_18_1828">
        <num>18-1828</num>
        <heading>Vote on commission report</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 18-1828 Vote on commission report. A commission appointed pursuant\nto this article shall report to the board of trustees within the time\nprovided in the local law creating such commission unless the board of\ntrustees, on its own motion, elects to extend such time, but in no\nevent, shall such time to report be extended more than ninety days. In\nthe event the commission prepares a local law establishing the position\nof village manager, such local law shall be filed with the board of\ntrustees who shall submit such local law to the village attorney or an\nattorney employed by the village to review the legal sufficiency of such\nlocal law. The attorney shall review such local law and report to the\nboard whether or not such local law complies with sections twenty and\ntwenty-seven of the municipal home rule law and whether such local law\nis consistent with the constitution and other laws of this state. If\nsuch local law be filed after the first day of the month in which the\ngeneral village election is to be held and before the first day of the\nmonth two months prior to the next general village election, a\nproposition for the approval of such local law shall be submitted at a\nspecial election of such village to be held not less than ten nor more\nthan sixty days after the filing of such petition. If such local law be\nso filed on or after the first day of the month two months prior to the\ndate on which the general village election is to be held and on or\nbefore the first day of the month in which the general village election\nis to be held, the proposition for the approval of such local law shall\nbe submitted at the said general village election. A special election\nhereunder shall be noticed, conducted, canvassed and otherwise held in\nthe same manner as provided in article nine of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>