<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-214"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-214"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-214"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-214/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-214/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_214">
        <num>2-214</num>
        <heading>Notice of election</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-214 Notice of election. No later than three days after the right\nto an election is complete, the commission shall direct the town clerk\nof each town in which any portion of such territory is located to post\nin six public places in that part of such territory located in such town\nand also to be published at least twice in the newspaper or newspapers\ndesignated pursuant to subdivision eleven of section sixty-four of the\ntown law, a joint notice by the clerks of all such towns that at a\nconvenient place in such territory, between the hours of twelve o'clock\nnoon and nine o'clock in the evening and on a day not less than twenty\nnor more than thirty days after the date of the posting and first\npublication, which date and place shall be specified therein, an\nelection will be held to determine whether the proposed village of\n(naming it) shall be incorporated. No later than five days after\nreceiving direction from the commission, the town clerk or clerks shall\nprovide to the commission a list of the six locations where such notices\nare to be posted. Should the commission object to any such locations\nsubmitted by the town clerk or clerks, the commission shall, no later\nthan seven business days after receipt of such list of locations, direct\nthe town clerk or clerks to post such notices in alternative locations\ndesignated by the commission. In such instance, the postings of such\nnotices shall be made by the town clerk or clerks no later than twenty\ndays after the right to an election is complete. Such election shall not\nbe held on a day of a town election or of a general election in a town\nin which any part of such territory is located. For the purposes of this\nsection, in the event that the town maintains a website, one of the\nposting requirements required by this section may be fulfilled by\nposting such information on the town's website. Such posting shall also\nbe made on the secretary of state's website.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>