<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-218"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-218"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-218"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-218/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-218/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_218">
        <num>2-218</num>
        <heading>Registration list of voters</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-218 Registration list of voters. 1. Preparation. It shall be the\nduty of the clerk of each town in which a portion of such territory is\nlocated to make and file in their office, at least twenty days before\nsuch election an accurate list of voters, alphabetically arranged, who\nare qualified to vote at such election. Such list shall be copied from\nthe registration poll records for the last preceding general election,\nand shall be modified in accordance with whatever information the town\nclerk may have or receive from the board of elections.\n  2. Inspection of and additions to registration list. At least three\ndays prior to such election and not on a Sunday the registration list\nfor such election shall be open for inspection by the public in the\noffice of the town clerk preparing same between the hours of twelve\no'clock noon and nine o'clock in the evening where and when any person\nclaiming to be qualified to vote at such election whose name is not\nincluded in the registration list of voters therefor may apply to such\nclerk for a revision of such list to include his or her name. The clerk,\nupon presentation of proper proofs showing that such person is or will\nat the time of such election be qualified to vote for town officers of\nsuch town as a resident of such territory, shall revise such list to\ninclude the name of such person.\n  3. Notice of availability of list for inspection and additions. Within\nten days after the right to an election is complete the town clerk of\neach town in which any portion of such territory is located shall cause\nto be posted in six public places in that part of such territory located\nin such town and also to be published at least twice in the newspaper or\nnewspapers designated pursuant to subdivision eleven of section\nsixty-four of the town law, a notice: that a registration list of voters\nqualified to vote at such election will be available for inspection in\ntheir office between the hours of twelve o'clock noon and nine o'clock\nin the evening on a day specified therein which day shall not be on a\nSunday and shall be at least three days prior to such election; that at\nsaid time and place said list will be available for inspection by the\npublic; and also that at said time and place persons claiming to be\nqualified to vote at such election whose names are not on such list may,\nupon presentation of proper proofs, have their names added thereto.\nPrior to posting, the town clerk or clerks shall provide to the\ncommission a list of the six locations where such notices are to be\nposted. Should the commission object to any such locations submitted by\nthe town clerk or clerks, the commission shall, no later than seven days\nafter receipt of such list of locations, direct the town clerk or clerks\nto post such notices in alternative locations designated by the\ncommission. The postings of such notices shall be made by the town clerk\nor clerks no later than twenty days after the right to an election is\ncomplete. For the purposes of this section, in the event that the town\nmaintains a website, one of the posting requirements required by this\nsubdivision may be fulfilled by posting such information on the town's\nwebsite.\n  4. No person shall be entitled to vote at such election whose name\ndoes not appear on the registration list of voters.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>