<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-220"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-220/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-220/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_220">
        <num>2-220</num>
        <heading>Conduct of election</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-220 Conduct of election. 1. Time and place. An election shall be\nheld at the time and place specified in the notice of election.\n  2. Manner of voting. Voting may be either by voting machine or by\npaper ballots. Paper ballots may be written or printed and shall be\nconsecutively numbered. Ballots shall contain the words "for\nincorporation" and "against incorporation".\n  3. Inspectors of election. The election shall be conducted by a board\nof inspectors of election consisting of the town clerks and supervisors\nof each town in which any portion of such territory is located. The town\nclerk of each such town shall serve a copy of the notice of election and\na notice of the composition of the board of inspectors of election upon\nthe supervisor or supervisors thereof at least ten days before the date\nfixed for such election. The town board or boards of such towns shall\nalso jointly designate four alternate members of the board of inspectors\nof election who shall be qualified voters of such territory to\nsubstitute for any of the original board of inspectors of election who\ndo not attend at the time and place fixed for such election. Notice of\nsuch designation together with copies of the notices herein required to\nbe served on supervisors shall be served on such designees at least ten\ndays prior to such election. If less than all of the officers\nconstituting the original board of inspectors of election attend at the\ntime and place fixed for the election, those attending shall appoint\nsuch number of the aforementioned alternate designees as are necessary\nto form a full board. The inspectors conducting the election shall\nreceive such compensation as shall be fixed by the town board or boards\nappointing them.\n  4. Powers and duties of inspectors. The inspectors shall execute the\nconstitutional oath of office and file same in the office of the town\nclerk wherein was filed a copy of the petition. They shall supervise and\nconduct such election and in connection therewith shall possess all the\npowers conferred by law upon a board of inspectors of election at a town\nelection, so far as the same are applicable.\n  5. Applicability of election law. The provisions of the election law\nnot inconsistent herewith shall apply to such election so far as the\nsame are practicable.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>