<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-224"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-224"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-224"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-224/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-224/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_224">
        <num>2-224</num>
        <heading>Review of election</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-224 Review of election. A person qualified to vote at such\nelection may, not more than ten days after the filing of the original of\nthe certificate of election, institute a proceeding to determine the\nvalidity or regularity of such election before the supreme court or any\njustice thereof within the judicial district in which such territory or\nany part of it is located.  Such court or justice thereof shall, in\nconnection therewith, determine any question arising and make such order\nas justice may require in respect to the validity and regularity of such\nelection. The proceeding shall be heard upon verified petition and such\noral or written proof as may be offered and, in addition to the notice\nhereinafter required, upon such further notice to such persons as the\ncourt or justice shall direct. The proceeding shall be summarily\ndetermined and shall have preference over all other causes in all\ncourts. Certified copies of the decision shall be filed in the office of\nthe clerk of each town in which any portion of such territory is\nlocated.  No costs shall be allowed to any party to such proceeding.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>