<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-232"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-232"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-232"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-232/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-232/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-232/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-232/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_232">
        <num>2-232</num>
        <heading>Report of incorporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-232 Report of incorporation. After ten and within fifteen days\nfrom the filing of the certificate of election certifying that a\nmajority of the votes cast were cast for incorporation and if no\nproceeding is instituted to review the validity and regularity of the\nelection or within fifteen days after the filing of a final\ndetermination in such a proceeding sustaining the validity and\nregularity of the election, the town clerk with whom the original of the\ncertificate of election was filed shall prepare and deliver a report of\nincorporation to the secretary of state, state comptroller, commissioner\nof taxation and finance and to the county clerk and county treasurer of\neach county and to the clerk of any other town in which any part of such\nterritory is located. Such report of incorporation shall include:\n  a. A copy of the certificate of election certified by the inspectors\nof election.\n  b. A statement that the time to institute a proceeding for a review of\nthe election has expired and that no such proceeding has been commenced;\nor a certified copy of the final determination, if any, of the court or\njustice sustaining the results of the election.\n  c. An outline map and a metes and bounds description of the territory\nwithin such village which the clerk shall furnish or cause to be\nprepared at the original expense of the towns in which such territory is\nlocated. Such original expense shall be borne equally by each such town\nunless otherwise agreed.\n  d. A statement of the population of the territory as it appears by the\nexhibit attached to the petition for incorporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>