<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-234"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-234"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-234"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_234">
        <num>2-234</num>
        <heading>Date and certificate of incorporation and effective dates</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-234 Date and certificate of incorporation and effective dates. 1.\nThe secretary of state upon receipt of the report of incorporation shall\nforthwith file same in his office and, in a certificate of\nincorporation, shall certify, under the seal of his office, to the clerk\nof each town in which any portion of such territory is located that said\nreport has been filed in his office giving the date of filing thereof.\nThe village shall be incorporated as of the date of the filing of said\nreport; provided, however, that such incorporation shall only become\neffective on the following dates for the following purposes:\n  a. from the date of incorporation:\n  (1) to perform any and all acts authorized in sections 2-236 through\n2-250 inclusive, hereof\n  (2) to appoint a village clerk, treasurer, attorney\n  (3) to hold meetings of the board of trustees\n  (4) to appoint a zoning commission\n  (5) to engage necessary clerical assistants to the clerk\n  (6) to designate an official newspaper\n  (7) to fix the compensation of and to pay all salaries, fees, costs\nand disbursements in connection with any of the foregoing and to borrow\nby tax anticipation notes in the manner provided in the local finance\nlaw, such money as may be needed to make such payments.\n  (8) such officers, commission, and employees as are authorized by this\nparagraph shall have power to perform their necessary duties.\n  b. from the first day of January next succeeding the date of\nincorporation:\n  (1) to perform all acts and fulfill all requirements of title two of\narticle fourteen of the real property tax law\n  (2) to perform all acts and fulfill all requirements of this chapter\nin the article entitled "Finances".\n  (3) to pay all necessary costs and disbursements in connection with\nthe foregoing and to borrow by tax anticipation notes in the manner\nprovided in the local finance law, such money as may be needed to make\nsuch payments.\n  c. from the first day of June following the first day of January next\nsucceeding the date of incorporation, to have and exercise all the\nrights, powers, duties, privileges and immunities granted villages by\nthe constitution or any other provision of law.\n  2. The town clerks of all towns in which any part of such territory is\nlocated shall, uopn the appointment of the village clerk as provided in\nsection 2-240 of this article, deliver to said clerk the certificates of\nincorporation filed with them for permanent inclusion in the official\nrecords of said village.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>