<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-242"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-242"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-242"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-242/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-242/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-242/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-242/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_242">
        <num>2-242</num>
        <heading>First election of officers, terms of office</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-242 First election of officers, terms of office. 1. Except as\nprovided in section 17-1703 of this chapter, an election, which shall be\ndeemed a special election, shall be held pursuant to the election law in\nthe village no more than sixty days after the appointment of the village\nclerk.\n  2. At such first election a mayor and four trustees shall be chosen.\n  3. If such first election be held on or after the first Monday in\nApril and before the first Monday of October in any one year, the terms\nof office of two of the trustees shall expire at noon on the first\nMonday in April next succeeding such first election.\n  4. If such first election be held at any other time, the terms of\noffice of such two trustees shall expire one year after the first Monday\nin April next succeeding such first election.\n  5. The terms of office of the mayor and the other two trustees shall\nexpire at noon on the first Monday in April next succeeding the\nexpiration of the terms of office of the first two trustees above\nmentioned.\n  6. The terms of office of officers elected under this section commence\nas soon as they have qualified in the manner hereinafter provided in\nthis chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>