<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-244"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-244"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2-244"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-244/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-244/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-244/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-2-244/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_244">
        <num>2-244</num>
        <heading>Notice of election, appointment of inspectors</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2-244 Notice of election, appointment of inspectors. 1. Within ten\ndays after his appointment, the village clerk shall cause to be\nconspicuously posted, in at least six public places in the village, and\nalso to be published at least once in a newspaper of general circulation\ntherein, a notice of such election specifying the time and place of\nholding the election, the hours of opening and closing the polls which\nshall be from twelve o'clock noon to nine o'clock in the evening, and\nthe offices and the terms thereof to be filled. For the purposes of this\nsection, in the event that the village maintains a website, one of the\nposting requirements required by this subdivision may be fulfilled by\nposting such information on the website.\n  2. Also within ten days after his appointment the village clerk shall\nappoint four persons qualified to vote at the first election of officers\nto serve as inspectors of such election. The persons so appointed shall\nfile their constitutional oath of office with the village clerk within\nthree days after their appointment.\n  3. The provisions of this section shall not apply to villages\nincorporated to embrace the entire territory of a town.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>