<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-20-2006"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-20-2006"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="20-2006"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-20-2006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-20-2006/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-20-2006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-20-2006/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20_2006">
        <num>20-2006</num>
        <heading>Violation of ordinances</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 20-2006 Violation of ordinances. 1. The board of trustees of a\nvillage may enforce obedience to its ordinances adopted prior to\nSeptember first, nineteen hundred seventy-four as follows:\n  a. by prescribing therefor fines for each violation thereof not to\nexceed two hundred fifty dollars. b. by prescribing therefor that for\neach violation thereof it shall constitute a violation pursuant to the\npenal law.  However, in no case shall the fine imposed exceed two\nhundred fifty dollars.  c. in all cases the board of trustees may\nenforce obedience of its ordinances by injunction.\n  1-a. A violation of a zoning ordinance adopted prior to September\nfirst, nineteen hundred seventy-four is hereby declared to be an\noffense, punishable by a fine not exceeding three hundred fifty dollars\nor imprisonment for a period not to exceed six months, or both for\nconviction of a first offense; for conviction of a second offense both\nof which were committed within a period of five years, punishable by a\nfine not less than three hundred fifty dollars nor more than seven\nhundred dollars or imprisonment for a period not to exceed six months,\nor both; and, upon conviction for a third or subsequent offense all of\nwhich were committed within a period of five years, punishable by a fine\nnot less than seven hundred dollars nor more than one thousand dollars\nor imprisonment for a period not to exceed six months, or both. However,\nfor the purpose of conferring jurisdiction upon courts and judicial\nofficers generally, violations of such zoning ordinance shall be deemed\nmisdemeanors and for such purpose only all provisions of law relating to\nmisdemeanors shall apply to such violations. Each week's continued\nviolation shall constitute a separate additional violation.\n  2. Except as otherwise provided by subdivision two-a, upon the\nadoption of a resolution by the board of trustees of a village\nauthorizing the village attorney or an attorney other than the one\nregularly employed to prosecute a violator of a village ordinance or\nlocal law or a person accused of committing any offense, infraction or\ncriminal act within the village and providing the village attorney or an\nattorney other than the one regularly employed is designated as an\nassistant district attorney, as provided by law, to prosecute in the\nname of the people of the state of New York, the violator of a village\nordinance or local law or a person accused of committing any offense,\ninfraction or criminal act within the village, the board of trustees may\npay a reasonable compensation to such village attorney or an attorney\nother than the one regularly employed therefor.\n  2-a. On the adoption of a resolution by the board of trustees of a\nvillage within a county having a population of more than one million\ninhabitants and adjacent to a city having a population of more than one\nmillion inhabitants, authorizing a village attorney or an attorney,\nother than one regularly employed, to prosecute in the village courts of\nsuch county a violator of a village ordinance or local law, or a person\naccused of committing any offense, infraction or criminal act within the\nvillage, such attorney may prosecute in the name of the people of the\nstate of New York and the board of trustees may pay a reasonable\ncompensation to such attorney. Nothing herein shall be construed to\nabrogate or otherwise limit the authority of the district attorney of\nsuch a county to prosecute an offense cognizable by a village court\nwithin such a county.\n  3. Any ordinance or local law heretofore adopted by the board of\ntrustees of any village which provides that any person violating such\nordinance or local law shall be a disorderly person shall continue to be\nvalid and any violator of such ordinance or local law may be prosecuted\npursuant to the criminal procedure law for the violation of a petty\noffense and such disorderly person shall be deemed to have committed a\npetty offense.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>