<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-308"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-308"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-308"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-308/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-308/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-308/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-308/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_308">
        <num>3-308</num>
        <heading>Separate boards of commissioners</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-308 Separate boards of commissioners. 1. The board of trustees may\nestablish or abolish a board or boards of fire, ambulance, water, light,\nsewer, park or cemetery commissioners or a single municipal board having\nthe powers, duties and responsibilities of two or more such separate\nboards.\n  2. The board of trustees may also establish or abolish a separate\nboard of police commissioners.\n  3. The board of trustees shall establish the composition, powers,\nduties and responsibilities of each board of commissioners and may, from\ntime to time, amend same.\n  4. Any board established hereunder shall be composed of not less than\nthree members, who shall perform their duties subject to the approval of\nthe board of trustees.\n  5. The mayor, subject to the approval of the board of trustees, shall\nappoint the members of any board of commissioners and the first\nappointments of members thereto shall be for terms so fixed that at\nleast one will expire at the end of each official year commencing at the\nend of the current such year and continuing in succeeding year until the\nentire original appointments run out. No such term shall exceed five\nyears.\n  6. Commencing with the first annual meeting following the\nestablishment of any such board, and continuing annually thereafter,\nsuccessors to former appointees, the term of whose offices have then\nexpired, shall be appointed for a full term. The length of such term\nshall be determined by the board of trustees but in no event shall\nexceed five years.\n  7. A person who has been convicted of arson in any degree shall not be\neligible for appointment to any board of fire commissioners. Any fire\ncommissioner who is convicted of arson in any degree during his term of\noffice shall be disqualified from completing such term of office.\n  8. The board of trustees may also abolish any such board or boards\nestablished under any prior provision of law. If not so abolished such\nboard or boards shall continue and the commissioners thereof shall\ncontinue in office during their respective terms.\n  9. Any action of the board of trustees hereunder establishing,\nrelating to or abolishing any such board or fixing the terms of office\nof the members thereof shall be by resolution or local law adopted at a\nregular meeting by a majority vote of the entire board. No such action\nshall be taken unless a public hearing has first been held of which at\nleast ten days public notice shall have been given by publication in the\nofficial village newspaper, or, if there be none, in a newspaper of\ngeneral circulation in the village.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>