<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-304"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_304">
        <num>3-304</num>
        <heading>Changing number of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-304 Changing number of trustees. The board of trustees by\nresolution or local law, subject to permissive referendum, may change\nthe number of trustees. Such action shall be in accordance with the\nfollowing:\n  a. If the number of trustees be increased, the additional trustees\nshall be elected at the next general village election when trustees are\nregularly scheduled to be elected.  At that election half of the\nadditional trustees shall be elected for a single term equal to half of\nthe full term for which said office is regularly scheduled to be filled\nand the other half for a full such term. At all subsequent general\nvillage elections such offices shall be filled for full terms.\n  b. If the number of trustees be reduced, no trustees shall be elected,\nother than to fill an unexpired term, until by expiration of terms of\noffice the number of trustees in office shall equal that prescribed by\nsuch resolution. Thereafter at the next general village election\none-half of such prescribed number of trustees shall be elected for a\nsingle term equal to half of the full term for which said office is\nregularly scheduled to be filled and the other half of such trustees\nshall be elected for a full term. At all subsequent general village\nelections such offices shall be filled for full terms.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>