<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-08-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-301"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_301">
        <num>3-301</num>
        <heading>Village officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-301 Village officers. 1. Every village shall have the following\nofficers:\n  a. a mayor;\n  b. four trustees, except that the board of trustees of a village may\nchange the number of trustees as authorized by section 3-304 of this\narticle;\n  c. a treasurer;\n  d. a clerk.\n  2. Any village may have the following officers:\n  a. except as provided in section 3-303 of this article, no more than\ntwo village justices, but in the event a village has one justice, it\nshall also have an associate justice who shall serve when requested by\nthe village justice or in the absence or inability of the village\njustice to serve. The office of village justice is continued in every\nvillage in which it is now established. The board of trustees of any\nother village may establish such office by resolution or local law,\nsubject to a permissive referendum. The board of trustees of any village\nby resolution or local law, subject to permissive referendum, may\nabolish such office, but to take effect only upon the expiration of the\nthen current term of such office, or establish the office of additional\nvillage justices, which justice once elected shall have all the powers\nand duties of a village justice. The resolution or local law in the\nlatter case shall provide for a term pursuant to section 3-302 of this\narticle. The clerk of the court of a village shall be discharged from\nemployment only upon the advice and consent of the village justice or\njustices when the clerk, in his or her village duties, works solely for\nthe village justice or justices.\n  b. assessor or assessors, provided, however, that the board of\ntrustees by resolution or local law may consolidate the offices of\nclerk, treasurer, and assessor or any two of such offices. The board of\ntrustees may also determine, by local law or resolution, that such board\nof trustees shall act as the board of assessors or may appoint such\nboard from their members. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of\nthis paragraph, a village which has enacted a local law as provided in\nsubdivision three of section fourteen hundred two of the real property\ntax law shall not have an assessor or assessors in any year in which\nsuch local law is in effect.\n  c. such other officers, including deputies, as the board of trustees\nshall determine, provided, however, that the board of trustees by\nresolution or local law may consolidate the offices of deputy clerk, and\ndeputy treasurer.\n  3. The mayor, trustees and village justices shall be elective\nofficers.  All other officers shall be appointed by the mayor, subject\nto the approval of the board of trustees.\n  4. The mayor and the trustees of a village shall constitute the board\nof trustees thereof.\n  5. A person who has been convicted of a felony pursuant to the laws of\nthis state or who has been convicted in federal court or in another\nstate for a crime or offense that would constitute a felony under the\nlaws of this state shall be permanently ineligible to be a candidate for\nvillage justice or to be appointed or continue to hold such office.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>