<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-300"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-300"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-09-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-300"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-300/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-300/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-300/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-3-300/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_300">
        <num>3-300</num>
        <heading>Eligibility for election or appointment to, and continuance in office</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_300__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the board of trustees\nof a village may provide, in lieu of any other residency requirement\nimposed by law, that any appointed village officer may reside within a\ncounty in which the village is wholly or partially situated,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3_300__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nboard of trustees of a village with a population of less than three\nthousand may provide, in lieu of any other residency requirement imposed\nby law, that the village justice may reside within a county in which the\nvillage is wholly or partially situate.\n  3. No person shall simultaneously hold an elective and an appointive\nvillage office except that: not more than two members of the board of\ntrustees may be members of each board and commission; members of the\nboard of trustees may be single commissioners in charge of village\ndepartments except as provided in the zoning article in this chapter.\n  4. Except as is otherwise provided by law, no person shall be\ndisqualified from holding a village office by reason of holding any\npublic office unless such public officer could not fully discharge the\nduties and obligations of the village office while carrying out the\nduties and obligations of any such other office.\n  * 5. Notwithstanding any provisions of this chapter or any other\ngeneral law, local law, ordinance or special act, the village board of\ntrustees of the incorporated village of Croton-on-Hudson, Westchester\ncounty, may, by resolution, provide that the village clerk of the\nvillage of Croton-on-Hudson, Westchester county, need not be a resident\nof said village but must be a resident of New York state.\n  * NB (Expired first Monday of the month following general village\nelection, 1980)\n  6. Notwithstanding any provisions of this chapter or any other general\nlaw, local law, ordinance or special act, the village board of trustees\nof the incorporated village of New Square, Rockland county, may, by\nresolution, provide that the village justice of the village of New\nSquare, Rockland county, need not be a resident of said village but must\nbe a resident of New York state.\n  7. Notwithstanding any provisions of this chapter or any other general\nlaw, local law, ordinance or special act, the village board of trustees\nof the incorporated villa...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>