<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-4-412"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-4-412"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4-412"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-4-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-4-412/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-4-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-4-412/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4_412">
        <num>4-412</num>
        <heading>The board of trustees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in clause (ii) of this subparagraph, prior\nto commencing the negotiation process for such contract with an\nincorporated fire company, the incorporated fire company shall file with\nthe board of trustees a statement itemizing the estimated costs of the\nincorporated fire company attributable to the provision of services\nunder the prospective contract. The estimated costs attributable to the\nprovision of services under the prospective contract itemized in the\nstatement shall include, at a minimum, those, if any, for: supplies;\nmaterials; operation, maintenance and repair of equipment and apparatus;\ninsurance; training; protective clothing, gear and other personnel\ncosts; building rental, maintenance and operation; and a specified\nproportionate share of capital costs. If the fire company is required to\nprepare any of the following documents, copies shall be included with\nthe statement:\n  (A) the fire company's most recent annual report of directors pursuant\nto section five hundred nineteen of the not-for-profit corporation law;\n  (B) the fire company's most recent verified certificate pursuant to\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_412__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen hundred two of the not-for-profit\ncorporation law;\n  (C) the fire company's most recent internal revenue service form 990;\nand\n  (D) the fire company's most recent annual report pursuant to section\nthirty-a of the general municipal law.\n  (ii) Upon good cause shown, the board of trustees may, by resolution,\nwaive in whole or in part the requirement that the fire company file the\nstatement, and copies of documents, required by clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubparagraph.\n  b. The period for which such service may be furnished under any such\ncontract shall not exceed five years. The contract shall specify a\ndefinite sum to be paid each year for such service. No such contract\nshall be entered into until a public hearing has been held by the board\nof trustees. Notice of such hearing shall be published at least once in\nat least one newspaper having general circulation in the village. Such\nnotice shall specify the time when and place where said hearing will be\nheld, and describe in general terms the proposed contract. The first\npublication thereof shall be at least ten days prior to the day\nspecified for such hearing.\n  c. By mutual consent of the contracting parties, and after a public\nhearing held pursuant to notice in the manner aforesaid, any such\ncontract heretofore or hereafter executed may be</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>amended,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nterminated, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>terminated and a new contract may be entered into in\nlieu thereof, if the board of trustees, after such hearing, shall\ndetermine, by resolution, that it is in the public interest so to do.\nSuch notice shall state in general terms the reason why any existing\ncontract is to be amended or terminated, and if a new contract is to be\nentered into the notice shall also describe the new contract in general\nterms.\n  d. The provisions of this subdivision shall not be deemed to have\namended subdivision two of section two hundred nine-b or section two\nhundred nine-d of the general municipal law, or any other general,\nspecial or local law requiring the consent of a fire department, fire\ncompany or an emergency rescue and first aid squad to the entering into\nof a contract for services to be performed by such department, company\nor squad.\n  e. The term "fire protection", as used in this section, includes\ninspections of buildings and properties in the village or portion\nthereof, requir...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Air rights and subsurface areas. May, in addition to such powers\nas may be granted by any other law, lease to any person, firm or\ncorporation, for commercial or private use, the air rights over or the\nsubsurface area under any property of the village acquired or to be\nacquired for street purposes, public parking garages, parking spaces or\npublic off-street loading facilities. Such lease may only be entered\ninto when such air rights or subsurface areas are not needed for village\npurposes. Any such lease may be for a term not exceeding fifty years and\nmay be renewed for such additional term or terms as the board of\ntrustees may provide. Any such lease shall contain provisions requiring\nthe lessee to construct facilities adequate to support and maintain,\nwithout interference, the village parking or off-street loading\nfacilities being conducted by the village and in such manner as to\nminimize or avoid the relocation of public utility facilities and may\nalso contain such other...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Every officer, board or agency of a village shall let all\ncontracts for public work and all purchase contracts to the lowest\nresponsible bidder after advertisement for bids where so required by\nsection one hundred three of the general municipal law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An officer or person who assumes to create a liability or\nappropriate money or property of the village without authority of law,\nor assents thereto, is personally liable for such debt, or to the\nvillage for such money or property. Each member of a village board\npresent at a meeting thereof when such unlawful action is taken is\ndeemed to have assented thereto, unless he expressly dissents and\nrequests such dissent to be entered upon the minutes of the meeting. If\nany person shall have heretofore appropriated or shall hereafter\nappropriate money or preperty of the village, contrary to law, and the\nfacts in relation thereto are known to the board of trustees, and, after\nthis section as amended takes effect, such board fail for thirty days to\nbring an action against such person to recover such money or property,\neach member of the board having such knowledge shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor and liable to removal from office unless within such period\nof thirty days he shall fi...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_4_412__subsec_i__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Loitering. May prohibit and punish loitering; provided however,\nthat such ordinance or law shall only prohibit loitering for a specific\nillegal purpose or loitering in a specific place of restricted public\naccess and shall therein set forth guidelines for application of such\nprohibitions by law enforcement officers so as to prevent arbitrary or\ndiscriminatory enforcement of such prohibitions.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>