<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-506"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-506"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-11-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-506"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-506/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-506/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_506">
        <num>5-506</num>
        <heading>Form and content of tentative budget</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-506 Form and content of tentative budget. 1. The tentative budget\nshall consist of the following schedules and statements:\n  a. A schedule of appropriations for all expenses authorized or\nrequired by law, other than expenses of operation of a municipal\nelectric, gas or steam utility service, or a water utility for which an\nannual estimate is not filed pursuant to subdivision five of section\n5-502 of this article, and also for all expenditures to be financed from\nspecial assessments and proceeds of obligations authorized by the local\nfinance law. The appropriations shown on such schedule shall be\nclassified by funds, administrative units, character and object of\nexpenditure and shall be so arranged as to show in parallel columns the\nfollowing comparative information:\n  (1) Expenditures for the last completed fiscal year;\n  (2) Appropriations for the current fiscal year reflecting supplemental\nappropriations to a date not more than forty-five days prior to the\nfiling of the tentative budget with the village clerk; and\n  (3) The budget officer's recommended appropriations for the ensuing\nfiscal year. Such schedule may contain an amount recommended as\nnecessary to be appropriated for contingencies, which amount shall not\nexceed ten per centum of the total of other appropriations excluding\ndebt service and judgments. A statement of the amount recommended to be\nappropriated for a reserve for uncollected taxes may also be included,\nwhich amount shall be not less than the principal amount of taxes levied\nby the board of trustees for the last completed fiscal year and\nremaining uncollected at the end of such year, including the amount of\nsuch taxes sold to the village at tax sale and unredeemed at the end of\nsuch last completed fiscal year.\n  b. A schedule of estimated revenues to be received by the village\nduring the ensuing fiscal year other than real estate taxes to be levied\nas stated in paragraph e of subdivision one of this section, income from\noperations of a municipal electric, gas or steam utility service or a\nwater utility for which an annual estimate is not filed, pursuant to\nsubdivision five of section 5-502 of this article, proceeds of special\nassessments for capital projects and proceeds of obligations authorized\nby the local finance law. The estimated revenues shown on such schedule\nshall be classified by funds and itemized as to sources and shall be so\narranged as to show in parallel columns the following comparative\ninformation:\n  (1) revenues for the last completed fiscal year;\n  (2) estimated revenues for the current fiscal year reflecting\nmodifications to a date not more than forty-five days prior to the\nfiling of the tentative budget with the village clerk; and\n  (3) the budget officer's estimate of revenues for the ensuing fiscal\nyear.\n  c. A schedule of fund balances estimated to be on hand at the close of\nthe current fiscal year, classified by funds, together with a breakdown\nof such fund balance estimated for encumbrances, amounts appropriated\nfor the ensuing fiscal year's budget, amounts reserved for stated\npurposes pursuant to law, including reserve funds established pursuant\nto the general municipal law, and the remaining unappropriated\nunreserved fund balance, provided that the remaining estimated\nunappropriated unreserved fund balance for each fund shall not exceed a\nreasonable amount, consistent with prudent budgeting practices,\nnecessary to ensure the orderly operation of village government and the\ncontinued provision of services, taking into account factors including,\nbut not limited to, the size of the fund, cash flows, the certainty with\nwhich the amounts of revenues and expenditures can be estimated, and the\nvillage's experience in prior fiscal years. Such schedule shall not\ninclude fund balance of any fund established as the result of issuance\nand sale of obligations pursuant to the provisions of the local finance\nlaw.\n  d. A schedule of each special reserve fund showing for each such fund\nthe purpose for which established and by parallel columns the amount\ntherein as of a date not more than forty-five days prior to the filing\nof the tentative budget, and the amount, if any, recommended to be spent\ntherefrom to meet appropriations for the ensuing fiscal year. A\nrequirement of law that an expenditure from any such reserve fund be\nsubject to a permissive or mandatory referendum shall not prevent the\ninclusion of a recommendation for such expenditure in the tentative\nbudget.\n  e. A schedule showing the computation of the amount to be levied on\nreal estate which amount shall be equal to the difference between the\ntotal of all recommended appropriations as shown in the schedule\nrequired by paragraph a of subdivision one of this section and the total\nof estimates shown in the schedules required by paragraph b through d of\nsubdivision one of this section. Such schedule shall be so arranged as\nto show such recommendations and estimates by funds in parallel columns.\n  f. A schedule of wages and salaries to be paid which shall be\nsubdivided by administrative units and shall show in parallel columns,\nfor each office or position of employment, the title, the number of\npersons in the title, the recommended rate of compensation for the title\nand the total recommended appropriation for the title.\n  g. A statement of the estimated income and proposed expenditures of a\nmunicipal electric, gas or steam utility service or a water utility for\nwhich an annual estimate is not filed, pursuant to subdivision five of\nsection 5-502 of this article which shall be in the form and detail\nprescribed in subdivision four of section 5-502 of this article.\n  2. The tentative budget shall include any other data which the board\nof trustees may, by resolution, require or which the budget officer\nshall deem advisable.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>