<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-510"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-510"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-510"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-510/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-510/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-510/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-510/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_510">
        <num>5-510</num>
        <heading>Change in fiscal years</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-510 Change in fiscal years. l. The board of trustees of any\nvillage may, by resolution, adopt a fiscal year to commence on the first\nday of August and end on the thirty-first day of July.  If the board of\ntrustees shall so adopt a fiscal year commencing on the first day of\nAugust as aforesaid, all of the provisions of this article and of the\nreal property tax law fixing times or dates within which or by which\ncertain acts shall be performed in relation to the preparation of the\nassessment roll, the preparation of the budget and the levy and\ncollection of taxes and special assessments shall be correspondingly\nchanged so that the collection of taxes shall commence on the first day\nof the fiscal year.\n  2. The board of trustees of a village which has elected, pursuant to\nformer section one hundred seventeen of the village law as enacted by\nsection fourteen of chapter eight hundred nine of the laws of nineteen\nhundred fifty-four, to retain its fiscal year or which has adopted or\nhereafter adopts, pursuant to this section, a fiscal year commencing on\nthe first day of August may, at any time determine, by resolution, to\nchange to a fiscal year commencing on the first day of June.\n  3. The board of trustees of a village which has enacted a local law as\nprovided in subdivision three of section fourteen hundred two of the\nreal property tax law may, by resolution, adopt a fiscal year to\ncoincide with the fiscal year of the town or towns or county within\nwhich the village is located. If the board of trustees shall adopt such\na fiscal year, all of the provisions of this article and of the real\nproperty tax law fixing times or dates within which or by which certain\nacts shall be performed in relation to the preparation of the budget and\nthe levy and collection of taxes and special assessments shall be\ncorrespondingly changed so that the collection of taxes shall commence\non the first day of the fiscal year.\n  4. A certified copy of a resolution adopting a new fiscal year shall\nbe filed within ten days in the office of the state department of audit\nand control at Albany, New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>