<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-525"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-525"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-525"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-525/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-525/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-525/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-525/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_525">
        <num>5-525</num>
        <heading>Purchasing of products for public use</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-525 Purchasing of products for public use. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of section one hundred three of the general municipal law,\nwhen purchasing products the officer, board or agency of a village may,\nwherever recycled products meet contract specifications and the price of\nsuch products is reasonably competitive, purchase such products. For the\npurpose of this section and until July first, nineteen hundred\nninety-six, "recycled product" shall mean any product which has been\nmanufactured from secondary materials, as defined in subdivision one of\nsection two hundred sixty-one of the economic development law, and meets\nsecondary material content requirements adopted by the office of general\nservices under subdivision one of section one hundred seventy-seven of\nthe state finance law for products available to the village under state\ncontract or, if no such contract for such product is available, any\nproduct which meets the secondary material content requirements adopted\nby the village with respect to a specific commodity procurement by the\nvillage. After July first, nineteen hundred ninety-six, "recycled\nproduct" shall mean, for the purposes of this section, any product which\nis manufactured from secondary materials, as defined in subdivision one\nof section two hundred sixty-one of the economic development law, and\nwhich meets the requirements of subdivision two of section 27-0717 of\nthe environmental conservation law and regulations promulgated pursuant\nthereto. For the purpose of this section, "reasonably competitive" shall\nmean that the cost of the recycled product does not exceed a cost\npremium of ten percent above the cost of a comparable product that is\nnot a recycled product or, if at least fifty percent of the secondary\nmaterials utilized in the manufacture of that product is generated from\nthe waste stream in New York state, the cost of the recycled product\ndoes not exceed a cost premium of fifteen percent above the cost of a\ncomparable product that is not a recycled product.\n  Whenever such officer, board or agency shall purchase or cause the\npurchase of printing on recycled paper pursuant to this section, he or\nshe shall require the printed material to contain the official state\nrecycling emblem established pursuant to subdivision two of section\n27-0717 of the environmental conservation law and regulations\npromulgated pursuant thereto if such paper has been approved by the\ndepartment of environmental conservation as satisfying the requirements\nof such statute and regulations, or, if such paper has not been so\napproved, require the printed material to include a printed statement\nwhich indicates the percentages of pre-consumer and post-consumer\nrecycled material content of such paper.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>