<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-528"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-528"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5-528"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-5-528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5_528">
        <num>5-528</num>
        <heading>Appropriations to maintain municipal conferences and associations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5-528 Appropriations to maintain municipal conferences and\nassociations. l. The board of trustees of any village is hereby\nauthorized to annually include in the budget and raise by taxation a sum\nto meet its proportionate share of the actual and necessary expenses of\nmaintaining and continuing the conference of mayors and other municipal\nofficials of the state of New York and any of its activities in this\nstate for the purpose of devising practical ways and means for obtaining\ngreater economy and efficiency in the government thereof.\n  2. The board of trustees of any village is hereby authorized and\nempowered to include annually in the budget and raise by taxation in\nsuch village, a sum sufficient to defray the proportionate share of such\nvillage to meet the actual and necessary expenses of maintaining and\ncontinuing a conference of village officials of the villages in the\ncounty in which such village is located or a conference composed of\nvillage officials of villages located in an area of adjoining counties,\nand any of its activities in this state, for the purpose of devising\npractical ways and means of promoting and obtaining greater economy and\nefficiency in the government of such village.\n  3. The board in control of an electric utility, owned and operated by\nthe village is hereby authorized to pay from the proceeds of the\noperation of said utility its proportionate share of the actual and\nnecessary expenses of maintaining and continuing the municipal electric\nutilities association of the state of New York, and any of its\nactivities in this state, for the purpose of devising practical ways and\nmeans for obtaining greater economy and efficiency in the operation of\nmunicipally owned electric light plants.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>