<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-610"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-610"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-610"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-610/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-610/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_610">
        <num>6-610</num>
        <heading>Dedication of streets</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-610 Dedication of streets. An owner of land in a village who has\nlaid out a street thereon may dedicate such street, or any part thereof,\nor an easement therein, to the village for a public street, or an owner\nmay dedicate for such purpose land not laid out as a street. Upon an\noffer in writing by the owner to make such a dedication, the board of\ntrustees may, by resolution, determine to accept a dedication of the\nwhole or any part of the land described in such offer or the whole or\nany part of such street, to be described in such resolution. Upon the\nadoption of such a resolution the owner may execute and deliver to the\nvillage clerk a proper conveyance of the land to be dedicated. The board\nof trustees may by resolution, accept the conveyance, and the\nconveyance, shall thereupon be recorded in the office of the county\nclerk. Upon the acceptance of the conveyance the land described therein\nshall become and be a public street of the village. No street less than\ntwo rods in width shall be accepted by dedication, unless the resolution\nadopting same is passed by unanimous vote of the board of trustees. All\noffers of dedication must be entered at length in the minutes of the\nboard of trustees.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>