<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-624"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-624"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-624"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-624/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-624/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_624">
        <num>6-624</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of lands for parks, squares, athletic fields and playgrounds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-624 Acquisition of lands for parks, squares, athletic fields and\nplaygrounds. The board of trustees may, on behalf of the village, accept\nby grant or devise a gift of land for a public park, square, athletic\nfield or playground, within the village or wholly within five miles of\nthe boundaries thereof, or may, if such land is outside of the village\nand wholly within three miles of the boundaries thereof, upon the\nadoption of a resolution by unanimous vote purchase such land\naccordingly. If unable to agree with the owners for the purchase\nthereof, the board of trustees on behalf of the village may acquire\ntitle thereto by condemnation. If such land is within the village, the\nboard of trustees on behalf of the village may upon the adoption of a\nresolution, purchase such land accordingly, or if unable to agree with\nthe owners for the purchase thereof, may acquire title thereto by\ncondemnation. The board of trustees may lease in the name of the\nvillage, lands within the village or outside of such village and wholly\nwithin three miles of the boundaries thereof for a public park, athletic\nfield or playground and may equip the same with suitable buildings,\nstructures and apparatus and may thereafter maintain and improve the\nsame at the expense of the village. The amount of such rent shall be\npaid in annual installments commencing with the date of the lease. Upon\nthe acquition of land for the purposes of this section, either by gift,\npurchase or lease, the board may establish and maintain the same for its\nintended purposes and shall have the power to perform all the duties of\na separate board of park commissioners as provided for in this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>