<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-622"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-622"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-622"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-622/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-622/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-622/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-6-622/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_622">
        <num>6-622</num>
        <heading>Pavements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-622 Pavements. The board of trustees may cause a street in the\nvillage or a part thereof, to be graded and paved or repaved wholly at\nthe expense of the village, or wholly at the expense of the owners of\nthe adjoining land or partly at the expense of each. If the street or\npart thereof is wholly within the village, but the exterior line thereof\nconstitutes the village boundary, such improvements may be made as to\nthe part of such street within the village either wholly at the expense\nof the village or wholly at the expense of the owners of adjoining land\nwithin and without the village or partly at the expense of each.  Before\nany such street or portion thereof is graded or paved, wholly or partly\nat the expense of the owners of the adjoining land, a hearing shall be\nheld and notice thereof given as hereinbefore provided for. If such\nexpense, or any part thereof, is to be assessed upon adjoining land, the\nboard of trustees may apportion it upon the lands and assess the same as\na whole or by installments.  Provided, however, where a street is so\nimproved wholly at the expense of the owners of the adjoining land, the\ncost thereof shall be assessed in proportion, as nearly as may be, to\nthe benefit which each lot or parcel will derive therefrom.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>