<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-706"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-706"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-706"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-706/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-706/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-706/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-706/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_706">
        <num>7-706</num>
        <heading>Method of procedure</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_706__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the property of the housing authority erecting or owning a housing\nproject authorized under the public housing law; upon the executive\ndirector of such housing authority and the chief executive officer of\nthe municipality providing financial assistance thereto;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_706__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the boundary of a city, village or town; upon the clerk thereof;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_706__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the boundary of a county; upon the clerk of the board of\nsupervisors or other person performing like duties;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_706__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the boundary of a state park or parkway; upon the regional state\npark commission having jurisdiction over such state park or parkway.\n  3. Public hearing. The public, including those served notice pursuant\nto subdivision two of this section, shall have the opportunity to be\nheard at the public hearing. Those parties set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_706__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_706__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_706__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_706__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section, however, shall not\nhave the right of review by a court as hereinafter provided.\n  4. Additional requirements.  The procedural requirements set forth\nherein shall be in addition to the requirements of the provisions of\nsections two hundred thirty-nine-l and two hundred thirty-nine-m of the\ngeneral municipal law relating to review by a county planning board or\nagency or regional planning council; the provisions of the state\nenvironmental quality review act under article eight of the\nenvironmental conservation law and its implementing regulations which\nare codified in part six hundred seventeen of title six of the New York\ncodes, rules and regulations and any other general laws relating to land\nuse and any amendments thereto.\n  5. Filing. Every zoning law and every amendment thereto (excluding any\nmap incorporated therein) adopted pursuant to the provisions of this\nchapter shall be entered in the minutes of the village board and a copy,\nsummary or abstract thereof (exclusive of any map incorporated therein)\nshall be published once in the official newspaper and a copy of such\nlocal law or amendment together with a summary or abstract of any map\nincorporated therein shall be posted conspicuously at or near the main\nentrance to the office of the village clerk and affidavits of the\npublication and posting thereof shall be filed with the village clerk.\nSuch minutes shall describe and refer to any map adopted in connection\nwith such local law or amendment.\n  6. Map. Each village clerk shall maintain every map adopted in\nconnection with a zoning local law or amendment.\n  7. Effective date. Such local law shall take effect upon filing in the\noffice of the secretary of state, but such local law or amendment shall\ntake effect from the date of its service as against a person served\npersonally with a copy thereof, certified by the village clerk; and\nshowing the date of its passage and entry in the minutes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>