<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-700"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-700"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-700"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-700/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-700/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-700/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-700/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_700">
        <num>7-700</num>
        <heading>Grant of power</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-700 Grant of power. For the purpose of promoting the health,\nsafety, morals, or the general welfare of the community, the board of\ntrustees of a village is hereby empowered, by local law, to regulate and\nrestrict the height, number of stories and size of buildings and other\nstructures, the percentage of lot that may be occupied, the size of\nyards, courts and other open spaces, the density of population, and the\nlocation and use of buildings, structures and land for trade, industry,\nresidence or other purposes.  As a part of the comprehensive plan and\ndesign, the village board is empowered by local law, to regulate and\nrestrict certain areas as national historic landmarks, special historic\nsites, places and buildings for the purpose of conservation, protection,\nenhancement and perpetuation of these places of natural heritage. Such\nregulations shall provide that a board of appeals may determine and vary\ntheir application in harmony with the general purpose and intent, and in\naccordance with general or specific rules therein contained.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>