<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-712-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-712-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-712-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-712-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-712-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-712-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-712-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_712_B">
        <num>7-712-B</num>
        <heading>Permitted action by board of appeals</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of appeals, on appeal from the\ndecision or determination of the administrative officer charged with the\nenforcement of such local law, shall have the power to grant use\nvariances, as defined herein.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No such use variance shall be granted by a board of appeals\nwithout a showing by the applicant that applicable zoning regulations\nand restrictions have caused unnecessary hardship. In order to prove\nsuch unnecessary hardship the applicant shall demonstrate to the board\nof appeals that for each and every permitted use under the zoning\nregulations for the particular district where the property is located,\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the applicant cannot realize a reasonable return, provided that lack\nof return is substantial as demonstrated by competent financial\nevidence;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the alleged hardship relating to the property in\nquestion is unique, and does not apply to a substantial portion of the\ndistrict or neighborhood;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the requested use variance, if\ngranted, will not alter the essential character of the neighborhood; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>that the alleged hardship has not been self-created.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of appeals, in the granting of use variances, shall\ngrant the minimum variance that it shall deem necessary and adequate to\naddress the unnecessary hardship proved by the applicant, and at the\nsame time preserve and protect the character of the neighborhood and the\nhealth, safety and welfare of the community.\n  3. Area variances.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The zoning board of appeals shall have the\npower, upon an appeal from a decision or determination of the\nadministrative official charged with the enforcement of such local law,\nto grant area variances as defined herein.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In making its determination, the zoning board of appeals shall\ntake into consideration the benefit to the applicant if the variance is\ngranted, as weighed against the detriment to the health, safety and\nwelfare of the neighborhood or community by such grant. In making such\ndetermination the board shall also consider:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>whether an undesirable\nchange will be produced in the character of the neighborhood or a\ndetriment to nearby properties will be created by the granting of the\narea variance;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>whether the benefit sought by the applicant can be\nachieved by some method, feasible for the applicant to pursue, other\nthan an area variance;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>whether the requested area variance is\nsubstantial;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>whether the proposed variance will have an adverse\neffect or impact on the physical or environmental conditions in the\nneighborhood or district; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>whether the alleged difficulty was\nself-created; which consideration shall be relevant to the decision of\nthe board of appeals, but shall not necessarily preclude the granting of\nthe area variance.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_712_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board of appeals, in the granting of area variances, shall\ngrant the minimum variance that it shall deem necessary and adequate and\nat the same time preserve and protect the character of the neighborhood\nand the health, safety and welfare of the community.\n  4. Imposition of conditions. The board of appeals shall, in the\ngranting of both use variances and area variances, have the authority to\nimpose such reasonable conditions and restrictions as are directly\nrelated to and incidental to the proposed use of the property. Such\nconditions shall be consistent with the spirit and intent of the zoning\nlocal law, and shall be imposed for the purpose of minimizing any\nadverse impact such variance may have on the neighborhood or community.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>