<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-724"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-724"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-724"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-724/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-724/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-724/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-724/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_724">
        <num>7-724</num>
        <heading>Official maps, changes in official map; notice of hearing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7-724 Official maps, changes in official map; notice of hearing.\nEvery village may by resolution of its board of trustees establish an\nofficial map of the village showing the streets, highways and parks\ntheretofore laid out, adopted and established by law. Drainage systems\nmay also be shown on this map. Such map is to be deemed to be final and\nconclusive with respect to the location and width of streets, highways,\ndrainage systems and the location of parks shown thereon. Such official\nmap is hereby declared to be established to conserve and promote the\npublic health, safety and general welfare. The clerk of every village\nwhich has established such an official map shall immediately file a\ncertificate of that fact with the clerk or register of the county in\nwhich said village is located.  Such board of trustees is authorized and\nempowered, whenever and as often as it may deem it for the public\ninterest, to change or add to the official map of the village so as to\nlay out new streets, highways or parks, or to widen or close existing\nstreets, highways or parks. There shall be a public hearing on any\nproposed action with reference to any such change in the official map.\nBefore making any such addition or change the board of trustees shall\nrefer the matter to the planning board for report thereon, but if the\nplanning board shall not make its report within thirty days of such\nreference, it shall forfeit the right further to suspend action. Such\nadditions and changes when adopted shall become a part of the official\nmap of the village, and shall be deemed to be final and conclusive with\nrespect to the location of the streets, highways and parks shown\nthereon. The granting by the board of trustees of a petition for the\napproval of the laying out, altering, widening, narrowing or\ndiscontinuing of a street, shall be deemed to be an addition or change\nof the official map and shall be subject to all the provisions of this\narticle with regard to such additions or changes.  Drainage systems may\nalso be shown on this map.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>