<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-732"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-732"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7-732"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-732/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-732/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-732/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-7-732/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7_732">
        <num>7-732</num>
        <heading>Subdivision review; record of plats</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_732__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No plat of a subdivision of land showing\nlots, blocks or sites, shall be filed or recorded in the office of the\ncounty clerk or register until it has been approved by a planning board\nwhich has been empowered to approve such plats. Further, such approval\nmust be endorsed in writing on the plat in such manner as the planning\nboard may designate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_732__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such endorsement shall stipulate that the plat does not conflict\nwith the county official map, where one exists, or in cases where plats\ndo front on or have access to or are otherwise related to roads or\ndrainage systems shown on the county official map, that such plat has\nbeen approved in the manner specified by subdivision two of section two\nhundred thirty-nine-f of the general municipal law.\n  2. Notification of filing. It shall be the duty of the county clerk or\nregister to notify the planning board in writing within three days of\nthe filing or recording of any plat approved by such planning board,\nidentifying such plat by its title, date of filing or recording, and\nofficial file number.\n  3. Effect of filing. After such plat is approved and filed, the\nstreets, highways and parks shown on such plat shall be and become a\npart of the official map or plan of the village.\n  4. Cession or dedication of streets, highways or parks.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_732__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All\nstreets, highways or parks shown on a filed or recorded plat are offered\nfor dedication to the public unless the owner of the affected land, or\nthe owner's agent, makes a notation on the plat to the contrary prior to\nfinal plat approval. Any street, highway or park shown on a filed or\nrecorded plat shall be deemed to be private until such time as it has\nbeen formally accepted by a resolution of the local legislative body, or\nuntil it has been condemned by the village for use as a public street,\nhighway or park.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_7_732__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that such approved plat is not filed or recorded\nprior to the expiration date of the plat approval as provided in section\n7-728 of this article, then such offer of dedication shall be deemed to\nbe invalid, void and of no effect on and after such expiration date.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>