<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-902"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-902"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-902"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-902/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-902/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-902/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-902/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_902">
        <num>9-902</num>
        <heading>Referendum on petition; registration list of electors</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_902__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Register of electors in last preceding village election.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_902__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Towns register of electors for last preceding general election\ncovering all the area of the village.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_902__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Last preceding county register of electors.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_902__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any other official record or source that will aid in producing the\nmost accurate registration list of electors.\n  Such registration list of electors shall be made available and\ndisclosed to any elector of the village upon request. Any elector of the\nvillage claiming to be qualified to vote upon such a proposition whose\nname is not included in the registration list of electors therefor as\nmade by the village clerk, may apply to such clerk for a revision of\nsuch list of electors to include his or her name. The village clerk upon\nthe presentation of proper proofs showing that the applicant is a duly\nqualified elector shall revise such list of electors to include the name\nof the applicant. The application to revise any such list of electors\nmay be made to the village clerk on or before the date of the election\nat which the proposition is to be submitted.\n  4. The failure or refusal of the village clerk to revise any such list\nof electors to include the name of a qualified elector so applying may\nbe reviewed in a proceeding under article seventy-eight of the civil\npractice law and rules. The court upon petition for such a review shall\ncause to be served upon the village clerk an order directing such clerk\nto show cause why the statement should not be revised to include the\nname of the petitioner. Such order must be made returnable on a date to\nbe fixed by the court not less than twenty-four hours after the order is\nissued and served. If it shall appear upon the return of the order that\nthe petitioner is qualified to vote upon the proposition, the court\nshall order the name of the petitioner to be included in the list of\nelectors and the village clerk shall revise such list accordingly. The\nprovisions of article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules,\nnot inconsistent with this act, shall apply to the review provided by\nthis section.\n  5. If such petition be so filed after the first day of the month in\nwhich the general village elec...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>