<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="VIL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-910"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-910"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-910"/>
          <FRBRname value="VIL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-910/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-910/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-910/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/vil/section-9-910/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_910">
        <num>9-910</num>
        <heading>Referendum for adoption of local law at village elections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 9-910 Referendum for adoption of local law at village elections. 1.\nWhenever, pursuant to law, public sports, exercises or shows are\npermitted on the first day of the week after five minutes past one\no'clock in the afternoon upon the adoption of a local law by the board\nof trustees of a village and the board of trustees of any village has\nneglected, failed or refused to adopt a local law permitting such\nsports, exercises or shows on the first day of the week after five\nminutes past one o'clock in the afternoon, a petition, signed and\nacknowledged by electors of the village qualified to vote as provided by\nthe election law may be filed with the village clerk requesting the\nboard of trustees to submit, at a village election, a proposition upon\nthe question of permitting such sports, exercises or shows on the first\nday of the week after five minutes past one o'clock in the afternoon.\n  2. Upon the presentation of such petition, the board of trustees shall\ncause the proposition to be submitted as hereinafter provided.\n  3. The proposition shall embody therein the language of local law\ndesigned to permit such sports, exercises or shows on the first day of\nthe week after five minutes past one o'clock in the afternoon.\n  4. If such local law shall be approved by the affirmative vote of a\nmajority of the qualified electors of such village as above described\nvoting on such proposition, it shall be and become a local law of such\nvillage without being adopted by the board of trustees thereof.\n  5. A local law adopted as provided in this section may be amended or\nrepealed in the same manner herein provided for its adoption.\n  6. If a petition under this section be filed after the first day of\nthe month in which the general village election is to be held and before\nthe first day of the month two months prior to the next general village\nelection, a special election shall be held not less than ten nor more\nthan sixty days after the filing of such petition.\n  7. If a petition be so filed on or after the first day of the month\ntwo months prior to the month in which the general village election is\nto be held and on or before the first day of the month in which the\ngeneral village election is to be held, the proposition shall be\nsubmitted at the said general village election.\n  8. No special election shall be held hereunder in the month of March.\n  9. A special election hereunder shall be noticed, conducted, canvassed\nand otherwise held in the same manner as a general village election.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>