<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-120"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-120"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="120"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-120/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-120/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_120">
        <num>120</num>
        <heading>Creation; board; employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 120. Creation; board; employees. The governing body of each city\nhaving a population of fifty thousand or more is hereby authorized to\ncreate a city drug control authority. Such authority shall consist of\nnot less than five nor more than nine members who shall be appointed by\nthe governing body of the city, at least one of whom shall be a\nphysician licensed to practice medicine in this state. Any person\nserving as a member of a city narcotic guidance council, community board\nnarcotic guidance council in the city of New York, drug abuse commission\nor mental health board shall be eligible to serve as a member of the\nboard of a city drug authority created pursuant to this article.  The\nchairman of the board shall be designated by the governing body of the\ncity from among the members so appointed. The compensation of the\nmembers shall be fixed by the governing body of the city within the\namount available therefor by appropriation.  The board shall appoint a\ncounsel, an administrative officer and such other officers, employees,\nagents and consultants as may be necessary, prescribe their duties, fix\ntheir compensation and provide for payment of their expenses, all within\namounts appropriated therefor by the city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>