<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_E">
        <num>13-E</num>
        <heading>Expenses of meeting rooms for veterans' and other organizations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 13-e. Expenses of meeting rooms for veterans' and other\norganizations.  Any city may appropriate and make available a sum of\nmoney not exceeding five hundred dollars in any one year for each\nchapter, post, camp or garrison, as the case may be, of the Grand Army\nof the Republic, the United Spanish War Veterans, the Veterans of\nForeign Wars, the American Legion, the Disabled American Veterans, the\nMilitary Order of the Purple Heart, Inc., the Army and Navy Union of the\nUnited States, the Marine Corps League, AMVETS, American Veterans of\nWorld War II, the Italian American War Veterans of the United States,\nIncorporated, Veterans of World War I of the United States of America\nDepartment of New York, Inc., Polish-American Veterans of World War II,\nAmsterdam, N. Y., Inc., Polish-American Veterans of World War II,\nSchenectady, N. Y., Inc., Polish Legion of American Veterans, Inc., the\nJewish War Veterans of the United States, Inc., the Catholic War\nVeterans, Inc., Masonic War Veterans of the State of New York, Inc., the\nAmerican Gold Star Mothers, Inc., Regular Veterans Association, Inc.,\nthe Viet Nam Veterans of America, the Eastern Paralyzed Veterans\nAssociation, the 369th Veterans Association, Inc., the Tri-County\nCouncil of Vietnam Veterans, the National Congress of Puerto Rican\nVeterans, the Navy Seabee Veterans of America, the Korean War Veterans\nAssociation, the Women's Army Corps Veterans Association, or the Navy\nClub of the U.S.A., located within its boundaries, for the purpose of\nassisting in defraying the rental or maintenance expenses, or both, of\nrooms for the holding of meetings of any such post, camp, garrison or\nchapter. All sums hereby authorized to be expended shall be\nappropriated, raised and expended, in the same manner as moneys for\nother municipal expenses in the city are appropriated, raised and\nexpended.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>