<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-11-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-13/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13">
        <num>13</num>
        <heading>Moneys for Memorial and Veterans days; how expended</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 13. Moneys for Memorial and Veterans days; how expended. The moneys\nappropriated by a city for observance of Memorial and Veterans days\ntherein pursuant to section twelve of this chapter shall be expended\nunder the direction of a board composed of the mayor and the commanders\nand quartermasters of the Grand Army posts, the American Legion, the\nUnited Spanish War Veterans camps, the Veterans of Foreign Wars of the\nUnited States, the Army and Navy Union of the United States, the Marine\nCorps League, Inc., the Catholic War Veterans, Inc., the Italian\nAmerican War Veterans of the United States, Incorporated, the Jewish War\nVeterans of the United States and commanders and treasurers of Sons of\nVeterans, Military Order of the Purple Heart, Inc., Disabled American\nVeterans camps, AMVETS, American Veterans of World War II, Masonic War\nVeterans of the State of New York, Inc., Veterans of World War I of the\nUnited States of America Department of New York, Inc., Polish-American\nVeterans of World War II, Amsterdam, N. Y., Inc., Polish-American\nVeterans of World War II, Schenectady, N. Y., Inc., Polish Legion of\nAmerican Veterans, Inc., United Veteran's Association of America,\nIncorporated, Vietnam Veterans of America and the United Veterans\nMemorial and Executive Committee of such city. The whole amount of such\nmoney appropriated or any part thereof may be spent by such board in\nobservance of Memorial and Veterans days. Bills properly verified for\nall claims and expenditures arising under section twelve of this chapter\nor under this section, shall be presented to and audited by such board\nand shall be paid by the common council of any such city. The moneys\nappropriated shall be raised by tax on the real and personal property\nliable to taxation in any such city in the same manner as the ordinary\nexpenses of maintaining the city government.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>