<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-14"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-14"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-14/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-14/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14">
        <num>14</num>
        <heading>Permits for erection of booths and arches</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 14. Permits for erection of booths and arches. The mayor of any city\nof the first class or the commissioner of transportation in the city of\nNew York, may, in his discretion, grant temporary permits for the\nerection of booths, stands, arches, overhead passageways, or flagstaffs\nfor the stringing of flags or banners, upon or over the sidewalks or\nstreets of such city for the purpose of a public celebration,\nexposition, fair, political demonstration or any charitable or patriotic\ndrive, function or celebration; provided, however, that no such permit\nshall be granted for the erection of any such structure or device which\nis to be used in whole or in part for business or commercial advertising\npurposes. No such permit shall be granted by virtue of this section\nwithout the consent of the owners of the abutting property constituting\nmore than one-half of the foot frontage upon both sides of such street\nin the block formed by the nearest cross-streets on each side of such\nstructure or erection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>