<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-18"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-18"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="18"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-18/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-18/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-18/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-18/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_18">
        <num>18</num>
        <heading>License to operate moving picture apparatus</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 18. License to operate moving picture apparatus. It shall not be\nlawful for any person or persons, save as excepted in section eighteen-a\nof this article, to operate any moving picture apparatus and its\nconnections in a city of the first class unless such person or persons\nso operating such apparatus is duly licensed as hereinafter provided.\nAny person desiring to act as such operator shall make application for a\nlicense to so act to the mayor or licensing authority designated by the\nmayor, unless the charter of said city so designates, which officer\nshall furnish to each applicant blank forms of application which the\napplicant shall fill out. Such officer shall make rules and regulations\ngoverning the examination of applicants and the issuance of licenses and\ncertificates. A license shall not be granted to an applicant unless he\nshall have served as an apprentice under a licensed operator, for a\nperiod of not less than six months prior to the date of the application;\nthe application must be made in writing, and contain a verified\nstatement to that effect; it must be accompanied by the affidavit of the\nlicensed operator to the same effect; before entering upon the period of\napprenticeship the applicant must register his name and address with the\nofficer issuing such license. The applicant shall be given a practical\nexamination under the direction of the officer required to issue such\nlicense and if found competent as to his ability to operate moving\npicture apparatus and its connections shall receive within six days\nafter such examination a license as herein provided. Such license may be\nrevoked or suspended at any time by the officer issuing the same.  Every\nlicense shall continue in force for one year from the date of issue\nunless sooner revoked or suspended. Every license, unless revoked or\nsuspended, as herein provided, may at the end of one year from the date\nof issue thereof be renewed by the officer issuing it in his discretion\nupon application and with or without further examination as he may\ndirect. Every application for renewal of license must be made within the\nthirty days previous to the expiration of such license.  With every\nlicense granted there shall be issued to every person obtaining such\nlicense a certificate, certifying that the person named therein is duly\nauthorized to operate moving picture apparatus and its connections. Such\ncertificate shall be displayed in a conspicuous place in the room where\nthe person to whom it is issued operates moving picture apparatus and\nits connections. No person shall be eligible to procure a license unless\nhe shall be of full age. Any person offending against the provisions of\nthis section, as well as any person who employs or permits a person not\nlicensed as herein provided to operate moving picture apparatus and its\nconnections, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction\nthereof shall be punished by a fine not exceeding the sum of one hundred\ndollars, or imprisonment for a period not exceeding three months, or\nboth.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>