<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-20-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-20-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="20-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-20-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-20-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-20-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-20-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_20_D">
        <num>20-D</num>
        <heading>Alternative procedure for acquisition of certain real property, personal property and franchises of omnibus lines within cities having a ...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 20-d. Alternative procedure for acquisition of certain real\nproperty, personal property and franchises of omnibus lines within\ncities having a population of one million or more inhabitants.\nNotwithstanding any other provision of law, general, special or local,\ncities with a population of one million or more inhabitants shall have\nthe additional power to acquire by acquisition any property and the\nfranchises of any person, firm or corporation situated within such city,\nused and usable in the operation of omnibus lines which are entirely\nwithin and do not extend beyond the boundaries of such city, the\nimmediate acquisition of which property and franchises is determined by\nthe board of estimate or other appropriate governing body of such city\nto be necessary to serve the public convenience through the provision of\nadequate omnibus transportation, notwithstanding the fact that such\nproperty and franchises were or are devoted to a public use. The term\n"property" as used in this subdivision is defined to include lands,\nwaters, rights in lands or waters, structures, franchises and interests\nin land, including lands under water and riparian rights, and any and\nall other things and rights usually included within the said term and\nincludes also any and all interests in such property less than full\ntitle, such as easements permanent or temporary, rights-of-way, uses,\nleases, licenses and all other incorporeal hereditaments and every\nestate, interest or right legal or equitable, and omnibuses, rolling\nstock and any other form of real or personal property. Acquisition of\nsuch property shall be in accordance with the provisions of the eminent\ndomain procedure law.\n  Notwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local law to\nthe contrary, such city may authorize, issue and sell obligations,\npursuant to the local finance law, to pay for the cost of any\nacquisition or acquisitions of such property used and usable in the\noperation of omnibus lines provided, however, that no such obligations\nshall be authorized, issued, sold or refunded after September thirtieth,\nnineteen hundred sixty-three. The maximum period of probable usefulness\nfor each such object or purpose for which obligations may be issued\nhereunder is hereby determined to be as follows:\n  a. The acquisition of real property, thirty years.\n  b. The acquisition of omnibuses and other necessary personal property,\nfive years.\n  c. The acquisition of franchises, five years.\n  The provisions of this section constitute an alternative procedure to\nthe procedure set forth in subdivision two of section twenty of this\nchapter and any city having a population of one million or more\ninhabitants may proceed under the authority of this section or of such\nsubdivision two of section twenty.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>