<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_C">
        <num>21-C</num>
        <heading>Passenger stations of railroad redevelopment corporations in certain cities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 21-c. Passenger stations of railroad redevelopment corporations in\ncertain cities.  1. Each city having a population of more than one\nmillion may from time to time contract with a railroad redevelopment\ncorporation providing passenger service by rail to or from any passenger\nstation within such city and currently certified by the state\ncommissioner of transportation as eligible to receive the exemptions\nprovided by title two-b of the real property tax law to reimburse such\ncorporation for all or part of the costs incurred by it in the operation\nand maintenance of one or more such stations, owned or used by it,\nincluding the buildings, appurtenances, platforms, land and approaches\nincidental or adjacent thereto, provided, however, that such contract\nshall contain provisions pursuant to which:\n  a. The corporation agrees for the term of such contract not to\ndiscontinue all passenger or all freight service, or petition any\nregulatory agency having jurisdiction in respect thereof for permission\nto discontinue all passenger or all freight service, to or from such\nstations without the consent of such city;\n  b. The corporation agrees for the term of such contract to continue\nthe operation and maintenance of such existing facilities or portions\nthereof as may be required in the public interest for the sale of\npassenger tickets and the handling of baggage mail and freight at such\nstations;\n  c. The corporation shall use the portions of any such station which\nare not required for the sale of passenger tickets, the handling of\nbaggage, mail and freight or its railroad operations for public purposes\nor for uses generally available to or serving the general public,\nincluding but not limited to access to the railroad and related\nservices, facilities for the convenience and comfort of the general\npublic, the parking of vehicles, public assembly, recreation, cultural\nactivities, shelter, and terminal facilities for other modes of\ntransportation; and\n  d. Such contract shall expire not later than the first day of July\nnext succeeding its effective date.\n  Any contract made pursuant to this section may contain such other\nterms and conditions, not inconsistent with the foregoing, as the city\nand the corporation may agree.\n  2. Reimbursement of the costs of maintenance and operation of such\nstations, and reimbursement of any part thereof, are hereby declared\ncity purposes and the cost thereof shall be a city charge to be paid\nfrom city funds annually appropriated, raised and expended for city\npurposes in the manner provided by law.\n  3. Any contract made pursuant to this section shall be authorized by\nthe board of estimate of such city by resolution and shall require the\nseparate approval of the mayor of such city. Such resolution may be\namended from time to time.\n  4. Each city entering into a contract pursuant to this section shall\nfile a copy thereof within ten days of its execution with the director\nof the state office of transportation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>