<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-21-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_F">
        <num>21-F</num>
        <heading>Operating assistance for certain public utility services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 21-f. Operating assistance for certain public utility services. Each\ncity having a population of one million or more shall be authorized to\nmake an appropriation, notwithstanding any provision of general, special\nor local law to the contrary, to a public utility service operated by\nsuch city in accordance with a local law adopted pursuant to article\nfourteen-A of the general municipal law for the purpose of reducing the\nrates charged for the electricity sold and billed by such public utility\nservice to non-residential energy users, without the billing services of\na utility, so as to enable such public utility service to reduce its\nrates and charges in a proportion substantially equivalent to reductions\neffected by rebates made to non-residential energy users in accordance\nwith a local law adopted pursuant to authorization contained in article\ntwo-G of this chapter. Any funds so appropriated shall be used by such\npublic utility service to effect a reduction of rates and charges of\nsuch public utility service in the manner hereinabove described. For\npurposes of this section the terms "non-residential energy user",\n"rebate" and "utility" shall have the meanings ascribed by article two-G\nof this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>