<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-25-A-38"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-25-A-38"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="25-A-38"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-25-A-38/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-25-A-38/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-25-A-38/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-25-A-38/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_25_A_38">
        <num>25-A-38</num>
        <heading>Requirements concerning returns, notices, records and statements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_25_A_38__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>General.--The administrator may prescribe regulations\nas to the keeping of records, the content and form of returns and\nstatements, and the filing of copies of federal income tax returns and\ndeterminations.  The administrator may require any person, by regulation\nor notice served upon such person, to make such returns, render such\nstatements, or keep such records, as the administrator may deem\nsufficient to show whether or not such person is liable under this local\nlaw for tax or for collection of tax.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_25_A_38__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Partnerships.--Every partnership having a resident partner shall\nmake a return for the taxable year setting forth all items of income,\ngain, loss and deduction and such other pertinent information as the\nadministrator may by regulations and instructions prescribe. Such return\nshall be filed on or before the fifteenth day of the fourth month\nfollowing the close of each taxable year. For purposes of this\nsubdivision, "taxable year" means year or period which would be a\ntaxable year of the partnership if it were subject to tax under this\nlocal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_25_A_38__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Information at source.--The administrator may prescribe\nregulations and instructions requiring returns of information to be made\nand filed on or before February twenty-eighth of each year as to the\npayment or crediting in any calendar year of amounts of six hundred\ndollars or more to any taxpayer under this local law. Such returns may\nbe required of any person, including lessees or mortgagors of real or\npersonal property, fiduciaries, employers, and all officers and\nemployees of this state, or of any municipal corporation or political\nsubdivision of this state, having the control, receipt, custody,\ndisposal or payment of interest, rents, salaries, wages, premiums,\nannuities, compensations, remunerations, emoluments or other fixed or\ndeterminable gains, profits or income, except interest coupons payable\nto bearer. A duplicate of the statement as to tax withheld on wages,\nrequired to be furnished by an employer to an employee, shall constitute\nthe return of information required to be made under this section with\nrespect to such wages.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_25_A_38__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notice of qualification as receiver, etc.--Every receiver, trustee\nin bankruptcy, assignee for benefit of creditors, or other like\nfiduciary shall give notice of his qualification as such to the\nadministrator, as may be required by regulation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>