<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-29"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-29"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-29/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-29/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-29/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-29/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29">
        <num>29</num>
        <heading>Official map, changes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 29. Official map, changes. Such legislative body is authorized and\nempowered, whenever and as often as it may deem it for the public\ninterest, to change or add to the official map of the city so as to lay\nout new streets, highways or parks, or to widen or close existing\nstreets, highways or parks.  Drainage systems may also be shown on this\nmap. At least five days' notice of a public hearing on any proposed\naction with reference to such change in the official map shall be\npublished at least once in an official publication of said city or in a\nnewspaper of general circulation therein. No change in the official map\nshall be made for the lay out of a new street or the opening or widening\nof any street unless notice shall have been sent by registered mail,\nreturn receipt requested, to the person and address noted on the last\npreceding real property tax notice issued on the property which is to be\nincluded in such proposed layout, opening or widening of such streets.\nBefore making such addition or change the matter shall be referred to\nthe planning board for report thereon, but if the planning board shall\nnot make its report within thirty days of such reference, it shall\nforfeit the right further to suspend action.  Such additions and changes\nwhen adopted shall become a part of the official map of the city, and\nshall be deemed to be final and conclusive with respect to the location\nof the streets, highways and parks shown thereon.\n  The layout, widening or closing, or the approval of the layout,\nwidening or closing of streets, highways or parks by the city under\nprovisions of law other than those contained in this article shall be\ndeemed to be a change or addition to the official map, and shall be\nsubject to all the provisions of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>