<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-3-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-3-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-3-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-3-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-3-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-3-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_C">
        <num>3-C</num>
        <heading>Unlawful offers or agreements by municipal officials or omnibus lines with respect to omnibus line operations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3-c. Unlawful offers or agreements by municipal officials or omnibus\nlines with respect to omnibus line operations. 1. No officer, employee\nor agent of any city or any person acting on his behalf shall, directly\nor indirectly, make an offer to or agree with any private owner or\noperator of an omnibus line within such city or any person acting on\nbehalf of such owner or operator, to approve or recommend the approval\nof an increase in fare or any other benefit for such owner or operator\nat some future time, in consideration of the promise or agreement of\nsuch owner or operator to delay making any application for a fare\nincrease until some future time, or to enter into a contract with a\nlabor organization.\n  2. No private owner or operator of an omnibus line within any city or\nany person acting on behalf of such owner or operator shall, directly or\nindirectly, make an offer to or agree with any officer, employee or\nagent of such city, or any person acting on his behalf, to delay making\nan application for a fare increase until some future time, or to enter\ninto a contract with a labor organization, in consideration of the\npromise or agreement of such officer, employee or agent of such city to\napprove or recommend the approval of an increase in fares or any other\nbenefit for such owner or operator at some future time.\n  3. The violation of any provision of this section shall constitute a\nmisdemeanor. Any public officer or employee who is convicted of a\nviolation of this section shall forfeit his office or employment and\nshall forever be disqualified from holding any public office or\nemployment under the state or any political subdivision thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>