<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-36"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-36"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-07-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="36"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-36/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-36/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-36/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-36/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_36">
        <num>36</num>
        <heading>Municipal improvements in streets, buildings not on mapped streets</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_36__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an\nexception if the circumstances of the case do not require the structure\nto be related to existing or proposed streets or highways and/or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an\narea variance pursuant to section eighty-one-b of this chapter, and the\nsame provisions are hereby applied to such appeals and to such board as\nare provided in cases of appeals on zoning regulations. The board may in\npassing on such appeal make any reasonable exception and issue the\npermit subject to conditions that will protect any future street or\nhighway layout. Any such decision shall be subject to review under the\nprovisions of article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules.\n  2. A city having a population of one million or more. No public\nmunicipal street utility or improvement shall be constructed by any city\nhaving a population of one million or more in any street or highway\nuntil it has become a public street or highway and is duly placed on the\nofficial map or plan, with the exception that a city may construct\nimprovements and provide services to any public way (mapped or unmapped)\nif the public way has been open and in use to the public for a minimum\nof ten years. The existence of the public way must be attested to by\ndocuments satisfactory to the municipality, such as reports of city\nagencies providing municipal services. No certificate of occupancy shall\nbe issued in such city for any building unless a street or highway\ngiving access to such structure has been duly placed on the official map\nor plan, which street or highway, and any other mapped street or highway\nabutting such building or structure shall have been suitably improved to\nthe satisfaction of the department of transportation of the city in\naccordance with standards and specifications approved by such department\nas adequate in respect to the public health, safety and general welfare\nfor the special circumstances of the particular street or highway, or,\nalternately, unless the owner has furnished to the department of\ntransportation of such city a performance bond naming the city as\nobligee, approved by such department, to the full cost of such\nimprove...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the\ncorporation counsel of the city of New York has issued an opinion\ndetermining that the public way has been open and in use to the public\nfor a minimum of ten years and has been attested to by documents\nsatisfactory to the municipality, that the unmapped street abutting such\nbuilding or structure shall have been suitably improved to the\nsatisfaction of the department of transportation of the city of New York\nin accordance with standards and specifications approved by such\ndepartment as adequate in respect to the public health, safety and\ngeneral welfare for the special circumstances of the particular unmapped\nstreet, and that such building or structure is equipped with an\nautomatic fire sprinkler, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_36__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the department of buildings of the\ncity of New York determines that such one or two family residential\ndwelling is located within the same block and fronting on the same\nunmapped street in question as another building or structure that\nsuccessfully appealed to the board of standards and appeals and has been\nissued a certificate of occupancy and provided the unmapped street\nfronting such one or two family residential dwelling has been suitably\nimproved to the standards and specifications of such department of\ntransportation, and further provided that such one or two family\nresidential dwelling is equipped with an automatic fire sprinkler\nsystem. Nothing contained in this subdivision shall limit the\njurisdiction of the board of standards and appeals to determine the\napplication of the zoning resolution.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>