<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-44"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-44"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="44"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-44/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-44/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-44/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-44/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44">
        <num>44</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 44. Powers and duties. The several examining boards of plumbers\nshall have power and it shall be their duty:\n  1. To meet at stated intervals in their respective cities; they shall\nalso meet whenever the board of health of such city or the mayor thereof\nshall in writing request them so to do.\n  2. To have jurisdiction over and to examine all persons desiring or\nintending to engage in the trade, business or calling of plumbing as\nemploying plumbers in the city in which such board shall be appointed\nwith the power of examining persons applying for certificates of\ncompetency as such employing or master plumbers or as inspectors of\nplumbing, to determine their fitness and qualifications for conducting\nthe business of master plumbers or to act as inspector of plumbing, and\nto issue certificates of competency to all such persons who shall have\npassed a satisfactory examination before such board and shall be by it\ndetermined to be qualified for conducting the business as employing or\nmaster plumbers or competent to act as inspectors of plumbing.\n  3. To formulate in conjunction with the local board of health of the\ncity or an officer, board or body performing the duties of a board of\nhealth a code of rules regulating the work of plumbing and drainage in\nsuch city, including the materials, workmanship and manner of executing\nsuch work and from time to time to add to, amend or alter the same, or\nin their discretion to adopt the standard plumbing code recommended by\nthe state department of health.\n  4. To charge and collect from each person applying for examination the\nsum of ten dollars for each examination made by such board, and all\nmoneys so collected shall be paid over by the board monthly to the\nchamberlain or treasurer of such city in which such board shall be\nappointed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>