<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-45-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-45-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="45-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-45-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-45-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-45-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-45-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_B">
        <num>45-B</num>
        <heading>Further requirements relating to the business of plumbing</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 45-b. Further requirements relating to the business of plumbing.\n1.  No person otherwise qualified shall engage in the trade, business or\ncalling of a plumber or of plumbing in a city of this state as employing\nor master plumber until he has first procured from the board of health\nor the examining board of plumbers if so designated by local law in such\ncity or, in the city of New York, from the department of health, a metal\nplate or sign appropriately lettered or marked "licensed plumber;" such\nplate or sign to be conspicuously posted in the window of the place\nwhere such business is conducted. Any person retiring, abandoning or not\nactually engaged in such trade, business or calling hereinbefore\nmentioned, shall surrender to the board of health or the examining board\nof plumbers if so designated by local law of the city, or, in the city\nof New York, to the department of health such metal plate or sign and\nshall not again engage in such trade, business or calling until he has\nagain procured a metal sign as herein provided.\n  2. Within thirty days after this section takes effect, the board of\nhealth or the examining board of plumbers if so designated by local law\nin every city of this state and in the city of New York, the department\nof health, shall prepare metal plates or signs, at least fourteen inches\nwide and not less than twenty-two inches in length appropriately\nlettered or marked "licensed plumber," the lines of each letter to be\nfour inches long and five-eighths of an inch wide; such plate or sign\nshall, on some part thereof, contain an identification number, which\nnumber together with the name and location of the place of business of\nthe person to whom issued shall be recorded in the office of such board\nof health or the examining board of plumbers if so designated by local\nlaw, or such department of health in the city of New York. Every person\nnow actually engaged or about to engage in the trade, business or\ncalling of a plumber or of plumbing as employing or master plumber, who\nhas otherwise complied with the provisions of law relating to the\nconduct of such business upon the payment of five dollars to the board\nof health or the examining board of plumbers if so designated by local\nlaw of such city, or in the city of New York to the department of\nhealth, shall have issued to him a sign or plate hereinbefore described.\nIn the city of New York a renewal fee of two dollars per annum shall be\ncharged for each such plate or sign which shall be issued without\nreexamination, such fee to be paid by the holder of such plate or sign\nto the department of health annually during the month of January. Any\nperson to whom such plate or sign has been issued who shall loan, rent,\nsell or transfer the same to another person whether such person be\nentitled to receive a similar plate or sign or not, or otherwise\nwilfully violates the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a\nmisdemeanor punishable by a fine of not exceeding fifty dollars for the\nfirst offense, and not less than one hundred dollars nor more than five\nhundred dollars for a subsequent offense, and in addition thereto shall\nforfeit his license and certificate of qualifications.\n  The provisions of this section shall apply to all cities of the state,\nincluding the city of New York.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 45-b's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>