<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-48"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-48"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-09-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="48"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-48/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-48/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-48/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-48/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_48">
        <num>48</num>
        <heading>Inspectors; qualifications; notice</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 48. Inspectors; qualifications; notice. The local board of health or\nan official or board designated by local law of such city, as the case\nmay be shall detail, designate or appoint an inspector or inspectors of\nplumbing, subject, however, to the provisions or limitations of law,\nregulating the appointment of such inspectors by such board of health or\nan official or board designated by local law of such city. All\ninspectors of plumbing who are detailed, designated or appointed shall\nbe practical plumbers and shall not be engaged directly or indirectly in\nthe business of plumbing, during the period of their appointment. They\nshall be citizens and actual residents of the city in which they are\nappointed; except in the cities of Cortland and Corning, where such\ninspectors shall be citizens and actual residents of the county or\ncounties wherein the city is situated, or in an abutting or adjacent\ncounty; except in the city of Rochester, where such inspectors shall be\ncitizens and actual residents of the county wherein the city is\nsituated; except in the city of Watertown, where such inspectors shall\nbe citizens and actual residents of the county wherein the city is\nsituated except in the city of Middletown, where such inspectors shall\nbe citizens and actual residents of the county wherein the city is\nsituated, or within a twenty-five mile radius of the city of Middletown\nas long as such inspectors are citizens and actual residents of this\nstate; except in the city of Jamestown, where such inspectors shall be\ncitizens and actual residents of the county wherein the city is\nsituated; except in the city of Tonawanda, where such inspectors shall\nbe citizens and actual residents of the county wherein the city is\nsituated, or in an abutting or adjacent county; except in any city with\na population of less than twenty-five thousand, where such inspectors\nshall be citizens and actual residents of the county or counties wherein\nthe city is situated. Before entering upon the discharge of their duties\nas such inspectors they shall each be required to obtain a certificate\nof competency from said examining board. They shall be entitled to\nreceive compensation to be fixed by the officer, board, commission or\ndepartment having power to fix salaries generally or, if there be no\nofficer, board, commission or department thereof having such power, by\nthe board of alderpersons or common council.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>