<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-5/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-5/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5">
        <num>5</num>
        <heading>Certain parades and processions forbidden; penalty</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 5. Certain parades and processions forbidden; penalty. All\nprocessions or parades occupying or marching on any street of any city\nto the exclusion or interruption of other citizens in their individual\nright and use thereof, excepting the National Guard and the police and\nfire departments, and the associations of veteran soldiers, are\nforbidden, unless written notice of the object, time and route of such\nprocession or parade be given by the chief officer thereof, not less\nthan six hours previous to its forming or marching, to the police\nauthorities of such city; and such police authorities may designate to\nsuch procession or parade how much of the street in width it can occupy\nwith especial reference to crowded thoroughfares through which such\nprocession may move; and, when so designated, the chief officer of such\nprocession or parade shall be responsible that the designation is\nobeyed; and it shall be the duty of the police authorities to furnish\nsuch escort as may be necessary to protect persons and property and\nmaintain the public peace and order. A person wilfully violating any\nprovision of this section shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, punishable\nby a fine not exceeding twenty dollars or imprisonment not exceeding ten\ndays, or both.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>