<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="GCT">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-53"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-53"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="53"/>
          <FRBRname value="GCT"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-53/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/gct/section-53/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_53">
        <num>53</num>
        <heading>Plumbing and drainage to be executed according to rules</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 53. Plumbing and drainage to be executed according to rules.  The\nplumbing and drainage of all buildings, both public and private, in each\nof the cities of this state, shall be performed by persons authorized\nunder the rules and regulations adopted by the local board of examining\nplumbers, in conjunction with the board of health for plumbing and\ndrainage, and all plumbing and drainage work shall be executed in\ncompliance with such rules and regulations. And all repairs and\nalterations in the plumbing and drainage of all buildings heretofore\nconstructed shall also be performed and executed in accordance with such\nrules and regulations; but this section shall not be construed to repeal\nany existing provision of law requiring plans for the plumbing and\ndrainage of new buildings to be filed with any local board of health and\nbe previously approved in writing by such board of health and be\nexecuted in accordance therewith, except that in case of any conflict\nwith such plans, rules and regulations of the board of examiners, the\nlatter shall govern.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>