<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0501"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0501"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0501"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0501">
        <num>11-0501</num>
        <heading>Fish and wildlife management practices cooperative program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0501. Fish and wildlife management practices cooperative program.\n  1. Purpose.\n  The cooperative program provided in this section is authorized for the\npurpose of obtaining on the privately owned or leased lands and waters\nof the state practices of fish and wildlife management which will\npreserve and develop the fish and wildlife resources of the state and\nimprove access to them for recreational purposes by the people of the\nstate.\n  2. Definitions.\n  a. "Fish and wildlife management" means management of either fish or\nwildlife, or both.\n  b. "Region" means a fish and wildlife management region established as\nprovided in subdivision 3.\n  c. "Regional board" means a board constituted as provided in\nsubdivision 4. "State board" means the board constituted as provided in\nsubdivision 5.\n  d. "Cooperator" means a person with whom an agreement is made as\nprovided in subdivision 9.\n  e. "Regional supervisor for natural resources" means the employee of\nthe department bearing that title in each region.\n  f. "Department", "commissioner", "fish" and "wildlife" have the\nmeanings stated in section 11-0103.\n  3. Fish and wildlife management regions.\n  The commissioner shall establish not to exceed fifteen fish and\nwildlife management regions of one or more counties each, which shall\ninclude all counties of the state not wholly included within a city.\n  4. Regional fish and wildlife management boards.\n  a. A regional fish and wildlife management board shall be appointed in\neach of the regions established under subdivision 3 of this section.\nSuch regional board shall consist of three members from each county\nwithin the region which has appointed its members. In each county, one\nmember shall be a member of or represent the board of supervisors or\ncounty legislative body, one member shall represent the landowners of\nthe county and one member shall represent the sportsmen of the county.\nSuch members from each county shall be appointed by the chairman of the\nboard of supervisors of such county with the approval of the board of\nsupervisors, except that in a county having a county president, a county\nexecutive or other chief executive officer, the chief executive officer\nshall appoint the members representing such county with the approval of\nthe board of supervisors of such county. In a county having an elected\nlegislative body the presiding officer shall appoint the members\nrepresenting such county with the approval of the legislative body. If\nthere is no presiding officer then the members representing such county\nshall be appointed by the legislative body as a whole. If a member of\nthe board of supervisors or legislative body is not available to\nactively participate on the fish and wildlife management board, a\nrepresentative shall be selected who is an elected county official or\nwho is employed by the county government in a position having\nadministrative or managerial authority. A landowner representative must\nactually reside upon rural lands within the county and actually be\nengaged in the operation of such lands for production of agricultural\ncommodities or forest products. If a landowner representative with such\nqualifications is not available to actively participate on the fish and\nwildlife management board, a representative may be appointed who has\nbeen for at least five of the past ten years, before commencing his\nfirst term in any series of consecutive terms, engaged in such operation\nof rural lands, and who resides within the county he represents. If no\nlandowner representative with either of these qualifications is\navailable to actively participate on the fish and wildlife management\nboard a representative may be appointed who is a resource manager\nengaged in such operations on rural lands, and designated by the\ncorporate owner of those lands to represent the landowner's agricultural\nor silvicultural interests. In the case of certain counties designated\nby the full state board with a scarcity of rural lands operated for\nproduction of agricultural commodities or forest products, the landowner\nrepresentative shall own such rural lands in New York state, whether or\nnot those properties lie within the county wherein he resides and\nrepresents. A sportsman representative must be a resident of the county.\nThe said chief executive officer, presiding officer or legislative body\nshall receive and consider for appointment as the landowner\nrepresentative, the recommendations made by the county farm bureau and\nPomona grange, and for appointment as the sportsmen's representative,\nthe recommendations made by the county units of organized sportsmen's\ngroups, as well as considering the advantages of new representatives.\nThe term of office of regional board members shall be two calendar\nyears. A member shall be eligible for reappointment to successive terms\nof office where otherwise qualified. The term of the sportsmen's\nrepresentative and the board of supervisors or county legislative body\nrepresentative shall expire at the end of the odd numbered years; the\nterm of the landowner representative shall expire at the end of the even\nnumbered years. An alternate board of supervisors or county legislative\nbody representative, sportsmen's representative and landowner\nrepresentative may also be appointed, who shall be available to serve in\nthe event of the temporary inability of the member sportsmen's\nrepresentative or member landowner representative or board of\nsupervisors or county legislative body representative to so function. A\nvacancy in membership of a regional board shall be filled in the same\nmanner as the original appointment for the balance of the unexpired term\nduring which the vacancy occurs; if a supervisor member or county\nlegislative body member shall cease to be a supervisor or member of the\nlegislative body before the expiration of his term as a member of the\nregional board, a successor shall be appointed for the unexpired balance\nof the term as a member of the regional board. The chairman of the Board\nof Directors of each soil and water conservation district and the\nchairman of each regional forest practice board within the fish and\nwildlife management region, or his or their representatives, shall be\nadvisory members without vote.\n  b. Each regional board shall elect annually from its members a\nchairman, a vice chairman and a representative to the state board and\nmay elect a secretary. The regional supervisor for natural resources may\nserve as secretary of the board if the board so requests, but in any\nevent such supervisor's services shall always be available to the board.\n  5. State fish and wildlife management board.\n  a. There shall be a state fish and wildlife management board which\nshall consist of three representatives, one each representing\nlandowners, sportsmen, and county legislative bodies, from each of the\nexisting regional boards, and, as advisory members of the board without\nvote, the following persons during their term of office as such, or\ntheir representatives: the Commissioner of Environmental Conservation,\nthe Commissioner of Agriculture and Markets, the Commissioner of\nTransportation, the Commissioner of Parks, Recreation and Historic\nPreservation, the dean of the New York State College of Agriculture and\nLife Sciences, the president of the State University of New York College\nof Environmental Science and Forestry, the chairman of the State Soil\nand Water Conservation Committee, the chairman of the State Forest\nPractice Board, the president of the New York Farm Bureau, the Master of\nthe New York State Grange, the president of the New York State\nConservation Council, and the president of the New York State Division\nof Izaak Walton League.\n  b. Each member other than the advisory members shall be elected by and\nfrom the membership of the respective regional boards for a term of one\nyear from the day of his election, unless within such period he shall\ncease to be a member of the regional board which elected him, in which\nevent he shall cease to be a member of the state board on the day he\nceases to be a member of such regional board. Any vacancy in the state\nboard other than in the office of an advisory member shall be filled for\nthe balance of the unexpired term so vacated by election from its\nmembership by the regional board in which such vacancy occurred.\n  c. The members of the state board shall elect one of their voting\nmembers to serve as chairman, and another as vice chairman, to serve in\nthe absence or inability to serve of the chairman. An officer of the\ndepartment designated by the commissioner may act as secretary for the\nboard if the board so elect; otherwise a secretary shall be elected from\nthe membership.\n  d. The state board shall meet at the call of the chairman or secretary\nwhen and where necessary within the state.\n  6. Regional and state board members; expenses.\n  Regional and state board members, including advisory members, shall\nreceive no salary, but their necessary traveling expenses when attending\nmeetings of the regional or state boards shall be paid from moneys\nappropriated to the department for travel and shall be paid on vouchers\ncertified by the chairman of the appropriate regional board or state\nboard upon the audit of the comptroller in the manner provided by law.\n  7. Duties of regional boards.\n  a. Each regional board shall formulate a statement of fish and\nwildlife management practices appropriate for its region and submit it\nfor approval to the state board and the commissioner. After such a\nstatement of practices has been approved by the state board and the\ncommissioner, the regional board shall formally adopt such statement of\npractices and encourage landowners, lessees and sportsmen within the\nregion to adopt and carry out the practices approved.\n  b. A copy of each resolution so adopting a statement of practices\ns</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>