<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0707"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0707"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0707"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0707">
        <num>11-0707</num>
        <heading>Exemptions from requirement of hunting, fishing and trapping licenses</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0707. Exemptions from requirement of hunting, fishing and trapping\n             licenses.\n  1. Resident owners and lessees and members of their immediate\nfamilies, actually occupying and cultivating farm lands, on such farm\nlands and the waters thereof, shall have the right,\n  a. to hunt wildlife except wild deer and bear,\n  b. to trap bobcat, coyote, fox, mink, muskrat, raccoon, opossum,\nweasel, skunk, and unprotected wildlife that may lawfully be taken by\ntrapping (except that only the owner or lessee thereof may trap without\nlicense on a registered muskrat marsh) and\n  c. to take fish and frogs, except that they may not take bait fish by\nnet or trap, all as if they held the licenses defined in section 11-0701\nand required by section 11-0703, subdivision 6.\n  2. Minors under the age of sixteen may take fish and frogs as if they\nheld fishing licenses, except that they may not take bait fish by net or\ntrap.\n  3. Any person who is a patient at any facility in this state\nmaintained by the United States Veterans Health Administration or at any\nhospital or sanitorium for treatment of tuberculosis maintained by the\nstate or any municipal corporation thereof or resident patient at any\ninstitution of the department of Mental Hygiene, or resident patient at\nthe rehabilitation hospital of the department of Health, or any\nincarcerated individual of a conservation work camp within the youth\nrehabilitation facility of the department of corrections and community\nsupervision, or any incarcerated individual of a youth opportunity or\nyouth rehabilitation center within the Office of Children and Family\nServices, any resident of a nursing home or residential health care\nfacility as defined in subdivisions two and three of section\ntwenty-eight hundred one of the public health law, or any staff member\nor volunteer accompanying or assisting one or more residents of such\nnursing home or residential health care facility on an outing authorized\nby the administrator of such nursing home or residential health care\nfacility may take fish as if he or she held a fishing license, except\nthat he or she may not take bait fish by net or trap, if he or she has\non his or her person an authorization upon a form furnished by the\ndepartment containing such identifying information and data as may be\nrequired by it, and signed by the superintendent or other head of such\nfacility, institution, hospital, sanitarium, nursing home, residential\nhealth care facility or rest camp, as the case may be, or by a staff\nphysician thereat duly authorized so to do by the superintendent or\nother head thereof. Such authorization with respect to incarcerated\nindividuals of said conservation work camps shall be limited to areas\nunder the care, custody and control of the department.\n  4. If persons holding fishing licenses issued under the New York Fish\nand Wildlife Law are not required to have licenses issued by a state\nnamed in paragraph a, b, c or d of this subdivision when fishing in that\npart of the waters, specified in such paragraph, which lies within that\nstate, then, in such case, a person holding a fishing license issued by\nsuch state may, without a fishing license issued under the New York\nState Fish and Wildlife Law, take fish as provided in title 13, from\nthat part of such waters specified in paragraph a, b, c or d which lies\nwithin this state:\n  a. License issued by Vermont: that part of Lake Champlain lying\nbetween New York and Vermont;\n  b. License issued by Pennsylvania: that part of the Delaware River\nlying between New York and Pennsylvania;\n  c. License issued by Connecticut: those parts of Indian Lake, and of\nSamuel Bargh Reservoir (Mianus Reservoir) lying between New York and\nConnecticut;\n  d. License issued by New Jersey: that part of Greenwood Lake lying\nbetween New York and New Jersey.\n  7. The owner or lessee of a registered muskrat marsh may, without\nlicense, trap muskrat, bobcat, coyote, fox, mink, raccoon, opossum,\nweasel, skunk, and unprotected wildlife permitted to be taken by\ntrapping, on such registered muskrat marsh.\n  8. The enrolled members of an Indian tribe having a reservation\nlocated wholly or partly within the state and such other Indians as are\npermitted by the tribal government having jurisdiction over such\nreservation may hunt, fish, trap upon such reservation subject only to\nrules, regulations and fish and wildlife laws established by the\ngoverning body of such reservation. Before fish and wildlife taken on\nreservations by Indians shall be transported or possessed off the\nreservation it shall be tagged for identification purposes in a manner\nto be required by the governing body of such reservation. This\nsubdivision shall in no way limit or otherwise impair the existing\npowers of any tribal government to regulate hunting, fishing and\ntrapping and/or to issue licenses for same.\n  9. A minor under the age of twelve may accompany and assist a licensed\ntrapper who is the minor's parent or legal guardian or who is a person\neighteen years of age or older designated in writing by the minor's\nparent or legal guardian on a form prescribed by the department and such\nparent, legal guardian or designee has had at least three years of\ntrapping experience. Such minor may assist the licensed adult in all\naspects of trapping without possessing a trapping license.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>