<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0321"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0321"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0321"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0321/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0321/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0321/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0321/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0321">
        <num>11-0321</num>
        <heading>"Restricted areas"; additional enforcement on private premises</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0321. "Restricted areas"; additional enforcement on private\n             premises.\n  1. Without limitation of the purpose and policy described in section\n11-0303, or of the powers conferred in other sections, the department is\nauthorized:\n  a. to adopt by regulation, classifications of "restricted areas" lying\nwithin the boundaries of premises, or of two or more sets of contiguous\npremises, privately owned and with respect to which a cooperation\nagreement pursuant to section 11-0501 is in force, or owned by the state\nor a political subdivision or public corporation thereof, in which\nhunting, fishing or trapping, or any of them, shall be, as provided by\nsuch regulation with respect to the classification in question,\nprohibited, or shall be restricted or regulated as to the manner, time\nor conditions applicable to the exercise in such "restricted areas" of\nthe privilege of entry upon such premises for purposes of hunting,\nfishing or trapping;\n  b. to adopt regulations with respect to the manner in which, and the\nconditions upon which, such "restricted areas" shall be recognized,\nincluding obligations to be undertaken by the owner or lessee of the\npremises for the furtherance of sound management practices and public\naccess for hunting, fishing or trapping, to premises outside the\n"restricted area", identification and notice to the public of the\nboundaries of the "restricted area", and the manner in which, and the\ngrounds upon which, the recognition of a "restricted area" may be\nrevoked or its classification changed;\n  c. to adopt regulations with respect to prohibitions applicable to\neach classification of a "restricted area";\n  2. Such restricted areas may be established pursuant to this section\nand regulations may be made with respect to the use of such areas for\none or more of the following purposes:\n  a. providing safety zones in and around buildings;\n  b. providing safety zones deemed necessary for temporary periods of\ntime for the protection of life or property during farm and woodlot\noperations;\n  c. protecting agricultural or forest crops from trampling or other\ndamage during critical growth periods;\n  d. development or carrying out of a program of research in game\nmanagement in connection with which the department deems it desirable to\ncontrol the hunting, fishing or trapping pressures or to put into effect\nspecial regulations authorized by section 11-0311 or by any other\nprovision of the Fish and Wildlife Law;\n  e. protecting the water supply or otherwise providing for the\nprotection of the health of the people of the state;\n  f. such other purposes relating to farm operation, woodlot\ndevelopment, fish and wildlife habitat improvement or public health and\nsafety which in the opinion of the department require special\nrestrictions on the use of particular premises.\n  3. No person shall charge or collect a fee or rental for the privilege\nof hunting, fishing or trapping in a restricted area established under\nthe authority of this section.\n  4. a. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 11-2111, a restricted\narea shall be deemed to be in existence and subject to the regulations\nestablished pursuant to this section with respect to restricted areas of\nthe classification to which it is assigned, when signs identifying its\nexistence shall have been erected on the premises in such manner as may\nbe required by the regulations of the department applicable thereto,\nmade as prescribed in paragraph b of subdivision 1 of this section.\n  b. No person shall enter or remain unlawfully or engage in any\nactivity upon land which has been posted pursuant to such regulations in\nviolation of the terms of such posted signs.\n  c. No unauthorized person shall injure, conceal, deface or remove a\nsign erected and maintained in accordance with such regulations.\n  d. The requirements of posting provided in section 11-2111 shall not\nbe applicable to the erection of signs identifying a restricted area.\n  e. Restricted areas may be established notwithstanding that the lands\nor waters or part of them, included within said restricted area may have\nbeen stocked with fish and game by the state.\n  f. The existence of the restricted area shall terminate in such manner\nas may be provided by regulations of the department.\n  5. The department is further authorized, at the discretion of the\ncommissioner, to exercise all of the powers and authority set forth in\nthis section, in relation to premises with respect to which agreements\nare in effect between the owner of such premises and the Agricultural\nStabilization and Conservation Service of the United States Department\nof Agriculture and such agreements provide for such regulations, whether\nor not such premises are the subject of an agreement pursuant to section\n11-0501. Payments to such landowners by the United States Department of\nAgriculture under such agreements shall not constitute a fee or rental\nwithin the meaning of subdivision 3 of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>