<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0925"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0925"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0925"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0925/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0925/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0925/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0925/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0925">
        <num>11-0925</num>
        <heading>Special dog training areas</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0925. Special dog training areas.\n  1. a. A dog owner or trainer may establish and maintain a special dog\ntraining area on land which the owner or trainer owns or has legal\ncontrol.\n  b. The operator of a special dog training area may at any time during\nthe year train the operator's own dogs or the dogs of other persons on\nsuch area, and permit others to train dogs. The operator may hold field\ntrials on wild game, or on liberated game, or on liberated artificially\npropagated game, or on led or confined game, or may in writing permit\nothers to hold such trials, under such conditions as shall be agreed\nupon by the operator and such other person; but no game shall be taken\nby shooting at such field trial. No persons shall, on a special dog\ntraining area, train a dog, hold a field trial, enter accompanied by a\ndog, or permit a dog of which he is the owner or trainer to enter,\nexcept as provided in this section or in rules adopted pursuant hereto.\nA permit from the department must be obtained before liberation of any\nwildlife, and such a permit may be withheld if, in the opinion of the\ndepartment, granting it would endanger the health of native wildlife\nspecies.\n  2. The department may adopt rules regulating the use of special dog\ntraining areas.\n  3. No person shall hunt on a special dog training area except as\nprovided in this section or rules adopted pursuant thereto. The owner of\nthe lands may hunt unprotected wildlife thereon at any time, and the\nowner of the land and others authorized by such owner may hunt deer\nthereon during the open season but at no other time.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>