<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0519"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0519"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0519"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0519/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0519/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0519/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0519/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0519">
        <num>11-0519</num>
        <heading>Disposition of fish, wildlife, game, shellfish, crustacea or protected insects seized by or surrendered to enforcement officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0519. Disposition of fish, wildlife, game, shellfish, crustacea or\n             protected insects seized by or surrendered to enforcement\n             officers.\n  1. When any fish, game, wildlife, shellfish, crustacea or part\nthereof, or any protected insect, or any bird plumage, is\n  a. seized by an enforcement officer as provided in section 71-0907 and\nit is thereafter determined that the possession thereof, by the person\nfrom whom it was seized, was unlawful under any provision of the Fish\nand Wildlife Law or regulation pursuant thereto; or\n  b. found in or released from a trap, snare, net or other device\nconstituting a nuisance which the officer is authorized summarily to\nabate as provided in section 71-0915; or\n  c. surrendered to an enforcement officer for disposition by any person\nhaving lawful custody or possession; possession thereof shall be deemed\nvested in the department on behalf of the state. All such things shall\nbe disposed of as may be determined by the enforcement officer, subject\nto law and any applicable regulations of the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>