<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0915"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0915"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0915"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0915/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0915/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0915/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0915/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0915">
        <num>11-0915</num>
        <heading>Disposal of deer, moose and bear killed unintentionally by collision</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0915. Disposal of deer, moose and bear killed unintentionally by\n               collision.\n  The owner of a motor vehicle which has been damaged by unintentional\ncollision with a deer, moose or bear shall be entitled to possess such\ndeer, moose or bear under the following conditions:\n  1. The accident is reported to an environmental conservation officer,\na member of the State Police, a member of the sheriff's department in\nwhich the accident occurred or, if the accident occurred on lands under\nthe jurisdiction of the office of parks, recreation and historic\npreservation, to an officer of the regional park police having law\nenforcement responsibilities on such lands, or to any police officer of\na city, town or village located in the county of such accident within 24\nhours thereafter.\n  2. The officer shall investigate and, if he finds the deer, moose or\nbear has been killed or so injured as to require that it be killed and\nthe damage has been done as alleged, he shall issue a permit to the\nowner of the motor vehicle entitling such owner to possess the carcass.\nSuch permit shall authorize the owner of the motor vehicle to transfer\nthe carcass to a designated person.\n  3. Whenever the owner of such damaged motor vehicle declines to\npossess such deer, moose or bear, the officer may in his discretion,\nissue a permit to possess the carcass to any other party requesting such\npossession.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>