<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0536"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0536"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0536"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0536/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0536/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0536/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0536/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0536">
        <num>11-0536</num>
        <heading>Sale of certain wild animals or wild animal products prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0536. Sale of certain wild animals or wild animal products\n             prohibited.\n  1. Except as provided in subdivision three hereof, no part of the skin\nor body, whether raw or manufactured, of the following species of wild\nanimals or the animal itself may be sold or offered for sale by any\nindividual, firm, corporation, association or partnership within the\nstate of New York:--Leopard (Panthera pardus), Snow Leopard (Uuncia),\nClouded Leopard (Neofelis nebulosa), Tiger (Panthera tigres), Asiatic\nLion (Panthera leo persica), Cheetah (Acinoyx jubatus), Alligators,\nCaiman or Crocodile of the Order Crocodylia (except as provided in\nsubdivision two of this section), tortoises of the genus Gopherus,\nmarine turtles of the family Cheloniidae and the family Dermochelidae,\nVicuna (Vicugna vicugna), Wolf (Canis lupus), Red Wolf (Canis niger), or\nTasmanian Forester Kangaroo (Macropus giganteus tasmaniensis) or Polar\nBear (Thalarctos maritimus), Mountain Lion, sometimes called Cougar\n(Felis Concolar), Jaguar (Panthera onca), Ocelot (Felis pardalis), or\nMargay (Felis wiedii), Sumatran Rhinoceros (Dicerorhinus sumatrensis),\nor Black Rhinoceros (Dicero bicornis).\n  2. The commissioner may permit, under such terms and conditions as he\nmay prescribe, the importation and sale of the skin, body or parts\ntherefrom of Alligators, Caiman or Crocodile of the Order Crocodylia.\n  3. Any officer or agent authorized by the commissioner, or any police\nofficer of the state of New York, or any police officer of any\nmunicipality within the state of New York, shall have authority to\nexecute any warrant to search for and seize any goods, merchandise or\nwildlife sold or offered for sale in violation of this section, or any\nproperty or item used in connection with a violation of this section;\nsuch goods, merchandise, wildlife or property shall be held pending\nproceedings in any court of proper jurisdiction. Upon conviction, or\nupon the entry of a judgment restraining the sale or offer for sale of\nsuch goods, merchandise or wildlife on the ground that such items were\nsold or offered for sale in violation of this section, such seized\ngoods, merchandise or wildlife shall be forfeited and, upon forfeiture,\neither offered to a recognized institution for scientific or educational\npurposes, or destroyed.\n  4. The commissioner may permit, under such terms and conditions as he\nmay prescribe, the importation, transportation, possession or sale of\nany species or subspecies of fish or wildlife listed in this section for\nzoological, educational, and scientific purposes, and for the\npropagation of such fish or wildlife in captivity for preservation\npurposes, unless such importation, transportation, possession or sale is\nprohibited by any federal law or regulation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>