<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0515"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0515"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0515"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0515/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0515/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0515/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0515/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0515">
        <num>11-0515</num>
        <heading>Licenses to collect, possess or sell for propagation, scientific or exhibition purposes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0515. Licenses to collect, possess or sell for propagation,\n             scientific or exhibition purposes.\n  1. The department may issue to any person a license revocable at its\npleasure to collect or possess fish, wildlife, shellfish, crustacea, or\naquatic insects, birds' nests or eggs for propagation, banding,\nscientific or exhibition purposes. The department in its discretion may\nrequire an applicant to pay a license fee of ten dollars, and to file a\nbond of two hundred dollars to be approved by the department that he or\nshe will not violate any provisions of this article. Each licensee shall\nfile with the department a report containing such information as the\ndepartment may require. Such license shall be in force for one year only\nand shall not be transferable.\n  2. The department may also issue a license revocable at its pleasure\nto possess and sell protected fish, wildlife, shellfish, crustacea or\naquatic insects for propagation, scientific or exhibition purposes. The\ndepartment in its discretion may require a license fee of ten dollars.\nSuch license shall be in force for one year only and shall not be\ntransferable. Each licensee shall file with the department a report\ncontaining such information as the department may require. Fish,\nwildlife, shellfish, crustacea or aquatic insects lawfully possessed\nunder this section may be sold at any time by the licensee for\npropagation, scientific or exhibition purposes only.\n  3. The department may also issue a revocable license to possess\ndistressed wildlife for rehabilitation purposes. The department may\nadopt regulations concerning the qualifications, appointment and duties\nof wildlife rehabilitators and the procedures for license issuance and\nrevocation.\n  4. The department shall have power to make regulations governing the\npossession of such fish, wildlife, shellfish, crustacea and aquatic\ninsects to protect them from cruelty, disease or undue discomfort and to\nprotect the public from attack or contamination.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>