<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0911"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0911"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0911"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0911">
        <num>11-0911</num>
        <heading>Procedure on taking wild deer and bear; transportation of wild deer</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0911. Procedure on taking wild deer and bear; transportation of\n             wild deer.\n  1. a. When a wild deer is taken the taker shall immediately fill out\nthe deer tag in an electronic or other acceptable format as provided in\nregulations of the department. The taker shall report details of the\nlocation and date of harvest and data on the deer as required by\nregulation.\n  b. When a bear is taken, the taker shall immediately fill out the bear\ntag in an electronic or other acceptable format as provided in\nregulations of the department. The taker shall report details of the\nlocation and date of harvest and data on the bear as required by\nregulation.\n  c. The department shall adopt regulations for the tagging or\ndesignating by self-locking metal seals or other means of deer of either\nsex taken in Westchester county pursuant to the provisions of paragraph\nc of subdivision 1, of section 11-0907, in addition to the limit of one\ndeer in a license year.\n  2. The taker shall remove his deer out of the woods or open country to\na camp or other inhabited location by midnight of the day immediately\nfollowing the expiration of the open season in the county or part of a\ncounty in which the deer was taken.\n  3. A person licensed to hunt deer pursuant to this chapter who has\nfilled all of his/her valid deer tags may assist and/or supervise other\nlicensed hunters in hunting deer, except that such person shall not\nshoot or attempt to shoot deer.\n  4. a. The taker may transport the entire carcass of his deer, with the\nhead attached in a natural way and his license tag attached to the\ncarcass.\n  b. He may detach the head of a male deer for mounting only and\ntransport it to a licensed taxidermist. If the head is detached, the\ntaker shall immediately attach to it a tag supplied by himself bearing\nhis signature, address and license number, the name and address of the\ntaxidermist and the number of points on each antler, and the head shall\nbe shipped to the taxidermist immediately. The tag shall remain attached\nto the head continuously until the head is received by the taxidermist\nand retained by him for six months after the head is mounted. If at any\ntime during transportation the head is in possession of a person other\nthan the taker or a carrier, his name and address shall be written on\nthe tag at the time the head comes into his possession.\n  c. The head of a female deer with antlers not less than the minimum\nlegal length may be detached for mounting.  The detached head shall be\nhandled in the manner provided in this subdivision with respect to the\nhead of a male deer.\n  d. The taker may transport the carcass of a male deer, from which he\nhas removed the head, if the carcass bears evidence of sex, or the\ncarcass of a female deer from which the head has been removed, if the\nmetal tag is attached thereto, provided in either case that his deer tag\nis attached to the carcass and on the reverse side of the tag there\nappears the name and address of the taxidermist to whom the head is to\nbe delivered and the number of points on each antler.\n  5. a. The taker may transport by carrier, except parcel post, one deer\nto which his deer tag is attached, together with an additional tag\nsupplied by him stating the name and address of the consignee. He shall\nbe in personal attendance on the carcass of his deer while it is being\ntransported by any method other than by carrier, except that if the head\nhas not been removed, and if there are attached to the carcass the\ntaker's deer tag and a tag supplied by him on which is written legibly\nin ink the name and address of the person transporting the deer and the\nname and address of the consignee, the deer may be transported for him\nby another.\n  b. The taker may cut portions of the meat from the carcass and\ntransport or cause them to be transported to consignees for consumption\nas food only, provided that his deer tag remains attached at all times\nto the portion of the carcass retained by him, and that each portion\ntransported has attached a tag supplied by the taker and personally\nsigned by him, on which he shall write legibly in ink his name, address\nand license number, the date when the portions were cut, and the name\nand address of the consignee. If at any time during transportation any\nsuch portion is in possession of a person other than the taker or his\nconsignee, the name and address of such person shall be written legibly\non the tag in ink. The tag shall remain attached to the meat until it is\nprepared for consumption. Where such portions are transported wrapped or\nboxed, the outside of the package shall bear the word "venison" and be\nmarked as provided in this paragraph for tags.  Portions of deer tagged\nas provided in this paragraph, and packages containing portions of deer,\nso marked, may be transported by carrier except parcel post.\n  6. a. The taker may transport the carcass of the bear, for the\npurposes of harvesting the gallbladder and/or bile, only if the bear tag\nis attached thereto.\n  b. No person taking, possessing or transporting bear shall fail to\ncomply with the mandatory requirements of this section and section\n11-0917 of this title.\n  7. No person taking, possessing or transporting wild deer shall fail\nto comply with the mandatory requirements of this section, and no person\nshall possess or transport wild deer or any portion of a wild deer\nexcept as provided in this section, or at a time not permitted by\nsection 11-0917.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>