<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0935"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0935"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0935"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0935/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0935/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0935/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0935/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0935">
        <num>11-0935</num>
        <heading>Deer hunting program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0935__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such minor is accompanied by their parent or legal guardian, or by\na person designated in writing by such parent or legal guardian on a\nform prescribed by the department who is twenty-one years of age or\nolder; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0935__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such parent, guardian or person has had at least three year's\nexperience in hunting deer; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0935__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such parent, guardian or person holds a hunting license; and\n  (ii) such parent, guardian or person maintains physical control over\nthe minor at all times while hunting. For the purposes of this paragraph\n"physical control" shall mean that the physical proximity of such minor\nto the parent, guardian or person is such that the parent, guardian or\nperson is reasonably able to issue verbal directions and instructions,\nmaintain constant visual contact, and otherwise provide guidance and\nsupervision to the minor; and\n  (iii) such parent, guardian or person and the minor remain at ground\nlevel at all times while hunting; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_0935__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such parent, guardian or person and the minor shall each display\neither a minimum total of two hundred fifty square inches of solid\nfluorescent orange or pink or patterned fluorescent orange or pink\nconsisting of no less than fifty percent fluorescent orange or pink\nmaterial worn above the waist and visible from all directions, or a hat\nor cap with no less than fifty percent of the exterior consisting of\nsolid fluorescent orange or pink material and visible from all\ndirections.\n  2. For the purposes of this section "eligible area" shall include a\ncounty that has passed a local law authorizing participation in the\npilot program and has notified the department of such participation,\nprovided, however, that the following counties: Westchester; Richmond;\nBronx; New York; Kings; Queens; Nassau; and Suffolk shall not be deemed\nto be eligible.\n  3. The department shall prepare a report by February first of each\nyear including the following information at a minimum: number of\nviolations; hunting related incidents and revocations pursuant to\nsection 11-0719; the number of counties participating; the number of\nminors participating; and the number of deer taken.\n  * NB Repealed December 31, 2028\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>