<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0701"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0701">
        <num>11-0701</num>
        <heading>Definitions of licenses and privileges of licensees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0701. Definitions of licenses and privileges of licensees.\n  1. A hunting license:\n  a. entitles a holder who is twelve or thirteen years of age to hunt\nwildlife, except big game, as provided in title 9 of this article\nsubject, specifically, to the provisions of section 11-0929 of this\narticle. It entitles such holder to possess firearms as provided in\nsection 265.05 of the penal law. A holder who is twelve or thirteen\nyears of age shall not hunt with a crossbow.\n  b. entitles a holder who is fourteen or fifteen years of age to hunt\nwildlife, including wild deer and bear, as provided in title 9 of this\narticle, subject, specifically, to the provisions of section 11-0929 of\nthis article. It entitles such holder to possess firearms as provided in\nsection 265.05 of the penal law.\n  2. a. A hunting license entitles the holder to hunt wildlife subject\nto the following:\n  (1) a holder who is eighteen years of age or older may hunt wildlife\nas provided in title 9 of this article,\n  (2) a holder who is sixteen years of age or older may hunt wildlife,\nexcept big game, as provided in title 9 of this article, and\n  (3) a holder who is between the ages of sixteen and eighteen may hunt\nbig game pursuant to the provisions of title 9 of this article while the\nholder is accompanied by a parent, guardian or person over the age of\neighteen as required by section 11-0929 of this article.\n  A holder may take fish with a longbow as provided in titles 9 and 13\nof this article.\n  b. A special antlerless deer license is applicable to the hunting of\nwild antlerless deer in a special open season fixed pursuant to\nsubdivision 6 of section 11-0903 of this article in a tract within a\nWilderness Hunting Area and entitles the holder of a hunting license to\nhunt antlerless deer in such special open season, as provided in title 9\nof this article if he or she has on his or her person while so hunting\nboth his or her hunting license and his or her special antlerless deer\nlicense.\n  3. A bowhunting privilege when included on a hunting license entitles\na holder:\n  (1) who is between the ages of twelve and sixteen years to hunt wild\ndeer and bear with a longbow during the special archery season and\nduring the regular season, as provided in title 9 of this article,\nsubject to the provisions of section 11-0929 and subdivision 3 of\nsection 11-0713 of this article;\n  (2) who is eighteen years of age or older to hunt wild deer and bear\nwith a longbow, as provided in title 9 of this article, in a special\nlongbow season; and\n  (3) who is sixteen or seventeen years of age to exercise the same\nprivileges subject to the provisions of section 11-0929 and subdivision\n3 of section 11-0713 of this article.\n  4. A fishing license entitles the holder to take fish by angling,\nspearing, hooking, longbow and tipups, to take frogs by spearing,\ncatching with the hands or by use of a club or hook, and to take bait\nfish for personal use, as provided in titles 9 and 13 of this article,\nexcept that such license shall not entitle the holder to take migratory\nfish of the sea or to take fish from the waters of the marine district.\n  5. A non-resident bear tag entitles a person who has not been a\nresident of the state for more than thirty days who also possesses a\nhunting license to hunt bear during the regular open season therefor or\nin an open season fixed by regulation pursuant to subdivision eight of\nsection 11-0903 of this article. It entitles a non-resident holder who\nalso possesses a hunting license with bowhunting privilege to hunt bear\nwith a longbow during the open bear season. It entitles a non-resident\nholder who also possesses a hunting license with muzzle-loading\nprivilege to hunt bear with a muzzleloader during the open bear season.\n  6. A seven-day fishing license entitles the holder to exercise the\nprivileges of a fishing license for the seven consecutive days specified\nin the license.\n  7. A one-day fishing license entitles the holder to exercise the\nprivileges of a fishing license on the day specified on the license.\n  8. A trapping license entitles the holder to trap beaver, otter,\nfisher, mink, muskrat, skunk, raccoon, bobcat, coyote, fox, opossum,\nweasel, pine marten and unprotected wildlife except birds, as provided\nin title 11, subject to the provisions of section 11-0713 of this\narticle.\n  9. A muzzle-loading privilege when included on a hunting license\nentitles a holder who is fourteen years of age or older to hunt wild\ndeer and bear with a muzzle-loading firearm or crossbow, as provided in\ntitle 9 of this article, in a special muzzle-loading firearm season.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>