<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0527"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0527"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0527"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0527/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0527/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0527/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0527/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0527">
        <num>11-0527</num>
        <heading>State aid to counties participating in control of rabies in wildlife</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0527. State aid to counties participating in control of rabies in\n             wildlife.\n  1. The board of supervisors or county legislative body of any county\nmay appropriate moneys for the purpose of controlling the disease rabies\nin wildlife.\n  2. Any county situated in an area wherein the infection of wild foxes\nor other wildlife populations is certified to exist with danger to\nhealth and welfare, in accordance with the provisions of section\n11-0525, may submit a plan for joint approval by the state departments\nof Health, Agriculture and Markets and Environmental Conservation for\nthe purposes of eliminating, reducing or confining the disease rabies.\nIf such plan, or a modification of such plan, is approved by such\ndepartments and is duly carried out by any such county in accordance\nwith such regulations as may be adopted by the Department of\nEnvironmental Conservation (which regulations when adopted shall be made\na part of such plan) then such county shall be reimbursed by the state\nto the extent of fifty per centum of the amount by it expended in the\nexecution of such plan; provided, however, that such reimbursement to\nany county shall not exceed six thousand dollars in any state fiscal\nyear.\n  3. A county shall not be reimbursed for any moneys expended by it for\nthe payment of bounties for the taking of wildlife.\n  4. Not later than the last day of each of the months of June,\nSeptember, December and March the county treasurer of each such county\nwhich has been certified under section 11-0525 and approved under this\nsection, and has incurred expenditures pursuant to the provisions of\nthis section during the three months' period ending on such days, shall\nmake a report to the Commissioner of Environmental Conservation of the\namount of such expenditures and apply for the state reimbursement herein\nauthorized.\n  5. Such report and application shall be in such form and contain such\ninformation as may be required by the Commissioner of Environmental\nConservation. The commissioner shall thereupon promptly certify to the\ncomptroller for payment the amount of state reimbursement due the county\nthereon. The amounts so certified by the Commissioner of Environmental\nConservation, after audit by and on the warrant of the Comptroller,\nshall be paid to the county treasurers of the respective counties to\nwhich such reimbursement is due, from any moneys available by\nappropriation therefor. No reimbursement shall be made for expenditures\nincurred by any county after such time as the Departments of Health and\nAgriculture and Markets shall have certified that danger to health and\nwelfare from the disease rabies no longer exists in such county.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>