<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0533"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0533"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0533"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0533/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0533/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0533/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0533/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0533">
        <num>11-0533</num>
        <heading>Licensing of guides</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0533. Licensing of guides.\n  1. As used in this section, the term "guide" shall mean a person who\noffers services for hire part or all of which includes directing,\ninstructing, or aiding another in fishing, hunting, camping, hiking,\nwhite water canoeing, rafting or rock and ice climbing.\n  2. All guides engaging in the business of guiding on all lands and\nwaters of the state shall possess a license issued by the department,\nexcept for any persons operating or assisting upon a public vessel for\nhire (passenger carrying vessels), licensed by the United States Coast\nGuard or New York state, upon the Atlantic Ocean and all other marine\nand coastal waters, tidal waters including the Hudson river up to the\nTroy barrier dam, St. Lawrence river, Great Lakes and the navigable\nportion of their tributaries, and other navigable waters, as determined\nby the department.\n  3. Except while guiding for the purposes of hunting and/or fishing, no\nlicense as defined in section 11-0701 is required for such acts.\n  4. Employees of children's camps as defined in subdivision one of\nsection one thousand four hundred of the public health law shall be\nexempt from the provisions of subdivisions one and two of this section,\nprovided such activities are carried out within the scope of said\nemployment.\n  5. A license as required under subdivision two of this section shall\nbe issued for a period of five calendar years and the fee therefor shall\nbe established by the department, not to exceed two hundred dollars.\n  6. Every licensed guide while engaged in guiding shall wear in plain\nsight identification furnished by the department. Licensed guides shall\nbe at least eighteen years of age. They shall be skilled in the use of\nboats and canoes whenever use of these craft is required and shall be\npersons competent to guide one or more of the following: camping,\nhunting, fishing, hiking, white water canoeing/rafting, rock or ice\nclimbing or other similar activities. The department shall by regulation\nestablish standards and procedures for testing and licensing of guides.\n  7. Any licensed guide who violates any provision of this chapter or\nwho makes any false statement in his application for a license shall in\naddition to any other penalties, immediately surrender his license to\nthe department, which may be revoked by the department for up to one\nyear following the date of such surrender.\n  8. The department shall publish a list of guides annually.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>