<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0525"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0525"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-0525"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0525/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0525/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0525/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-0525/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_0525">
        <num>11-0525</num>
        <heading>Control of rabies in wildlife</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-0525. Control of rabies in wildlife.\n  1. Whenever the disease rabies occurs in any area of the state and the\ninfection of wild foxes or other wildlife populations is certified to\nexist therein by the joint determination of the Departments of Health,\nAgriculture and Markets and Environmental Conservation, and\ncertification is made to the Commissioner of Environmental Conservation\nby the Commissioners of Health and of Agriculture and Markets that the\nhealth and welfare of the human population or the health and welfare of\ndomestic livestock are in danger therefrom, the department is thereupon\nauthorized and directed to undertake through the use of professional\ntrappers or by other means such fox control or wildlife control measures\nin the certified area as in its judgment will eliminate, reduce or\nconfine the disease.\n  2. Such control measures shall be continued until the Commissioners of\nHealth, Agriculture and Markets and Environmental Conservation shall\njointly determine that control measures should be terminated.\n  3. Necessary expenses for such control work shall be financed by\nmoneys made available by appropriation or otherwise to the department\nout of moneys in the state treasury, in the general fund, to the credit\nof the state purpose fund not otherwise appropriated.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>