<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1905"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1905"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1905"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1905/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1905/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1905">
        <num>11-1905</num>
        <heading>Breeding of domestic game animals</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-1905. Breeding of domestic game animals.\n  1. The department may, in its discretion, issue to an owner or lessee\nof wholly enclosed lands or an entire island a domestic game animal\nbreeder's license permitting him to possess and propagate domestic game\nanimals provided such animals are confined and cared for according to\nspecifications and regulations which the department, by order, shall\nadopt. The license shall expire on March 31 every fifth year. The\ndepartment shall prescribe and furnish forms for application for such\nlicense. Applicants shall pay, and the department shall be entitled to\nreceive, fees in accordance with the type of license issued.\n  a. Class A license, two hundred dollars. This license shall allow the\nholder thereof to purchase, possess, propagate, transport and sell\ndomestic game animals dead or alive.\n  b. Class B license, forty dollars. This license shall allow the holder\nthereof to purchase, possess and propagate domestic game animals for his\nown use. No animals may be sold, exchanged or given away except that\nportions of the carcass may be given away provided they are packaged and\nthe package bears the name and license number of the licensee.\n  2. The department may revoke the license of any licensee convicted of\na violation of this section, and no license shall be issued to him for\nthe ensuing two years.\n  3. Only domestic game animals legally propagated or acquired shall be\npossessed under these licenses.\n  4. On the premises described in the application for the license, the\nlicensee may kill domestic game animals at any time and in any manner\nand, with the consent of the licensee, any person may take domestic game\nanimals by shooting at any time.\n  5. The holder of a domestic game animal breeder's license shall keep\nrecords and make reports as required by and upon forms furnished by the\ndepartment. The reports shall be subscribed by the licensee, and shall\ncontain an affirmation that the statements therein are made subject to\nthe penalties of perjury. The records shall be continuous and shall be\nkept on the licensed premises, and the licensee shall allow any\nrepresentative of the department to enter the premises to inspect his\noperations and records. Records must be retained for a period of three\nyears.\n  6. Domestic game animal carcasses and parts shall be identified as\nrequired by section 11-1721 of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>