<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1911"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1911"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1911"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1911">
        <num>11-1911</num>
        <heading>Farm fish ponds</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_1911__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\npermission to control undesirable fish, aquatic vegetation and insect\nlife, interfering with the production of fish and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_11_1911__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>permission,\nnotwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter to the contrary, to\nrelease, stock and propagate fish in the licensed pond. The department\nmay specify in the license methods of control to be used and the manner\nof taking and type, size and mesh of gear to be used in taking fish. The\ndepartment may, for cause, revoke or suspend any license issued pursuant\nto this section.\n  3. No person shall release any species of fish into a farm fish pond\nunless permission to do so is first obtained from the department.\n  4. A licensee, any member of his immediate family, and any person\nactually employed by him in the cultivation of his farm or the\nmanagement of the licensed pond may without license issued under title 7\nof the Fish and Wildlife Law, take fish of any size, in any number, at\nany time, in any manner permitted by the department.\n  5. The holder of any type of fishing license, or a person entitled to\nexercise the privileges of such a license, may, with the permission of\nthe licensee, take fish by angling from the licensed pond provided the\nholder complies with the provisions of title 13 of the Fish and Wildlife\nLaw, with respect to open seasons, minimum size limits and daily and\nseasonal possession limits.\n  6. a. Fish protected by law, except trout, black bass, muskellunge and\nlandlocked salmon, legally taken from a licensed farm fish pond, may be\nbought and sold during their respective open seasons, and may be\npossessed and transported at any time. Trout, black bass, muskellunge\nand landlocked salmon, legally taken from a licensed farm fish pond may\nbe possessed and transported during their respective open seasons and\nuntil March 1 immediately following, but unless such fish were taken by\na person described in subdivision 4 or are frozen or otherwise processed\nand packaged for storage and are being transported to a place of storage\nor consumption, no person shall transport in any one day a quantity of\nsuch fish exceeding...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>