<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1901"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1901"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="11-1901"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1901/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-11-1901/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_11_1901">
        <num>11-1901</num>
        <heading>Breeding of domestic game birds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 11-1901. Breeding of domestic game birds.\n  1. The department may, in its discretion, issue to an owner or lessee\nof wholly enclosed lands, or an entire island, a domestic game bird\nbreeder's license permitting him to possess and propagate such species\nof domestic game birds as, in its opinion, he has facilities for\npropagating on the licensed premises. The license shall expire on March\n31 every fifth year. The department shall prescribe and furnish forms\nfor application for such license. Applicants shall pay to the\ndepartment, and the department shall be entitled to receive, fees\naccording to the type of license so issued as follows:\n  a. Class A license, two hundred dollars. This license shall allow the\nholder thereof to purchase, possess, propagate, transport and sell\ndomestic game birds, dead or alive, and their eggs.\n  b. Class B license, forty dollars. This license shall allow the holder\nthereof to purchase, possess and propagate domestic game birds for his\nown use. Birds may be killed for food or released to the wild for\nrestocking. No live birds or their eggs or carcasses may be sold,\nexchanged or given away.\n  2. The department may revoke the license of any licensee convicted of\na violation of this section, and no license shall be issued to him for\nthe ensuing two years. The licensee, unless he shall waive such right,\nshall have an opportunity to be heard. Notice of hearing shall be given\nby mailing the same in writing to the licensee at the address contained\nin his license. Attendance of witnesses may be compelled by subpoena.\nRevocation shall be deemed an administrative act reviewable by the\nsupreme court as such.\n  3. Only domestic game birds legally propagated or acquired shall be\npossessed under these licenses.\n  4. On the licensed premises the licensee may kill domestic game birds\nat any time in any manner except by shooting. Nothing in this section\nshall be construed to prohibit the shooting of domestic game birds\nliberated on the licensed premises if such shooting is done during the\nopen season for such species or pursuant to a license under section\n11-1903.\n  5. Each such domestic duck, goose, brant and swan shall be marked in\naccordance with requirements set forth in rules and regulations\nestablished by the department of the interior pursuant to 50 C.F.R. 21\nas may be amended from time to time. Such information shall be provided\nby department press release and any other means that the department\ndetermines to be appropriate and effective, including posting on the\ndepartment's public website. Birds so marked, which have escaped, may be\nrecaptured by the licensee. Escaped birds may be recaptured only on the\npremises of the licensee.\n  6. The holder of a domestic game bird breeder's license shall keep\nrecords and make reports as required by and upon forms furnished by the\ndepartment. The reports shall be subscribed by the licensee, and shall\ncontain an affirmation that the statements therein are made subject to\nthe penalties of perjury. The records shall be continuous and current\nand shall be kept on the licensed premises, and the licensee shall allow\nany representative of the department to enter upon the premises to\ninspect his operations and records. Records must be retained for a\nperiod of three years.\n  7. On the licensed premises the licensee may take any unprotected wild\nbird, or any predatory wildlife except, protected birds, disturbing\ndomestic game. Such birds or wildlife may be taken at any time and in\nany manner, except that no trap of the leg-gripping type, having teeth\nin the jaws or having a greater spread of jaws than six inches, shall be\nused for such purpose, nor shall a trap be set so that any wildlife when\ncaught shall be suspended. Carcasses of such birds or wildlife shall be\nimmediately buried or cremated, except that carcasses of unprotected\nwildlife, and of protected wildlife other than birds if taken during\ntheir respective open seasons, may be possessed, transported, bought and\nsold to the extent permitted by section 11-0917.\n  8. Domestic game bird carcasses and parts shall be identified as\nrequired by section 11-1721 of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>