<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0339-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0339-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0339_A">
        <num>13-0339-A</num>
        <heading>Atlantic cod (Gadus morhua), Atlantic sturgeon (Acipenser oxyrhynchus), shortnose sturgeon (Acipenser brevirostrum), American eel (Anguil...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 13-0339-a. Atlantic cod (Gadus morhua), Atlantic sturgeon (Acipenser\n               oxyrhynchus), shortnose sturgeon (Acipenser\n               brevirostrum), American eel (Anguilla rostrata), Atlantic\n               herring (Clupea horengus), American shad (Alosa\n               sapidissima), alewife (Alosa pseudoharengus), blueback\n               herring (Alosa aestivalis), squid (cephalopoda), and\n               hickory shad (Alosa mediocris).\n  1. The department may fix, by regulation, measures for the management\nof the following species:\n  a. Atlantic cod (Gadus morhua) until December thirty-first, two\nthousand twenty-six,\n  b. American eel (Anguilla rostrata) until December thirty-first, two\nthousand twenty-six,\n  c. Atlantic and shortnose sturgeon (Acipenser oxyrhynchus and\nbrevirostrum) until December thirty-first, two thousand twenty-six,\n  d. Atlantic herring (Clupea harengus) until December thirty-first, two\nthousand twenty-six,\n  e. American shad (Alosa sapidissima) until December thirty-first, two\nthousand twenty-eight,\n  f. alewife (Alosa pseudoharengus) until December thirty-first, two\nthousand twenty-eight,\n  g. blueback herring (Alosa aestivalis) until December thirty-first,\ntwo thousand twenty-six,\n  h. squid (cephalopoda) until December thirty-first, two thousand\ntwenty-six, and\n  i. hickory shad (Alosa mediocris) until December thirty-first, two\nthousand twenty-eight.\n  2. Such management regulations may include size limits, catch and\npossession limits, open and closed seasons, closed areas, restrictions\non the manner of taking and landing, requirements for permits and\neligibility therefor, recordkeeping requirements, requirements on the\namount and type of fishing effort and gear, and requirements relating to\ntransportation, possession and sale, provided that such regulations are\nno less restrictive than requirements set forth in this chapter and\nprovided further that such regulations are consistent with the\ncompliance requirements of applicable fishery management plans adopted\nby the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission and with applicable\nprovisions of fishery management plans adopted pursuant to the Federal\nFishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. ยง 1800 et seq.).\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>