<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0340-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0340-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0340-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0340-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0340-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0340-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0340-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0340_G">
        <num>13-0340-G</num>
        <heading>Monkfish (Lophius americanus, Lophius reticulatus and Lophius gastrophysus)</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 13-0340-g. Monkfish (Lophius americanus, Lophius reticulatus and\n               Lophius gastrophysus).\n  The department may, until December thirty-first, two thousand\ntwenty-seven, fix by regulation measures for the management of monkfish\n(Lophius americanus, Lophius reticulatus and Lophius gastrophysus),\nincluding size limits, catch and possession limits, open and closed\nseasons, closed areas, restrictions on the manner of taking and landing,\nrequirements for permits and eligibility therefor, recordkeeping\nrequirements, requirements on the amount and type of fishing effort and\ngear, and requirements relating to transportation, possession and sale,\nprovided that such regulations are no less restrictive than requirements\nset forth in this chapter and provided further that such regulations are\nconsistent with the compliance requirements of applicable fishery\nmanagement plans adopted by the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries\nCommission and with applicable provisions of fishery management plans\nadopted pursuant to the Federal Fishery Conservation and Management Act\n(16 U.S.C. ยง 1800 et seq.).\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>