<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0315"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0315"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0315"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0315">
        <num>13-0315</num>
        <heading>Shellfish shipper's and processor's permit</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_13_0315__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nreship shellfish previously shipped by the holder of a class A, B, C, D\nor E permit issued pursuant to this section, or similar permit issued by\nthe shellfish sanitation control agency of another state or foreign\ncountry; (ii) pack or repack shellstock received from the holder of a\ndigger's permit, pursuant to section 13-0311 of this title; or (iii)\npack or repack shellstock from the holder of a class A, B, C, D or E\npermit issued pursuant to this section, or similar permit issued by the\nshellfish sanitation control agency of another state or foreign country.\nThe fee for a class A permit shall be three hundred dollars.\n  b. Class B permit. This permit shall allow the holder thereof and any\nperson in the employ of the permit holder to engage in the activities\nauthorized by a class A permit, as described in paragraph a of this\nsubdivision, and to otherwise process shellfish as authorized by\nregulations adopted pursuant to section 13-0319 of this title. The fee\nfor a class B permit shall be six hundred dollars.\n  c. Class C permit. This permit shall allow the holder thereof and any\nperson in the employ of the permit holder, in accordance with\nregulations adopted pursuant to section 13-0319 of this title, to reship\nshellfish previously shipped by the holder of a class A, B, C, D or E\npermit issued pursuant to this section, or similar permit issued by the\nshellfish sanitation control agency of another state or foreign country.\nThe fee for a class C permit shall be two hundred dollars.\n  d. Class D permit. This permit shall allow the holder thereof, in\naccordance with regulations adopted pursuant to section 13-0319 of this\ntitle, to ship shellstock which the holder has legally harvested from\nshellfish lands of the state. The fee for a class D permit shall be\nseventy-five dollars.\n  e. Class E permit. This permit shall allow the holder thereof, members\nof the permit holder's immediate family and not more than two employees\nof the permit holde...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>