<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0705"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0705"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="13-0705"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-13-0705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_13_0705">
        <num>13-0705</num>
        <heading>Departmental responsibilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 13-0705. Departmental responsibilities.\n  1. The department shall designate seagrass management areas.\nDesignation of such areas shall include consideration, on a geographic\nor estuarine basis, of likely threats to seagrass.\n  2. For each designated seagrass management area, the department shall\ndevelop and adopt a seagrass management plan to guide the development of\nrules and regulations pursuant to subdivision three of this section.\nSuch plan shall be developed after consultation with local governments,\nrepresentatives of recreational boating interests, the marine industries\n(including commercial and recreational shell fishermen, and commercial\nshell fish farmers), affected property owners, and other stakeholders,\nso as to effectively manage and protect seagrass beds and seagrass\nrestoration efforts at those locations at which the restoration of\nseagrass is reasonably possible. Such plans shall, to the extent\npracticable, take into consideration, the goals of existing estuary\nprograms. In addition, seagrass management plans shall seek to preserve\ntraditional recreational activities, including recreational boating and\nmarina operations, as well as finfishing, shellfishing and tourism while\nensuring such activities do not threaten seagrass beds or negate\nseagrass restoration efforts.\n  3. The department shall have the authority to adopt rules and\nregulations to regulate coastal and marine activities that threaten\nseagrass beds or seagrass restoration efforts.\n  4. The department shall have the authority to restrict the use of\nmechanical-powered fishing or shellfishing gear which may directly\nimpact seagrass beds, including churning, dredges, rakes and tongs.\n  5. The department shall identify water quality impacts such as\nnitrogen pollution and make recommendations on how to minimize such\nimpacts.\n  6. The department shall make information concerning the importance of\nseagrass protection and the status of seagrass restoration efforts\navailable on the department website.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>