<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0315"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0315"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-0315"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-0315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_0315">
        <num>15-0315</num>
        <heading>Relations with other governmental bodies and agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-0315. Relations with other governmental bodies and agencies.\n  1. In order to adequately protect the interests of the state in its\nwater resources, the department is hereby authorized to:\n  a. Cooperate with the appropriate agencies of the federal government\nor this or other states, or any interstate bureau, group, division or\nagency with respect to the use of water from lakes, ponds, rivers and\nstreams, which are without or wholly or partially contained within this\nstate, and to endeavor to harmonize any conflicting claims which might\narise therefrom.\n  b. Appear, represent and act for the state in respect to any\nproceeding before either a federal or state governmental body or agency\nwhere the water resources of the state may be affected, and may do and\nperform such acts in connection therewith as it deems proper to protect\nthe interests of the state.\n  c. Present for the consideration of the Congress or officers of the\nfederal government, as occasion requires, the just rights of the state\nin relation to its waters and institute and prosecute appropriate\nactions and proceedings to secure such rights, and defend any action or\nproceeding calculated to impair such rights.\n  2. The department is designated as the agent of the state to obtain\nthe cooperation, aid and assistance of any appropriate federal agencies\nin the performance of the functions of the department or of any regional\nplanning and development board created under title 11 of this article.\nThe department may enter into contracts, when required, with any such\nfederal agencies for such purposes. Wherever it is required by a federal\nstatute, rule or regulations that such cooperation, aid and assistance\nbe given on a matching-funds basis, the department, if funds have been\nappropriated and are available therefor, is designated as the agent of\nthe state to enter into contracts on said basis; provided, however, that\npayment by the state shall not exceed one-half of the cost, including\npersonal service, of the services rendered by the federal agencies. All\ncontracts entered into by the department shall be executed by its\ncommissioner and in the manner and form prescribed by law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>