<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1957"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1957"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1957"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1957/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1957/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1957/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1957/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1957">
        <num>15-1957</num>
        <heading>Drainage fund</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1957. Drainage fund.\n  1. The Comptroller shall designate a depository or depositories for\nreceiving all moneys provided for the repair or enlargement of the\nditches or channels specified in section 15-1945. The fund thus created\nshall be known as "the drainage fund." Before any such deposit shall be\nreceived by any such depository, such depository shall execute and file\nwith the Comptroller a bond in such penal sum, with such sureties and\nupon such conditions as shall be approved by the Comptroller.\n  2. The department is hereby authorized and empowered to enlarge and\nrepair such ditches or channels in accordance with the procedure\nprescribed by that section and to pay the costs thereof from the\ndrainage fund herein created. All moneys received pursuant to section\n15-1945 shall be deposited by the comptroller to the credit of such\ndrainage fund. At the time of any such deposit, the department shall\nsend to the Comptroller an original duplicate of the deposit slip,\ntogether with a statement of the amount and by whom paid. The moneys of\nthe drainage fund shall be paid out by the Comptroller on the order of\nthe department or the authorized officer thereof.\n  3. The drainage fund may also be used to defray the costs of surveys,\ndetermination of enhancements, apportionment of costs or similar matters\nin a district or for maintenance of ditches and minor repairs thereto in\na district in lieu of raising the necessary funds pursuant to the Local\nFinance Law, provided, however, that no such proceeding or project shall\ncost more than five thousand dollars. Any moneys so advanced from this\nfund shall be repaid to it by the Comptroller as soon as they are\ncollected and paid to him by the county treasurer.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>