<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1735"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1735"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1735"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1735/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1735/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1735/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1735/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1735">
        <num>15-1735</num>
        <heading>Contracts extending beyond license period</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1735. Contracts extending beyond license period.\n  1. Whenever the public interest requires or justifies the execution by\na licensee whose license covers any state property, or who uses water\nthat cannot be lawfully used without the consent of the state, of a\ncontract for the sale and delivery of power for a period extending\nbeyond the terms of the license, such a contract may be entered into\nwith the approval of the department and the Public Service Commission,\nin which event the duty to perform such contract after the expiration of\nthe license period shall devolve upon the person or corporation to whom\nor which a new license covering the property of the former licensee is\nissued, and such new license shall so provide.\n  2. A licensee making such a contract shall not be liable thereon after\nthe expiration of his license, if it cover any state property or the use\nof water subject to state control, unless the new license is issued to\nhim. No such licensee without the written approval of the department\nshall enter into any contract for the sale or delivery of power for a\nterm or period extending beyond the time fixed for the revision of the\nchange or rental payable under his license.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>