<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1979"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1979"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1979"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1979/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1979/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1979/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1979/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1979">
        <num>15-1979</num>
        <heading>First annual meeting; members; officers; by-laws</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1979. First annual meeting; members; officers; by-laws.\n  1. Upon filing and recording, the articles of association shall be\ndeemed to be in effect and the drainage section association created\nthereby shall have the power and authority and shall assume the\nliabilities conferred and imposed by title 19 of this article. The\ntemporary secretary shall notify all members by mail of the time, not\nmore than ten days after such filing and recording, and of the place of\nthe first annual meeting of the association, at which time permanent\nofficers shall be elected for the coming year.\n  2. The original membership of the association shall consist of the\nsigners of the articles of association. Membership shall cease when a\nmember dies or when he divests himself of the entire drainable acreage\nowned by him. Grantees, devisees and heirs of the fee of a member's\nentire drainable acreage shall be members and entitled to all the rights\nof membership, and they shall be bound by the articles of association.\nGrantees, devisees and heirs of the fee of a part of a member's\ndrainable acreage shall be members, shall be entitled to all the rights\nof membership, shall be bound by the articles of association and shall\nbe liable in the proportion that such granted, devised or inherited part\nbears to the total of the drainable acreage of the member from whom they\nhave taken title.\n  3. The officers of the association shall be members thereof and shall\nconsist of a president, vice-president, and secretary-treasurer. If an\nofficer's membership in the association shall terminate, the association\nshall call a special meeting to elect his successor for the remainder of\nthe term for which he was elected. The term of office of all officers\nshall be one year.\n  4. The association shall adopt at the first annual meeting by-laws,\nnot inconsistent with law or with the articles of association. The\nby-laws shall fix the time and place of future annual meetings and\nregular meetings of the association and shall provide for the calling\nand holding of special meetings; shall provide the number of members,\nnot less than one-third, to constitute a quorum at its meetings; shall\nprovide the method of conduct of elections of its officers at annual\nmeetings; shall provide the form of notice, in writing, to be given to\nall members of the amount of assessment due to pay the debts of the\nassociation, and to pay all costs, expenses, fees and damages as\nprovided in the articles of association; and may provide for the\nimposition and collection of annual dues and for any other matter\nnecessary to carry out the conduct of the affairs of the association.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>