<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1959"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1959"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1959"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1959/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1959/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1959/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1959/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1959">
        <num>15-1959</num>
        <heading>Corrections and revisions of assessments, determinations of drainage enhancements and apportionment of costs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1959. Corrections and revisions of assessments, determinations of\n             drainage enhancements and apportionment of costs.\n  1. In the event that obvious errors or discrepancies should be\ndiscovered in any assessment, determination of drainage enhancements or\ngeneral or special apportionments of cost, the department may correct\nthe same by filing corrected copies of the statement of such assessment,\ndetermination or apportionments and following the procedure specified in\ntitle 19 of this article.\n  2. Should such corrections be made, the county legislative body is\nempowered to levy additional sums on or to give credit to certain\nparcels to the end that the amount collected from each parcel shall be\nwhat it should have been had an error not been made. The county\nlegislative body is also empowered to apply to the department for an\nadjustment of assessments among the various parts into which an original\nparcel may have subdivided.\n  3. The department shall file and record its findings in such cases as\namendments to the original or corrected assessments, and shall give\nnotice to the parties affected, but need hold no hearing thereon unless\nsuch hearing be demanded by a party affected within ten days after\nnotice is given.\n  4. None of the above proceedings shall be held to reopen a\ndetermination of enhancements or an apportionment of cost, except as to\nthe particular matter involved. Should the department at any time find\nthat a former assessment, determination or apportionment appears with\nthe lapse of time or in the light of new knowledge and experience to\nhave become inequitable, it may so declare by written order and proceed\nto review the whole matter by following the full procedure laid down in\nwhichever one of the following sections is appropriate:  15-1919,\n15-1925, 15-1937 or 15-1939.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>