<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1515"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1515"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1515"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1515/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1515/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1515/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1515/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1515">
        <num>15-1515</num>
        <heading>Supervision of construction and operation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1515. Supervision of construction and operation.\n  1. All construction work which the Department of Environmental\nConservation is authorized to undertake by virtue of the provisions of\nsections 15-1507 through 15-1519 shall be done under the direction of\nthe Commissioner of Transportation. After the works shall have been\nconstructed, they shall thereafter be maintained and operated for the\nbenefit of the applicant by the Commissioner of Transportation under the\ndirection of the Department of Environmental Conservation.\n  2. All costs of such supervision of construction, operation and\nmaintenance shall be paid by the applicant in the manner specified in\nsection 15-1513 of this article, except that the applicant shall not be\ncharged with the salaries and expenses of such officials and regular\nemployees of the state who, in addition to other duties, exercise only\ngeneral supervision over the work done under the provisions of sections\n15-1507 through 15-1519.\n  3. The Department of Environmental Conservation is authorized to\nemploy such engineers and other persons as may in its judgment be\nnecessary to carry out the provisions of sections 15-1507 through\n15-1519 and to fix the compensation for such employees. Such\ncompensation shall be paid by the applicant.\n  4. Except for such expenses and salaries as are specifically exempted\nby subdivision 2 of this section, no moneys of the state shall be\nexpended, nor shall the state incur any liability or indebtedness by\nvirtue of the provisions of sections 15-1507 through 15-1519.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>