<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1725"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1725"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1725"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1725/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1725/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1725/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1725/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1725">
        <num>15-1725</num>
        <heading>Prosecution of project works</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1725. Prosecution of project works.\n  1. The licensee shall commence the construction of the project works\nwithin the time fixed therefor in the license. He shall thereafter in\ngood faith and with due diligence continue the construction thereof, and\nwithin the time fixed in the license complete and put into operation the\nwhole of such development work or such part or parts thereof as the\nlicense prescribes; except that when not incompatible with the public\ninterest, the department may, from time to time, for good cause, by\nresolution extend the time either for the commencement of construction\nor for the completion thereof.\n  2. The licensee shall, when required by the department and as often as\nonce in every six months during the course of the construction, file\nwith the department a detailed statement of the cost of the project\nduring the period covered by the statement. Within six months after the\nlicensee has filed its final statement after the completion of the\nproject, the department shall file a statement of the total cost of the\ninvestment.\n  3. The department at such time or times as it deems proper may examine\nany statement of the licensee, whether partial or complete, and hold a\nhearing to determine whether the same correctly states the cost of the\nproject or part thereof, as therein set forth, and shall have power to\ndetermine whether any part of the expenditure has been made wastefully,\nor in disregard of the terms of the license, or in bad faith, and to\ndeduct such items improperly included as may be necessary to make such\nstatement or statements conform to the fair and actual cost of the\nproject or part thereof. Subject to review as provided in section\n15-0905, the determination of the department shall be conclusive for all\npurposes as to the amount of such investment as shown by any such\nstatement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>