<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1505"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1505"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-1505"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1505/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1505/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1505/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-1505/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_1505">
        <num>15-1505</num>
        <heading>Interbasin diversions and water supply to other states</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-1505. Interbasin diversions and water supply to other states.\n  1. No person shall transport or carry through pipes, conduits, ditches\nor canals the waters of any fresh water lake, pond, brook, river,\nstream, or creek in this state or any well, subsurface or percolating\nwaters of this state into any other state for use therein without first\nobtaining a permit from the department pursuant to this title.\n  2. No person shall make a new or increased interbasin diversion which\nresults in a diversion in excess of one million gallons per day, as\ndetermined by the limiting maximum capacity of the treatment or\nconveyance system, or construct facilities or equipment therefor, until\nsuch person has registered the diversion with the department. No later\nthan February fifteenth, two thousand thirteen, all existing interbasin\ndiversions in excess of one million gallons per day, as determined by\nthe limiting maximum capacity of the treatment or conveyance system,\nshall be registered with the department.\n  3. Registration is not required for an interbasin diversion which is\npart of a water withdrawal system for which the department has issued a\npermit under this title, or which is operating pursuant to a duly\nauthorized permit issued by the department or its predecessors.\n  4. Registration shall be renewed every year or whenever ownership of\nthe facilities which create an interbasin diversion is transferred,\nwhichever occurs first. Registration shall be made on forms prescribed\nby the department and shall contain all information requested by the\ndepartment relative to the water withdrawal, use and discharge. Each\nperson who is required under this section to register shall annually, on\na form prescribed by the department, report all information requested by\nthe department, including the amount of water diverted. Information on\ninterbasin diversions shall be posted on the department's website.\n  5. No person shall make a new or increased interbasin diversion which\nresults in a significant adverse impact on the water quantity of the\nsource New York major drainage basin.\n  6. Diversions from the Great Lakes-St. Lawrence river basin are\nprohibited by the Great Lakes-St. Lawrence River Basin Water Resources\nCompact, as enacted in title ten of article twenty-one of this chapter.\nLimited exceptions for public water supply systems will only be\nconsidered when in compliance with that Compact.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>