<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2309"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2309"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2309"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2309/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2309/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2309/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2309/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2309">
        <num>15-2309</num>
        <heading>Entry upon lands, structures and waters; acquisition of property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2309. Entry upon lands, structures and waters; acquisition of\n             property.\n  The department, its members, officers, employees and agents may enter\nupon any land, structures and waters necessary for the purposes of title\n23 of this article and may determine what rights in and to such property\nare to be acquired therein. If the owner of any property to be taken, or\non or over which an easement is to be taken, for such improvement shall\nagree with the department upon the sum to be paid therefor, or for the\nright to use and occupy the same, or for any damages sustained, such sum\nshall be paid as hereinafter provided as part of the necessary expense\nincurred for the purpose of such improvement. If the department cannot\nagree with the owners upon the compensation and damages to be paid for\nthe property or easement to be so taken the department shall proceed to\nacquire title thereto under the provisions of the eminent domain\nprocedure law. All real property acquired by a river improvement\ndistrict shall be exempt from taxation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>