<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2139"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2139"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2139"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2139/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2139/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2139/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2139/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2139">
        <num>15-2139</num>
        <heading>Hudson River Regulating District and Black River Regulating District: transfer of functions; pending actions and proceedings; interpretat...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2139. Hudson River Regulating District and Black River Regulating\n             District: transfer of functions; pending actions and\n             proceedings; interpretation of documents; existing rights\n             and remedies.\n  1. Except as hereinafter provided, the contracts, books, maps, plans,\npapers, records and property of whatever description within the\njurisdiction or under the control of the Hudson River Regulating\nDistrict or the Black River Regulating District, including moneys\nappropriated and available to such districts, pertaining to or used in\nconnection with the exercise or performance of the functions, powers and\nduties hereby transferred and assigned, shall be delivered to the\nsecretary of the board of the Hudson River-Black River Regulating\nDistrict, who is hereby authorized to take possession thereof.\n  2. For the purposes of succession, the functions, powers and duties\ntransferred, assigned to, and devolving upon the Hudson River-Black\nRiver Regulating District shall be deemed to constitute a continuation\nof such functions, powers and duties exercised by the Hudson River\nRegulating District and the Black River Regulating District, and the\nacts, orders, rules, regulations and determinations of such districts\nshall have, and continue with, the same force and effect as though done\nby or made by the Hudson River-Black River Regulating District.\n  3. Any business or matter heretofore undertaken or commenced by or\nbefore the Hudson River Regulating District or the Black River\nRegulating District, or any action or proceeding heretofore brought by\nor against such districts, pertaining to or connected with the\nfunctions, powers and duties hereby transferred and assigned to the\nHudson River-Black River Regulating District may be conducted,\ncompleted, prosecuted and defended by and in the name of the Hudson\nRiver-Black River Regulating District. In all such actions and\nproceedings the Hudson River-Black River Regulating District, upon\napplication to the court, may be substituted as a party.\n  4. When the Hudson River Regulating District or the Black River\nRegulating District is referred to or designated in any law, contract or\ndocument, such reference or designation shall be deemed to refer to and\ninclude the Hudson River-Black River Regulating District so far as such\nlaw, contract or document pertains to matters which are within its\njurisdiction by reason of such transfer and assignment of functions,\npowers and duties.\n  5. No existing right or remedy of any character shall be lost, or\naffected by reason of the provisions of sections 15-2137, 15-2139 and\n15-2141.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>