<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2713"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2713"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="15-2713"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2713/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2713/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2713/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-15-2713/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_2713">
        <num>15-2713</num>
        <heading>Initial designations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 15-2713. Initial designations.\n  The following rivers which are located within the boundaries of the\nAdirondack park, as now defined by law, are to be initially included in\nthis system being classified by the above-stated criteria:\n  1. Wild rivers\n  a. Cedar river--Approximately seven miles from the southwest boundary\nof lot 82, township 17, Totten and Crossfield's Purchase to the Hamilton\ncounty line.\n  b. Cold river--Approximately fourteen miles from the Duck Hole to the\nconfluence with the Raquette river and the entire three-mile length of\nOuluska Pass brook.\n  c. Hudson river--Approximately ten and one-half miles from the\nconfluence of the Cedar river to the confluence with Boreas river.\n  d. Indian river--Approximately thirteen miles from Brook Trout lake to\nthe confluence with the south branch of the Moose river.\n  e. Opalescent river--Approximately eleven miles from Flowed Lands to\nthe confluence with the Hudson river.\n  f. East branch of the Sacandaga river--Approximately eleven and\none-half miles from Botheration pond to a point one-half mile above the\nconfluence with Cook brook.\n  g. West branch of the Sacandaga river--Approximately seven miles from\nthe confluence of the Piseco lake outlet to the confluence with Dugway\ncreek.\n  h. West Canada creek--Approximately eight miles from Mud lake to the\nOld Mitchell dam site.\n  2. Scenic rivers\n  a. Ampersand brook--Approximately eight miles from Ampersand pond to\nthe confluence with the Raquette river.\n  b. Ausable river--Approximately nine miles from Marcy swamp to St.\nHubert's.\n  c. Boreas river--Approximately eleven and one-half miles from Cheney\npond to the confluence with the Hudson river.\n  d. Bouquet river--Approximately six miles of the North Fork from the\nheadwaters on Dial mountain to the bridge on route 73. Approximately\nfive and one-half miles of the South Fork from the headwaters to the\nbridge on route 73.\n  e. Cedar river--Approximately five miles from the Hamilton County line\nto the confluence with the Hudson river.\n  f. Hudson river--Approximately nine miles from the hamlet of Newcomb\nto the confluence with the Cedar river and approximately four miles from\nthe confluence with the Boreas river to a point one mile north of the\nhamlet of North river.\n  g. South branch of the Moose river--Approximately eighteen miles from\nthe east boundary of the state land immediately west of Little Moose\nlake to the west boundary of state land near Rock Dam and approximately\nsix and one-half miles from the east boundary of state land just north\nof Woodhull mountain downstream to the state land boundary near the\nconfluence with the middle branch of the Moose river.\n  3. Recreational rivers\n  a. West branch of Ausable river--Approximately five miles from the\nstate boundary along the River road east of Big Cherry Patch pond\ndownstream to the state boundary immediately west of High Falls.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>