<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0115"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0115"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16-0115"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_0115">
        <num>16-0115</num>
        <heading>Municipal participation in federal program; raising and disbursement of funds; local cooperation agreements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0115__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0115__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of this section.\n  3. The assignment of responsibility for all required non-federal items\nof cooperation shall be specified in the local cooperation agreement as\nfollows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0115__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state shall bear fifty percent of those costs required by the\nfederal government including lands, easements, rights-of-way,\nrelocations, and cash contributions if any.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0115__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the benefiting municipality or municipalities shall bear fifty\npercent of those costs required by the federal government including\nlands, easements, rights-of-way, relocations, and cash contributions if\nany.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0115__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the costs of all lands, easements, rights-of-way and relocations\nborne by the state or a benefiting municipality or municipalities shall\nbe a credit against the respective shares of the state and the\nbenefiting municipality or municipalities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0115__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the operation and maintenance of the project, once constructed,\nshall be the responsibility of the benefiting municipality or\nmunicipalities in accordance with the guidance and direction of the\nstate and under the controlling principle that flood control is the\nprimary purpose.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0115__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>replacement of project facilities shall be the responsibility of\nthe state provided that replacement is not due to deferred maintenance.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, for any flood\ncontrol project for which a local cooperation agreement was developed or\na letter of intent was furnished to the federal government before\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven, the state of New York\nshall not pay less than the total costs of all lands, easements,\nrights-of-way, bridges and relocations, with the exception of lands\nowned by the benefiting municipality or municipalities and the\nrelocation of facilities owned by the benefiting municipality or\nmunicipalities.\n  5. Any local cooperation agreement may include such additional terms\nand conditions as the commissioner may determine to be necessary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>