<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="16-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-16-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_16_0107">
        <num>16-0107</num>
        <heading>Acquirement of property for flood control</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>May determine whether any property taken for\nany of the purposes connected with flood control projects pursuant to\nthis section may be leased, sold or exchanged on terms beneficial to the\nstate, and in all cases of such determination subject to compliance with\nsection four hundred six of the eminent domain procedure law, he may,\nlease, sell or exchange such property; in order to carry any such lease,\nsale or exchange into effect, the commissioner is hereby authorized to\nexecute and deliver, in the name of the people of the state, a quit\nclaim or lease of such property.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>May also convey to the United States for flood control purposes\nall right, title and interest of the state in and to any property\nheretofore or hereafter so taken for any of such purposes for which\nreimbursement by the United States is made in accordance with section\ntwo of the federal flood control act of nineteen hundred thirty-eight\nbeing public law, numbered seven hundred and sixty-one, seventy-fifth\ncongress, and including improvements made thereon for such purposes.\nSuch conveyance shall be by deed or instrument of quit claim, executed\nby the commissioner in the name of the people of the state, delivered to\nthe federal authority having jurisdiction.  This paragraph shall not\nprevent reservations, if any, in such a conveyance, agreed to by such\ncommissioner and federal authority, to protect leases or easement, if\nany, theretofore lawfully made or created by such commissioner.\nWhenever the United States, acting by and through said federal authority\nhaving jurisdiction, shall cause to be filed in the office of the\nsecretary of state of this state, a duplicate original of the deed or\ninstrument of conveyance to the United States of any such property for\nthe  purposes herein specified, such jurisdiction as may be required for\nflood control purposes is thereupon ceded to the United States over the\nproperty described in said deed or instrument of conveyance, during the\ntime that the United States shall be or remain the owner thereof and\nshall use such property for flood control purposes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_16_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Is hereby authorized to agree with the United States as to the\nvalue of the property appropriated and for legal damages caused by any\nsuch appropriation thereof, as and for reimbursement by the United\nStates, and the commissioner is authorized to convey such property to\nthe United States, in the manner herein provided, specifying in such\nconveyance that the consideration stated therein is the agreed value of\nsuch property and legal damages, and is in full reimbursement thereof by\nthe United States.\n  18.  The attorney general is hereby authorized and empowered to\ncertify to the United States of America or a department, agency or\nauthority thereof having jurisdiction therein, the right, title or\ninterest vested in the people of the state of New York in and to\nproperty acquired for the purpose of this act for which reimbursement is\nto be made by the United States of America to the people of the state of\nNew York.\n  19.  If the commissioner shall determine subsequent to the acquisition\nof a temporary easement right in property and subsequent to the filing\nof a description and map of such property in the office of the county\nclerk, as aforesaid, that the purposes for which such easement right was\nacquired have been accomplished and that the use and occupancy of said\nproperty for flood control purposes are no longer necessary, and that,\ntherefore, the term of such easement should be further limited, or if\nthe appropriation of such easement was for an indefinite period, that\nsuch period should be fixed and determined, or that the period of such\neasement has by its terms expired, the commissioner shall make a\ncertificate that the use and occupancy of such property for flood\ncontrol purposes are no longer necessary, that the property in which\nsuch easement right was acquired is surrendered back to the affected\nowner of said property and that such easement right is thereupon\nterminated, released and extinguished.  The commissioner shall cause a\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>