<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-0305"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_0305">
        <num>17-0305</num>
        <heading>Establishment of a program to monitor water quality by private citizens under the direction of the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 17-0305. Establishment of a program to monitor water quality by\n             private citizens under the direction of the department.\n  1. The commissioner shall establish a program which shall be known as\nthe "citizens statewide lake assessment program". The purpose of this\nprogram is to establish a network of volunteers belonging to lake\nassociations throughout the state to monitor the condition of their\nrespective lakes under the guidance and direction of the department.\nThe volunteers, designated by the commission, will sample the assigned\nlakes on a weekly basis between May and September. Water quality\ninformation will be obtained by measuring water transparency and taking\nsamples for water chemistry. Samples shall be processed by the\nvolunteers and forwarded to a contract chemistry laboratory for\nanalysis.\n  2. The commissioner shall establish and fill a new permanent position\nof program coordinator for the monitoring program within the division of\nwater.\n  3. The commissioner shall establish a training program for the purpose\nof providing the volunteers with the skills necessary to accomplish\ntheir monitoring tasks. Quality control checks will be carried out on a\nregular basis by the program coordinator, and through the lake\nclassification and inventory survey.\n  4. The commissioner will provide the volunteers with all of the\nequipment and materials necessary to accomplish the monitoring.\n  5. Chemistry parameters shall include, but are not limited to, tests\nfor total phosphorus, nitrate, color and chlorophyll. Additional survey\ndata shall include, but not be limited to, aquatic vegetation surveys,\nangler surveys and questionnaires/surveys for water users concerning\nproblems, issues and use impairment.\n  6. The program coordinator shall prepare an annual report which will\ninclude a summary of the information collected on the monitored waters\nduring the previous season. This information shall be distributed to the\nprogram participants and other interested parties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>