<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0815"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0815"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-0815"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0815/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-0815/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_0815">
        <num>17-0815</num>
        <heading>SPDES permits; additional terms and conditions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 17-0815. SPDES permits; additional terms and conditions.\n  SPDES permits shall include the following provisions, terms,\nrequirements and conditions;\n  1. that all discharges authorized by the permit shall be consistent\nwith the provisions, terms, requirements and conditions of such permit.\n  2. that facility expansions, production increases or process\nmodifications by the permittee which result in new or increased\ndischarges of pollutants into the waters of the state shall be reported\nby the permittee by submission of a new SPDES application.\n  3. that the discharge of any pollutant not identified and authorized\nby such permit or the discharge of any pollutant more frequently than or\nat a level in excess of that permitted by such permit shall constitute a\nviolation of the terms of the permit.\n  4. that, where the permit is for a publicly owned treatment works,\nnotice shall be given the department of any new introduction into such\nworks of pollutants or substantial changes in volume or character of\npollutants.\n  5. that for discharges from publicly owned treatment works appropriate\nmeasures will be established by the permittee to insure compliance by\nindustrial users with any system of user charges and recovery of\nconstruction costs required under the provisions of the Act.\n  6. that such permit may be modified, suspended or revoked where the\ndepartment finds.\n  a. a violation of any term of the permit;\n  b. that the permit was obtained by misrepresentation or failure to\ndisclose fully all relevant facts; or\n  c. a change in conditions or the existence of a condition which\nrequires either a temporary or permanent reduction or elimination of the\nauthorized discharge.\n  7. such other terms, provisions, requirements or conditions as may be\nnecessary to meet the requirements of the Act.\n  8. recording, reporting, monitoring, and sampling requirements\napplicable under the Act.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>