<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1704"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1704"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1704"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1704">
        <num>17-1704</num>
        <heading>Discharge of sewage and other offensive matter from new or renovated wastewater disposal systems to the surface waters of the Owasco lake...</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 17-1704. Discharge of sewage and other offensive matter from new or\n             renovated wastewater disposal systems to the surface waters\n             of the Owasco lake watershed extending from the city dam on\n             the outlet to the existing Moravia village outfall sewer on\n             the inlet are prohibited.\n  1. No person or corporation shall cause or permit the fall, flow or\ndischarge into the surface waters of the Owasco lake watershed extending\nfrom the city dam on the outlet to the existing Moravia village outfall\nsewer on the inlet, of any sewage matter, or other foul, noxious or\ndeleterious, solid or liquid matter or effluent from any wastewater\ndisposal system located therein except for those operating under a duly\nauthorized permit from the state or county health departments and except\nfor run-off from accepted agricultural practices.\n  2. Existing permitted surface water outlets shall be eliminated by\nJanuary 1, 1991. In the event of change of ownership or major alteration\nor renovations to existing wastewater disposal systems, the existing\nwastewater outlets shall be eliminated and be replaced by an approved\nsub-surface disposal system.\n  3. The Cayuga county board of health shall examine any alleged offense\nof this section within its jurisdiction and cause the same to be abated\nby injunction or otherwise if found to exist.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>