<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1733"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1733"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1733"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1733/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1733/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1733/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1733/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1733">
        <num>17-1733</num>
        <heading>Record of permits; inspection of local boards of health</heading>
        <content>
          <p>* ยง 17-1733. Record of permits; inspection of local boards of health.\n  1. Each local board of health shall preserve in its office and on a\nform prescribed by the commissioner, a permanent record of the\nfollowing:\n  a. Each permit issued by the commissioner granting the right to\ndischarge sewage or refuse or waste matter into any of the waters of the\nstate within the municipality;\n  b. Each revocation of a permit; and\n  c. Each report received by the local board of health concerning each\nsewer system and each shop, factory, mill or industrial establishment\nwhich on May 7, 1903, was discharging sewage or refuse or waste matter\ninto any of the waters of the state within the municipality.\n  2. Each local board of health shall make and maintain such inspection\nas will, at all times, enable it to determine whether section 17-1701 is\nbeing complied with in respect to the discharge of sewage, refuse or\nwaste matter or other materials prohibited by said section, into any of\nthe waters of the state within that municipality.\n  3. For the purpose of such inspection every member of such local board\nof health, or its health officer, or any person duly authorized by it,\nshall have the right to make all necessary examinations of any premises,\nbuilding, shop, factory, mill, industrial establishment, process or\nsewer system.\n  * NB Expired September 1, 1973\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>