<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1713"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1713"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1713"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1713/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1713/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1713/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1713/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1713">
        <num>17-1713</num>
        <heading>Discharge of sewage and other offensive matter into Brant Lake, Loon Lake, Friends Lake and Schroon Lake prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>* ยง 17-1713. Discharge of sewage and other offensive matter into Brant\n               Lake, Loon Lake, Friends Lake and Schroon Lake\n               prohibited.\n  1. No person or corporation shall cause or permit the fall, flow or\ndischarge into Brant lake, Loon lake or Friends lake in the county of\nWarren or Schroon lake located partly in the county of Essex and partly\nin the county of Warren or any of their tributaries, of any sewage\nmatter, or other foul, noxious or deleterious, solid or liquid matter,\nor effluent from any sewage disposal plant, or any matter that may be\ndeclared such by the board of health of any municipality adjacent to any\nsuch lake where any such fall, flow or discharge shall occur.\n  2. The board of health of any such municipality shall examine into any\nalleged offense against this section within its jurisdiction and cause\nthe same to be abated, by injunction or otherwise, if found to exist.\n  3. The prohibition of the discharge of sewage effluent into Schroon\nlake as hereinbefore in this section provided shall not apply to the\ntreated effluent from a sewage or waste treatment plant which has been,\nor may be constructed, maintained and operated in accordance with plans\napproved and a permit issued by the former Water Pollution Control\nBoard. Such permit shall prohibit the discharge of sewage effluent into\nSchroon lake or any of its tributaries in any quantities which will\nadversely affect said waters or which will render said waters unsuitable\nfor any purpose recognized under the classification of said waters by\nthe former Water Pollution Control Board.\n  * NB Expired September 1, 1973\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>