<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1013"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1013"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="17-1013"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1013/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1013/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1013/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-17-1013/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_17_1013">
        <num>17-1013</num>
        <heading>State petroleum bulk storage advisory council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 17-1013. State petroleum bulk storage advisory council.\n  1. There is hereby created within the department the "state petroleum\nbulk storage advisory council" hereinafter referred to as the "council".\nSuch council shall consist of seven members, at least one of whom shall\nbe a representative of operators other than owners in the state, at\nleast one of whom shall be a representative of owners in the state, at\nleast one of whom shall be a representative of municipal corporations,\nand at least two of whom shall be representatives of organizations whose\nprime function is the protection of natural resources and enhancement of\nthe environmental quality of the state. The members of the council shall\nbe appointed by the commissioner within three months of the effective\ndate of this title. Each member shall be, by professional training or\nexperience and attainment, qualified to analyze and interpret matters\npertaining to bulk storage of petroleum.\n  2. One member shall be elected chairman of the advisory council by a\nmajority vote of the members of such council.\n  3. The members of the council shall serve without compensation for\ntheir services as members of the council, except that each of them may\nbe allowed the necessary and actual expenses which he shall incur in the\nperformance of his duties under this section.\n  4. The council shall have the power, duty and responsibility to:\n  a. Serve as a working forum for the exchange of views, concerns,\nideas, information and recommendations relating to the bulk storage of\npetroleum.\n  b. Advise the department on the proposal, preparation and revision of\nthe rules and regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this\ntitle.\n  c. Request and receive from the department at each meeting of the\ncouncil any portions of the rules and regulations then available for\nreview, whether in final or draft form, and any supporting documents or\nother pertinent data.\n  d. Before promulgation of the rules and regulations required by this\ntitle, the commissioner shall first submit such rules and regulations to\nthe council for review. The council shall, within sixty days of such\nsubmission, recommend in writing to the commissioner any suggested\nmodifications to such rules and regulations.\n  5. The recording of council proceedings shall be performed by\npersonnel of the department.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>