<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0301"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0301">
        <num>19-0301</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0301__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Act\nfor sale and use in states other than California; provided, however,\nthat nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed to limit the authority\nof the department to adopt a rule, regulation or standard for:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_0301__subsec_k__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>fuel oxygen content or fuel volatility; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_0301__subsec_k__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the composition of fuels necessary to implement section 7586 of\nthe Act; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_0301__subsec_k__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the composition of fuels necessary to implement section 7507 of\nthe Act if such fuel standard is adopted and implemented regionally\npursuant to agreement with any three states sharing a boundary with New\nYork; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_19_0301__subsec_k__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the composition of fuels if the commissioner finds that no other\nmeasures would bring about timely attainment or maintenance of a\nnational primary or secondary ambient air quality standard for which New\nYork state must file a state implementation plan pursuant to the Act, or\nthat other existing and technically possible measures are unreasonably\ncostly or impracticable and the commissioner has included such measure\nin the implementation plan pursuant to section 7410 of the Act.\n  b. No provision of this subdivision shall be deemed to authorize the\nuse of methyl tertiary butyl ether as an oxygenate in any motor fuel\nimported into, or sold or offered for sale in this state.\n  4. Any final order or determination or other final action by the\ncommissioner and the validity or reasonableness of any code, rule or\nregulation promulgated by the department pursuant to this article shall\nbe subject to review as provided in article seventy-eight of the civil\npractice law and rules; pro...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0301__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Act.  Such rules and regulations shall include provision\nfor cooperating with the commissioner of motor vehicles pursuant to\nparagraph one of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0301__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section 301 of the vehicle and\ntraffic law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>