<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0306"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0306">
        <num>19-0306</num>
        <heading>Municipal solid and regulated medical waste incineration facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0306__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the level of protection provided the public health and\nenvironment;\n  (ii) the likely or potential reductions of acid gas emissions from a\nseparate, nearby source of such emissions as a result of a proposed\nfacility becoming operational;\n  (iii) the likely economic impact of such controls due to associated\ncapital and operating costs, and in relation to alternative solid waste\nmanagement options, including landfilling; and\n  (iv) the appropriateness of reduced or modified levels of such\ncontrols for smaller facilities;\n  d. Combustion efficiency;\n  e. Monitoring of emissions for toxic air contaminants, or surrogates\nthereof where appropriate, to determine compliance with permit emission\nlimits twice within the first eighteen months of operation and once each\nwithin the next two eighteen month intervals and subsequently at the\ndiscretion of the commissioner, and following any detection of permit\nviolations in a manner to be determined by the commissioner;\n  f. Continuous monitoring for oxygen, carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide,\nopacity and temperature;\n  g. Sampling and testing of the combined ash and dust residue at least\nannually to determine appropriate disposition or disposal based on\nrelative toxicity; provided, however, that separate testing of ash and\ndust shall be required if they are not mixed prior to disposal.\n  3. The department shall undertake further investigation of appropriate\ncooling methods for achieving the condensation and collection of air\ncontaminants and of the necessity for, and appropriate means of,\nregulating fine particulates. Upon such investigation, the commissioner\nshall issue a report on his findings and may promulgate appropriate\nregulations.\n  4. The department shall, in promulgating any new or revised rule or\nregulation, accompany such rule making with an environmental impact\nstatement or a written assessment stating the extent to or means by\nwhich such rule or regulation will prevent, control or prohibi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>