<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-03-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0306-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0306-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0306_B">
        <num>19-0306-B</num>
        <heading>Zero-emissions cars and trucks</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 19-0306-b. Zero-emissions cars and trucks.\n  1. It shall be a goal of the state that one hundred percent of new\npassenger cars and trucks offered for sale or lease, or sold, or leased,\nfor registration in the state shall be zero-emissions by two thousand\nthirty-five. It shall be a further goal of the state that one hundred\npercent of medium-duty and heavy-duty vehicles offered for sale or\nlease, or sold, or leased, for registration in the state be\nzero-emissions by two thousand forty-five for all operations where\nfeasible. It shall be further a goal of the state to transition to one\nhundred percent zero-emissions from new off-road vehicles and equipment\npurchased beginning in two thousand thirty-five, where feasible.\n  2. The department, to the extent consistent with federal law, shall\ndevelop and propose:\n  a. Passenger vehicle and truck regulations requiring increasing\nvolumes of new zero-emissions vehicles offered for sale or lease, or\nsold, or leased, for registration in the state towards the target of one\nhundred percent of in-state sales by two thousand thirty-five.\n  b. Medium-duty and heavy-duty vehicle regulations requiring increasing\nvolumes of new zero-emissions trucks and buses offered for sale or\nlease, or sold, or leased, for registration and operated in the state\ntowards the target of one hundred percent of the fleet transitioning to\nzero-emissions vehicles by two thousand forty-five everywhere feasible.\n  c. Strategies, in coordination with other state agencies, other states\nand the federal environmental protection agency, to achieve one hundred\npercent zero-emissions from new off-road vehicles and equipment\noperations in the state by two thousand thirty-five. In implementing the\nprovisions of this paragraph, the department shall act consistently with\nsafety, technological feasibility and cost-effectiveness.\n  3. The New York state energy research and development authority, in\nconsultation with the department, the department of economic\ndevelopment, the public service commission, the department of\ntransportation, the department of motor vehicles, and other state\nagencies, local agencies and other interested parties, shall develop a\nzero-emissions vehicle market development strategy by January\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty-three, and an update every three years\nthereafter, that:\n  a. Ensures coordinated and expeditious implementation of the system of\npolicies, programs and regulations necessary to achieve the goals and\norders established by this section.\n  b. Outlines state agencies' actions to support new and used\nzero-emissions vehicle markets for broad accessibility for all residents\nof this state.\n  4. The department, the New York state energy research and development\nauthority, the public service commission and other state agencies, shall\nuse existing authorities to accelerate deployment of affordable powering\noptions for zero-emissions vehicles, in ways that serve all communities\nand particularly low-income and disadvantaged communities, consistent\nwith state and federal law.\n  5. The department, the New York state energy research and development\nauthority, the department of motor vehicles and the department of\ntransportation, in consultation with the other state agencies, shall on\nor before July fifteenth, two thousand twenty-three, identify near term\nactions and investment strategies to improve sustainable transportation,\nfreight and transit options, including where feasible:\n  a. Supporting bicycle and pedestrian options, particularly in\nlow-income and disadvantaged communities in the state, by incorporating\nsafe and accessible infrastructure into projects where appropriate.\n  b. Supporting light, medium, and heavy-duty zero-emissions vehicles\nand infrastructure as part of larger transportation projects, where\nappropriate.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>