<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0320"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0320"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0320"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0320/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0320/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0320/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0320/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0320">
        <num>19-0320</num>
        <heading>Emissions inspections of heavy duty vehicles</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0320__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nparagraph F of subdivision seven of section four hundred one of the\nvehicle and traffic law, and vehicles specified in subdivision thirteen\nof section four hundred one of the vehicle and traffic law, and farm\ntype tractors and all terrain type vehicles used exclusively for\nagricultural or mowing purposes, or for snow plowing, other than for\nhire, farm equipment, including self-propelled machines used exclusively\nin growing, harvesting or handling farm produce, and self-propelled\ncaterpillar or crawler-type equipment while being operated on the\ncontract site, and timber harvesting equipment such as harvesters, wood\nchippers, forwarders, log skidders, and other processing equipment used\nexclusively off highway for timber harvesting and logging purposes,\nshall not be deemed heavy duty vehicles for purposes of this section.\n  b. "Roadside program" means a roadside examination program conducted\npursuant to the heavy duty vehicle emissions reduction act for the\ninspection of emissions and emission control equipment, at any public or\nquasi-public location as designated by the commissioner of\ntransportation with the concurrence of the department and, where\nappropriate, the New York state thruway authority.\n  c. "Annual inspection program" means a program in which heavy duty\nvehicles registered or required to be registered in counties in the\nstate designated as being in serious, severe or extreme non-attainment\nof the National Ambient Air Quality Standard for ozone pursuant to the\n1990 amendments of the federal Clean Air Act (42 U.S.C. 7511) are\nannually inspected in accordance with this article.\n  2. The department, jointly with the departments of motor vehicles and\ntransportation, shall develop a program for the inspection of emissions\nfrom heavy duty vehicles. Such inspection program shall consist of an\nannual inspection program and a roadside program. The annual inspection\nprogram developed in accordance with this section shall be limited ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>