<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0911"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0911"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0911"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0911">
        <num>19-0911</num>
        <heading>Final control target</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 19-0911. Final control target.\n  1. a. In the absence of a controlling federal statute or program which\nthe commissioner determines is consistent with the purpose and intent of\nthis title, the department shall formulate, no later than January first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-one, a final control target to bring about\nreductions in the state's contribution to the total sulfate deposition\nat each sensitive receptor area.\n  b. As part of such determination, the commissioner shall provide a\nwritten analysis of any actions taken or being contemplated by states\nthat border on or are to the east of the Mississippi river or by the\nCanadian provinces of Ontario or Quebec and the potential or estimated\neffect of any such action on acid deposition in sensitive receptor\nareas.\n  c. Any such final control target formulated pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be submitted, in the form of legislative\nrecommendations, to the governor and the legislature.\n  2. The department shall not adopt or implement the final control\ntarget until such time as further specific statutory authorization shall\nhave been enacted, except that any such final control target shall\npermit the use of all reasonable sulfur dioxide emission control\ntechniques as identified in subdivision two of section 19-0909 of this\ntitle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>