<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0315"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0315"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0315"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0315/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0315/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0315">
        <num>19-0315</num>
        <heading>Small business stationary source compliance advisory panel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 19-0315. Small business stationary source compliance advisory panel.\n  1. There is hereby established a small business stationary source\ncompliance advisory panel which shall have the responsibility to:\n  a. provide guidance to the department on the development of the small\nbusiness stationary source technical and environmental compliance\nassistance program;\n  b. render advisory opinions concerning the effectiveness of the small\nbusiness stationary source technical and environmental compliance\nassistance program, including the adequacy of funding available to the\nprogram, difficulties encountered, and degree and severity of\nenforcement;\n  c. make periodic reports to the commissioner and the administrator of\nthe United States environmental protection agency concerning the\ncompliance of the small business stationary source technical and\nenvironmental compliance assistance program with the requirements of the\nfederal paperwork reduction act, 42 U.S.C. ยง 3501 et seq.; the\nregulatory flexibility act, 42 U.S.C. ยง 601 et seq.; and the equal\naccess to justice act, 5 U.S.C. ยง 504;\n  d. review information for small business stationary sources to assure\nthat such information is understandable by the layperson;\n  e. review and advise the department on the development of rules and\nregulations, the state implementation plan as it affects small business\nstationary sources, and other programs affecting small business\nstationary sources implemented by the department pursuant to the Act;\nand\n  f. make recommendations for the development of programs to further\nassist small business stationary sources, including technical and\nfinancial assistance programs.\n  2. The small business stationary source compliance advisory panel\nshall consist of nine members who shall be appointed no later than\nNovember fifteenth, nineteen hundred ninety-three. The panel shall\nconsist of:\n  a. two persons, who are not owners or representatives of owners of\nsmall business stationary sources, selected by the governor to represent\nthe general public;\n  b. six persons who are owners or who represent owners of small\nbusiness stationary sources, two selected by the president pro tem of\nthe senate, two selected by the speaker of the assembly, one selected by\nthe minority leader of the senate and one selected by the minority\nleader of the assembly; and\n  c. one person selected by the commissioner to represent the\ndepartment.\n  3. The panel shall meet at least quarterly and shall designate one of\nits members, other than the commissioner's representative, to serve as\nchairperson. Members of the panel shall serve for terms of three years\nfrom the date of their appointment, except that the members appointed by\nthe commissioner shall serve at the pleasure of the commissioner.\nMembers shall serve without compensation, except that they shall be\nallowed their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance\nof their duties pursuant to this section.\n  4. The department or its designee shall serve as the secretariat for\nthe panel for development and dissemination of reports and advisory\nopinions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>