<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0907"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0907"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="19-0907"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0907/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-19-0907/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_19_0907">
        <num>19-0907</num>
        <heading>Sulfur deposition control program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_19_0907__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>total sulfate deposition from all sources; and\n  (ii) total sulfate deposition from instate sources; and\n  (iii) the ratio of total sulfate deposition from instate sources to\ntotal sulfate deposition from all sources.\n  c. Identify and publish a preliminary list of environmental threshold\nvalues for each sensitive receptor area.\n  d. Identify and publish a preliminary list or inventory of all\nfacilities and stationary sources in the state which emit sulfur\ndioxide.\n  e. Prepare such supporting documentation as the department considers\nappropriate.\n  2. a. Before publishing any preliminary list or report pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section, the department shall conduct a review\nof all appropriate existing acid deposition reports and data as prepared\nby the department, other agencies of the state, agencies of other\nstates, agencies of the federal government or agencies of foreign\ngovernments. The department shall further review appropriate acid\ndeposition reports, data, documents, studies, surveys or analyses as\ncurrently exist in the scientific literature.\n  b. The department shall set forth in writing its presuppositions and\nassumptions, mathematical modeling techniques, sampling methodologies,\nand analytical protocols, based upon existing scientific knowledge, that\nare utilized to derive the preliminary lists and reports required by\nthis section.\n  3. Based on the activities listed in subdivisions one and two of this\nsection, the department shall formulate a preliminary final control\ntarget for each sensitive receptor area, and shall develop a strategy\nidentifying any emissions reductions for the various facilities and\nstationary sources in the state that will be required to meet the\ndeposition control targets. These targets and strategies, together with\nthe lists, reports and supporting documentation described in this\nsection, and together with an analysis of the economic impact of the\nimplementation of such targets and stra...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>