<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-0503"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_0503">
        <num>21-0503</num>
        <heading>Commissioners</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 21-0503. Commissioners.\n  1. The Governor shall, by and with the advice and consent of the\nsenate, appoint four commissioners to the interstate environmental\ncommission created by the tri-state compact, each of whom shall be a\nresident voter of the state of New York. The Commissioner of\nEnvironmental Conservation, and each of his successors in such office,\nalso shall be a commissioner of the interstate environmental commission.\nEach commissioner shall hold office until his successor has been\nappointed and qualified. The commissioners serving on the effective date\nof this article shall continue in office until the expiration of their\nterms, or until their successors have qualified, or until otherwise\nceasing to be commissioners pursuant to law. The Commissioner of\nEnvironmental Conservation may appoint a member of his department to act\nas his statutory representative on the commission.\n  2. At the expiration of the term of each appointive commissioner and\nof each succeeding appointive commissioner, the Governor shall, by and\nwith the advice and consent of the senate, appoint a successor who shall\nhold office for a term of four years or until his successor has been\nappointed and qualified. In the event of a vacancy occurring in the\noffice of an appointive commissioner by death, resignation or otherwise,\nthe Governor shall, by and with the advice and consent of the senate,\nappoint a successor, who shall hold office for the unexpired term. Any\ncommissioner may be removed upon charges and after hearing by the\nGovernor. The commissioners shall have the powers and duties, and be\nsubject to the limitations provided for in the compact and applicable\nlaws of this state. The commissioners shall serve without compensation,\nbut shall be paid their actual expenses incurred and incident to the\nperformance of their duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>