<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0115"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0115"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-0115"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_0115">
        <num>21-0115</num>
        <heading>Additional powers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 21-0115. Additional powers.\n  1. The state reaffirms its support of the cooperative approach to the\nabatement and control of water pollution as embodied in the New England\nInterstate Water Pollution Control Compact. In view of the increases in\npopulation concentrations, the growing need of industry and agriculture\nfor water of reasonable quality and the quality reqirements of water\nbased recreation and other uses, the New England Interstate Water\nPollution Control Commission shall develop and maintain its programs,\nincluding research on water quality problems at such levels as may be\nappropriate including, to the extent necessary, levels above those\noriginally provided when the state first enacted the compact.\n  2. In addition to the minimal personnel authorizations contained in\narticle IV of the New England Interstate Water Pollution Control\nCompact, the commission may employ such engineering, technical and other\nprofessional, secretarial and clerical personnel as the proper\nadministration and functioning of the commission may require.\n  3. a. This state hereby concurs in the conferring of any powers or\nduties on the New England Interstate Water Pollution Control Commission\nby other states in addition to those conferred by provision of the New\nEngland Interstate Water Pollution Control Compact. This concurrence is\npursuant to article II of said compact.\n  b. The concurrence is subject to the following limitations:\n  (1) Unless this state specifically confers a power or duty on the\ncommission, other than one conferred by the compact itself, no financial\nor other burden or duties shall be placed upon this state, or any\nagency, officer or subdivision thereof, by reason of the conferring or\nexercise of the power or duty. At any time, the Governor, Attorney\nGeneral, or the State Comptroller shall have the power to make inquiry\nof the commission and to examine its books and records in order to\nascertain the state of compliance with this act.\n  (2) The rights, privileges and responsibilities of the state with\nrespect to the New England Interstate Water Pollution Control Compact\nand the commission established thereby shall not be limited or impaired.\n  (3) The commission shall include in its reports to the Governor a full\naccount of any additional powers or duties exercised or performed by it.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>