<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-0305"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_0305">
        <num>21-0305</num>
        <heading>Commissioners; cooperation by departments and officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 21-0305. Commissioners; cooperation by departments and officers.\n  1. In pursuance of article four of said compact, there shall be three\nmembers (hereinafter called commissioners) of the Ohio River Valley\nWater Sanitation Commission (hereinafter called commission) from the\nstate of New York. The Governor, by and with the advice and consent of\nthe senate, shall appoint two persons as two of such commissioners, each\nof whom shall be a resident and citizen of the state of New York.  The\nterms of such commissioners shall continue to be for six years. Each\ncommissioner shall hold office until his successor shall be appointed\nand qualified. Vacancies occurring in the office of any such\ncommissioner for any reason or cause shall be filled by appointment by\nthe Governor, by and with the advice and consent of the senate, for the\nunexpired term. The third commissioner from the state of New York shall\nbe the Commissioner of Environmental Conservation of the state of New\nYork ex officio, and the term of any such ex officio commissioner shall\nterminate at the time he ceases to hold said office of Commissioner of\nEnvironmental Conservation, and his successor as a commissioner shall be\nhis successor as said Commissioner of Environmental Conservation.  With\nthe exception of the issuance of any order under the provisions of\narticle nine of the compact, said ex officio commissioner may delegate,\nfrom time to time, to any deputy or other subordinate in his department\nor office the power to be present and participate, including voting, as\nhis representative or substitute at any meeting of, or hearing by, or\nother proceeding of the commission. The commissioners serving on the\neffective date of this article shall continue in office until the\nexpiration of their terms, or until their successors have qualified, or\nuntil otherwise ceasing to be commissioners pursuant to law.\n  2. Any commissioner may be removed from office by the Governor upon\ncharges and after a hearing, but opportunity to be heard shall be given.\n  3. There is hereby granted to the commission and the commissioners\nthereof all the powers provided for in the said compact and all the\npowers necessary or incidental to the carrying out of said compact in\nevery particular. All officers of the state of New York are hereby\nauthorized and directed to do all things falling within their respective\nprovinces and jurisdiction necessary or incidental to the carrying out\nof said compact in every particular; it being hereby declared to be the\npolicy of the state of New York to perform and carry out the said\ncompact and to accomplish the purposes thereof. All officers, bureaus,\ndepartments and persons of and in the state government or administration\nof the state of New York are hereby authorized and directed at\nconvenient times and upon request of the said commission to furnish the\nsaid commission with information and data possessed by them or any of\nthem and to aid said commission by loan of personnel or other means\nlying within their legal powers respectively.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>