<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0501"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0501"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-09-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-0501"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0501/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-0501/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_0501">
        <num>21-0501</num>
        <heading>Tri-state compact</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In Connecticut, Long Island sound and estuaries and tidal waters\nthereof between the easterly side of New Haven harbor at Morgan Point\nand the Connecticut-New York state boundary, and the Housatonic river up\nto the northerly boundary lines of the towns of Stratford and Milford.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In New York, all of the tidal waters of Greater New York city;\nincluding Kill Van Kull and Arthur Kill, Long Island Sound and the\nestuaries and tidal waters thereof between the New York city line and\nthe New York-Connecticut state boundary and between the New York city\nline and the easterly side of Port Jefferson harbor; the Atlantic ocean\nand the estuaries and tidal waters thereof between the New York city\nline and the easterly side of Fire Island inlet; and the Hudson river\nand estuaries and tidal waters thereof between the New York and New\nJersey state boundary and the northerly line of Rockland county on the\nwesterly side and between the northerly line of New York city and the\nnortherly line of Westchester county on the easterly side of the river.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In New Jersey, the Hudson river and New York upper bay and\nestuaries and tidal waters thereof between the New York-New Jersey\nboundary and Constable Point on Constable Hook, the Kill Van Kull and\nArthur Kill to the mouths of the rivers entering into the Kills; Newark\nbay and the estuaries thereof up to the mouth of the Passaic river; and\nup to the mouth of the Hackensack river; Raritan bay together with the\nRaritan river up to the Victory bridge on said river between Perth Amboy\nand South Amboy; together with the Cheesequake creek up to the New York\nand Long Branch Railroad bridge on said creek at Morgan; together with\nthe Matawan creek up to the New York and Long Branch Railroad bridge on\nsaid creek at Matawan; Sandy Hook bay; together with the Shrewsbury\nriver up to the passenger railroad bridge between Navesink Light and\nHighland Beach on said river.\n                               ARTICLE III\n  1. There is hereby created the Interstate Environmental Commission\n(hereinafter referred to as the commission) which shall be a body\ncorporate and politic, having the powers, duties and jurisdiction herein\nenumerated and such other and additional powers as shall be conferred\nupon it by the act or acts of a signatory state concurred in by the\nothers and by the act or acts of congress when necessary.\n                               ARTICLE IV\n  1. The commission shall consist of five commissioners from each state,\neach of whom shall be a resident voter of the state from which he is\nappointed.\n  The commissioners shall be chosen in the manner and for the terms\nprovided by law of the state from which they shall be appointed, and\neach commissioner may be removed or suspended from office as provided by\nthe law of the state from which he shall be appointed. The commissioners\nshall serve without compensation, but shall be paid their actual\nexpenses incurred and incident to the performance of their duties.\n                                ARTICLE V\n  1....</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Class "A", in which the designated water areas are expected to be\nused primarily for recreational purposes, shellfish culture or the\ndevelopment of fish life;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Class "B", in which the designated water areas are not expected to\nbe used primarily for recreational purposes, shellfish culture or the\ndevelopment of fish life.\n                               ARTICLE VII\n  1. It is agreed between the signatory states that no sewage or other\npolluting matters shall be discharged or permitted to flow into, or be\nplaced in, or permitted to fall or move into the tidal waters of the\ndistrict, except under the following conditions and restrictions:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>All sewage discharged or permitted to flow into Class "A" waters\nof the district shall first have been so treated as\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to remove all floating solids and at least sixty per centum (60%)\nof the suspended solids; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to effect a reduction of organisms of the B. Coli group\n(intestinal bacilli) so that the probable number of such organisms shall\nnot exceed one per cubic centimeter in more than fifty per centum (50%)\nof the samples of sewage effluent tested by the partially confirmed\ntest; provided, however, that in the case of discharge into waters used\nprimarily for bathing this bacterial standard need not be required\nexcept during the bathing season; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to effect a reduction in the oxygen demand of the sewage effluent\nsufficient to maintain an average dissolved oxygen content in the tidal\nwaters of the district and in the general vicinity of the point of\ndischarge of the sewage into those waters, at a depth of about five feet\nbelow the surface, of not less than fifty per centum (50%) saturation\nduring any week of the year.\n  2. All sewage discharged or permitted to flow into class "B" waters of\nthe district shall first have been so treated as\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to remove all floating solids and at least ten per centum (10%) of\nthe suspended solids, or such additional percentage as may by reason of\nlocal conditions be necessary to avoid the formation of sludge deposits\nin the class "B" waters of the district; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_0501__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to effect a reduction in the oxygen demand of the sewage effluent\nsufficient to maintain an average dissolved oxygen content in the tidal\nwaters of the district and in the general vicinity of the point of\ndischarge of the sewage into those waters, at a depth of about five feet\nbelow the surface, of not less than thirty per centum (30%) saturation\nduring any week of the year.\n                              ARTICLE VIII\n  1. Each of the signatory states agrees, that in so far as waters\nwithin its jurisdiction may flow into any portion of the district, all\nsewage discharged or permitted to flow into any stream tributary to the\ntidal waters of the district shall be treated to that extent, if any,\nwhich may be necessary to maintain such tributary immediately above its\nconfluence with the tidal waters of the district in a sanitary condition\nat least equal to the classification requirements determined by the\ncommission for the tidal waters of the district into which it\ndischarges. The waters of the Hudson river, immediately above the mouth\nof Sparkhill creek on the westerly side and the New York-New Jersey\nboundary extended on the easterly side of the river, shall be maintained\nin a sanitary condition at ebb tide at least equal to the sanitary\ncondition prevailing in the waters of the river immediately below said\nboundary at flood tide.\n                               ARTICLE IX\n  1. Nothing in this compact shall be construed to repeal or prevent the\nenactment of any legislation or the enforcement of any requirement by\nany signatory state imposing any additional conditions and restrictions\nto further lessen or prevent the pollution of waters within its\njurisdiction.\n                                ARTICLE X\n  1. Subject to the provisions of this compact the commission, as soon\nas may be after its organization, after an investigation and after\nconducting public hearings upon due notice, shall by order prescribe the\nreasonable date on or before w...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>