<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-09-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-1701"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_1701">
        <num>21-1701</num>
        <heading>The Delaware river basin water commission compact approved</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to meet the domestic and industrial requirements of political\nsubdivisions and metropolitan areas within those States;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to provide an adequate minimum flow in the Delaware River for the\nprotection of public health, for the benefit of industry and of\nfisheries, such as oysters, clams, and other shellfish, for animal and\naquatic life, for recreation, for general sanitary conditions, for the\ndilution and abatement of pollution, and for the prevention of undue\nsalinity; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to provide for such other uses of water as navigation, flood\ncontrol, production of hydro-electric power, and related uses.\n  2. In order to effectuate the foregoing purposes, the Commission shall\ndetermine the exact locations and character of, formulate plans for, and\ndetermine all matters in connection with, the construction, operation\nand maintenance of dams, reservoirs, and appurtenant structures within\nthe Delaware River Basin as herein defined for the storage and effective\nregulation of the water resources thereof, and treatment plants,\naqueducts, conduits, or other facilities, and shall finance, construct,\noperate, and maintain such structures and facilities as are deemed\nnecessary to the following project, or a reasonable modification\nthereof, that is to say:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a dam across the West Branch of the\nDelaware River near Cannonsville, New York;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a dam across the\nDelaware River near Barryville, New York;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a dam across the Neversink\nRiver near Godeffroy, New York;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a dam across the Delaware River near\nWallpack Bend;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a dam across the East Branch of the Delaware River\nnear Fish Eddy;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a dam across Flat Brook near Flatbrookville, New\nJersey;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an aqueduct connecting the reservoir created by the dam\nacross the Delaware River near Barryville, New York, with the reservoir\non the Neversink River created by a dam near Godeffroy, New York;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an\naqueduct, with equalizing reservoir en route, to convey a supply of\nwater from the reservoir on the Neversink River created by the dam near\nGodeffroy, New York, to municipalities in northern New Jersy and to New\nYork City; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such dams, reservoirs, tunnels, conduits, and other\nfacilities as may be required to furnish water supply to Philadelphia\nand adjacent areas.\n  3. For the purpose of this compact the "Delaware River Basin" is\ndefined as all that land from which surface water drains naturally into\nthe Delaware River.\n                               ARTICLE II\n                              COMMISSIONERS\n  1. The Commission shall consist of three members from each signatory\nState, who shall be citizens and residents thereof and shall be\nappointed by the Governor of that State, by and with the consent of its\nSenate, unless its Constitution otherwise provides.\n  2. The term of each such commissioner shall be for five years,\nprovided, however, that the terms of the three commissioners first\nappointed by each state shall be as follows, to wit: one for three\nyears, one for four years, and one for five years. All commissioners\nshall continue to hold office after the expiration of the terms for\nwhich they shall have been appointed until their respective successors\nshall have been appointed and qualified, but no period during which any\ncommissioner shall hold over shall be deemed to be an extension of his\nterm of office for the purpose of computing the date on which his\nsuccessor's term expires.\n  3. Any commissioner may be removed or suspended from office as\nprovided by the Constitution or applicable law of the State which he\nrepresents.  In the event of a vacancy in the office of any\ncommissioner, from any reason or cause, such vacancy shall be filled by\nappointment by the Governor of the State concerned, subject to\nconfirmation as above provided, for the unexpired term.\n  4. The commissioners shall serve without compensation but shall be\npaid their actual and necessary expenses incurred in and incident to the\nperformance of their duties, provided, however, that the elected\nofficers of the Commission shall receive such compensation as may be\nfixed by the Commis...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To sue in its own name in Federal and State courts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To acquire, own, hire, use, operate, and dispose of personal\nproperty.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To acquire, own, use, and operate real property and interests\ntherein, to make improvements thereon, and to convey, lease or otherwise\ndispose of any such property no longer necessary for the authorized\npurposes of the Commission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To grant, by lease or otherwise, the use of any property or\nfacility owned or controlled by the Commission, and to make charges\ntherefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To exercise the right of eminent domain, as provided in Article V\nof this compact.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To borrow money, make and issue from time to time negotiable bonds\nand notes, to fund and refund the same, and to provide for the rights of\nthe holders of its bonds and notes, as provided in Article XIII of this\ncompact.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To establish, levy, and collect, without being subject to the\nsupervision or regulation of any commission, board, bureau or agency of\nany of the signatory States or political subdivisions thereof, such\nrentals, fees or other charges for use of the facilities of or for the\nservices rendered by the Commission, and to revise such rentals, fees,\nor other charges as may be necessary to assure revenues at least\nadequate to defray the expenses of operation and maintenance of the said\nfacilities, to pay the interest on and principal of any bonds or other\nobligations of the Commission, and to establish any reasonable reserves\ntherefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To accept such payments, appropriations, grants, gifts, loans, and\nother funds, properties, and services as may be made available to it by\nthe Federal government or any of its agencies, by the governments and\npolitical subdivisions of the signatory States, or by private agencies,\ncorporations, or individuals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To conduct surveys of dam, reservoir, treatment plant, aqueduct,\nor conduit locations and study subsurface conditions affecting the\nselection of such locations. Members of the Commission and its duly\naccredited agents, engineers, contractors, and employees may enter upon\nany lands, structures, and waters within any of the signatory States for\nsuch purposes or whenever it is deemed necessary for any of the purposes\nauthorized by this compact, and such entry shall not be deemed a\ntrespass or an entry under any condemnation proceedings which may be\nthen pending. In the exercise of this power, the Commission shall save\nharmless the signatory States from, and be responsible to any property\nowner for, any damage caused by surveys or by entry on lands or any\nother damage resulting therefrom, and the Commission shall require every\ncontractor or other agency performing work for said Commission to\nprovide security for the faithful performance of any contract with the\nCommission and to save harmless the Commission and the signatory States\nfrom damages caused as aforesaid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To determine the exact locations and character of, to formulate\nplans for, and to determine all matters in connection with, the\nconstruction, operation, and maintenance of the dams, reservoirs, and\nappurtenant structures within the Delaware River Basin as herein defined\nfor the storage and effective regulation of the water resources thereof,\nand treatment plants, aqueducts, conduits, and other facilities deemed\nnecessary or convenient to effectuate the structures and facilities\ndescribed in paragraph 2 of Article I of this compact, and to finance,\nconstruct, operate and maintain such structures and facilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To prepare, upon the request of two or more signatory States, or\nupon its own initiative, in appropriate form for submission to the\nlegislatures of the signatory States, a report covering plans for, and\nthe method of financing of, any new project, or any expansion of the\nproject authorized and described in paragraph 2 of Article I of this\ncompact; and, upon approval of such report by the legislatures of the\nsignatory States and upon approval by the appropriate agency or agencies\nof the State or States of the detailed plans and specifications, all in\naccordance with the provisions of Article XI of this compact, to\nfinance, construct, operate and maintain such new or expanded project.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To determine and to allocate, subject to the provisions of\nparagraph 2 of Article III, to each of the signatory States an equitable\napportionment of available water supply in order to meet domestic and\nindustrial requirements of political subdivisions and metropolitan areas\ntherein.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To release, subject to the provisions of Article IX, the quantity\nof water required to be released from storage in order to maintain an\nadequate minimum flow in the Delaware River during periods of low flow\ntherein for the protection of public health, for the benefit of industry\nand of fisheries, such as oysters, clams, and other shellfish, for\nanimal and aquatic life, for recreation, for general sanitary\nconditions, for the dilution and abatement of pollution, and for the\nprevention of undue salinity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To provide for such other uses of the water and water resources of\nthe Delaware River Basin as navigation, flood control, production of\nhydro-electric power, and related uses, and to cooperate with other\nappropriate agencies for that purpose.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To develop, or to provide for the development of, subject to the\nprovisions of Article X, hydro-electric power and energy inherent in the\ndevelopment and use of the waters to which this compact relates and\nincident to the control and conservation of such waters.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_p">
          <num>(p)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To make, enter into, and perform contracts with the Federal\ngovernment, with any of the signatory States or any of their political\nsubdivisions, with public or private agencies, and with corporations or\nindividuals, including</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_p__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>contracts for the sale of water for water\nsupply, for the sale of falling water and hydro-electric power and\nenergy, subject to the provisions of Article X, or for other services,\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_p__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>contracts for payments by the signatory States, or the political\nsubdivisions thereof, for benefits resulting from water released from\nstorage in order to maintain an adequate minimum flow in the Delaware\nRiver during periods of low flow therein, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_p__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any other contracts\nnecessary or incidental to the performance of its duties and the\nexecution of its powers under this compact.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_q">
          <num>(q)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To take all measures necessary to guard and protect the areas in\nwhich its facilities or developments are located or in which any work of\nconstruction under authority of this compact is in progress, and to\nprotect its facilities and developments from damage by pollution or\notherwise, and to appoint a suitable number of persons as guards for\nsuch purposes. Such persons shall possess the power and authority of a\nconstable, peace officer, or police officer and shall have full power to\nserve as such officers within the signatory States and to enforce the\nprovisions of such laws thereof as are applicable to the purposes of\nthis paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_r">
          <num>(r)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To do all acts and things necessary or convenient to carry out the\npowers expressly granted in this compact.\n  2. The signatory States consent to suits, actions or proceedings of\nany form or nature at law, in equity or otherwise (including proceedings\nto enforce arbitration agreements) against the Commission, and to\nappeals therefrom and reviews thereof, except as hereinafter provided in\nsubparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The foregoing consent does not extend to civil suits, actions or\nproceedings for the recovery of statutory penalties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The foregoing consent does not extend to suits, actions or\nproceedings for judgments, orders or decrees restraining, enjoining or\npreventing the Commission from committing or continuing to commit any\nact or acts, other than suits, actions or proceedings by the attorney\ngeneral of any of the signatory States. The attorney general of each of\nthe signatory States is hereby authorized to bring such suits, actions\nor proceedings in his discretion on behalf of any person or persons\nwhatsoever who requests him so to do except in the cases excluded by\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof; provided, that in any such suit, action or\nproceeding, no judgment, order or decree shall be entered except upon at\nleast two days' prior written notice to the Commission of the proposed\nentry thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The foregoing consent is granted upon the condition that venue in\nany suit, action or proceeding against the Commission shall be laid\nwithin a county or a judicial district, established by any of the said\nsignatory States or by the United States, and situated wholly or\npartially within one of the signatory States. The Commission shall be\ndeemed to be a resident of each such county or judicial district for the\npurpose of such suits, actions or proceedings. Although the Commission\nis engaged in the performance of governmental functions, the signatory\nStates consent to liability on the part of the Commission in such suits,\nactions or proceedings for tortious acts committed by it and its agents\nto the same extent as though it were a private corporation.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The foregoing consent is granted upon the condition that any\nsuit, action or proceeding prosecuted or maintained hereunder shall be\ncommenced within one year after the cause of action therefor shall have\naccrued, and upon the further condition that in the case of any suit,\naction or proceeding for the recovery or payment of money, prosecuted or\nmaintained hereunder, a notice of claim shall have been served upon the\nCommission by or on behalf of the plaintiff or plaintiffs at least sixty\ndays before such suit, action or proceeding is commenced. The provisions\nof this subparagraph shall not apply to claims arising out of provisions\nof any workmen's compensation law of any of the signatory States.\n  * NB Effective until concurrence by members of the Delaware River\nBasin Water Commission\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The foregoing consent is granted upon the condition that any\nsuit, action or proceeding prosecuted or maintained hereunder shall be\ncommenced within one year and ninety days after the cause of action\ntherefor shall have accrued, and upon the further condition that in the\ncase of any suit, action or proceeding for the recovery or payment of\nmoney, prosecuted or maintained hereunder, a notice of claim shall have\nbeen served upon the Commission by or on behalf of the plaintiff or\nplaintiffs within the time limit established by and in compliance with\nsection fifty-e of the general municipal law. The provisions of this\nsubparagraph shall not apply to claims arising out of provisions of any\nworkmen's compensation law of any of the signatory States.\n  * NB Effective upon concurrence by the members of the Delaware River\nBasin Water Commission\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The notice of claim required by subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof shall be\nin writing, sworn to by or on behalf of the claimant or claimants, and\nshall set forth</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name and post office address of each claimant\nand of his attorney, if any,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the nature of the claim,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the time\nwhen, the place where and the manner in which the claim arose, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nthe items of damage or injuries claimed to have been sustained so far as\nthen practicable. Such notice may be served in the manner in which\nprocess may be served, or in lieu thereof, may be sent by registered\nmail to the Commission at its principal office. Where the claimant is an\ninfant or is mentally or physically incapacitated and by reason of such\ndisability no notice of claim is filed or suit, action or proceeding\ncommenced within the time specified in subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof, or where\na person entitled to make a claim dies and by reason of his death no\nnotice of claim is filed or suit, action or proceeding commenced within\nthe time specified in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof, then any court in which\nsuch suit, action or proceeding may be brought may in its discretion\ngrant leave to serve the notice of claim and to commence the suit,\naction or proceeding within a reasonable time but in any event within\nthree years after the cause of action accrued. Application for such\nleave must be made upon an affidavit showing the particular facts which\ncaused the delay and shall be accompanied by a copy of the proposed\nnotice of claim if such notice has not been served, and such application\nshall be made only upon notice to the Commission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioners, officers or employees of the Commission shall\nnot be subject to suits, actions or proceedings for judgments, orders or\ndecrees restraining, preventing or enjoining them in their official or\npersonal capacities from committing or continuing to commit any act or\nacts on behalf of the Commission other than suits, actions and\nproceedings brought by the attorney general of any of the signatory\nStates. The attorney general of each of the signatory States is hereby\nauthorized to bring such suits, actions or proceedings in his discretion\non behalf of any person or persons whatsoever who requests him so to do\nexcept in the cases excluded by subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hereof; provided, that\nin any such suit, action or proceeding brought by an attorney general,\nno judgment, order or decree shall be entered except upon at least two\ndays' notice to the defendant of the proposed entry thereof.\n                                ARTICLE V\n                        CONDEMNATION PROCEEDINGS\n  1. The commission shall have the power, except as hereinafter provided\nand limited, to acquire by condemnation lands, lands lying under water,\nrights in land, riparian rights, water rights, waters, and other\nproperty within the Delaware River basin as defined herein or required\nfor aqueducts, or conduits deemed necessary or convenient to effectuate\nthe structures and facilities described in paragraph two of Article I of\nthis compact. This grant of the power of eminent domain includes, except\nas hereinafter provided and limited, but is not limited to, the power to\ncondemn property, within the Delaware river basin as defined herein or\nrequired for aqueducts, or conduits deemed necessary or convenient to\neffectuate the structures and facilities described in paragraph two of\nArticle I of this compact, owned or held by a political subdivision for\nmunicipal or public purposes, by a public district, by a public\ncorporation or by a public authority, and includes as well the power to\ncondemn any property already devoted to a public purpose, by whomsoever\nowned or held, other than property owned or held by the signatory States\nand other than property owned or held by the City of New York, wherever\nsituate, for its water supply or for its water supply system. Nothing\nherein shall be deemed to include the power to condemn the lands,\nstructures or properties necessary or convenient to the exercise of the\nrights reserved in Article XVI of this compact.\n  2. Such power shall be exercised in accordance with the provisions of\nsuch special law, specifically applicable to the said Commission, as may\nnow or hereafter be in force in the signator...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon and after completion of a storage reservoir on the West\nBranch of the Delaware River near Cannonsville, New York, sufficient\nwater shall be released from the aforesaid reservoir to maintain a\nminimum flow in the Delaware River, as measured at the stream gaging\nstation at Port Jervis, New York, of at least 1800 cubic feet per\nsecond.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon and after completion of storage reservoirs on the West Branch\nof the Delaware River near Cannonsville, New York, on the main channel\nof the Delaware River near Barryville, New York, and on the Neversink\nRiver near Godeffroy, New York, sufficient water shall be released from\nthe system consisting of the three aforesaid reservoirs to maintain a\nminimum flow in the Delaware River, as measured at the stream gaging\nstation at Trenton, New Jersey, of at least 4000 cubic feet per second.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon and after completion of storage reservoirs on the West Branch\nof the Delaware River near Cannonsville, New York, on the main channel\nof the Delaware River near Barryville, New York, on the Neversink River\nnear Godeffroy, New York, and on the main channel of the Delaware River\nnear Wallpack Bend, sufficient water shall be released from the system\nconsisting of the four aforesaid reservoirs to maintain a minimum flow\nin the Delaware River, as measured at the stream gaging station at\nTrenton, New Jersey, of at least 4800 cubic feet per second.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The intent and purpose of the requirements of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this article are to provide for a flow at all times of at least\n4000 cubic feet per second, or at least 4800 cubic feet per second, as\nthe case may be, from the non-tidal section of the Delaware River above\nTrenton into the tidal section of the Delaware River below Trenton.\nAccordingly, the requirements for the flow of at least 4,000 cubic feet\nper second, or at least 4800 cubic feet per second, at Trenton may be\nreduced by the Commission in such a manner as to carry out this intent\nand purpose in the event the Commission is called upon to utilize a part\nof the waters which would otherwise flow in the Delaware River at\nTrenton as a source of water supply for the City of Philadelphia and\nother political subdivisions and metropolitan areas in the greater\nPhiladelphia-South Jersey area which are situated wholly within the\nDelaware River Basin.\n                                ARTICLE X\n                     HYDROELECTRIC POWER AND ENERGY\n  In the exercise of its power to develop, or to provide for the\ndevelopment of, hydroelectric power and energy, no water shall be used\nin addition to the water which would otherwise be developed and used by\nthe Commission for water supply and for water required to be released\nfrom storage in order to maintain an adequate minimum flow in the\nDelaware River during periods of low flow therein. The Commission shall\nnot engage in the transmission and distribution of power and energy\nexcept for its own use.\n                               ARTICLE XI\n                    FORMULATION AND APPROVAL OF PLANS\n  1. Upon the request of two or more signatory States, or upon its own\ninitiative, the Commission shall prepare, in appropriate form for\nsubmission to the legislatures of the signatory States, a report\ncovering plans for, and the method of financing, any new project, or any\nexpansion of the project authorized and described in paragraph 2 of\nArticle I of this compact, for the construction, operation, and\nmaintena...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conduct investigations in such manner as to give appropriate\nconsideration and weight to the interrelation of the proposed project\nwith projects and programs of other agencies, public and private,\nfederal, interstate, state, and local, concerning the development,\nutilization, control and conservation of the water resources of the\nDelaware River Basin.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Transmit a copy of its tentative draft of a report concerning any\nproposed project to the following agencies, or their respective\nsuccessors, for the purpose of affording such agencies an opportunity to\nsubmit to the Commission, within ninety days from the date of receipt of\nsuch tentative draft, written statements of their views and\nrecommendations regarding any such project: Water Pollution Control\nCommission of the State of Delaware; Division of Water Policy and Supply\nof the State of New Jersey; Water Power and Control Commission of the\nState of New York; Water and Power Resources Board of the Commonwealth\nof Pennsylvania; and the Interstate Commission on the Delaware River\nBasin. Representatives of each of the aforesaid agencies may, in order\nto analyze and appraise any project proposed by the Commission created\nby this compact, enter upon any lands, structures, and waters within the\nstates in which the Delaware River Basin is located, for the purpose of\nsurveying dam, reservoir, treatment plant, aqueduct, or conduit\nlocations, studying subsurface conditions affecting the selection of\nsuch locations, and for such other purposes as may be deemed necessary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Include in its report, for submission to the legislatures of the\nsignatory States, the statements of views and recommendations, if any,\nof the aforesaid agencies.\n  3. The report, prepared after compliance with the procedures\nhereinbefore provided, shall be submitted by the Commission to the\nlegislatures of the signatory States. The Commission shall have\nauthority to proceed with the project proposed in the said report when\nsuch report has been approved by the legislatures of all the signatory\nStates, or by the legislatures of the States of New Jersey and New York\nand the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.\n  4. Prior to proceeding with any construction which is a part of the\nproject authorized and described in paragraph 2 of Article I of this\ncompact, or of any authorized expansion thereof, or of any authorized\nnew project, the Commission shall submit detailed plans and\nspecifications for the construction of any structure, or part thereof,\nto, and secure the approval of, the appropriate agency or agencies of\nthe State or States within which such construction is necessary as a\npart of the said project.\n                               ARTICLE XII\n     GRANTS, LOANS, OR PAYMENTS BY STATES OR POLITICAL SUBDIVISIONS\n  1. Any or all of the signatory States, or any political subdivisions\nthereof, may after appropriate legislative authorization for that\npurpose,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Appropriate to the Commission such funds as may be necessary to\npay preliminary expenses such as the expenses incurred in the making of\nborings and other studies of sub-surface conditions, in the preparation\nof contracts for the sale of water, and in the preparation of detailed\nplans and estimates required for the financing of a construction\nproject.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>advance to the Commission, either as grants or loans, such funds\nas may be necessary or convenient to finance the operation and\nmanagement of, or construction by, the Commission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make payments to the Commission for benefits received, or to be\nreceived, from the operation of any of the structures or facilities of\nthe Commission.\n  2. Any funds which may be loaned to the Commission either by a\nsignatory State, or a political subdivision thereof, shall be repaid by\nthe Commission through the issuance of bonds, or out of other income of\nthe Commission, such repayment to be made within such period and upon\nsuch terms as may be agreed upon between the Commission and the State or\npolitical subdivision making the loan.\n                              ARTICLE XIII\n                                FINANCING\n  1. The Commission shall have power and is hereby authorized, from time\nto time, to issue its negotiable bonds for any of its authorized\npurposes, to issue its bonds to refund bonds issued by it, to issue its\nnegotiable notes in anticipation of bonds, and to pay its bonds and\nnotes from revenues of the Commission and the proceeds of its bonds and\nother moneys of the Commission, as the resolution authorizing the\nissuance may provide:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Refunding bonds may be issued partially to refund bonds then\noutstanding and partially for any other of its authorized purposes.\nRefunding bonds may be issued whenever the Commission deems expedient,\nwhether the bonds to be refunded have or have not matured, and may be\nexchanged for the bonds to be refunded with such cash adjustments as may\nbe agreed, or may be sold before the bonds to be refunded become due and\nthe proceeds applied to the purchase, redemption or payment of the bonds\nto be refunded, including interest accrued, and any redemption premiums\npayable, thereon.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as may be otherwise expressly provided by the Commission,\nevery issue of bonds shall be general obligations payable out of any\nmoneys or revenues of the Commission, subject only to any agreements\nwith the holders of any bonds pledging any moneys or revenues.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whether or not bonds or notes issued by the Commission are of such\nform and character as to be negotiable instruments, such bonds or notes\nshall be fully negotiable within the meaning and for all the purposes of\nthe Negotiable Instruments Law, subject only to any provisions of the\nbonds for registration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Commission may issue temporary bonds, with or without coupons,\npending the preparation of definitive bonds, exchangeable for definitive\nbonds.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Bonds shall be authorized by resolution of the Commission and\nshall bear such date or dates, mature at such time or times, bear\ninterest at such rate or rates not exceeding five per centum per annum,\nbe in such denominations, be in such form, either coupon or registered,\ncarry such registration privileges, be executed in such manner, be\npayable in such medium of payment and at such place or places, and be\nsubject to such terms of redemption, as such resolution or resolutions\nmay provide, but in no event shall the redemption price of a bond exceed\nthe par value thereof and a premium of four per centum plus accrued\ninterest. The official seal of the Commission, or a facsimile thereof,\nshall be impressed, engraved, or otherwise reproduced on each bond or\nnote, and be attested by the Secretary or by such other officer or agent\nas the Commission shall appoint and authorize. If any officer or\nauthorized agent whose signature, or a facsimile thereof, shall appear\non any bonds, coupons, or notes, shall cease to be such officer or\nauthorized agent before the delivery of the bonds or notes, such\nsignature or such facsimile signature shall be valid and sufficient for\nall purposes the same as if he had continued in office until such\ndelivery. The bonds shall be sold at public sale for a price not less\nthan ninety-six per centum of the par value thereof plus accrued\ninterest, provided that the interest cost to maturity of the money for\nany issue of such bonds shall not exceed five per centum per annum.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any resolution of the Commission authorizing the issuance of bonds\nmay appoint a trustee or trustees, a fiscal agent or fiscal agents, a\npaying agent or paying agents, and such other fiduciaries as such\nresolution may provide. Any trustee, fiscal agent, paying agent and\nother fiduciary so appointed may be any trust company or bank having the\npowers of a trust company within any one of the signatory States.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to secure the payment of its bonds the Commission shall\nhave power, in the resolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds\n(which shall be deemed a contract with the bondholders):\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to pledge all or any part of its revenues to which its right then\nexists or may thereafter come into existence, and the moneys derived\ntherefrom, and the proceeds of bonds;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to covenant against pledging all or any part of its revenues, or\nagainst mortgaging all or any part of its real or personal property then\nowned or thereafter acquired, or against permitting or suffering any\nlien on such revenues or property; to covenant with respect to\nlimitations on its right to sell, lease or otherwise dispose of any\nproject or any part thereof, or any property of any kind;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to covenant as to the bonds to be issued and the limitations\nthereon and the terms and conditions thereof and as to the custody,\napplication and disposition of the proceeds thereof, and to covenant as\nto the issuance of additional bonds or as to limitations on the issuance\nof additional bonds and on the incurring of other debts by it;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to provide for the replacement of lost, destroyed or mutilated\nbonds;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to provide for the investment of all or a part of its funds on\ndeposit with the trustee or other fiduciary in such obligations as the\nresolution authorizing the issuance of the bonds may provide;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to covenant against extending the time for the payment of bonds or\ninterest thereon; to covenant as to the redemption premiums and other\nterms and conditions thereof;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to covenant as to the payment of the principal of or interest on\nthe bonds, or any other obligations, as to the sources and methods of\nsuch payment, as to the rank or priority of any such bonds or\nobligations with respect to any lien or security or as to the\nacceleration of the maturity of any such bonds or obligations;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to covenant as to the rates of fees or other charges to be\nestablished and to be charged, and the amount to be raised each year or\nother period of time by such charges or other revenues and as to the use\nand disposition to be made thereof; to create or authorize the creation\nof special funds or moneys to be held in pledge or otherwise for\nconstruction, operating expense, payment or redemption of bonds,\nreserves or other purposes and to covenant as to the use and disposition\nof the moneys held in such funds;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to establish the procedure, if any, by which the terms of any\ncontract or covenant with or for the benefit of the bondholders may be\namended or abrogated, the amount of bonds the holders of which must\nconsent thereto, and the manner in which such consent may be given;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to covenant as to the maintenance of its real and personal\nproperty, the replacement thereof, the insurance to be carried thereon,\nand the use and disposition of insurance moneys;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to provide for the rights and liabilities, powers and duties\narising upon the breach of any covenant, condition or obligation; to\nprescribe the events of default and the terms and conditions upon which\nany or all of the bonds shall become or may be declared due and payable\nbefore maturity and the terms and conditions upon which any such\ndeclaration and its consequences may be waived;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_g__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to vest in a trustee or trustees such property, rights, powers\nand duties in trust for the bondholders, as the Commission may\ndetermine, which may include any or all of the rights, powers and duties\nof the statutory trustee appointed by the holders of bonds pursuant to\nsub-paragraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph 2 of this Article; to limit or abrogate\nthe rights of the holders of such bonds to appoint such statutory\ntrustee, or to limit the rights, duties and powers of such statutory\ntrustee;\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to limit the rights of the bondholders to enforce any pledge or\ncovenant securing the bonds; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to make covenants other than and in addition to the covenants\nherein expressly authorized, of like or different character; and to make\nsuch covenants to do or refrain from doing such acts and things as may\nbe necessary or convenient or desirable in order to better secure the\nbonds or which, in the absolute discretion of the commission, will tend\nto make the bonds more marketable, notwithstanding that such covenants,\nacts or things may not be enumerated herein.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any pledge of revenues or other moneys made by the Commission\nshall be valid and binding from the time when the pledge is made; the\nrevenues or other moneys so pledged and thereafter received by the\nCommission shall immediately be subject to the lien of such pledge\nwithout any physical delivery thereof or further act, and the lien of\nany such pledge shall be valid and binding as against all parties having\nclaims of any kind in tort, contract or otherwise against the\nCommission, irrespective of whether such parties have notice thereof.\nNeither the resolution nor any other instrument by which a pledge is\ncreated need be filed or recorded except in the records of the\nCommission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Bonds may be issued under the provisions of this compact without\nobtaining the consent of any department, division, commission, board,\nbureau or agency of any of the signatory States, and without any other\nproceedings or the happening of any other conditions or things than\nthose proceedings, conditions or things which are specifically required\nby this compact.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Commission shall not have power to mortgage real property.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Moneys of the Commission or moneys held in pledge or otherwise for\nthe payment of bonds or in any way to secure bonds and the deposits of\nsuch moneys may be secured in such manner as the Commission may require\nand all banks and trust companies in each of the signatory States are\nauthorized to give such security therefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Neither the members of the Commission nor any person executing the\nbonds shall be liable personally on the bonds or be subject to any\npersonal liability or accountability by reason of the issuance thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The Commission shall have the power to purchase its bonds out of\nany funds available therefor. The Commission may refund, or it may hold,\ncancel, or resell, such bonds subject to and in accordance with\nagreements with bondholders.\n  2. The following provisions shall be applicable to an issue of bonds\nauthorized or issued by the Commission, only if the resolution of the\nCommission authorizing or providing for the issuance of such bonds shall\nprovide in substance that the holders of the bonds of such issue shall\nbe entitled to the benefits and be subject to the provisions of this\nparagraph 2:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the event that there shall be a default in the payment of\nprincipal of or interest on any bonds of such issue after the same shall\nbecome due, whether at maturity or upon call for redemption, and such\ndefault shall continue for a period of thirty days, or in the event that\nthe Commission shall fail or refuse to comply with the provisions of\nthis compact or shall fail or refuse to carry out and perform the terms\nof any contract or covenant with or for the benefit of the holders of\nany such bonds, and such failure or refusal shall continue for a period\nof thirty days after written notice by any holder of bonds of such issue\nor by a trustee for bondholders to the Commission of its existence and\nnature, the holders of twenty-five per centum (25%) in aggregate\nprincipal amount of the bonds of such issue then outstanding by\ninstrument or instruments filed in the office of the Secretary of State\nof each signatory State and proved or acknowledged in the same manner as\na deed to be recorded, may appoint a statutory trustee to represent the\nholders of the bonds of such issue for the purposes provided in this\nparagraph 2.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such statutory trustee may and, upon written request of the\nholders of twenty-five per centum (25%) in aggregate principal amount of\nthe bonds of such issue then outstanding, shall, in his or its own name:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>by civil action or suit, enforce all rights of the holders of such\nbonds, including the right to require the Commission to charge and\ncollect revenues adequate to carry out any contract as to, or pledge of,\nsuch charges and revenues, and to require the Commission to carry out\nand perform the terms of any contract or covenant with or for the\nbenefit of the holders of such bonds or its duties under this compact;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>bring action or suit upon all or any part of such bonds or\ninterest coupons or claims appurtenant thereto;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>by action or suit require the Commission to account as if it were\nthe trustee of an express trust for the holders of such bonds;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>by action or suit enjoin any acts or things which may be unlawful\nor in violation of the covenants of the Commission or the rights of the\nholders of such bonds; or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>declare all such bonds due and payable, whether or not in advance\nof maturity, upon thirty days' prior notice in writing to the Commission\nand if all defaults shall be made good, then with the consent of the\nholders of twenty-five per centum (25%) of the principal amount of such\nbonds then outstanding, annul such declaration and its consequences.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Before declaring the principal of all such bonds due and payable\nthe statutory trustee shall first give thirty days' notice in writing to\nthe Commission.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any such statutory trustee, whether or not the issue of bonds\nrepresented by such trustee has been declared due and payable, shall be\nentitled as of right to the appointment of a receiver of any part or\nparts of the property of the Commission the revenues derived from which\nproperty are pledged for the security of the bonds of such issue and\nsuch receiver may enter and take possession of such part or parts of\nsuch property and subject to any pledge or agreement with bondholders\nshall take possession of all moneys and other property derived from or\napplicable to the construction, operation, maintenance and\nreconstruction of such part or parts of such property and proceed with\nany construction thereon which the Commission is under obligation to do\nand to operate, maintain and reconstruct such part or parts of the\nproperty and collect and receive all revenues thereafter arising\ntherefrom subject to any pledge thereof or agreement with bondholders\nrelating thereto, and perform the public duties and carry out the\nagreements and obligations of the Commission under the direction of the\ncourt. In any suit, action or proceeding by the statutory trustee the\nfees, counsel fees and expenses of the said trustee and of the receiver,\nif any, shall constitute taxable disbursements and all costs and\ndisbursements allowed by the court shall be a first charge on any\nrevenues derived from such property.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such statutory trustee shall, in addition to the foregoing, have\nand possess all of the powers necessary or appropriate for the exercise\nof any function specifically set forth herein or incident to the general\nrepresentation of bondholders in the enforcement and protection of their\nrights.\n  3. Notes issued in anticipation of bonds shall be paid from any moneys\nof the Commission available therefor and not otherwise pledged or from\nthe proceeds of sale of the bonds of the Commission in anticipation of\nwhich they were issued. The notes shall be issued and sold in the same\nmanner as the bonds and such notes and the resolution or resolutions\nauthorizing the same may contain any provisions, conditions or\nlimitations which the bonds or a bond resolution of the Commission may\ncontain. Such note shall be as fully negotiable as the bonds of the\nCommission.\n  4. Bonds issued by the Commission under the provisions of this compact\nare hereby made securities in which any signatory State and all\npolitical subdivisions thereof, their officers, boards, commissions,\ndepartments or other agencies, all banks, bankers, savings banks, trust\ncompanies, savings and loan associations, investment companies and other\npersons carrying on a banking business, all insurance companies,\ninsurance associations, and other persons carrying on an insurance\nbusiness, and other fiduciaries, and all other persons whatsoever,\nexcept as hereinafter provided, who now are or may hereafter be\nauthorized to invest in bonds or other obligations of any signatory\nState, may properly and legally invest any funds, including capital\nbelonging to them or within their control; provided that,\nnotwithstanding the provisions of any other general or special law to\nthe contrary, such bonds shall not be eligible for the investment of\nfunds, including capital, of trusts, estates or guardianships under the\ncontrol of individual administrators, guardians, executors, trustees and\nother individual f...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it has been adopted and enacted\ninto law by the respective legislatures of the said States and\nCommonwealth, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it has been signed by the respective Governors of\nthe said States and Commonwealth, after authorization therefor by their\nrespective legislatures, and has been attested by the Secretary of the\nState of each of said States and Commonwealth and the Seal of each of\nsaid States and Commonwealth has been affixed thereto, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nCongress of the United States of America has consented thereto.\n  2. This compact shall become effective and binding with respect to the\nState of Delaware, either at the same time it becomes effective and\nbinding between the States of New Jersey and New York and the\nCommonwealth of Pennsylvania as provided in the first paragraph of this\nArticle or at any time thereafter, when</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it has been adopted and\nenacted into law by the legislature of the State of Delaware, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1701__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it\nhas been signed by the Governor of the State of Delaware, after\nauthorization therefor by the legislature thereof, and has been attested\nby the Secretary of State of the State and the Seal of that State has\nbeen affixed thereto.\n  3. This compact shall be signed, attested, and sealed in five\noriginals, one original to be forwarded to the Governor of each\nsignatory State for filing in accordance with the laws of that State and\none original to be deposited in the archives of the Commission upon its\nestablishment.\n  IN WITNESS WHEREOF, and in evidence of the adoption and enactment into\nlaw of this compact by the legislatures of the respective States, the\nrespective Governors of the signatory States do hereby, in accordance\nwith authority conferred by the legislatures of their respective States,\nsign this compact in five originals, as attested by the respective\nSecretaries of State of the said States, and have caused the respective\nSeals of the said States to be hereunto affixed,\nthis...................day of......................,19....\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>