<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-1001"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_1001">
        <num>21-1001</num>
        <heading>The Great Lakes-St</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are\nenvironmentally sound, (ii) reflect best practices applicable to the\nwater use sector, (iii) are technically feasible and available, (iv) are\neconomically feasible and cost effective based on an analysis that\nconsiders direct and avoided economic and environmental costs and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nconsider the particular facilities and processes involved, taking into\naccount the environmental impact, age of equipment and facilities\ninvolved, the processes employed, energy impacts and other appropriate\nfactors.\n  Exception means a transfer of Water that is excepted under Section 4.9\nfrom the prohibition against Diversions in Section 4.8.\n  Exception Standard means the standard for Exceptions established in\nSection 4.9.4.\n  Intra-Basin Transfer means the transfer of Water from the watershed of\none of the Great Lakes into the watershed of another Great Lake.\n  Measures means any legislation, law, regulation, directive,\nrequirement, guideline, program, policy, administrative practice or\nother procedure.\n  New or Increased Diversion means a new Diversion, an increase in an\nexisting Diversion, or the alteration of an existing Withdrawal so that\nit becomes a Diversion.\n  New or Increased Withdrawal or Consumptive Use means a new Withdrawal\nor Consumptive Use or an increase in an existing Withdrawal or\nConsumptive Use.\n  Originating Party means the Party within whose jurisdiction an\nApplication or registration is made or required.\n  Party means a State party to this Compact.\n  Person means a human being or a legal person, including a government\nor a non-governmental organization, including any scientific,\nprofessional, business, non-profit, or public interest organization or\nassociation that is neither affiliated with, nor under the direction of\na government.\n  Product means something produced in the Basin by human or mechanical\neffort or through agricultural processes and used in manufacturing,\ncommercial or other processes or intended for intermediate or end use\nconsumers.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Water used as part of the packaging of a Product shall be\nconsidered to be part of the Product. (ii) Other than Water used as part\nof the packaging of a Product, Water that is used primarily to transport\nmaterials in or out of the Basin is not a Product or part of a Product.\n(iii) Except as provided in</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>above, Water which is transferred as\npart of a public or private supply is not a Product or part of a\nProduct. (iv) Water in its natural state such as in lakes, rivers,\nreservoirs, aquifers, or water basins is not a Product.\n  Proposal means a Withdrawal, Diversion or Consumptive Use of Water\nthat is subject to this Compact.\n  Province means Ontario or Quebec.\n  Public Water Supply Purposes means water distributed to the public\nthrough a physically connected system of treatment, storage and\ndistribution facilities serving a group of largely residential customers\nthat may also serve industrial, commercial, and other institutional\noperators. Water Withdrawn directly from the Basin and not through such\na system shall not be considered to be used for Public Water Supply\nPurposes.\n  Regional Body means the members of the Council and the Premiers of\nOntario and Quebec or their designee as established by the Agreement.\n  Regional Review means the collective review by the Regional Body as\ndescribed in Article 4 of this Compact.\n  Source Watershed means the watershed from which a Withdrawal\noriginates.  If Water is Withdrawn directly from a Great Lake or from\nthe St.  Lawrence River, then the Source Watershed shall be considered\nto be the watershed of that Great Lake or the watershed of the St.\nLawrence River, respectively. If Water is Withdrawn from the watershed\nof a stream that is a direct tributary to a great lake or a direct\ntributary to the St.  Lawrence River, then the Source Watershed shall be\nconsidered to be the watershed of that Great Lake or the watershed of\nthe St. Lawrence River, respectively, with a preference to the direct\ntributary stream watershed from which it was Withdrawn.\n  Standard of Review and Decision means the Exception Standard,\nDecision-Making Standard and reviews as outlined in Article 4 of this\nCompact.\n  State means one of the states of Illinois, Indiana, Michigan,\nMinnesota, New York, Ohio or Wisconsin or the C...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nprepared by each Party in accordance with this Section, shall constitute\nthe baseline volume.\n  c. The list</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall be furnished to the Regional Body and the Council\nwithin one year of the effective date of this Compact.\n  3. Timing of Additional Applications. Applications for New or\nIncreased Withdrawals, Consumptive Uses or Exceptions shall be\nconsidered cumulatively within ten years of any application.\n  4. Change of Ownership. Unless a new owner proposes a project that\nshall result in a Proposal for a new or Increased Diversion or\nConsumptive Use subject to Regional Review or Council approval, the\nchange of ownership in and of itself shall not require Regional Review\nor Council approval.\n  5. Groundwater. The Basin surface water divide shall be used for the\npurpose of managing and regulating New or Increased Diversions,\nConsumptive Uses or Withdrawals of surface water and groundwater.\n  6. Withdrawal Systems. The total volume of surface water and\ngroundwater resources that supply a common distribution system shall\ndetermine the volume of a Withdrawal, Consumptive Use or Diversion.\n  7. Connecting Channels. The watershed of each Great Lake shall include\nits upstream and downstream connecting channels.\n  8. Transmission in Water Lines. Transmission of Water within a line\nthat extends outside the Basin as it conveys Water from one point to\nanother within the Basin shall not be considered a Diversion if none of\nthe Water is used outside the Basin.\n  9. Hydrologic Units. The Lake Michigan and Lake Huron watersheds shall\nbe considered to be a single hydrologic unit and watershed.\n  10. Bulk Water Transfer. A Proposal to Withdraw Water and to remove it\nfrom the Basin in any container greater than 5.7 gallons shall be\ntreated under this Compact in the same manner as a Proposal for a\nDiversion. Each Party shall have the discretion, within its\njurisdiction, to determine the treatment of Proposals to Withdraw Water\nand to remove it from the Basin in any container of 5.7 gallons or less.\n  Section 4.13. Exemptions.\n  Withdrawals from the Basin for the...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or hearing</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for an Application, time and place of\nsuch a meeting or hearing, and procedures for conducting of the same.\n  4. Provide the record of decision for public inspection including\ncomments, objections, responses and approvals, approvals with conditions\nand disapprovals.\n                                ARTICLE 7\n                   DISPUTE RESOLUTION AND ENFORCEMENT\n  Section 7.1. Good Faith Implementation.\n  Each of the Parties pledges to support implementation of all\nprovisions of this Compact, and covenants that its officers and agencies\nshall not hinder, impair, or prevent any other Party carrying out any\nprovision of this Compact.\n  Section 7.2. Alternative Dispute Resolution.\n  1. Desiring that this Compact be carried out in full, the Parties\nagree that disputes between the Parties regarding interpretation,\napplication and implementation of this Compact shall be settled by\nalternative dispute resolution.\n  2. The Council, in consultation with the Provinces, shall provide by\nrule procedures for the resolution of disputes pursuant to this section.\n  Section 7.3. Enforcement.\n  1. Any Person aggrieved by any action taken by the Council pursuant to\nthe authorities contained in this Compact shall be entitled to a hearing\nbefore the Council. Any Person aggrieved by a Party action shall be\nentitled to a hearing pursuant to the relevant Party's administrative\nprocedures and laws. After exhaustion of such administrative remedies,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any aggrieved Person shall have the right to judicial review of a\nCouncil action in the United States District Courts for the District of\nColumbia or the District Court in which the Council maintains offices,\nprovided such action is commenced within 90 days; and, (ii) any\naggrieved Person shall have the right to judicial review of a Party's\naction in the relevant Party's court of competent jurisdiction, provided\nthat an action or proceeding for such review is commenced within the\ntime frames provided for by the Party's law. For the purposes of this\nParagraph, a State or Province is deemed to be an aggrieved Person with\nrespect to any Party action pursuant to this Compact.\n  2. a. Any Party or the Council may initiate actions to compel\ncompliance with the provisions of this Compact, and the rules and\nregulations promulgated hereunder by the Council. Jurisdiction over such\nactions is granted to the court of the relevant Party, as well as the\nUnited States District Courts for the District of Columbia and the\nDistrict Court in which the Council maintains offices. The remedies\navailable to any such court shall include, but not be limited to,\nequitable relief and civil penalties.\n  b. Each Party may issue orders within its respective jurisdiction and\nmay initiate actions to compel compliance with the provisions of its\nrespective statutes and regulations adopted to implement the authorities\ncontemplated by this Compact in accordance with the provisions of the\nlaws adopted in each Party's jurisdiction.\n  3. Any aggrieved Person, Party or the Council may commence a civil\naction in the relevant Party's courts and administrative systems to\ncompel any Person to comply with this Compact should any such Person,\nwithout approval having been given, undertake a New or Increased\nWithdrawal, Consumptive Use or Diversion that is prohibited or subject\nto approval pursuant to this Compact.\n  a. No action under this subsection may be commenced if:\n  i. The Or...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>