<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-1101"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_1101">
        <num>21-1101</num>
        <heading>Champlain basin compact</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this compact, provided that the\nCommission takes specific action setting aside such funds prior to the\nincurring of any obligation to be met in whole or in part in such\nmanner.\n  4.4  The Commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and\ndisbursements. The receipts and disbursements of the Commission shall be\nsubject to the audit and accounting procedures established under its\nbylaws. However, all receipts and disbursements of funds handled by the\nCommission shall be audited by a qualified public accountant and the\nreport of the audit shall be included in and become part of the annual\nreport of the Commission.\n  4.5  The accounts of the Commission shall be open at any reasonable\ntime for inspection by such agency, representative, or representatives\nof the jurisdictions which appropriate funds to the Commission.\n             ARTICLE 5--CHAMPLAIN REGION--ORDERLY DEVELOPMENT\n  5.1  The Commission shall act as a general forum for the problems of\nthe region, including, but not limited to, those for which the agreement\nestablishes separate consideration by the Basin Panel and Valley\nCouncil, and to that end shall encourage and implement channels of\ncommunication and coordination among those departments and agencies of\nthe signatory parties and their subdivisions as have significant\ninterest in the subject matters of the Commission's activities and may\nmake such recommendations to those parties, and those departments,\nagencies, and subdivisions as may be desirable for the welfare and\norderly development of the region.\n  5.2  The Commission shall hold an annual general conference and such\nother conferences or meetings, general or particular, as it may deem\nadvisable to promote the welfare and orderly development of the region.\n  5.3  The Commission shall sponsor, organize or encourage and aid\nconferences of the local governments of the Basin or such areas thereof\nas may be appropriate to implement inter-governmental information,\nc...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1101__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_21_1101__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph shall\nnot be interpreted to preclude recommendations on matters not so listed.\nNothing in this article shall be construed to prohibit action by a\nsignatory party, or the signatory parties by means of legislation other\nthan legislation concurred in by both states.\n  8.5  Nothing in this Compact or in any regulation issued under the\nprovisions of this article or concurrent legislation enacted in\naccordance therewith shall be interpreted to supersede actions of a park\ndistrict created under the laws of either state lying wholly or\npartially in the Lake Champlain Park unless the Valley Council\nspecifically states such effect is necessary for the adequate protection\nof the amenities and values of the Lake Champlain Park.\n  Nor shall this compact be interpreted to prohibit more stringent\naction by a signatory party.\n                                 ARTICLE 9\n  Except as may be stipulated in Title II of Article 6 nothing in this\nCompact shall be construed to impair, or otherwise affect the\njurisdiction of any interstate agency in which any party state\nparticipates not to abridge, impair, or otherwise affect the provisions\nof any compact to which any one or more of the party states may be a\nparty, nor to supersede, diminish, or otherwise affect any obligation\nassumed under any such compact; nor shall anything in this compact be\nconstrued to discourage additional interstate compacts among some or all\nof the party states or the establishment of intergovernmental agencies\nin sub-areas of the region or to limit the jurisdiction or activities of\nany participating government, agency, or officer thereof, or any private\nperson or agency.\n                                ARTICLE 10\n  The provisions of this Compact shall be severable and if phrase,\nclause, sentence or provision of this Compact is declared to be\nunconstitutional or the applicability thereof to any state, agency,\nperson or circumstance is held invalid, the constitutionali...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>