<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1007"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1007"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-1007"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1007/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1007/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_1007">
        <num>21-1007</num>
        <heading>The Great Lakes Basin advisory council; convening</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 21-1007. The Great Lakes Basin advisory council; convening.\n    1. Not later than three months after the effective date of this\nsection, the commissioner shall convene the Great Lakes Basin advisory\ncouncil pursuant to section 21-0917 of this article.\n  2. The advisory council shall be convened for the purpose of\ndeveloping recommendations for legislation, regulations or rules that\nare necessary to implement and effectuate the requirements and purposes\nof the Compact. The recommendations shall include, but shall not be\nlimited to the following:\n  a. the evaluation and recommendations of the threshold levels to be\nincluded in the implementing legislation regulation or rules for\nregulating new or increased water withdrawals in the state;\n  b. the establishment of a permitting program or alternative programs\nin order to meet the water management objectives of this state;\n  c. the development of the state's water conservation and efficiency\nprograms;\n  d. the method for establishing the baseline for determining a new or\nincreased diversion, consumptive use, or withdrawal pursuant to Section\n4.12.2 of the Compact; and\n  e. the collection and application of scientific information to improve\nunderstanding of the waters of the Great Lakes Basin and the impacts of\nwithdrawals and diversions.\n  3. The advisory council shall present its final recommendations to the\ngovernor and the legislature not later than eighteen months after the\neffective date of this section.\n  4. The department shall not adopt any rule or regulation pursuant to\nthe Compact prior to advisory council issuing its final recommendations\nto the governor and the legislature.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>