<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1703"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1703"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="21-1703"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-21-1703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_1703">
        <num>21-1703</num>
        <heading>Force and effect of the compact</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 21-1703. Force and effect of the compact.\n  Upon its signature by the respective governors on behalf of at least\nthe state of New Jersey and the commonwealth of Pennsylvania and by the\nGovernor on behalf of the state of New York, and upon the attestation\nthereof by the secretary of state of each of the signatory states and\ncommonwealth and the affixing thereto of the seal of each of the said\nstates and commonwealth, and the aforesaid compact, which may be known\nand cited as the Delaware basin compact, shall be and become binding and\nshall have the force and effect of a statute of the state of New York,\nand the Delaware river basin water commission shall thereupon become\nvested with all the powers, rights and privileges, and be subject to the\nduties and obligations, contained in said compact as though the same\nwere specifically authorized and imposed by statute, and the state of\nNew York shall be bound by all of the obligations assumed by it under\nsaid compact; and the Governor shall transmit an original signed copy\nthereof to the Secretary of State of the state of New York for filing in\nhis office.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>