<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23-0311"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0311/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0311/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23_0311">
        <num>23-0311</num>
        <heading>New York state oil, gas and solution mining advisory board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 23-0311. New York state oil, gas and solution mining advisory board.\n  1. A thirteen member New York state oil, gas and solution mining\nadvisory board shall be created within the department to advise and\nassist the commissioner and other state agencies on activities and\npolicies related to the development, operation and regulation of the\noil, gas and solution mining industry. The members shall be appointed by\nthe governor, with a majority representative of the respective\nindustries. Three of the members shall be appointed upon recommendation\nof the majority leader of the senate and three of the members shall be\nappointed upon recommendation of the speaker of the assembly.\nAppointments shall be made for three-year terms. Members shall continue\nin office until their successors have been appointed and qualified. The\ngovernor shall select a chair from among the members. The board shall\nmeet at least twice yearly and the members shall receive reimbursement\nfor expenses. The department shall provide the board with secretarial\nservices.\n  2. The chair of the public service commission, the president of the\nNew York state energy research and development authority, the state\ngeologist, and the commissioner shall serve the board in an ex-officio\ncapacity.\n  3. The commissioner shall seek the views of the board on matters\nwithin their scope of concern and shall specifically request the board's\nparticipation at an early developmental stage of any new rules,\nregulations and policies being contemplated or developed. In addition to\nsuch other duties as the commissioner may suggest or the board on its\nown volition may choose to undertake, the board shall:\n  a. Review and comment on the criteria to be used by the department in\nselecting abandoned wells for plugging or replugging.\n  b. Review and comment on proposed rules and regulations and department\nactivities affecting the industry.\n  c. Recommend to the governor, the commissioner, and other state\nagencies program directions or modifications related to the development,\noperation, and regulation of the oil, gas, and solution mining industry.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>