<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23-0503"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23_0503">
        <num>23-0503</num>
        <heading>Well spacing in oil and natural gas pools and fields</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_23_0503__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a description and a map of\nthe proposed alternative spacing unit; (ii) a technical justification of\nthe proposed alternative spacing unit, which shall include a description\nand analysis of the scientific data intended by the owner to support its\nproposed spacing unit configuration; and (iii) the name, address and\nexperience of any expert witness proposed to support the proposed\nalternative spacing unit configuration. The department may request the\nowner challenging the spacing unit to present its scientific data to the\ndepartment.\n  d. The department shall determine whether substantive and significant\nissues have been raised. If the department receives no comments or if\nthe comments do not raise a substantive and significant issue, the\ndepartment shall issue the permit and the final spacing order. If the\ndepartment determines that substantive and significant issues have been\nraised in a timely manner, the department shall schedule an adjudicatory\nhearing.\n  4. The department may issue permits to drill infill wells on a\nreasonably uniform pattern within the spacing unit after an integration\norder has been issued, if required, and only if it determines that\ndrilling infill wells is necessary to satisfy the policy objectives of\nsection 23-0301 of this article. The distances from the unit boundaries\nset forth in paragraph b of subdivision 1 of section 23-0501 of this\ntitle shall apply to any infill wells. For purposes of this section, new\nlateral wellbores drilled from the original wellbore in the unit are not\nconsidered infill wells if they are drilled prior to the first product\nsales from the original surface location. In a spacing unit established\npursuant to clause (vi) of subparagraph 1 of paragraph b of subdivision\n1 of section 23-0501 of this title, infill wells shall be deemed\nnecessary, and the number of infill wells required to satisfy the policy\nobjectives of section 23-0301 of this article must be drilled within\nthree years of t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>