<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1707"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1707"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23-1707"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1707/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1707/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23_1707">
        <num>23-1707</num>
        <heading>Environmental safety permit; siting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 23-1707. Environmental safety permit; siting.\n  No person shall commence the preparation of a site for, or begin the\nconstruction of, a liquefied natural or petroleum gas storage or\nconversion facility in the state without having first obtained an\nenvironmental safety permit issued with respect to such facility or\nactivity by the commissioner pursuant to this title. Any such facility\nwith respect to which a permit is issued shall not thereafter be built,\nmaintained or operated, and any such activity with respect to which a\npermit is issued, shall not be carried out, except in conformity with\nsuch permit and any terms, limitations or conditions contained therein;\nprovided that nothing herein shall exempt such facility from compliance\nwith state law and regulations thereunder or with municipal laws and\nregulations thereunder not inconsistent with the provisions of such\npermit. A permit may be transferred, subject to the approval of the\ncommissioner, to a person who agrees to comply with the terms,\nlimitations and conditions contained therein. This section shall not\napply to a liquefied natural or petroleum gas storage or conversion\nfacility in actual use and operation on September first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-six.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>