<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1903"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1903"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-02-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23-1903"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1903/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1903/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23_1903">
        <num>23-1903</num>
        <heading>Imposition of oil, gas and solution mining regulation and reclamation fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 23-1903. Imposition of oil, gas and solution mining regulation and\n             reclamation fees.\n  1. When a permit is granted to a person by the department pursuant to\nsection 23-0305 of this article to drill a well or when a person\nconverts a well to one subject to the oil, gas and solution mining law,\nsuch person shall pay to the department:\n  a. A one hundred dollar fee to be credited to the oil and gas account\nestablished under chapter fifty-eight of the laws of nineteen hundred\neighty-two; and\n  b. A fee in accordance with the depth drilled or expected to be\ndrilled as set forth below:\n     0-  500ft. - $  190\n   501- 1000ft. - $  380\n  1001- 1500ft. - $  570\n  1501- 2000ft. - $  760\n  2001- 2500ft. - $  950\n  2501- 3000ft. - $1,140\n  3001- 3500ft. - $1,330\n  3501- 4000ft. - $1,520\n  4001- 4500ft. - $1,710\n  4501- 5000ft. - $1,900\n  5001- 5500ft. - $2,090\n  5501- 6000ft. - $2,280\n  6001- 6500ft. - $2,470\n  6501- 7000ft. - $2,660\n  7001- 7500ft. - $2,850\n  7501- 8000ft. - $3,040\n  8001- 8500ft. - $3,230\n  8501- 9000ft. - $3,420\n  9001- 9500ft. - $3,610\n  9501-10,000ft.- $3,800\n  over 10,000ft.- $3,800 plus $190 for each incremental 500\n  feet of depth over 10,000 feet.\n  A person who has paid the fees described shall not be required to pay\nany additional fee for a well conversion.  The fee for well deepening\npermits pertaining to wells for which a well drilling permit was issued\nafter August twenty-fifth, nineteen hundred eighty-one, shall be\ncalculated on the basis of the additional depth drilled.\n  In the event the actual depth drilled exceeds the depth expected to be\ndrilled, an additional amount shall be paid such that the total fee paid\nshall be in accordance with the schedule set forth in this paragraph.\n  2. Upon requesting from the department any determination under the\nNatural Gas Policy Act, such person shall pay a fifty dollar fee per\nwell for each such determination.\n  3. The department shall have the authority to establish reasonable\nfees by rule for closed-loop boreholes deeper than five hundred feet\nbelow the earth's surface pursuant to subdivision fifteen of section\n23-0305 of this article to be credited to the oil and gas account\nestablished under chapter fifty-eight of the laws of nineteen hundred\neighty-two for the purposes of environmental protection or greenhouse\ngas emission reduction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>