<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1713"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1713"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23-1713"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1713/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1713/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1713/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-23-1713/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23_1713">
        <num>23-1713</num>
        <heading>Transportation of liquefied natural and petroleum gas; certified routes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 23-1713. Transportation of liquefied natural and petroleum gas;\n             certified routes.\n  1. Except for transportation by navigable waterways, all intrastate\ntransportation of liquefied natural and petroleum gas in its cryogenic\nstate must be along established routes in accordance with a schedule\nfiled with the department, and approved in accordance with this section.\n  2. The department of transportation in consultation with the\ndepartment of environmental conservation shall establish criteria for\nthe safe transportation of such liquefied natural and petroleum gas.\nSuch criteria shall take into consideration the proximity of the route\nor routes to contiguous populations, the capability of municipal fire\ndepartments to protect communities and contiguous populations against\nfire cloud damage attendant upon vapor release of the gas from its\ncryogenic state due to accident or malfunction in equipment, and the\nrisk of further accident related thereto and conflagration attendant\nupon its ignition. Such department's criteria shall be no less\nrestrictive than existing federal regulations. Such department shall\nwithin one year from the effective date of this section, adopt\nregulations prescribing the forms and procedures to be followed, which\nshall include notice to all affected municipal police and fire\ndepartments, for the certification of routes to be used for the safe\nintrastate transportation of such liquefied natural and petroleum gas.\n  3. The department of transportation in consultation with the\ndepartment of environmental conservation shall maintain a map of\ncertified routes for the intrastate transportation of such liquefied\nnatural and petroleum gas. In order to have a route certified under this\nsection, any person proposing to undertake intrastate transportation of\nsuch liquefied natural or petroleum gas shall file with such department\nthe proposed transportation route, subject to approval as herein\nprovided.\n  4. Upon application therefor, and before certifying a route for\nintrastate transportation of such liquefied natural or petroleum gas\nunder subdivision three, the department of transportation shall hold a\npublic hearing and shall render a decision with respect thereto in\naccordance with the requirements of section 23-1711, and, to the extent\napplicable, section 23-1709. In addition, upon route certification, such\nlimitations as are appropriate for safety purposes shall be established\nby such department for each such certified route, and the department,\nfurther, shall establish procedure and notice requirements for the\nparticular route, in accordance with subdivision two hereof, to be given\nto all affected municipal police and fire departments, to assure\nadequate notice to all affected municipalities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>