<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="24-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-24-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_24_0107">
        <num>24-0107</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lands and submerged lands commonly called marshes, swamps,\nsloughs, bogs, and flats supporting aquatic or semi-aquatic vegetation\nof the following types:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>wetland trees, which depend upon seasonal or permanent flooding or\nsufficiently water-logged soils to give them a competitive advantage\nover other trees; including, among others, red maple (Acer rubrum),\nwillows (Salix spp.), black spruce (Picea mariana); swamp white oak\n(Quercus bicolor), red ash (Fraxinus pennsylvanica), black ash (Fraxinus\nnigra), silver maple (Acer saccharinum), American elm (Ulmus americana),\nand Larch (Larix laricina);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>wetland shrubs, which depend upon seasonal or permanent flooding\nor sufficiently water-logged soils to give them a competitive advantage\nover other shrubs; including, among others, alder (Alnus spp.),\nbuttonbush (Cephalanthus occidentalis), bog rosemary (Andromeda\nglaucophylla), dogwoods (Cornus spp.), and leatherleaf (Chamaedaphne\ncalyculata);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>emergent vegetation, including, among others, cattails (Typha\nspp.), pickerelweed (Pontederia cordata), bulrushes (Scirpus spp.),\narrow arum (Peltandra virginica), arrowheads (Sagittaria spp.), reed\n(Phragmites communis), wildrice (Zizania aquatica), bur-reeds\n(Sparganium spp.), purple loosetrife (Lythrum salicaria), swamp\nloosestrife (Decodon verticillatus); and water plantain (Alisma\nplantago-aquatica);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>rooted, floating-leaved vegetation; including, among others,\nwater-lily (Nymphaea odorata), water shield (Brasenia schreberi), and\nspatterdock (Nuphar spp.);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>free-floating vegetation; including, among others, duckweed (Lemna\nspp.), big duckweed (Spirodela polyrhiza), and watermeal (Wolffia spp.);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>wet meadow vegetation, which depends upon seasonal or permanent\nflooding or sufficiently water-logged soils to give it a competitive\nadvantage over other open land vegetation; including, among others,\nsedges (Carex spp.), rushes (Juncus spp.), cattails (Typha spp.), rice\ncut-grass (Leersia oryzoides), reed canary grass (Phalaris arundinacea),\nswamp loosestrife (Decodon verticillatus), and spikerush (Eleocharis\nspp.);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>bog mat vegetation; including, among others, sphagnum mosses\n(Sphagnum spp.), bog rosemary (Andromeda glaucophylla), leatherleaf\n(Chamaedaphne calyculata), pitcher plant (Sarracenia purpurea), and\ncranberries (Vaccinium macrocarpon and V. oxycoccos);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>submergent vegetation; including, among others, pondweeds\n(Potamogeton spp.), naiads (Najas spp.), bladderworts (Utricularia\nspp.), wild celery (Vallisneria americana), coontail (Ceratophyllum\ndemersum), water milfoils (Myriophyllum spp.), muskgrass (Chara spp.),\nstonewort (Nitella spp.), water weeds (Elodea spp.), and water smartweed\n(Polygonum amphibium);\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lands and submerged lands containing remnants of any vegetation\nthat is not aquatic or semi-aquatic that has died because of wet\nconditions over a sufficiently long period, provided that such wet\nconditions do not exceed a maximum seasonal water depth of six feet and\nprovided further that such conditions can be expected to persist\nindefinitely, barring human intervention;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>lands and waters substantially enclosed by aquatic or semi-aquatic\nvegetation as set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision or by dead\nvegetation as set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the\nregulation of which is necessary to protect and preserve the aquatic and\nsemi-aquatic vegetation; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the waters overlying the areas set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision and the lands underlying paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision.\n  2. "Freshwater wetlands map" shall mean a map developed by the\ndepartment pursuant to section 24-0301 of this article on which are\nindicated the boundaries of any freshwater wetlands. Freshwater wetland\nmaps depict the approximate location of wetlands and are not necessarily\ndeterminative as to whether a permit is required pursuant to section\n24-0701 of this article.\n  3. "Boundaries of a freshwater wetland" shall mean the outer limit of\nthe vegetation specified in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nthis section and of the lands and waters specified in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsuch subdivision.\n  4. "Local government" shall mean a village, town, city, or county.\n  5. "State agency" shall mean any state department, bureau, commission,\nboard or other agency, public authority or public benefit corporation.\n  6. "Person" means any corporation, firm, partnership, association,\ntrust, estate, one or more individuals, and any unit of government or\nagency or subdivision thereof, including the state.\n  7. "Board" shall mean the freshwater wetland appeals board.\n  8. "Pollution" shall mean the presence in the environment of\nhuman-induced conditions, or contaminants in quantities or\ncharacteristics which are or may be injurious to human, plant or\nwildlife, or other animal life or to property.\n  9. "Unusual importance" shall mean a freshwater wetland, regardless of\nsize, that possesses one or more of the following characteristics as\ndetermined by the department pursuant to regulations:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it is located in a watershed that has experienced significant\nflooding in the past, or is expected to experience significant flooding\nin the future from severe storm events related to climate change;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it is located within or adjacent to an urban area, as defined by\nthe United States census bureau;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it contains a plant species occurring in fewer than thirty-five\nsites statewide or having fewer than five thousand individuals\nstatewide;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it contains habitat for an essential behavior of an endangered or\nthreatened species or a species of special concern as defined under\nsection 11-0535 of this chapter or listed as a species of greatest\nconservation need in New York's wildlife action plan;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it is classified by the department as a Class I wetland;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it was previously classified and mapped by the department as a\nwetland of unusual local importance;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it is a vernal pool that is known to be productive for amphibian\nbreeding;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it is located in an area designated as a floodway on the most\ncurrent Digital Flood Insurance Rate Map (DFIRM) produced by the Federal\nEmergency Management Agency;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it was previously mapped by the department as a wetland on or\nbefore December thirty-first, two thousand twenty-four;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it has wetland functions and values that are of local or regional\nsignificance; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_24_0107__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it is determined by the commissioner to be of significant\nimportance to protecting the state's water quality.\n  10. "Delineation" shall mean a precise representation of a regulated\nfreshwater wetland as defined in subdivision one of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>