<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0911"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0911"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-0911"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0911/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-0911/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_0911">
        <num>27-0911</num>
        <heading>Standards applicable to owners and operators of hazardous waste treatment, storage, and disposal facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-0911. Standards applicable to owners and operators of hazardous\n             waste treatment, storage, and disposal facilities.\n  1. Standards applicable to owners and operators of hazardous waste\ntreatment, storage and disposal facilities shall be those established in\ntitle seven of this article, and the regulations promulgated thereunder,\nshall be consistent with comparable standards promulgated by the\nadministrator pursuant to RCRA, and shall also include compliance with\nthe manifest system established in section 27-0905 of this title. Where\nappropriate and consistent with the provisions of RCRA, such standards\nmay authorize the granting of exemptions from requirements, or variances\nin requirements, according to criteria established therein.\n  2. Such standards shall require corrective action, including\ncorrective action beyond the facility boundary where necessary to\nprotect human health and the environment, for all releases of hazardous\nwaste or constituents from any solid waste management unit at a\ntreatment, storage or disposal facility seeking a permit under section\n27-0913 of this title, regardless of the time at which waste was placed\nin such unit.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>