<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1420"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1420"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1420"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1420/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1420/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1420/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1420/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1420">
        <num>27-1420</num>
        <heading>Brownfield cleanup program report</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1420. Brownfield cleanup program report.\n  1. The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of taxation\nand finance, shall prepare on or before April thirtieth of each year, a\nreport concerning the brownfield cleanup program which contains the\nfollowing information for the preceding fiscal year:\n  a. the number of requests for participation received by the\ndepartment;\n  b. the number of remedial investigations commenced, and the number of\nremedial investigations completed;\n  c. the number of requests for participation withdrawn or terminated\nprior to issuance of certificate of completion;\n  d. for each request for participation that resulted in a certificate\nof completion, the length of time from the date the department received\nthe request, to the date the commissioner issues the certificate of\ncompletion;\n  e. the total number of certificates of completion issued; and\n  f. such other information as the commissioner may determine is\nrelevant to the status of the administration of the program.\n  2. Copies of this report shall be submitted to the governor, the\ndirector of the budget, the temporary president of the senate, the\nspeaker of the assembly, the chair of the senate finance committee, the\nchair of the assembly ways and means committee and the New York\nbrownfields advisory board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>