<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1313"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1313"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1313"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1313/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1313/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1313/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1313/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1313">
        <num>27-1313</num>
        <heading>Remedial programs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1313__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to delegate such\nresponsibility for a specific site to the municipality in which such\nsite is located and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1313__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to contract with the environmental facilities\ncorporation and any other person to perform necessary work in connection\nwith such sites.\n  3. a. Whenever the commissioner finds that hazardous wastes at an\ninactive hazardous waste disposal site constitute a significant threat\nto the environment, he may order the owner of such site and/or any\nperson responsible for the disposal of hazardous wastes at such site</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1313__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nto develop an inactive hazardous waste disposal site remedial program,\nsubject to the approval of the department, at such site, and (ii) to\nimplement such program within reasonable time limits specified in the\norder. Provided, however, that in the event the commissioner of health\nshall issue an order pursuant to subdivision three of section one\nthousand three hundred eighty-nine-b of the public health law, such\norder of the commissioner of health shall supersede any order issued\nhereunder.\n  b. Whenever the commissioner, after investigation, finds:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1313__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that hazardous wastes at an inactive hazardous waste disposal site\nconstitutes a significant threat to the environment; and\n  (ii) that such threat is causing or presents an imminent danger of\ncausing irreversible or irreparable damage to the environment; and\n  (iii) the threat makes it prejudicial to the public interest to delay\naction until a hearing can be held pursuant to this title, the\ndepartment may, pursuant to paragraph c of subdivision five of this\nsection and within the funds available to the department, develop and\nimplement an inactive hazardous waste disposal site remedial program for\nsuch site. Findings required pursuant to this paragraph shall be in\nwriting and may be made by the commissioner on an ex parte basis subject\nto judicial review.\n  4. Any order issued pursuant to subdivision three of this section\nshall be issued only after notice and the opportunity for a hearing is\nprovided to persons who may be the subject of such order. The\ncommissioner shall determine which persons are responsible pursuant to\nsaid subdivision according to applicable principles of statutory or\ncommon law liability. Such persons shall be entitled to raise any\nstatutory or common law defense at any such hearing and such defenses\nshall have the same force and effect at such hearings as they would have\nin a court of law. In the event a hearing is held, no order shall be\nissued by the commissioner under subdivision three of this section until\na final decision has been rendered. Any such order shall be reviewable\npursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice law and rules\nwithin thirty days after service of such order. The commissioner may\nrequest the participation of the attorney general in such hearings.\n  5. a. Whenever a person ordered to eliminate a threat to the\nenvironment pursuant to paragraph a of subdivision three of this section\nhas failed to do so within the time limits specified in the order, the\ndepartment may develop and i...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1313__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever the commissioner has made findings pursuant to\nparagraph b of subdivision three of this section or the commissioner of\nhealth has made a declaration and finding pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1313__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of section one thousand three hundred eighty-nine-b of\nthe public health law, the department may develop and implement an\ninactive hazardous waste disposal site remedial program to contain,\nalleviate or end the threat to life or health or to the environment. The\ncosts incurred by the department in developing and implementing such a\nprogram shall be in an amount commensurate with the actions the\ndepartment deems necessary to eliminate such danger. In determining the\nscope, nature and content of such program, the department shall consider\namong others, the following factors:\n  (A) the technological feasibility of all actions;\n  (B) the nature of the danger to human health and the environment which\nthe actions are designed to address; and\n  (C) the extent to which the actions would reduce such danger to human\nhealth or the environment or would otherwise benefit human health or the\nenvironment, including if the actions would benefit a disadvantaged\ncommunity.\n  (ii) In implementing this title, the department shall consult with\nappropriate representatives of Indian nations on environmental and\ncultural resource issues related to this title of concern to either the\ndepartment or Indian nations.\n  d. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision c of this section,\nthe department shall be authorized to develop and implement an inactive\nhazardous waste disposal site remedial program at the site pursuant to\nthis subdivision if, in the discretion of the department, it is\ncost-effective for the department to develop and implement such a\nremedial program. The goal of any such remedial program shall be a\ncomplete cleanup of the site through the elimination of the significant\nthreat to the environment posed by the disposal of hazardous wastes at\nthe site and of the imminent danger of irreversible or irreparable\ndamage to the environment caused by such disposal. The factors to be\nconsidered by the department in determining whether...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_27_1313__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the ability of the department to determine, through the exercise\nof its scientific judgment, whether the elimination of the imminent\ndanger of irreversible or irreparable damage to the environment can be\nachieved through limited actions;\n  (ii) the ability of the department to identify the owner of the site\nand/or any person responsible for the disposal of hazardous wastes at\nsuch site with sufficient financial resources to develop and implement\nan inactive hazardous waste disposal site remedial program at such site;\n  (iii) the nature of the danger to human health and the environment\nwhich the actions are designed to address; and\n  (iv) the extent to which the actions would reduce such danger to human\nhealth or the environment or would otherwise benefit human health or the\nenvironment.\n  e. Whenever the commissioner of health makes a declaration and finding\npursuant to paragraph b of subdivision three of section one thousand\nthree hundred eighty-nine-b of the public health law, the department may\nimplement an inactive hazardous waste site remedial program in the same\nmanner as specified in paragraphs c and d of this subdivision.\n  f. The commissioner shall make every effort, in accordance with the\nrequirements for notice, hearing and review provided for in this title\nto secure appropriate relief from the owner or operator of such site\nand/or any person responsible for the disposal of hazardous wastes at\nsuch site, including, but not limited to, response costs, natural\nresource damages, and penalties.\n  g. When a municipality develops and implements pursuant to an\nagreement with the department an inactive hazardous waste disposal site\nremedial program as approved by the department for a site which is owned\nor has been operated by such municipality or when the department,\npursuant to an agreement with a municipality, develops and implements\nsuch a remedial program, the commissioner shall, in the name of the\nstate, agree in such agreement...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>