<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1113"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1113"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1113"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1113">
        <num>27-1113</num>
        <heading>Community advisory committees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1113. Community advisory committees.\n  1. In addition to any authority conferred by any other provision of\nlaw, a county within which an industrial hazardous waste treatment,\nstorage and disposal facility subject to this title is to be situated,\nshall constitute a committee for the purpose of entering into a dialogue\nwith the applicant to develop mutually acceptable solutions to problems\nwhich may be created by the siting of the facility in the community.\n  2. The committee shall have no fewer than nine and no more than\nfifteen members. No more than one-third of the members shall be\ndesignated by the chief executive officer, or if none, the chairman of\nthe county legislative body, of the affected county. No less than\ntwo-thirds of the members shall be designated by the chief executive\nofficer of the affected city, town or village as the case may be,\nprovided however, if the proposed facility is located in more than one\ncity, town or village, the chief executive officer of such cities,\ntowns, or villages shall have the authority to appoint an equal number\nof members to the local advisory committee, the total of which shall not\nbe less than two-thirds of such committee.\n  3. The members of the committee shall be deemed employees of the\npublic entity by which they were respectively designated for purposes of\nsection eighteen of the public officers law.\n  4. Within fifteen days after receipt of notification of the\nconstitution of a community advisory committee, the chairman of the\nboard or his designee shall convene and preside over a conference\nbetween the applicant and such committee. The chairman of the facility\nsiting board or his designee shall endeavor to foster a dialogue between\nthe applicant and the committee, and to that end, shall convene and\npreside over such additional conferences as may be necessary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>