<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1207"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1207">
        <num>27-1207</num>
        <heading>Use and reporting of the solid waste mitigation program and the drinking water response program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1207. Use and reporting of the solid waste mitigation program and\n             the drinking water response program.\n  1. Pursuant to the clean water infrastructure act of two thousand\nseventeen and within the up to one hundred thirty million dollars\nappropriated for such purposes, mitigation and remediation efforts to\naddress public drinking water contamination from emerging contaminants\nand solid waste sites causing or substantially contributing to drinking\nwater impairment that impacts public health may be conducted in\naccordance with this title.\n  2. The solid waste mitigation program shall receive no more than fifty\nmillion dollars from the clean water infrastructure act of 2017 and be\nmade available to the department and the department of health, as\napplicable, for the following purposes:\n  a. enumeration and assessment of solid waste sites;\n  b. investigation and environmental characterization of solid waste\nsites, including environmental sampling;\n  c. mitigation and remediation of solid waste sites;\n  d. monitoring of solid waste sites; and\n  e. administration and enforcement of the requirements of section\n27-1203 of this title.\n  3. The drinking water response program shall receive no more than\ntwenty million dollars annually from the clean water infrastructure act\nof 2017 and be made available to the department and the department of\nhealth, as applicable, for the following purposes:\n  a. mitigation of drinking water contamination;\n  b. investigation of drinking water contamination;\n  c. remediation of drinking water contamination; and\n  d. administration and enforcement of the requirements of this title\nexcept the provisions of section 27-1203.\n  4. On or before July first, two thousand nineteen and July first of\neach succeeding year, the department shall report on the status of the\nprograms. Such status report shall reflect information available to the\ndepartment as of March thirty-first of each year, and shall include\ninformation regarding the number of sites referred to the inactive\nhazardous waste disposal site remedial program based on information\nobtained pursuant to this title and an accounting of all monies expended\nor encumbered from the clean water infrastructure act of two thousand\nseventeen during the preceding fiscal year, such accounting to\nseparately list:\n  a. monies expended or encumbered for the purpose of conducting site\ninvestigations;\n  b. monies expended or encumbered for the purpose of conducting\nremedial investigations and feasibility studies;\n  c. monies expended for mitigation and remediation measures; and\n  d. an accounting of payments received and payments obligated to be\nreceived pursuant to this title, and a report of the department's\nattempts to secure such obligations.\n  5. all moneys recovered pursuant to title twelve of article\ntwenty-seven of this chapter shall be deposited into the capital\nprojects fund (30000), provided that such moneys recovered shall be used\nfor the same purposes as are authorized by this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>