<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1433"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1433"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1433"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1433/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1433/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1433/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1433/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1433">
        <num>27-1433</num>
        <heading>Waiver of interest or penalties or other charges on brownfield properties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1433. Waiver of interest or penalties or other charges on\n             brownfield properties.\n  Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the governing\nbody of any tax district shall be authorized, by resolution, to permit\nthe enforcing officer to effect the cancellation in whole or in part of\nany interest, penalties or other charges on real property where such\nreal property is subject to the brownfield site clean-up agreement\nentered into by a volunteer pursuant to section 27-1409 of this title.\nProvided, however, that in cases where such interest, penalties, or\nother charges, if collected by a tax district, belong to a municipal\ncorporation within such tax district, no reduction or remission in whole\nor in part of such interest, penalties, or other charges shall be made\nwithout the consent of the municipal corporation affected, which consent\nmay be given by resolution adopted after a public hearing. Failure of\nsuch real property to receive a certificate of completion pursuant to\nsection 27-1419 of this title or revocation of such certificate shall be\ngrounds for revocation of any waiver of interest, penalties, or charges\ngranted pursuant to this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>