<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="27-1307"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-27-1307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_27_1307">
        <num>27-1307</num>
        <heading>Reports to the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 27-1307. Reports to the department.\n  1. In order to facilitate the department's efforts to secure\ninformation about inactive hazardous waste disposal sites in the state,\nany person shall, upon the request of the department, furnish to the\ndepartment, in a form and manner prescribed by the department, the\nfollowing information:\n  a. The name and location of facilities within the state that have\ngenerated significant quantities of hazardous wastes or sites within the\nstate which have received wastes which are now or were formerly owned or\noperated by such person or to or from which such person has transported\nsuch wastes;\n  b. A description of current and past waste generating and disposal\nactivities at facilities identified pursuant to paragraph a of this\nsubdivision which have generated hazardous wastes including products\nmanufactured or services provided, generic type of processes used in the\nmanufacturing of products or provision of services, the type and annual\nquantity of hazardous wastes generated in significant quantities, the\nlocations of all sites used for the disposal of wastes generated by such\nfacilities, the years of use of such sites for the disposal of wastes,\nthe type and quantity of waste disposed of at such sites and the manner\nof disposal of hazardous wastes at such sites;\n  c. A description of current and past waste disposal activities at\nsites identified pursuant to paragraph a of this subdivision which have\nreceived wastes including years of use of such sites for the disposal of\nwastes, type and quantity of all hazardous wastes disposed of at such\nsites and the manner of disposal of hazardous wastes at such sites;\n  d. With respect to each site identified pursuant to paragraphs a and b\nof this subdivision, names of persons that have transported hazardous\nwastes to such sites, a description of any testing, monitoring or\nremedial actions undertaken or planned at such sites and any significant\nhealth or environmental problems known or suspected to exist at such\nsites; and\n  e. Any other information that the department may deem necessary to\nprepare the state inactive hazardous waste remedial plan or the registry\nrequired by section 27-1305 of this article.\n  2. In the event the person furnishing such information cannot fully\ncomply with the request for information, such person shall set forth his\nefforts to comply with such request.\n  3. Any information submitted to the department shall be considered a\n"written instrument" as defined in subdivision three of section 175.00\nof the penal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>