<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-02-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29-0701"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_0701">
        <num>29-0701</num>
        <heading>Financial requirements for low-level radioactive waste disposal facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_0701__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Trust funds.\n  (ii) Surety or performance bonds.\n  (iii) Letters of credit.\n  (iv) Liability insurance or annuities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_29_0701__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Guarantees provided by corporate or other legal or financial\naffiliates of the facility owner or operator.\n  c. Establish the duration of such financial requirements.\n  2. Any owner or operator of such a facility for the management of\nlow-level radioactive waste may request a modification of any of the\nfinancial requirements established pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection. A modification may be granted in the discretion of the\ndepartment if such financial requirements are found to be unnecessary or\ninappropriate, consistent with the public interest and the purposes of\nthis section and supported by written findings setting forth the reasons\nfor the modification. Such a modification request shall be considered a\nrequest for modification of the permit for the facility.  In no case\nshall a modification granted pursuant to this subdivision eliminate or\nreduce the minimum requirements established in subdivision four of this\nsection.\n  3. In addition to the financial requirements established pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section, any permits for such facilities for the\nmanagement of low-level radioactive waste issued by the department may,\nif it is determined that adequate protection of the public so requires,\ninclude conditions related to any or all of the following, including\nresponsibility for the costs thereof:\n  a. On-site environmental monitors whose function shall be to monitor\ncompliance with permit conditions. The commissioner may promulgate\nregulations regarding the use of such monitors.\n  b. Site safety plans whereby the permittee shall establish, with the\ncooperation of local government officials, a community and project\nsafety plan, including but not limited to an accident response based on\na worst-case condition, on-site and off-site, a personnel training\nprogram, provisions for coordination with local emergency services and\nregular training exercises. Any such plan shall be subject to the\napproval of the department...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>