<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29-0301"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_0301">
        <num>29-0301</num>
        <heading>Appointment of the commission</heading>
        <content>
          <p>* ยง 29-0301. Appointment of the commission.\n  1. There is hereby created a commission for siting low-level\nradioactive waste disposal facilities. The commission shall consist of\nseven members appointed by the governor whose appointment shall be\neffective when issued. The members of the commission, to the extent\npracticable, shall be competent and knowledgeable concerning low-level\nradioactive waste and shall be qualified as follows:\n  a. a geologist;\n  b. a medical doctor;\n  c. a health physicist;\n  d. a professional engineer;\n  e. a social scientist;\n  f. an environmentalist who represents a non-profit environmental\norganization;\n  g. a private citizen who shall be designated to act as chairperson.\n  2. The chairperson shall appoint an executive director to the\ncommission.\n  3. In the event of resignation of one of the commission members, the\ngovernor shall appoint a replacement. Each member shall receive the sum\nof two hundred dollars for each day in which the member is actually and\nprimarily engaged in the performance of the duties specified herein plus\nactual and necessary expenses incurred by such member in the performance\nof such duties.\n  4. The members of the commission, the executive director and any\nemployees of the commission shall be considered public officers for\npurposes of the public officers law.\n  5. Four of the seven members of the commission shall constitute a\nquorum for the transaction of business of the commission and the\ndecision of four members of the commission shall constitute action of\nthe commission; provided, however, that no application for certification\npursuant to section 29-0105 of this article shall be made except upon\nthe affirmative vote of four or more members of the commission.\n  * NB Commission existence pursuant to ยง 29-0309\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>