<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29-0305"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-29-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29_0305">
        <num>29-0305</num>
        <heading>Operation of the commission</heading>
        <content>
          <p>* ยง 29-0305. Operation of the commission.\n  1. The commission may hire or contract with such persons as it deems\nnecessary, convenient, or desirable to carry out its duties pursuant to\nthis title.\n  2. Officers and employees of the commission shall be appointed in\naccordance with civil service rules; provided, however, that officers\nand employees of state departments and agencies may be transferred to\nthe commission without examination and without loss of any civil service\nstatus or rights. Each employee who is transferred pursuant to this\nsubdivision is deemed to be on leave of absence from his or her former\nposition during the tenure of the commission. No such transfer may,\nhowever, be made except with the approval of the head of the state\ndepartment or agency involved, the director of the budget and the\nchairman of the commission, and in compliance with the rules and\nregulations of the civil service commission of the state.\n  3. After the department has approved, pursuant to subdivision 2 of\nsection 29-0303 of this title, a preferred disposal method, the\ncommission, its employees, agents, consultants, or contractors may,\nafter proper notification and identification, enter at reasonable times\nupon such lands, waters or premises as in the judgment of the commission\nmay be necessary, convenient, or desirable for the purpose of making\nsurveys, soundings, borings, and examinations to accomplish any purposes\nauthorized by this title, the commission being liable for actual damage\ndone. Each such entry shall be commenced and completed with reasonable\npromptness. If the officer or employee obtains any samples prior to his\nleaving the premises, he shall give to the owner, operator, or agent in\ncharge a receipt describing the sample obtained and, if requested, a\nportion of each such sample equal in volume or weight to the portion\nretained. If any analysis is made of such samples, a copy of the results\nof such analysis shall be furnished promptly to the owner, operator, or\nagent in charge.\n  4. The commission shall require all computerized data generated by its\nstaff and contractors, when obtainable by the public pursuant to article\nsix of the public officers law, to be made available in a format that is\naccessible for general use.\n  * NB Commission existence pursuant to ยง 29-0309\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>