<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0305"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0305"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3-0305"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0305/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-3-0305/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3_0305">
        <num>3-0305</num>
        <heading>Acquirement of real property by purchase or appropriation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 3-0305. Acquirement of real property by purchase or appropriation.\n  1.  The commissioner when moneys therefor have been appropriated by\nthe legislature or are otherwise available, may acquire any real\nproperty which he deems necessary for any of the purposes or functions\nof the department, by purchase or as provided in the eminent domain\nprocedure law.  Title to such real property shall be taken in the name\nof and be vested in the people of the state of New York.  No real\nproperty shall be so acquired by purchase unless the title thereto is\napproved by the attorney general.  The terms "property" or "real\nproperty" as used in this section shall mean "real property" as defined\nby section one hundred three of the eminent domain procedure law.\n  2.  Whenever real property is to be so acquired pursuant to the\nprovisions of the eminent domain procedure law, by appropriation, the\ncommissioner shall cause to be made an accurate acquisition map as so\nprovided in said law.\n  3. On the approval of such map by the commissioner, the original\ntracing of map shall, pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law, be\nfiled in the main office of the department.\n  4. If the commissioner shall determine, prior to the filing of a copy\nof such acquisition map in the office of the county clerk, that changes,\nalterations or modifications of such map as filed in the main office of\nthe department should be made, he or she shall, subject to the\nprovisions of article two of the eminent domain procedure law, if\napplicable, direct the preparation of an amended map. On the approval of\nsuch amended map by the commissioner, it shall be filed in the main\noffice of the department in the same manner as the original map was\nfiled and the amended map shall thereupon in all respects and for all\npurposes supersede the map previously filed.\n  5. If the commissioner shall determine prior to filing a copy of an\nacquisition map in the office of the county clerk, as provided in\nsection four hundred two of the eminent domain procedure law, that such\nmap should be withdrawn, he or she shall file a certificate of\nwithdrawal in the offices of the department and of the department of\nlaw. Upon the filing of such certificate of withdrawal, the map to which\nit refers shall be cancelled and all rights thereunder shall cease and\ndetermine.\n  6.  The commissioner shall deliver to the attorney general a copy of\nsuch acquisition map, whereupon it shall be the duty of the attorney\ngeneral to advise and certify to the commissioner the names of the\nowners of the real property described in the said acquisition map,\nincluding the owners of any right, title or interest therein, pursuant\nto the requirements of section four hundred three of the eminent domain\nprocedure law.\n  7.  If, at or after the vesting of title to such property in the\npeople of the state of New York in the manner provided for in the\neminent domain procedure law, the commissioner shall deem it necessary\nto cause the removal of an owner or other  occupant from such property,\nhe may cause such owner or occupant to be removed therefrom by\nproceeding in accordance with section four hundred five of such law.\nThe proceeding shall be brought in the name of the commissioner as agent\nof the state and the attorney general shall represent the petitioner in\nthe proceedings.  No execution shall issue for costs, if any, awarded\nagainst the state or the commissioner, but they shall be part of the\ncosts of the acquisition of the real property and be paid in like\nmanner.  Proceedings may be brought separately against one or more of\nthe owners or occupants of any such property, or one proceeding may be\nbrought against all or several of the owners or occupants of any or all\nsuch property within the territorial jurisdiction of the same court,\njustice or judge; judgment shall be given for immediate removal of\npersons defaulting in appearance or in answering, or withdrawing their\nanswers, if any, without awaiting the trial or decision of issues raised\nby contestants, if any.\n  8.  Upon making any agreement provided for in section three hundred\nfour of the eminent domain procedure law, the commissioner shall deliver\nto the comptroller such agreement and a certificate stating the amount\ndue such owner or owners thereunder on account of such appropriation of\nhis or their property and the amount so fixed shall be paid out of the\nstate treasury after audit by the comptroller from moneys appropriated\nfor the acquisition of such real property, but not until there shall\nhave been filed with the comptroller a certificate of the attorney\ngeneral showing the person or persons claiming the amount so agreed upon\nto be legally entitled thereto.\n  9.  Application for reimbursement as provided in section seven hundred\ntwo of the eminent domain procedure law, shall be made to the\ncommissioner upon forms prescribed by him and shall be accompanied by\nsuch information and evidence as the commissioner may require.  Upon\napproval of such application, the commissioner shall deliver a copy\nthereof to the comptroller together with a certificate stating the\namount due thereof, and the amount so fixed shall be paid out of the\nstate treasury after audit by the comptroller from moneys appropriated\nfor the acquisition of property under this section.\n  10.  The commissioner with the approval of the director of the budget,\nshall establish and may from time to time amend rules and regulations\nauthorizing the payment of actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses of occupants of property acquired pursuant to this section; of\nactual direct losses of tangible personal property as a result of moving\nor discontinuing a business or farm operation, but not exceeding an\namount equal to the reasonable expenses that would have been required to\nrelocate such property, as determined by the commissioner; and actual\nreasonable expenses in searching for a replacement business or farm, or\nin hardship cases for the advance payment of such expenses and losses.\nFor the purposes of making payment of such expenses and losses only the\nterm "business" means any lawful activity conducted primarily for\nassisting in the purchase, sale, resale, manufacture, processing or\nmarketing of products, commodities, personal property or services by the\nerection and maintenance of an outdoor advertising display or displays,\nwhether or not such display or displays are located on the premises on\nwhich any of the above activities are conducted.  Such rules and\nregulations may further define the terms used in this subdivision.  In\nlieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving expenses, any such\ndisplaced owner or tenant of residential property may elect to accept a\nmoving expense allowance, plus a dislocation allowance, determined in\naccordance with a schedule prepared by the commissioner and made a part\nof such rules and regulations.  In lieu of such actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses, any such displaced owner or tenant of\ncommercial property who relocates or discontinues his business or farm\noperation may elect to accept a fixed relocation payment in an amount\nequal to the average annual net earnings of the business or farm\noperation, except that such payment shall be not less than two thousand\nfive hundred dollars nor more than ten thousand dollars.  In the case of\na business, no such fixed relocation payment shall be made unless the\ncommissioner finds and determines that the business cannot be relocated\nwithout a substantial loss of its existing patronage, and that the\nbusiness is not part of a commercial enterprise having at least one\nother establishment, which is not being acquired by the state or the\nUnited States, which is engaged in the same or similar business.  In the\ncase of a business which is to be discontinued but for which the\nfindings and determinations set forth above cannot be made, the\ncommissioner may prepare an estimate of what the actual reasonable and\nnecessary moving expenses, exclusive of any storage charges, would be if\nthe business were to be relocated and enter into an agreed settlement\nwith the owner of such business for an amount not to exceed such\nestimate in lieu of such actual reasonable and necessary moving\nexpenses.  Application for payment under this subdivision shall be made\nto the commissioner upon forms prescribed by him and shall be\naccompanied by such information and evidence as the commissioner may\nrequire.  Upon approval of such application, the commissioner shall\ndeliver a copy thereof to the comptroller together with a certificate\nstating the amount due thereunder, and the amount so fixed shall be paid\nout of the state treasury after audit by the comptroller from moneys\nappropriated for the acquisition of property under this section.  As\nused in this subdivision the term "commercial property" shall include\nproperty owned by an individual, family, partnership, corporation,\nassociation or a non-profit organization and includes a farm operation.\nAs used in this subdivision the term "business" means any lawful\nactivity, except a farm operation, conducted primarily for the purchase,\nsale, lease and rental of personal and real property, and for the\nmanufacture, processing, or marketing of products, commodities, or any\nother personal property; for the sale of services to the public; or by a\nnon-profit organization.\n  11.  The commissioner pursuant to section three hundred five of the\neminent domain procedure law, may make agreements on such terms,\ncondition and consideration as he deems beneficial to the state with\nrespect to any property heretofore or hereafter acquired, whereby such\nproperty may be used and occupied by the former owner, tenant or by any\nother party from a date specified in said agreement, until such time as\nthe state requires and obtains actual physical possession.  The\nagr</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>