<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="33-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_0103">
        <num>33-0103</num>
        <heading>Exemptions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 33-0103. Exemptions.\n  1. The provisions of subdivisions 1 through 5 inclusive of section\n33-0303 and titles 5, 7, 11, 13 and 15 of this article shall not apply\nto:\n  a. Any carrier while lawfully engaged in transporting a pesticide\nwithin this state, if such carrier shall, upon request, permit the\ncommissioner or his designated agent to copy all records showing the\ntransactions in and movement of the articles;\n  b. The manufacturer or shipper of a pesticide for experimental use\nonly:\n  (1) By or under the supervision of an agency of this state or of the\nfederal government authorized by law to conduct research in the field of\npesticides which has a valid experimental permit issued by the\ncommissioner, or\n  (2) By others having a valid experimental permit issued by the\ncommissioner if the pesticide is not sold and if the container thereof\nis plainly and conspicuously marked "For experimental use only--Not to\nbe sold," together with the manufacturer's name and address. However, if\nsuch a written permit has been obtained from the commissioner,\npesticides may be sold for experimental purposes subject to such\nrestrictions and conditions as may be set forth in the permit.\n  2. No article shall be deemed in violation of this article when\nintended solely for export to a foreign country, and when prepared or\npacked according to the specifications or directions of the purchaser.\nIf not so exported, all of the provisions of this article shall apply.\n  3. Notwithstanding any other provision of this article, registration\nis not required in the case of a pesticide shipped from one plant within\nthis state to another plant within this state operated by the same\nperson.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>