<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1201"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1201"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-06-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="33-1201"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1201/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1201/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_1201">
        <num>33-1201</num>
        <heading>Pesticide sales and use computer data base</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 33-1201. Pesticide sales and use computer data base.\n  1. a. The department shall develop a pesticide sales and use computer\ndata base. The data base shall be maintained at the department.\n  b. Such data base shall consist of all information compiled from\nreports submitted to the department pursuant to sections 33-1205 and\n33-1207 of this title. Such reports shall be entered into and maintained\non a computerized data base and shall be updated annually. Information\nobtained for and contained in the data base shall be accessible by\ninterested parties only to the extent permitted pursuant to the\nprovisions of subdivision two of this section and paragraph a of\nsubdivision 1 of section 33-1203 of this title.\n  2. The commissioner shall prepare an annual report summarizing\npesticide sales, quantity of pesticides used, category of applicator and\nregion of application. Pesticide data shall be compiled and reported by\nboth EPA registration number and by active ingredient. The commissioner\nshall not provide the name, address, or any other information which\nwould otherwise identify a commercial or private applicator, or any\nperson who sells or offers for sale restricted use or general use\npesticides to a private applicator, or any person who received the\nservices of a commercial applicator. In accordance with article six of\nthe public officers law, proprietary information contained within such\nrecord, including price charged per product, shall not be disclosed. The\nreport shall be posted on the department's website annually by December\nthirty-first and be submitted to the governor, the temporary president\nof the senate and the speaker of the assembly.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>