<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="33-1001"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_1001">
        <num>33-1001</num>
        <heading>Requirements and restrictions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 33-1001. Requirements and restrictions.\n  1. Prior to any commercial lawn application the applicator shall enter\ninto a written contract with the owner of the property or his or her\nagent specifying the approximate date or dates of application, number of\napplications, and total cost for the service to be provided.\n  2. Prior to any commercial lawn application the applicator shall\nsupply the property owner or his or her agent with a copy of:\n  a. a list of substances to be applied including brand names and\ngeneric names of active ingredients;\n  b. any warnings that appear on the label of pesticides to be applied\nthat are pertinent to the protection of humans, animals or the\nenvironment; and\n  c. the company name, address, telephone number, business registration\nnumber and applicator certification identification card number.\n  Such information shall be supplied in either a written, digital or\nelectronic format which shall be determined by the owner or his or her\nagent provided however that the applicator must also have a written copy\nof such information in his or her possession.\n  3. In the event that application on the date or dates specified\nbecomes infeasible, the person who is to provide such application shall\ngive the owner or his agent oral or written notice of the proposed\nalternate date or dates, and shall receive acceptance of such alternate\ndate or dates from the owner or his agent prior to initiating commercial\nlawn application.\n  4. Persons providing commercial lawn applications shall maintain\ncopies of all contracts required pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>