<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="33-1301"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_1301">
        <num>33-1301</num>
        <heading>Unlawful acts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name and address of the\nmanufacturer, registrant, or person for whom manufactured;\n  (ii) the name, brand, or trade-mark under which said article is sold;\nand\n  (iii) the net weight or measure of the content; subject, however, to\nsuch reasonable variations as the commissioner may permit; or\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>meets the requirements of subparagraph one of this paragraph\nexcept that the container has been accidently damaged during handling\nprior to sale and the damage has been repaired by such person in\naccordance with his or her own specific "minor repair program" approved\nby the United States environmental protection agency pursuant to its\nOctober ninth, two thousand nine pesticide container repair interim\npolicy. A copy of the approved program shall be forwarded to the\ndepartment within thirty days of approval and shall be kept at the\nperson's place of business and be available for department review upon\nrequest.\n  * NB Effective until July 1, 2026\n  * b. Except as specified in regulation authorizing alternative\npesticide containers, any pesticide unless it is in the registrant's or\nthe manufacturer's unbroken immediate container, and there is affixed to\nsuch container, and to the outside container or wrapper of the retail\npackage, if there be one, through which the required...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name and address of the manufacturer, registrant, or person\nfor whom manufactured;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name, brand, or trade-mark under which said article is sold;\nand\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The net weight or measure of the content; subject, however, to\nsuch reasonable variations as the commissioner may permit.\n  * NB Effective July 1, 2026\n  c. Any pesticide which contains any substance or substances in\nquantities highly toxic to man, determined as provided in section\n33-0303, unless the label shall bear, in addition to any other matter\nrequired by this article:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The skull and crossbones;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The word "poison" prominently, in red, on a background of\ndistinctly contrasting color; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A statement of an antidote for the pesticide.\n  d. The pesticide commonly known as standard lead arsenate, basic lead\narsenate, calcium arsenate, magnesium arsenate, zinc arsenate, zinc\narsenite, sodium fluoride, sodium fluosilicate, and barium fluosilicate,\nunless they have been distinctly colored or discolored as provided by\nregulations issued in accordance with this article, or any other white\npowder pesticide which the commissioner, after investigation of and\nafter public hearing on the necessity for such action for the protection\nof the public health and the feasibility of such coloration or\ndiscoloration, shall, by regulation, require to be distinctly colored or\ndiscolored; unless it has been so colored or discolored; provided, that\nthe commissioner may exempt any pesticide to the extent that it is\nintended for a particular use or uses from the coloring or discoloring\nrequired or authorized by this section if he determines that such\ncoloring or discoloring for such ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ndirect application in circumstances when there is no actual or\nsignificant threat of direct human exposure and no effective and\npracticable alternative, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the following uses, pursuant to\nregulations promulgated by the department:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to maintain critical infrastructure;\n  (ii) to manage roadside vegetation to ensure public safety;\n  (iii) habitat management for the control of invasive species\nidentified pursuant to title seventeen of article nine of this chapter,\npests of significant public health importance, noxious weeds designated\nby the department as injurious to ecosystem health, and the protection\nof critical native plant species; and\n  (iv) for research purposes to develop sustainable alternatives for\nagricultural and environmental usages, as well as research regarding the\nenvironmental motility of glyphosate.\n  The department shall post information on its website regarding\nglyphosate usage pursuant to this section, including amount and\nlocation, by April first of each year.\n  13. a. It shall be unlawful for any person to apply or treat outdoor\nornamental plants and turf, except for the production of agricultural\ncommodities or structural commercial applications within one foot of a\nbuilding foundation perimeter to manage structural pests provided that\nthe application is not conducted on any blooming plant, with a pesticide\ncontaining:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the active ingredients imidacloprid, thiamethoxam or acetamiprid\non or after December thirty-first, two thousand twenty-six;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the active ingredients clothianidin or dinotefuran effective\nDecember thirty-first, two thousand twenty-four.\n  b.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The provisions of paragraph a of this subdivision shall not\napply where the department, by written order, determines that:\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a valid environmental emergency exists;\n  (ii) the pesticide would be effective in addressing the environmental\nemergency; and\n  (iii) no other, less harmful pesticide or pest management practice\nwould be effective in addressing the environmental emergency.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_33_1301__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any such order shall include the basis for the department's\ndetermination and specify the approved time period, geographic scope,\nand purpose of the permitted use of such pesticide. An order issued\npursuant to this section shall be valid for a period not to exceed one\nyear.\n  c. The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to pesticide\napplications by, or under the supervision of, a certified applicator for\ntreatment against invasive species affecting woody plants.\n  d. For the purposes of this subdivision "environmental emergency"\nmeans:  an occurrence of any pest which presents a significant risk of\nharm or injury to the environment, or significant harm, injury, or loss\nto agricultural crops, including, but not limited to, any exotic or\nforeign pest.\n  e. Applicators using a pesticide containing the active ingredients\nimidacloprid, thiamethoxam, acetamiprid, clothianidin, or dinotefuran\npursuant to paragraph b or c of this subdivision must take a department\nappr...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>