<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1005*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1005*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-12-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="33-1005*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1005*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1005*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1005*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-33-1005*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_33_1005*2">
        <num>33-1005*2</num>
        <heading>Commissioner's regulations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_33_1005*2__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the address of the premises where application is to be done;\n  (ii) the name and telephone number and pesticide business registration\nnumber or certified applicator number of the person providing the\napplication;\n  (iii) the specific date of each pesticide application and two\nalternative dates to the proposed date of application when, due to\nweather conditions, the pesticide application on the proposed date is\nprecluded;\n  (iv) the product name or names and the United States Environmental\nProtection Agency registration number or numbers of the pesticide or\npesticides to be applied;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_33_1005*2__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a prominent statement that reads: "This notice is to inform you of\na pending pesticide application to: 1. a neighboring property; or 2.\nthis premise. You may wish to take precautions to minimize pesticide\nexposure to yourself, family members, pets or family possessions.\nFurther information about the product or products being applied,\nincluding any warnings that appear on the labels of such pesticide or\npesticides that are pertinent to the protection of humans, animals or\nthe environment, can be obtained by calling the National Pesticides\nTelecommunications Network at 1-800-858-7378 or the New York State\nDepartment of Health Center for Environmental Health Info line at\n1-800-458-1158".\n  b. The commissioner shall review and revise as necessary the phone\nnumbers required to appear in notices pursuant to this section and\npursuant to section four hundred nine-h of the education law and section\nthree hundred ninety-c of the social services law. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of the state administrative procedure act, such phone numbers\nshall be established as a rule by publication in the environmental\nnotice bulletin.\n  c. The written notice required by paragraph b of subdivision one of\nsection 33-1004 of this article shall be in both the English and Spanish\nlanguages, and any other languages if the commissioner deems it\nnecessary pursuant to rules and regulations.\n  4. The commissioner shall promulgate rules and regulations specifying:\nthe manner in which persons providing commercial lawn application shall\nsupply written notice as required under paragraph b of subdivision one\nof section 33-1004 of this article including, but not limited to,\nmailing, or leaving with a responsible adult or in a conspicuous\nlocation on the premises or abutting property; the manner in which the\nowner or owner's agent of multiple family dwellings covered under\nparagraph b of subdivision one of section 33-1004 of this article shall\nsupply such written notice to t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>