<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="34-0102"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0102/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-34-0102/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_34_0102">
        <num>34-0102</num>
        <heading>Declaration of policy</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 34-0102. Declaration of policy.\n  It is declared to be the public policy of the state of New York that:\n  1. Those areas of the state's coastline most prone to erosion hazards\nshould be identified.\n  2. Any activities, development or other actions in such erosion hazard\nareas should be undertaken in such manner as to minimize damage to\nproperty, and to prevent the exacerbation of erosion hazards. Such\nactions may be restricted or prohibited if necessary to protect natural\nprotective features or to prevent or reduce erosion impacts.\n  3. Local governments should be encouraged to use all authorities that\ncan be applied within the identified erosion hazard areas to achieve\nthese objectives.\n  4. Public actions, such as the provision of additional municipal\nservices, which are likely to encourage new permanent activities or\ndevelopment within coastal erosion hazard areas should not occur unless\nsuch hazard areas have been protected by erosion protection structures\nor non-structural measures which are most likely to prevent damage from\neffects of erosion during the anticipated life of the proposed\nactivities or development.\n  5. Publicly-financed structures to minimize erosion damage should be\nutilized only where necessary to protect human life, existing investment\nin development or new development which requires a location within the\nerosion hazard area or adjacent coastal waters to be able to function.\nBoth publicly and privately financed erosion protective structures\nshould be designed to minimize damage to other man-made property or to\nnatural protective features or to other natural resources; long term\ncosts of such structures should be carefully weighed against public\nbenefits before construction is undertaken.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>