<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0211"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0211"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-01-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="37-0211"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0211/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0211/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_37_0211">
        <num>37-0211</num>
        <heading>Violations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 37-0211. Violations.\n  1. A violation of any of the provisions of this title or any rule or\nregulation promulgated pursuant thereto shall be punishable in the case\nof a first violation, by a civil penalty not to exceed ten thousand\ndollars. In the case of a second and any further violation, the\nliability shall be for a civil penalty not to exceed twenty-five\nthousand dollars for each violation.\n  2. No manufacturer or distributor of a product shall be held in\nviolation of this title who can show that, in the purchase of a package\nor packaging component, he or she relied in good faith on the written\nassurance of the manufacturer of such packaging or packaging component\nthat such packaging or packaging component met the requirements of this\ntitle. Such written assurance shall take the form of a certificate of\ncompliance stating that a package or packaging component is in\ncompliance with the requirements of this title, provided however, where\ncompliance is achieved under an exemption provided in subdivision two or\nthree of section 37-0207 of this title, the certificate shall state the\nspecific basis upon which the exemption is claimed. The certificate of\ncompliance shall be signed by an authorized official of the\nmanufacturing or distributing company.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>