<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0113"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0113"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-09-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="37-0113"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-37-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_37_0113">
        <num>37-0113</num>
        <heading>Lead and mercury-added wheel weights; prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 37-0113. Lead and mercury-added wheel weights; prohibited.\n  1. On and after April first, two thousand eleven any person replacing\nor balancing a tire on a motor vehicle required to be registered under\narticle fourteen of title four of the vehicle and traffic law, shall not\nuse a wheel weight or other product for balancing motor vehicle wheels\nif the weight or other balancing product contains more than 0.1 percent\nlead by weight.\n  2. On and after April first, two thousand eleven, a person shall not\nsell or offer to sell or distribute weights or other products for\nbalancing motor vehicle wheels if the weight or other balancing product\ncontains more than 0.1 percent lead by weight.\n  3. On and after April first, two thousand twelve, a person may not\nsell a new motor vehicle that is equipped with a weight or other product\nfor balancing motor vehicle wheels if the weight or other balancing\nproduct contains more than 0.1 percent lead by weight.\n  4. On or after April first, two thousand eighteen, any person\nreplacing or balancing a tire on a motor vehicle required to be\nregistered under article fourteen of title four of the vehicle and\ntraffic law, shall not use a wheel weight or other product for balancing\nmotor vehicle wheels if the weight or other balancing product contains\nmercury that was intentionally added during the manufacture of the\nproduct.\n  5. On and after April first, two thousand eighteen, a person shall not\nsell or offer to sell or distribute weights or other products for\nbalancing motor vehicle wheels if the weight or other balancing product\ncontains mercury that was intentionally added during the manufacture of\nthe product.\n  6. For purposes of this section, the following terms shall have the\nfollowing meanings:\n  a. "New motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle that is required to be\nregistered under article fourteen of title four of the vehicle and\ntraffic law that has not been previously sold to any person except a\ndistributor, wholesaler or motor vehicle dealer for resale.\n  b. "Person" means any individual, firm, association, partnership,\ncorporation, organization, or joint venture.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>