<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-40-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-40-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="40-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-40-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-40-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-40-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-40-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_40_0107">
        <num>40-0107</num>
        <heading>Registration and fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 40-0107. Registration and fees.\n  1. On or before July first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven, the\ndepartment shall promulgate a schedule of registration fees per storage\nfacility for the cost of inspecting such facilities and based on the\nsize and type of such facilities, which shall not exceed:\n  a. one hundred twenty-five dollars per facility, up to two hundred\nfifty facilities at a single contiguous site; and\n  b. seventy-five dollars per facility in excess of two hundred fifty\nfacilities at a single contiguous site.\n  In no case shall the registration fees charged to an owner exceed\nfifty thousand dollars for storage facilities located at a single\ncontiguous site. Fees shall be paid to the department at the time of\nregistration or registration renewal. Registration shall be renewed\nevery two years or whenever title to a storage facility is transferred,\nwhichever first occurs. Registration shall be on forms and in accordance\nwith procedures prescribed by the department.\n  2. Within one year of the promulgation of the schedule of registration\nfees pursuant to subdivision one of this section, all owners shall\nidentify and register each storage facility with the department.\n  3. The fees established pursuant to this section are intended to\nprovide revenues sufficient to meet the costs incurred by the department\nin implementing the provisions of this article on and after the\npromulgation of the schedule of registration fees. All fees collected\npursuant to this section shall be paid to the state comptroller for\ndeposit in the miscellaneous special revenue fund, hazardous substances\nbulk storage account, and shall be subject to appropriation and\nallocation pursuant to the state finance law.  Expenditures from the\nhazardous substances bulk storage account of the miscellaneous special\nrevenue fund shall be limited to the costs of the department related to\nthis article. The commissioner shall, on or before December\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight, report to the legislature\nand the governor on the adequacy of the fee schedule in providing\nsufficient revenues necessary to implement the provisions of this\narticle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>