<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-09-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="42-0101"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_42_0101">
        <num>42-0101</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 42-0101. Definitions.\n  1. "Partnership" shall mean the organization established as the\nHistoric Hudson-Hoosic Rivers Partnership pursuant to section 42-0103 of\nthis article.\n  2. "Reserve" shall mean a region in which there is a combination of\npublicly and privately owned lands and land uses, within a defined area\nwhere there are traditional patterns including agriculture and open\nspace, town settlement and economic activity, which due to their pattern\nand configuration, and because of the need for sustained productivity\ncould best be protected, developed and managed through the development\nof a comprehensive stewardship plan addressing matters including, but\nnot limited to, collaborative agriculture and open space protection,\ntourism development and revitalization of main streets, recreational\ndevelopment, and protection and interpretation of natural and cultural\nheritage.\n  3. "Historic Hudson-Hoosic Rivers area" or "area" shall mean the\ncontiguous area in Saratoga, Washington and Rensselaer counties within\nthe towns of Saratoga, Stillwater, Northumberland, Easton, Fort Edward,\nWaterford, Halfmoon, Greenwich, Schaghticoke, Hoosick, Moreau, White\nCreek, Cambridge, Kingsbury, Corinth and Pittstown; the villages of\nSouth Glens Falls, Cambridge, Hudson Falls, Valley Falls, Schaghticoke,\nCorinth and Hoosick Falls; and the city of Mechanicville.\n  4. "Historic Hudson-Hoosic Rivers fund" or "fund" shall be the fund\nestablished pursuant to section 42-0115 of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>