<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0109"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0109"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="42-0109"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_42_0109">
        <num>42-0109</num>
        <heading>Stewardship plan</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_42_0109__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>historic resources;\n  (ii) scenic resources;\n  (iii) recreational uses; and\n  (iv) farmland and agricultural related uses.\n  b. An economic plan that shall include but not be limited to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_42_0109__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A main street element for traditional commercial streets in\nreserve communities;\n  (ii) A tourism plan with elements of branding, marketing and\npromotion; and\n  (iii) A strategy for small enterprise business financing and support\nto nurture entrepreneurs interested in launching business activity in\nthe reserve particularly relating to services for tourists and\nbusinesses adaptively using historic structures.\n  c. Regional cost sharing opportunities helping municipalities in the\nreserve to approach common matters collectively through agreements.\n  d. An education program including publications and guided activities.\n  e. A financial plan for implementation of plan recommendations.\n  2. A draft plan shall be submitted to the commissioner, the\ncommissioner of parks, recreation and historic preservation and\nsecretary of state within thirty months of the effective date of this\narticle. The commissioner, in consultation with the commissioner of\nparks, recreation and historic preservation and secretary of state, may\napprove the plan, may return the plan to the partnership with\nrecommendations for approval, or may reject such plan. Prior to\nsubmission of the draft plan, the partnership shall hold at least one\npublic hearing on the draft plan in each county for which the plan is\napplicable. The local legislative body of each city, town or village\nwithin the boundaries designated by the draft plan must approve the plan\nfollowing the public hearing or hearings and before it is submitted to\nthe commissioner. A copy of the approved plan shall be provided to the\ngovernor, the temporary president of the senate and the speaker of the\nassembly.\n  3. Not less than once every five years the partnership shall review\nthe plan, and shall include as part of such review a public hearing in\neach county for which the plan is applicable. The partnership shall\npropose amendments to the management plan as they are deemed to be\nnecessary and appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>