<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-09-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="42-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_42_0103">
        <num>42-0103</num>
        <heading>The Historic Hudson-Hoosic Rivers Partnership</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 42-0103. The Historic Hudson-Hoosic Rivers Partnership.\n  1. The Historic Hudson-Hoosic Rivers Partnership is hereby established\nin the department to be a body corporate and public, and to consist of\nup to thirty-seven voting members. The following individuals shall be\ninvited to become members: the supervisor of the town of Saratoga, the\nsupervisor of the town of Fort Edward, the supervisor of the town of\nGreenwich, the supervisor of the town of Easton, the supervisor of the\ntown of Stillwater, the supervisor of the town of Waterford, the\nsupervisor of the town of Northumberland, the supervisor of the town of\nHalfmoon, the supervisor of the town of Mechanicville, the supervisor of\nthe town of White Creek, the supervisor of the town of Cambridge, the\nsupervisor of the town of Moreau, the supervisor of the town of\nSchaghticoke, the supervisor of the town of Pittstown, the supervisor of\nthe town of Hoosick, the supervisor of the town of Kingsbury, the\nsupervisor of the town of Corinth, the mayor of the city of\nMechanicville, the mayor of the village of Schuylerville, the mayor of\nthe village of Victory, the mayor of the village of Stillwater, the\nmayor of the village of Fort Edward, the mayor of the village of\nGreenwich, the mayor of the village of South Glens Falls, the mayor of\nthe village of Cambridge, the mayor of the village of Hudson Falls, the\nmayor of the village of Valley Falls, the mayor of the village of\nSchaghticoke, the mayor of the village of Corinth, the mayor of the\nvillage of Hoosick Falls and the mayor of the village of Waterford. In\naddition, six members shall be appointed as follows: two shall be\nappointed by the governor, two shall be appointed by the temporary\npresident of the senate and two shall be appointed by the speaker of the\nassembly. The commissioner and the commissioners of agriculture and\nmarkets, and parks, recreation and historic preservation shall be\nnonvoting ex-officio members of the partnership. The six appointed\nmembers of the partnership, two of which shall be residents of Saratoga\ncounty, two of which shall be residents of Rensselaer county and two of\nwhich shall be residents of Washington county, shall by training,\neducation and experience or attainment be qualified to analyze,\ninterpret and/or support matters relevant to historical, environmental,\neconomic or scenic preservation work of the partnership. Each ex-officio\nmember of the partnership may designate a representative to attend, in\nhis or her place, meetings of the partnership and to act in his or her\nbehalf at meetings and with respect to the business of the partnership.\n  2. The term of office for appointees shall be four years. Members may\nserve on the partnership until they resign or are replaced. In the event\nof a vacancy occurring other than by the expiration of a member's term,\nsuch vacancy shall be filled for the balance of the unexpired term in\nthe same manner as the original appointment.\n  3. A majority of the members of the partnership shall constitute a\nquorum.\n  4. The members of the partnership shall receive no compensation for\ntheir services, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their\nexpenses actually and necessarily incurred in the performance of their\nduties.\n  5. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of law, general,\nspecial or local, no officer or employee of the state or any civil\ndivision thereof, shall be deemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit his\nor her office or employment by reason of his or her acceptance of\nmembership on the partnership.\n  6. At the initial meeting, the partnership shall elect officers, who\nshall serve at the pleasure of the partnership.\n  8. The partnership shall meet at least once every two months until\napproval of the plan by the commissioner as provided pursuant to section\n42-0109 of this article, and at least once every quarter thereafter.\n  9. Every state agency and public corporation having jurisdiction of\nland within municipalities located within the Historic Hudson-Hoosic\nRivers Partnership Reserve shall, to the fullest extent practicable,\ncooperate and assist the partnership in carrying out the provisions of\nthis article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>