<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-12-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="42-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-42-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_42_0107">
        <num>42-0107</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of the partnership</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 42-0107. Powers and duties of the partnership.\n  The partnership shall have the power:\n  1. To sue and be sued.\n  2. To make by-laws for the management and regulation of its affairs.\n  3. To make and execute contracts and all other instruments necessary\nor convenient for the exercise of its powers and functions under this\narticle.\n  4. To appoint and remove an executive officer, officers, agents and\nemployees, and prescribe their duties and qualifications and fix their\ncompensation.\n  5. To contract for professional and technical assistance and advice,\nincluding retaining or employing counsel, private consultants and\nindependent contractors.\n  6. To accept gifts, grants, loans, or contributions from, and enter\ninto contracts or other transactions with, the United States and the\nstate or any commission of either of them, any municipality, any public\nor private corporation, individual or other legal entity, and to use any\nsuch gifts, grants, loans or contributions to advance any of its\ncorporate purposes.\n  7. To conduct scientific, economic and environmental studies.\n  8. To conduct environmental education programs.\n  9. To facilitate and provide passive recreational activities including\nhiking, nature study and photography.\n  10. To make recommendations regarding necessary facilities including\npaths and trails, education center and related parking areas.\n  11. To assist individuals, corporations, associations and public\nentities on ways to protect the resources of the reserve.\n  12. To prepare an annual report on the conduct of its activities which\nshall include a recommended budget for the next year.\n  13. To adopt and use a seal.\n  14. To construct or cause to have constructed necessary facilities,\nincluding paths and trails, a visitor education center, and related\nparking areas on the land described in section three of the chapter of\nthe laws of two thousand fifteen that added this subdivision.\n  15. To exercise and perform such other powers and duties as shall have\nbeen or may be conferred by law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>