<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0121"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0121"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="43-0121"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_0121">
        <num>43-0121</num>
        <heading>Compliance with sewage disposal requirements</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 43-0121. Compliance with sewage disposal requirements.\n  1. Where a provision of this chapter, or rules or regulations issued\npursuant thereto, or the Public Health Law or state sanitary code\nrequires that the sewage disposal facilities of a building or structure\nproposed to be erected or constructed comply with the requirements\nthereof, no such building or structure shall be erected, constructed or\nthereafter occupied within the boundaries of the Lake George park\nwithout a permit therefor having been first obtained from the village\nwithin which the real property on which it is to be erected, constructed\nor thereafter occupied is located, or if such real property is not\nlocated within a village, from the town within which such real property\non which it is to be erected, constructed or thereafter occupied is\nlocated.\n  2. No such permit for erection or construction shall be granted by any\nsuch village or town board until the applicant therefor has obtained the\napproval required under the provisions of this chapter, or rules or\nregulations issued pursuant thereto, or under the Public Health Law or\nstate sanitary code and no such permit for occupancy shall be granted by\nany such village or town board until the applicant therefor has obtained\nthe approval required under the provisions of this chapter, or rules or\nregulations issued pursuant thereto, or under the Public Health Law or\nstate sanitary code.\n  3. The board of trustees of such a village or a town board of such a\ntown may fix reasonable fees for such permits and may each delegate its\npower to issue such permits to an officer or employee of the village or\ntown, as the case may be.\n  4. The action of a village or town board, or of an authorized officer\nor employee thereof, in granting or denying any application for such a\npermit shall be reviewable pursuant to article 78 of the Civil Practice\nLaw and Rules.\n  5. Such a village board of trustees, town board, the Lake George park\ncommission or any voter or taxpayer of the village or town in which such\na building or structure is located shall have the right to bring a\nproceeding to enjoin the construction, continued construction or\noccupancy of any building or structure which is erected, constructed or\noccupied without compliance with the requirements of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>