<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0105"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0105"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="43-0105"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_0105">
        <num>43-0105</num>
        <heading>Lake George park commission; continuation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 43-0105. Lake George park commission; continuation.\n  There shall continue to be in the department a commission to be known\nas "Lake George park commission." Such commission shall be a body\ncorporate and politic. It shall consist of the commissioner, ex officio,\nand nine members to be appointed by the governor, by and with the advice\nand consent of the senate, at least two of whom shall reside in the\ncounty of Essex, two in the county of Warren and two in the county of\nWashington and at least three of whom shall be members of a civic,\nprotective or service association in the Lake George area. In making\nappointments pursuant hereto the governor shall give consideration to\nnominations made by such associations in such area. The members shall be\nappointed for overlapping nine year terms of office running from April\nfirst of the year in which such terms shall, respectively, commence,\nprovided, however, that of the members first appointed one shall be\nappointed for a one-year term of office beginning April 1, 1961, one for\na two-year term of office, one for a three-year term of office, one for\na four-year term of office, one for a five-year term of office, one for\na six-year term of office, one for a seven-year term of office, one for\nan eight-year term of office and one for a nine-year term of office,\neach of which shall commence on such date. An appointment to fill a\nvacancy shall be made for the remainder of the affected term of office.\nThe officers thereof shall consist of a chairman, vice-chairman and\nsecretary-treasurer to be elected by the commission. The members of the\ncommission shall receive no compensation but may be reimbursed for\nexpenses necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>