<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0110"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0110"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="43-0110"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0110/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-43-0110/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_43_0110">
        <num>43-0110</num>
        <heading>Wastewater management</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 43-0110. Wastewater management.\n  1. The commission, in consultation with the department, the department\nof health and each municipality located in whole or in part within the\npark, and subject to approval by the department and department of\nhealth, shall adopt, after public hearing according to the provisions of\nthe state administrative procedure act, rules and regulations for the\ndischarge of sewage or treated sewage effluent onto the land or into the\ngroundwater of the park to ensure optimum protection of ground and\nsurface waters within the park. Such rules and regulations may be more\nstringent than rules and regulations adopted by the department.  For\npurposes of this section, the discharges shall include sewage or treated\nsewage effluent applied to the soil or entering the groundwater through\nrunoff, seepage, percolation, spray irrigation and ground and spring\nwater flow.\n  2. The rules and regulations adopted by the commission under\nsubdivision one of this section shall be applicable to all development\nwithin the park with respect to the discharge of wastewater; provided,\nhowever, that nothing shall prevent a municipality from adopting a law,\ncode, ordinance or regulation which is more stringent than such rules\nand regulations adopted by the commission.\n  3. The commission may delegate all or some of its authority under this\nsection to any municipality located in whole or in part within the park\nsubject to such conditions as the commission may establish.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>