<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0121"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0121"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="44-0121"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0121/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0121/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_0121">
        <num>44-0121</num>
        <heading>Greenway trail</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 44-0121. Greenway trail.\n  1. The conservancy shall designate and develop or cause to be\ndeveloped a trail or pathway system consistent with the greenway\ncriteria connecting the city of New York from the southernmost boundary\nof the area designated as the greenway to the Erie canal lock two park\nin the town of Waterford, Saratoga county to be known as the Hudson\nriver valley greenway trail. To the fullest extent practicable, the\ntrail shall:\n  a. be located with direct physical or, if not physical, visual access\nto the Hudson river;\n  b. be planned for both sides of the Hudson river;\n  c. have segments that can be restricted to non-motorized use;\n  d. utilize existing heritage trails, bikeways, scenic highways,\nrailroad rights of way and esplanades and make connections with other\ntrails including trails along tributaries of the Hudson river;\n  e. highlight and link existing parks, urban cultural parks and\nhistoric sites;\n  f. provide for interpretive signage and opportunities to experience\nthe unique natural and cultural heritage of the valley;\n  g. reflect the natural and cultural diversity;\n  h. involve state and local agencies and private organizations in the\nplanning, development and maintenance of the trail of the greenway;\n  i. use the services of local school districts and the youth\nconservation corps to participate in trail development and maintenance;\n  j. have segment management plans prepared for each segment of the\ntrail to assure uniform maintenance and upkeep; and\n  k. have connections to pathways that highlight the character and\nresources of the countryside communities.\n  2. The greenway trail to the extent practicable shall be completed on\nor before June first, two thousand five; provided that the conservancy\nshall submit a plan for the trail to the governor and legislature within\ntwenty-four months of the effective date of this section and shall to\nthe extent practicable dedicate and open significant sections of the\ntrail on or before June first, two thousand. Planning for the trail\nshall commence with the council and the conservancy sponsoring a Hudson\nriver valley greenway trail symposium to prepare a plan of action for\nthe planning and development of the trail. Representatives of local\ngovernments in the greenway, interested nonprofit organizations,\nrepresentatives of the state and federal government, planners and\nlandscape architects along with any other interested parties shall be\ninvited to participate in the symposium.\n  3. The department and the office of parks, recreation and historic\npreservation, the department of transportation and the office of general\nservices are hereby authorized and directed to support and assist in the\nplanning and development of the trail.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>