<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0115"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0115"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="44-0115"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-44-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_44_0115">
        <num>44-0115</num>
        <heading>State agency reports and consistency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 44-0115. State agency reports and consistency.\n  1. The council in carrying out its functions and responsibilities\nunder this article, shall consult with, cooperate with, and, to the\nmaximum extent practicable, coordinate its activities with other\ninterested state agencies.\n  2. The following officers of state agencies with program\nresponsibilities that affect aspects of the greenway criteria shall\nprepare and submit to the council a program statement which shall detail\nactions in the areas of planning, development, use, assistance and\nregulation that can support and assist or would conflict with the\nestablishment and management of the greenway including the compact and\ndevelopment of the trail:\n  a. commissioner of the office of parks, recreation and historic\npreservation regarding the state historic preservation program, the\nstate urban cultural park program, state parks within the greenway,\noutdoor recreation and trail planning;\n  b. commissioner of economic development regarding the state tourism\nprogram including the identification of potential tourism destination\nareas within the greenway and recommendations for a system of\ninteractive information outlets throughout the greenway and the impact\nof greenway criteria on economic development activities;\n  c. commissioner of environmental conservation regarding the management\nof natural resources including plants, fish and wildlife and natural\ncommunities and protecting environmental quality;\n  d. commissioner of transportation regarding access and transportation;\n  e. secretary of state regarding the coastal zone management program\nand other planning programs administered by the department of state;\n  f. commissioner of the office of general services regarding the\nstewardship and disposition of state property; and\n  g. the commissioner of agriculture and markets regarding the\ncontribution of agricultural activities and programs to greenway\ncriteria.\n  Each such officer shall annually review such statements and submit\nrevisions and updates to the council as appropriate.\n  3. After the compact is in effect, any state agency conducting,\nfunding or approving activities directly affecting greenway resources\nshall, to the fullest extent practicable, consult with, cooperate with,\nand coordinate its activities with the council and the appropriate\nparticipating community. Any such state agency shall conduct or support\nsuch activities in a manner which is, to the maximum extent practicable,\nconsistent with the compact in addition to requirements of other laws,\nincluding those of article forty-two of the executive law. The compact\nshall be incorporated as part of the reviews of actions pursuant to the\nstate environmental quality review act as provided in article eight of\nthis chapter and the New York state historic preservation act of 1980.\nFor purposes of section 8-0113 of this chapter, the commissioner shall\nincorporate consideration of the greenway in rules and regulations\nadopted pursuant to such section. The council shall review and comment\nin writing upon the statement and effects on the greenway program, made\npursuant to section 8-0109 of this chapter and section 14.09 of the\nparks, recreation and historic preservation law.\n  4. Nothing in this article shall preempt the authority and\nresponsibilities of the department pursuant to article eleven of this\nchapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>