<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0117"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0117"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-07-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="45-0117"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0117/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0117/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0117/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0117/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_0117">
        <num>45-0117</num>
        <heading>Jurisdiction and administration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 45-0117. Jurisdiction and administration.\n  1. The department is hereby authorized to manage and exercise custody\nand control over lands dedicated pursuant to this article or to contract\nwith any city, county, town or village, or any combination thereof, or\nany state agency or the Albany Pine Bush commission established under\narticle forty-six of this chapter for the management, custody and\ncontrol of such real property subject to such conditions as may be\napproved by the director of the budget.\n  2. The lands dedicated to the preserve are enumerated as follows:\n  a. Skenoh Island in the town of Canandaigua, county of Ontario more\nfully described in chapter three hundred fifty-two of the laws of\nnineteen hundred seventy-five.\n  b. Showy Lady Slipper parcel in the town of New Hudson, county of\nAllegany more fully described in chapter one hundred thirty-three of the\nlaws of nineteen hundred seventy-seven.\n  c. Parrish Gully in the town of Italy, county of Yates more fully\ndescribed in chapter one hundred thirty-three of the laws of nineteen\nhundred seventy-seven.\n  d. Clark Gully in the towns of Middlesex and Italy, county of Yates\nmore fully described in chapter one hundred thirty-three of the laws of\nnineteen hundred seventy-seven.\n  e. Cicero Swamp in the town of Cicero, county of Onondaga more fully\ndescribed in chapter one hundred thirty-three of the laws of nineteen\nhundred seventy-seven.\n  f. Labrador Hollow in the town of Fabius, county of Onondaga and the\ntown of Truxton, county of Cortland more fully described in chapter\nthree hundred thirty-six of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-six.\n  g. Reinstein Woods in the town of Cheektowaga, county of Erie more\nfully described in chapter five hundred twenty-two of the laws of\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine.\n  h. Bog Brook in the town of Southeast and Patterson, county of Putnam\nmore fully described in chapter five hundred twenty-two of the laws of\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine.\n  i. The Oak Brush Plain State Preserve in the towns of Babylon and\nHuntington, county of Suffolk more fully described in chapter six\nhundred thirty-five of the laws of nineteen hundred eighty-seven.\n  j. The David A. Sarnoff Pine Barrens in the town of Southampton,\ncounty of Suffolk more fully described in chapter two hundred forty-nine\nof the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-three.\n  k. The Rocky Point Natural Resources Management Area in the town of\nBrookhaven, county of Suffolk more fully described in chapter two\nhundred forty-nine of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-three.\n  l. State lands dedicated to the Albany Pine Bush preserve pursuant to\narticle forty-six of this chapter.\n  m. The Camillus forest unique area in the town of Camillus, county of\nOnondaga more fully described in chapter four hundred sixty-three of the\nlaws of two thousand five.\n  n. The Zoar Valley Unique Area in the Towns of Otto and Persia, county\nof Cattaraugus and the town of Collins, county of Erie more fully\ndescribed in the chapter of the laws of two thousand seven which added\nthis paragraph.\n  3. Lands dedicated to the preserve are declared to be put to their\nhighest, best and most important use and are to be held for one or more\nof the following purposes:\n  a. As natural areas for maintaining plants, animals and natural\ncommunities, including preservation of old-growth forests dedicated to\nthe preserve specifically for that purpose;\n  b. As reservoirs of natural materials and ecological processes that\ncontribute to the state's biological diversity;\n  c. As field laboratories for scientific research and education in the\nnatural sciences, including the fields of biology, conservation,\necology, geology, natural history and paleontology; and\n  d. As places of natural and historical interest and beauty which\nprovide the public with passive recreational opportunities including,\nwhere appropriate, fishing, hunting and trapping, or commercial fishing\nopportunities that are compatible with protecting the ecological\nsignificance, historic features and natural character of the area.\n  4. The department, or the city, county, town, village or state agency\nexercising control over the site pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection, shall develop a written stewardship plan for each site\ndedicated to the preserve. Such plan shall include a description of\nstewardship activities required to monitor, protect, enhance and where\nappropriate actively manage the ecological, scenic, wilderness,\ngeological or historic resources that merited dedication of the site to\nthe preserve. Such plan shall also provide for passive recreational\nuses, including, where appropriate, fishing, hunting and trapping, or\ncommercial fishing opportunities that are compatible with protecting the\necological significance, historic features and natural character of the\nsite.\n  5. Nothing in this article shall be construed to diminish an existing\nproperty right held by any person who owns any interest in any real\nproperty that is located adjacent to any real property dedicated to the\npreserve.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>