<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="45-0111"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-45-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_0111">
        <num>45-0111</num>
        <heading>Functions, powers and duties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 45-0111. Functions, powers and duties.\n  The trustee shall have the duty of assisting the legislature and the\ngovernor in implementing the policy of the state as set forth in section\n4 of article XIV of the State Constitution, and in order to carry out\nsuch purposes he shall have the following functions, powers and duties:\n  1. To recommend to the Governor and legislature real property to be\nincluded in the preserve. In making such recommendations, the trustee\nshall first find that such real property qualifies for inclusion in the\npreserve because of its natural beauty, wilderness character, it\ncontains old-growth forest, or is of other geological, ecological or\nhistorical significance. Such recommendation shall include, where\nappropriate, the estimated value or cost of the real property,\njustification for its inclusion in the preserve, and provision for\nmanagement, care, custody and control of the real property. When the\ntrustee identifies a parcel of state land which may be an old-growth\nforest, the trustee shall evaluate the parcel, and if it meets the\ncriteria of an old-growth forest, recommend the parcel be included in\nthe preserve. When the trustee recommends property be placed in the\npreserve to protect old-growth forest, such recommendation shall include\nprovisions that the old-growth forest be protected with minimum\nmanagement or disturbance that only considers passive recreational\nopportunities with no construction of public amenities. In those\nprovisions, the protection of the old-growth forest from invasive\nspecies and diseases may be considered. Such real property may include,\nbut not be limited to real property presently owned in the name of the\nstate, unconditional or conditional grants, gifts and bequests to the\nstate of real property, and real property recommended by the trustee for\nacquisition.\n  2. To prepare and submit an annual report to the Governor and the\nlegislature on or before February first on the activities of the trust.\n  3. To undertake research and studies related to activities of the\ntrust.\n  4. To maintain a current inventory of all real property which has been\ndedicated to the preserve.\n  5. To request any state agency to render assistance in carrying out\nthe purposes of this article. Any state agency is authorized to render\nsuch assistance to the trustee.\n  6. To make such rules and regulations as the trustee may determine\nnecessary for the purposes of properly carrying out his functions,\npowers and duties, and to do all things necessary or convenient for\ncarrying out the foregoing functions.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>