<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-46-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-46-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="46-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-46-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-46-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-46-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-46-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_46_0107">
        <num>46-0107</num>
        <heading>Albany Pine Bush preserve</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 46-0107. Albany Pine Bush preserve.\n  The commissioner shall maintain a record of the boundaries of the\nlands which have been dedicated to the Albany Pine Bush preserve in text\nand depicted on a map.\n  1. Land owned by the state may be dedicated to be part of the preserve\nonly by action by the commissioner, the commissioner of the state office\nof parks, recreation and historic preservation or the commissioner of\nthe state office of general services, provided that state land dedicated\nhereunder may also be dedicated to be part of the state nature and\nhistorical preserve pursuant to article forty-five of this chapter.\n  2. Land owned by a local government may be dedicated to be part of the\npreserve only by action of its local legislative body.\n  3. Land owned by private persons or organizations may be dedicated to\nbe part of the preserve only through the voluntary execution of a\nconservation easement pursuant to article forty-nine of this chapter,\nand the acceptance of such instrument by the commission; provided,\nhowever, that the commission shall not have the power or authority,\nwithout the consent of the landowner, to require as a condition of or a\nprerequisite for obtaining any permit, license or other authorization to\nconduct any activity within or adjacent to the preserve, that any lands\nbe dedicated to the preserve.\n  4. Every proposed dedication shall be reviewed and approved by the\ncommission.\n  5. The commission shall have no authority to control or manage any\nprivate land unless such land has been dedicated pursuant to this\nsection or the owner thereof has executed a voluntary written agreement\nwith the commission authorizing the specific management actions which\nmay be taken by the commission.\n  6. Land owned by the commission shall be dedicated to be part of the\npreserve upon acquisition by the commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>