<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0105"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0105"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="47-0105"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0105/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0105/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_0105">
        <num>47-0105</num>
        <heading>Establishment of county environmental management councils; members and officers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 47-0105. Establishment of county environmental management councils;\n             members and officers.\n  1. The county governing body of any county may establish a county\nenvironmental management council. Such council may be constituted within\nthe organized structure of county government so as to provide for\neffective coordination among all agencies of the county for the purposes\nof this article. The council shall consist of one member of each city,\ntown, and village conservation advisory council within the county.\nAdditional members as the county appointing authority may provide, shall\nbe appointed to serve at the pleasure of the county appointing\nauthority, for a term not to exceed two years. The presiding officer or\nchairman shall be appointed by the county appointing authority from\namong the members of the council. In addition, the county appointing\nauthority may appoint members of the county governing body and the heads\nof those county departments whose work particularly affects or is\nparticularly affected by environmental considerations, as ex officio\nmembers of the council. For the purposes of this article, the term\ncounty appointing authority shall mean the body or officer of a county\nauthorized by law to make appointments.\n  2. The county appointing authority is hereby authorized\nnotwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law to appoint up to four\nmembers to the council who are between the ages of sixteen and\ntwenty-one.\n  3. Nothing contained in this article shall be deemed to prohibit the\nestablishment of a county environmental agency pursuant to other\nprovisions of law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>