<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0113"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0113"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="47-0113"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0113/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0113/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_0113">
        <num>47-0113</num>
        <heading>Regional environmental management councils</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 47-0113. Regional environmental management councils.\n  1. If in the opinion of the governing bodies of two or more counties,\nthe protection and management of the environment of the area could be\neffectively or efficiently provided by a regional council these counties\nmay enter into agreement to establish a regional environmental\nmanagement council for the several counties agreeing to the\nconsolidation.\n  2. The membership of the regional councils shall be made up of members\nof county environmental councils or individuals eligible to be members\nof county environmental councils.  Members shall be appointed by the\nseveral county governing bodies to assure fair representation, but in no\ncase shall there be more than twenty official members of the regional\ncouncil other than ex officio members.\n  3. The regional council shall supercede and replace the individual\ncounty councils and shall exercise all those powers otherwise accruing\nto the county councils.\n  4. The county governing bodies of the several counties agreeing to the\nformation of such a council may appropriate such funds as they see fit\nfor the work of the regional council including the compensation of\nmembers, the retention of staff and other assistance, the preparation\nand printing of reports, maps, books, charts, and pamphlets and the cost\nof other items related to their work.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>