<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0115"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0115"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="47-0115"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0115/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-47-0115/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_47_0115">
        <num>47-0115</num>
        <heading>Reimbursement</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 47-0115. Reimbursement.\n  Up to one-half of the expenditures during the state fiscal year of any\ncounty or regional environmental management council established pursuant\nto this article shall be reimbursed to the counties out of funds\nappropriated by the state to the Department of Environmental\nConservation for this purpose. Provided, however, that any county\nenvironmental agency established pursuant to a provision of law other\nthan this article shall be entitled to such reimbursement if the\ncommissioner of the department of environmental conservation finds that\nthe powers, duties, and reporting lines for the major reports of such\ncouncil are substantially the same as those provided in section 47-0107\nof this article, and that the membership structure thereof either\ncomplies with the provisions of subdivision one of section 47-0105 of\nthis article or that such membership structure is designed to encourage\nlocal participation and coordination in the planning of activities to\ninfluence the ecological balance of the locality. Necessary and\nappropriate rules and regulations for administration of the local\nassistance purposes of this act may be promulgated by the commissioner.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>