<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0205"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0205"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="49-0205"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49_0205">
        <num>49-0205</num>
        <heading>Comprehensive inventory of lands having statewide or regional significance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 49-0205. Comprehensive inventory of lands having statewide or regional\n             significance.\n  1. In order to help provide a basis for a strategy for the\npreservation of land resources in the state and the preparation of the\nstate land acquisition plan, the department and the office shall prepare\na comprehensive inventory of protected and unprotected resources having\nstatewide or regional environmental, historic, cultural or recreational\nsignificance. Such inventory shall include the following:\n  a. open space, forest land and park land owned by federal, state and\nlocal governmental entities including lands containing old-growth forest\ndedicated to the state nature and historical preserve pursuant to\narticle forty-five of this chapter;\n  b. forest land in private ownership under the terms of section four\nhundred eighty-a of the real property tax law;\n  c. wetlands protected by articles twenty-four and twenty-five of this\nchapter;\n  d. agricultural areas, including agricultural districts created\npursuant to article twenty-five-AA of the agriculture and markets law as\nrecommended by the commissioner of agriculture and markets;\n  e. water resources, including wild, scenic and recreational rivers,\nstreams and aquifer recharge areas protected by article fifteen of this\nchapter;\n  f. marine and other coastal resources, including coastal erosion\nhazard areas protected by article thirty-four of this chapter;\n  g. open space lands, forest lands and park lands dedicated by other\nthan governmental entities to ecological, wildlife management, forest\nmanagement or recreational purposes; and\n  h. lands which possess statewide or regional significance for\nhistoric, cultural, ecological, open space, outdoor recreation, resource\nprotection or wildlife management purposes, including the purpose of\nrestoring extirpated species, and preserving old-growth forests.\n  2. Such inventory, in such segments and such form as may be readily\navailable at any given time, shall be available to the regional land\nacquisition advisory committees and other members of the public.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>