<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-23" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="49-0503"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-49-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_49_0503">
        <num>49-0503</num>
        <heading>Establishment of state geological trail</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 49-0503. Establishment of state geological trail.\n  1. The commissioner, in cooperation with the commissioners of\ntransportation and economic development, shall establish a state\ngeological trail to include the areas, territories and sites designated\nby the commissioner pursuant to subdivision two of section 49-0501 of\nthis title. The purpose of such trail shall be to identify and promote\nsuch areas, territories and sites to the public, and promote the\neconomic, scientific, cultural and conservation aspects thereof.\n  2. To the greatest extent practicable, the state geological trail\nshall include areas and sites across the state going east and west, and\nnorth and south throughout the entire state. Consideration shall be\ngiven to having the designated portions of the state geological trail\nintersect at the city of Albany, in recognition of its importance in the\ngeology of the state. In designating the state geological trail\nconsideration shall also be given to scientific and/or scenic importance\nrelating to geological, and related cultural, ecological and\narcheological features.\n  3. In developing and approving such trail, the commissioner shall\nensure that proposed trail routes do not conflict with existing scenic\nbyways designated pursuant to section three hundred forty-nine-dd of the\nhighway law or wine trails designated pursuant to section three hundred\nforty-three-k of the highway law, and ensure that the trail route is\ndesigned and laid out so that it is relatively simple and easy to follow\nfor users and contains few branches or laterals that dead end.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>