<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="51-0101"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-51-0101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_51_0101">
        <num>51-0101</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 51-0101. Definitions.\n  As used in this article the following terms shall mean and include:\n  1. "Commissioner" shall mean the commissioner of environmental\nconservation except that within and for the purposes of title eleven of\nthis article, the commissioner of parks and recreation.\n  2. "Department" shall mean the department of environmental\nconservation.\n  3. "Federal assistance" except for federal public works act funds\ngranted for New York city's Betts avenue incinerator and Hamilton avenue\ntransfer station and as otherwise defined in this article, shall mean\nfunds available, other than by loan, from the federal government to a\nmunicipality, either directly or through allocation by the state for\nconstruction or program purposes pursuant to any federal law or program.\n  4. "Governing body" shall mean\n  a. in the case of a town, a town board;\n  b. in the case of a county outside of the city of New York, the county\nboard of supervisors or other elective governing body;\n  c. in the case of a city or village, the local legislative body\nthereof, as the term is defined in the municipal home rule law;\n  d. in the case of a public benefit corporation, the board of\ndirectors, members or trustees thereof;\n  e. in the case of a school district, the board of education thereof;\n  f. in the case of a supervisory district, the board of cooperative\neducational services thereof.\n  5. "Lands" shall mean lands, improvements and structures thereon or\nrights, franchises, and interests therein, lands under water and\nriparian rights, and shall also mean any and all interests in lands less\nthan full title, including without limitations, easements, permanent or\ntemporary, rights of way, uses, leases, licenses, and any other estate,\ninterests or right in lands, legal or equitable.\n  6. "Municipality," except as otherwise defined within this article,\nshall mean a city, county, town, village, public benefit corporation or\nschool district or an improvement district within a city, county, town\nor village, or any combination thereof.\n  7. "Office" shall mean the office of parks and recreation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>