<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1101"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1101"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-04-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="54-1101"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1101/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-54-1101/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_54_1101">
        <num>54-1101</num>
        <heading>Local waterfront revitalization programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 54-1101. Local waterfront revitalization programs.\n  1. The secretary is authorized to provide on a competitive basis,\nwithin amounts appropriated, state assistance payments and/or technical\nassistance as defined in section nine hundred seventeen of the executive\nlaw, to municipalities toward the development of any local waterfront\nrevitalization program, pursuant to article forty-two of the executive\nlaw including planning projects to mitigate future physical climate\nrisks and updates to existing local waterfront revitalization program\nplans to mitigate future physical climate risks. Eligible costs include\nplanning, studies, preparation of local laws, and construction projects.\n  2. State assistance payments and/or technical assistance, as defined\nin section nine hundred seventeen of the executive law, shall not exceed\nseventy-five percent of the cost of the program provided, however, in\nenvironmental justice communities, such assistance payments and/or\ntechnical assistance shall not exceed eighty-five percent of the cost of\nthe program. For the purpose of determining the amount of state\nassistance payments, costs shall not be more than the amount set forth\nin the application for state assistance payments approved by the\nsecretary. The state assistance payments shall be paid on audit and\nwarrant of the state comptroller on a certificate of availability of the\ndirector of the budget.\n  3. The secretary shall have the power to approve vouchers for payments\npursuant to an approved contract.\n  4. No moneys shall be expended as authorized by this section except\npursuant to an appropriation therefor.\n  5. The secretary shall impose such contractual requirements and\nconditions upon any municipality which receives state assistance\npayments pursuant to this article as may be necessary and appropriate to\nensure that a public benefit shall accrue from the use of such funds by\nthe municipality including but not limited to, a demonstration that\nfuture physical climate risk due to sea level rise, and/or storm surges\nand/or flooding, based on available data predicting the likelihood of\nfuture extreme weather events, including hazard risk analysis data if\napplicable, has been considered.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>