<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="55-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-55-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_55_0103">
        <num>55-0103</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 55-0103. Legislative findings.\n  The legislature finds that:\n  1. The scientific evidence of groundwater contamination is mounting;\n  2. Such contamination, once it occurs, is often irreversible;\n  3. Within this area subject to sole source aquifer designation, due to\ntheir particular rate of recharge and associated hydrogeological\nconditions, certain groundwater recharge watershed areas are\nparticularly critical for the maintenance of large volumes of high\nquality groundwater for long periods of time;\n  4. In the face of mounting cases of groundwater contamination from\ntoxic organic compounds, nutrients, salts and other pollutants, the\nstate needs a program for the designation, protection and management of\nspecial groundwater protection areas;\n  5. It is desirable to maintain natural vegetative and hydrogeologic\nconditions in special groundwater protection areas;\n  6. Prevention of the contamination of high quality groundwater and the\nprotection of special groundwater protection areas costs substantially\nless than measures to mitigate harm following contamination; and\n  7. There is a demonstrated need to protect, preserve and enhance the\nland and water resources of special groundwater protection areas through\na new program which combines the capabilities and resources of the\nlocal, state and federal governments and the private sector.\n  8. Some of the nonpoint source control strategies developed for the\nspecial groundwater protection areas can be used to minimize further\ncontamination in developed deep aquifer recharge areas.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>