<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="57-0111"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_57_0111">
        <num>57-0111</num>
        <heading>Long Island Pine Barrens maritime reserve council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 57-0111. Long Island Pine Barrens maritime reserve council.\n  1. There is hereby established, within the department, a Long Island\nPine Barrens maritime reserve council to help local governments and the\nstate coordinate the efforts of all municipal, county, state and federal\nagencies involved in the management of the preserve and to oversee and\nprepare a comprehensive intergovernmental management plan for the Long\nIsland Pine Barrens maritime reserve that the state and local\ngovernments may adopt.\n  2. The council shall be composed of seventeen voting members. The\ngovernor shall appoint three members. The county executive of the county\nof Suffolk, with the advice and consent of the county legislature, shall\nappoint four members. The town supervisors of the towns of Riverhead,\nSouthold, Shelter Island, Southampton, East Hampton and Brookhaven shall\neach appoint one member. The commissioner or his or her designee, the\ncommissioner of parks, recreation and historic preservation or his or\nher designee, the secretary of state or his or her designee for purposes\nof matters related to coastal resources and the commissioner of economic\ndevelopment or his or her designee for purposes of tourism shall serve\nas ex-officio members. All members, except ex-officio members shall be\nresidents of the county of Suffolk and shall have demonstrated expertise\nin the functional areas to be addressed by the commission. All initial\nappointments shall be made within sixty days of the effective date of\nthis title.\n  3. Members of the council shall serve for a term of two years or\nthereafter until a successor is appointed. A chairperson shall be\ndesignated by the governor. The council shall elect a vice-chairperson\nand such other officers as it may determine are necessary for the\nconduct of its duties.\n  4. Ten members of the council shall constitute a quorum.\n  5. The members of the council shall serve without compensation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>