<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0109"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0109"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="57-0109"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_57_0109">
        <num>57-0109</num>
        <heading>Establishment of Long Island Pine Barrens maritime reserve; core preservation area and compatible growth area</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 57-0109. Establishment of Long Island Pine Barrens maritime reserve;\n             core preservation area and compatible growth area.\n  1. The region encompassing and distinguished by the Peconic Bay\nsystem, lands which gather and transmit precipitation as either\ngroundwater or runoff into the Peconic Bay system, lands characterized\nby the growth of pitch pine, dwarf pine and/or scrub oak pine barrens\nincluding lands currently under the review and jurisdiction of the\nSuffolk county Pine Barrens review commission and lands used in\ntraditional patterns for agriculture, finfishing, shellfishing and\ntourism and made up of all lands and waters located in the towns of\nRiverhead, Southold, Shelter Island, Southampton and East Hampton and\nthe portion of the town of Brookhaven east of a north south line defined\nby extending County Road 83 to the northern most and southern most\nextension to their respective water boundaries of Brookhaven town and\nthe town's incorporated villages is hereby established and designated to\nbe the Long Island Pine Barrens Maritime reserve.\n  2. Within the reserve and within forty-five days of the effective date\nof this subdivision, the commission shall file with the secretary of\nstate the maps of the Central Pine Barrens area classifying and\ndepicting the core preservation area as defined, which comprises the\nlargest essentially intact areas of undeveloped pine barrens ecology,\nand the compatible growth area where appropriate patterns of development\nand regional growth shall be permitted and shall file a certified copy\nthereof with the county clerk of Suffolk county and the clerk of each\ntown or village whose boundaries are included within the Central Pine\nBarrens area. Notice of the filing and availability of such map shall be\npublished at least twice in the paper of general circulation in the\ncounty of Suffolk. An affected property owner may petition the\ncommission for precise delineation or adjustment of boundary as it\napplies to the affected property. The commission shall have\ndiscretionary powers to modify the boundaries of the core preservation\narea by up to three hundred feet as circumstances warrant after\nnotification to the affected property owner or owners, except no\nboundary defined by a state or county highway or navigable waterway\nshall be modified to extend beyond such highway or waterway.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>