<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0125"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0125"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="57-0125"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_57_0125">
        <num>57-0125</num>
        <heading>Addition of towns</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 57-0125. Addition of towns.\n  1. The legislature finds that in order to facilitate regional planning\nfor Long Island, local governments within the reserve but located\noutside of the Central Pine Barrens area may similarly benefit from the\nplanning effort undertaken by the commission. Therefore, after the\ncompletion, ratification, and adoption of the comprehensive land use\nplan and upon application to the commission, the towns of East Hampton,\nShelter Island, and Southold may elect, by duly adopted resolution of\ntheir town boards, to join the commission or establish a similar\nplanning effort for those areas outside the Central Pine Barrens area\nand within the reserve that warrant and would benefit from such regional\nefforts consistent with the goals and objectives of this title.\n  2. All benefits and obligations which accrue to municipalities which\nparticipate with the commission shall be afforded to the municipalities\nof the South and North Fork which elect to voluntarily participate in\nthis process, subject to the obligations of this title. Such benefits\nmay include funding for the development and implementation of regional\nplans. The provisions of this title with respect to the interim\nprovisions shall not apply. To the extent feasible, towns electing to\ndevelop and implement such regional plans consistent with this title,\nshall utilize the commission and its supportive structure.\n  3. Upon completion, ratification, and adoption of the comprehensive\nland use plan, and an expressed interest on the part of the towns of\nEast Hampton, Shelter Island, or Southold, the commission shall\nestablish criteria for participating in this process. Such criteria may\nnot include the imposition of a moratorium or restriction of development\nas a requirement for participation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>