<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0117"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0117"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="57-0117"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0117/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0117/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0117/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-57-0117/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_57_0117">
        <num>57-0117</num>
        <heading>Dedications to the Long Island Pine Barrens preserve; legislative protection</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 57-0117. Dedications to the Long Island Pine Barrens preserve;\n             legislative protection.\n  1. The commissioner shall maintain a record of the boundaries of the\nlands which have been dedicated to the Long Island Pine Barrens preserve\nin text and depicted on a map.\n  2. Land owned by the state within the Long Island Pine Barrens\nmaritime reserve may be dedicated to be part of the Long Island Pine\nBarrens preserve by the action of the commissioner or the commissioner\nof parks, recreation and historic preservation, or by action of the\nlegislature.\n  3. Land owned by a local government within the Long Island Pine\nBarrens maritime reserve may be dedicated to the Long Island Pine\nBarrens preserve by the action of its local legislative body.\n  4. Land owned by private individuals within the Long Island Pine\nBarrens maritime reserve may be dedicated to be part of the Long Island\nPine Barrens preserve by the execution of a conservation easement.\n  5. Land in the core preservation area which come in the public domain\nshall be deemed to be dedicated to the Long Island Pine Barrens\nPreserve.\n  6. Except for the core preservation area which shall be deemed to be\ndedicated to the preserve, the council shall review and must approve\neach dedication of land to the preserve.\n  7. No publicly owned real property, dedicated to the Long Island Pine\nBarrens preserve, shall be alienated except by law enacted by two\nsuccessive regular sessions of the legislature, but easements for public\nwater supply purposes may be maintained consistent with local\nordinances.\n  8. The council shall have no authority to manage any private land\nunless such land has been voluntarily dedicated pursuant to this title\nor the owner has executed a voluntary written agreement with the council\nauthorizing the specific management actions taken.\n  9. Nothing contained in this title shall affect any previous\ndedication of state land to the State Nature and Historic preserve. Any\nstate land dedicated to the Long Island Pine Barrens preserve may also\nbe dedicated to the State Nature and Historic preserve.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>