<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-58-0703"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-58-0703"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-08-18" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="58-0703"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-58-0703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-58-0703/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-58-0703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-58-0703/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_58_0703">
        <num>58-0703</num>
        <heading>Programs, plans and projects</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 58-0703. Programs, plans and projects.\n  1. Eligible climate change mitigation projects include, but are not\nlimited to:\n  a. costs associated with green building projects, projects that\nincrease energy efficiency or the use or siting of renewable energy on\nstate-owned buildings or properties including buildings owned by the\nstate university of the state of New York, city university of the state\nof New York, community colleges, and public schools;\n  b. costs associated with projects that utilize natural and working\nlands to sequester carbon and mitigate methane emissions from\nagricultural sources, such as manure storage through cover and methane\nreduction technologies;\n  c. costs associated with implementing climate adaptation and\nmitigation projects pursuant to section 54-1523 of this chapter;\n  d. costs associated with urban forestry projects such as forest and\nhabitat restoration, for purchase and planting of street trees and for\nprojects to expand the existing tree canopy and bolster community\nhealth;\n  e. costs associated with projects that reduce urban heat island\neffect, such as installation of green roofs, open space protection,\ncommunity gardens, cool pavement projects, projects that create or\nupgrade community cooling centers, and the installation of reflective\nroofs where installation of green roofs is not possible;\n  f. costs associated with projects to reduce or eliminate air pollution\nfrom stationary or mobile sources of air pollution affecting\ndisadvantaged communities;\n  g. costs associated with projects which would reduce or eliminate\nwater pollution, whether from point or non-point discharges, affecting\ndisadvantaged communities; and\n  h. costs associated with the purchase or conversion to zero emission\nschool buses, including costs associated with the supporting\ninfrastructure.\n  2. The department, the department of agriculture and markets, the\noffice of parks, recreation and historic preservation, the New York\nstate energy research and development authority and the office of\ngeneral services are authorized to provide state assistance payments or\ngrants to municipalities and not-for-profit corporations or undertake\nprojects pursuant to this section.\n  3. Provided that for the purposes of selecting projects for funding\nunder this section, the relevant agencies shall develop eligibility\nguidelines and post information on the department's website in the\nenvironmental notice bulletin providing for a thirty-day public comment\nperiod and upon adoption post such eligibility guidelines on the\nrelevant agency's website.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>