<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-70-0111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-70-0111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="70-0111"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-70-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-70-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-70-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-70-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_70_0111">
        <num>70-0111</num>
        <heading>Minor projects</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_0111__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before fifteen calendar days after the receipt of an\napplication for a permit for a minor project, the department shall mail\nwritten notice to the applicant of its determination whether or not the\napplication is complete. If the department fails to mail written notice\nto an applicant of its determination whether or not an application is\ncomplete within such fifteen calendar day period, the application shall\nbe deemed complete.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_0111__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within forty-five calendar days after the department mails written\nnotice to the applicant that an application for a permit for a minor\nproject is complete or within forty-five calendar days after the\napplication is deemed complete pursuant to the provisions of this\narticle and subject to the provisions of subdivisions four, five, and\nsix of section 70-0109, the department shall make a decision on the\napplication by mailing the applicant a permit, a permit with conditions\nor a statement that the permit applied for has been denied.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_0111__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the department fails to make a decision on an application for a\npermit for a minor project within such forty-five calendar day period,\nthen the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_0111__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of section\n70-0109 shall apply.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_70_0111__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department may provide, by rule and regulation pursuant to\nsection 70-0107 of this article, for the issuance of general permits\ncovering minor projects. Such general permits may be issued following\nsuch events as natural disasters or acts of God which lead numbers of\nindividuals to seek to undertake similar types of minor projects that\nare of a remedial nature. Such permits may be issued only upon a written\nstatement of necessity by the commissioner justifying the issuance of\nsuch general permit and may be issued only for a specified duration of\ntime.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>