<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0925"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0925"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-0925"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0925/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0925/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0925/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0925/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_0925">
        <num>71-0925</num>
        <heading>Civil penalties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_0925__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the violation involves the illegal taking of a deer prior to\nthe first day of the open season or after the last day of the open\nseason in the county or part of a county in which taken, or the taking\nof deer with aid of an artificial light, not less than five hundred\ndollars and not more than one thousand dollars for the first deer taken\nand a further penalty of not less than five hundred dollars and not more\nthan one thousand dollars for each succeeding deer taken; provided,\nhowever, that any person having been held liable for a violation\npursuant to this paragraph in the preceding five years shall be subject\nto a fine of not less than seven hundred fifty dollars and not more than\ntwo thousand dollars for the first deer taken and a further penalty of\nnot less than seven hundred fifty dollars and not more than two thousand\ndollars for each succeeding deer taken;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_0925__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the violation involves any illegal taking of a wild deer, other\nthan a taking described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_71_0925__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, five\nhundred dollars for the first deer taken and a further penalty of five\nhundred dollars for each succeeding deer taken;\n  4. If the violation was an act prohibited by section 11-1321 or by\nsubdivision 2 of section 11-0503, or by subdivision 2 of section\n11-0505, or section 13-0345, five hundred dollars, and an additional\npenalty of ten dollars for each fish taken, killed or possessed in\nviolation thereof;\n  5. If the violation was any act prohibited by subdivision 1 of section\n11-0503, not less than five hundred dollars nor more than one thousand\ndollars for each offense and an additional penalty of ten dollars for\neach fish killed in violation thereof;\n  6. If the violation was a violation of paragraph b of subdivision 4 of\nsection 11-0321, a violation of subdivision 1 of section 11-2113, or a\nviolation of section 11-2115, not less than twenty-five dollars nor more\nthan one hundred dollars; and in addition, as determined by the court,\nto either actual damages or the sum of ten dollars for each sign\ninjured, defaced or removed in violation of section 11-2113, which shall\nbe payable to the person sustaining the damage, injury, defacement or\nremoval of such sign, and costs of suit, all of which may be recovered\nin the same action;\n  7. If the violation was a violation of sections 13-0329, 13-0330,\n13-0331, 13-0333, 13-0334, 13-0335, subdivision one of section 13-0337,\n13-0338, 13-0339, 13-0339-a, 13-0340, 13-0340-a through 13-0340-g,\n13-0341, 13-0342, 13-0343, 13-0347, and 13-0349 of this chapter, or of\nany regulation adopted pursuant to the foregoing sections, the greater\nof two hundred fifty dollars or:\n  a. for violations involving one to five fish, shellfish or\ncrustaceans, twenty-five dollars for each fish, shellfish or crustacean\ntaken or possessed in violation of the above sections;\n  b. for violations involving six to twenty-five fish, shellfish or\ncrustaceans, fifty dollars for each fish, shellfish or cr...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0925__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of paragraph b of subdivision 1 of\nsection 11-0719, not less than five hundred dollars nor more than\nfifteen hundred dollars for each offense, and in addition the forfeiture\nto the state of the tongs, rakes, dredges or devices other than boats\nused by or in connection with such illegal taking;\n  9. If the violation was a failure by any public officer to perform any\nduty imposed by the Fish and Wildlife Law or by any rule or regulation\nof the department, one hundred dollars;\n  10. If the violation was an act prohibited by section 11-2117, one\nhundred dollars, one-half of which shall be payable to the owner or\noccupant of the damaged property, in addition to the actual damages, if\nany, recoverable by the person sustaining the damage;\n  11. If the violation involved the illegal taking or possessing of\nmuskrats taken from a registered muskrat marsh covered by a permit under\nsection 11-1109, when the violation is committed by the registrant\nholding the permit or other person ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0925__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the financial security provided by customers for the\nopportunity to take the animal or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_71_0925__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the value of a boar for meat\nproduction or as breeding stock.\n  16. If the violation was an act prohibited by section 11-0535-a of\nthis chapter, not more than three thousand dollars or not more than two\ntimes the value of the article involved, whichever is greater. If the\nviolation is a second or subsequent violation of such section 11-0535-a,\nnot more than six thousand dollars or not more than three times the\nvalue of the article involved, whichever is greater.\n  17. If the violation was an act prohibited by section 11-0535-b of\nthis chapter, not more than one thousand dollars or not more than two\ntimes the value of the article involved, whichever is greater. If the\nviolation is a second or subsequent violation of such section 11-0535-b,\nnot more than two thousand dollars or not more than three times the\nvalue of the article involved, whichever is greater.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>