<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0919"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0919"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-11-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-0919"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0919/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0919/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_0919">
        <num>71-0919</num>
        <heading>Punishment of violations of Fish and Wildlife Law</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 71-0919. Punishment of violations of Fish and Wildlife Law.\n  1. Any person who violates any provision of the Fish and Wildlife Law\nor any lawful order, rule or regulation of the department promulgated\npursuant thereto or the terms of any permit issued thereunder, and any\nperson, including a public officer, who fails to perform any duty\nthereby imposed on him:\n  a. In the case of offenses specified in section 71-0921 of this\nchapter, is guilty of a misdemeanor, punishable as provided in that\nsection, and\n  b. In the case of any other offense, is guilty of a violation,\npunishable as provided in section 71-0923 of this chapter, and\n  c. In addition thereto is liable in either case to the penalties\nprovided in the schedule set forth in section 71-0925 or provided\nelsewhere in this chapter; and\n  d. In the cases provided in sections 11-0719 and 11-2115, is liable to\nrevocation of licenses to hunt, fish or trap or for bowhunting privilege\nor muzzle-loading privilege, disqualification for such licenses and/or\nfor bowhunting privilege or muzzle-loading privilege and denial of the\nability to obtain any hunting, fishing or trapping license and\nbowhunting privilege and muzzle-loading privilege, as provided in those\nsections; and\n  e. In the case of violations for which such forfeiture or revocation\nis provided, is subject to revocation or forfeiture of other licenses\nissued pursuant to the Fish and Wildlife Law; and\n  f. In the cases provided in section 71-0909, is liable to forfeiture\nand confiscation of property involved in such violations, as provided in\nthat section.\n  g. In the case of having a license privilege revoked or suspended by a\nparticipating state in the Interstate Wildlife Violator Compact enacted\nunder title twenty-five of article eleven of this chapter, the violation\nand subsequent revocation or suspension in the participating state shall\nconstitute the basis for revocation or suspension in this state for the\nsame privileges and period of time.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>