<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0521"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0521"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="71-0521"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0521/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0521/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0521/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-71-0521/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_71_0521">
        <num>71-0521</num>
        <heading>Certificate by court or justice</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 71-0521. Certificate by court or justice.\n  The court or justice, other than a town justice or a village police\njustice, before whom any person shall be tried or before whom a\ncompromise of the civil penalties for a violation of any provision of\nthis chapter listed in section 71-0501 or under titles 5 through 15\ninclusive and title 33 of this article, shall have been made, or the\nclerk of the court, if there be a clerk, shall, at the termination of\nsuch trial or proceeding, forthwith mail or deliver to the department at\nAlbany, or to its representative at such trial or proceeding, a\ncertified statement of the disposition of the case or proceeding, giving\nthe date thereof, the name of the defendant, the name of the person upon\nwhose information the action or proceeding was instituted, the date and\nplace of the violation, the name of each witness sworn in support of the\ncharges, and the costs of the court or fees of the justice, and the fees\nof the constable, if any.  Provided, however, that a town justice or a\nvillage police justice before whom any person shall be tried or before\nwhom a compromise of the civil penalties for a violation of any\nprovision of this chapter listed in section 71-0501 or under titles 5\nthrough 15 inclusive and title 33 of this article, shall have been made\nshall forthwith mail or deliver to the department at Albany or to its\nrepresentative in attendance at such trial or proceeding such certified\nstatement, and within the first ten days of the month following the\ntermination of such trial or proceeding deliver to the State Comptroller\nat Albany a statement in such form as the Comptroller may require. The\nComptroller upon receipt of such statement shall, as provided in section\n71-0507, audit the bills of the justice of the peace and the constable\nfor fees in such trial or proceeding and shall pay to the persons\nentitled thereto the amounts allowed by such audit and shall charge same\nto the conservation fund.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>