<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="72-0303"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-72-0303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_72_0303">
        <num>72-0303</num>
        <heading>Operating permit program fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_72_0303__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Act.\n  8. If a city or county shall be delegated the authority to administer\nthe operating permit program established pursuant to section 19-0311 of\nthis chapter it may collect the fees established pursuant to this\nsection and no additional liability for fees under this section shall\naccrue for any such source.\n  9. No later than September thirtieth, nineteen hundred ninety-four and\nbefore September thirtieth of each subsequent year, the department shall\nreport to the governor, the legislature and the department of audit and\ncontrol on:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_72_0303__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the actual direct and indirect costs of the operating\npermit program incurred, and the revenues received pursuant to fees\nimposed by this section, during the previous fiscal year; (ii) the\nestimated direct and indirect costs of the operating permit program that\nwill be incurred, and the anticipated revenues received or anticipated\nto be received pursuant to fees imposed by this section, during the\ncurrent fiscal year; (iii) an estimate of the direct and indirect costs\nof the operating permit program that will be incurred, and the tonnages\nof pollutants anticipated to be subject to the fees imposed by this\nsection, during the subsequent fiscal year; (iv) an estimate of any\nbalance in the operating permit program account of the clean air fund\nthat will be available at the end of the current fiscal year;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_72_0303__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a\nrecommendation regarding adjustments to the fees imposed under this\nsection necessary to assure that the operating permit program account\nhas adequate funds to finance the direct and indirect cost of the\noperating permit program during future fiscal years; and (vi) the number\nof operating permit applications upon which the department has taken\nfinal action in the previous fiscal year, the average review time per\npermit, the number of person hours spent per permit, and the number of\ncompleted permit applications which are pending final action. Reports\nand accountings required to be filed with the administrator of the\nUnited States environmental protection agency may serve to satisfy this\nrequirement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>