<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="73-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-73-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_73_0107">
        <num>73-0107</num>
        <heading>Task force duties</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_73_0107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adaptive measures that can be taken to mitigate flood damages,\nincluding but not limited to feasible floodplain management activities,\nwetland restoration, flood control structures, communication systems and\nstructures and associated costs;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Evaluation which should include impacts on agriculture,\ntransportation, land use, health, insurance and economic sectors such as\nshipping, fisheries, power generation, tourism, and recreation. Impacts\non infrastructure, including bridges, low-lying roads, dams, locks,\ncauseways, water and wastewater treatment plants and docks shall be\nincluded in the evaluation; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Evaluation of canal operation procedures and plans which may have\na direct or indirect impact on flood mitigation and flood management\nincluding, but not limited to, debris management, communication, water\nmanagement and flood response.\n  2. Evaluation and assessment of any flood control or mitigation\nmeasures identified in terms of feasibility, economic and public health\nimpacts, and effectiveness, as well as identifying impediments to\nimplementing flood control and mitigation measures and where possible,\nactions that could be taken to resolve these issues.\n  3. The department and the canal corporation shall provide the task\nforce with such facilities, assistance and data as will enable the task\nforce to carry out its powers and duties. Additionally, all other\nagencies of the state or subdivisions thereof shall, at the request of\nthe chair provide the task force with such facilities, assistance, and\ndata as will enable the task force to carry out its powers and duties.\n  4. The task force shall have the power to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73_0107__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contract for professional and technical assistance and advice;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73_0107__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contract for and accept assistance including, but not limited to\ngifts, grants, easements, and loans of funds, real property and personal\nproperty from the federal government or any agency or instrumentality of\nthe state, or from any other public or private source to comply, subject\nto the provisions of this article, with the terms and conditions\nthereof, subject to the approval of the division of the budget.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of section eleven of the state finance\nlaw, the task force may accept gifts, grants, devises and bequests,\nwhether conditional or unconditional with the approval of the director\nof the budget; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_73_0107__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conduct scientific and environmental studies.\n  * NB Repealed 120 days after the New York State canal flood mitigation\ntask force has submitted its completed report (see ch. 456/2007 ยง2)\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>