<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-76-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-76-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-03-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="76-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-76-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-76-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-76-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-76-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_76_0103">
        <num>76-0103</num>
        <heading>The climate change adaptation cost recovery program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three hundred fourteen of the tax\nlaw.\n  e. i. The department shall issue notices of cost recovery demand to\nall responsible parties at the times set forth in paragraph a of\nsubdivision four of this section. Payment of a cost recovery demand\nshall be made in full on the applicable payment date provided that,\nnotwithstanding paragraph a of subdivision two of this section, the\ndepartment may provide that a responsible party may elect to pay an\namount no greater than ninety-two percent of the amount of the cost\nrecovery demand after the applicable payment date. Any such payments\npermitted to be made after the applicable payment date shall be made\nwithin twenty-four years of the applicable payment date, shall be no\nless frequent than annual beginning in the year following the applicable\npayment date, and shall not increase over time.\n  ii. Any responsible party who fails to make a payment required\npursuant to this subdivision shall pay a penalty of fifty per centum of\nthe unpaid payment amount, plus interest on the unpaid payment amount\ncomputed in accordance with section 6621</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>of the United States\ninternal revenue code of 1986 (Public Law 99-514, 26 U.S.C. section 1 et\nseq.) from the date the payment was required to be paid.\n  f. If there is any addition to the original amount of the final cost\nrecovery demand as of the applicable payment date for failure to timely\npay any amount required to be paid under this subdivision, a liquidation\nor sale of substantially all the assets of the responsible party\n(including in a proceeding under U.S. Code: Title 11 or similar case), a\ncessation of business by the responsible party, or any similar\ncircumstance, then the unpaid balance of all unpaid amounts shall be due\non the date of such event (or in the case of a proceeding under U.S.\nCode: Title 11 or similar case, on the day before the petition is\nfiled). The preceding sentence shall not apply to the sale of\nsubstantially all of the assets of a responsible party to a buyer if\nsuch buyer enters into an agreement with the department under which such\nbuyer...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a responsible party may file a request for reconsideration of its\ncost recovery demand with the department within sixty days following\nservice of the notice of cost recovery demand if within the United\nStates, and within ninety days following such service outside the United\nStates, and in doing so shall exhaust administrative remedies;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a request for reconsideration shall state the grounds for the\nrequest and include supporting documentation, which may include but is\nnot limited to documentation of the party's covered greenhouse gas\nemissions and the party's contacts with the state;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the department shall consider whether any such requests for\nreconsideration, including whether a responsible party refining\npetroleum products, or who is a successor in interest to such an entity,\nestablishes to the satisfaction of the department that a portion of the\ncost recovery demand amount was attributable to the refining of crude\noil extracted by a responsible party, or who is a successor in interest\nto such an entity, that was accounted for in determining the cost\nrecovery demand amount of such responsible party, and whether notices of\ncost recovery demand should be updated, and shall issue updated notices\nof cost recovery demand, if applicable, which shall include a statement\nof the grounds of the department's determination, within sixty days\nfollowing the expiration of all periods for submitting a request for\nreconsideration under item one of this subparagraph;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if notices of cost recovery demand issued pursuant to item three\nof this subparagraph result in a new responsible party receiving a\nnotice of cost recovery demand that was not issued a notice of cost\nrecovery demand by the date required by subparagraph iv of this\nparagraph, then, in the same manner as set forth in items one, two and\nthree of this subparagraph, such responsible party shall have sixty days\nfrom service within the United States, and ninety days from service\noutside the United States, to file a request for reconsideration, which\nfiling shall exhaust such responsible party's administrative remedies,\nand the department shall consider such request for reconsideration and\nissue updated notices of cost recovery demand, if applicable, in the\nmanner contemplated by item three of this subparagraph;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if any updating of notices of cost recovery demand pursuant to\nsuch processes for reconsideration results in a new responsible party\nthat was not previously issued a cost recovery demand, such new\nresponsible party shall also be given the opportunity to file a request\nfor reconsideration in the same manner as set forth in item four of this\nsubparagraph, and such process shall continue until no new responsible\nparty results from issuance of notices of cost recovery demand; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>if the processes in this subparagraph result in issuances of\nnotices of cost recovery demand after the applicable payment date, then\nthe applicable payment date shall be the date which is thirty days after\nthe final issuance of notices of cost recovery demand; and\n  vi. accepting payments from, pursuing collection efforts against, and\nnegotiating settlements with responsible parties.\n  b. The department shall hold at least two public hearings, one\nin-person and one virtual, on proposed regulations, with a minimum of\nthirty days' public notice in compliance with the provisions of article\nseven of the public officers law.\n  5. The department shall develop procedures to make publicly available,\nby posting on its website, all data related to fossil fuel extraction\nand refining by entities which the department obtains pursuant to the\nprogram, to the maximum extent practicable.\n  6. Within eighteen months of the promulgation of the final regulations\npursuant to subdivision fou...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>expenditures that benefit disadvantaged communities as defined in\nsection 75-0101 of this chapter;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>expenditures by project type;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>expenditures by percentage of overall funding used for grant\nprograms for municipalities and not-for-profit and community\norganizations; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_76_0103__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>expenditures for administration and implementation support;\n  iv. a review of climate change adaptive infrastructure projects'\nstatus, including the number of projects that have been completed and\nthose projects which have been identified and remain unfunded;\n  v. a summary of the geographic distribution of climate change adaptive\ninfrastructure projects; and\n  vi. identification of future spending needs.\n  b. Such evaluation shall be made public on the department's website\nand provided to the governor, the temporary president of the senate and\nthe speaker of the assembly on or before January first of the second\ncalendar year following the year in which this article is enacted into\nlaw, and annually on or before September thirtieth thereafter.\n  11. The department shall publish all information, requests for\nproposals, application forms, procedures and guidelines relating to\nclimate change adaptive infrastructure projects on its website and in a\nmanner that is accessible ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>