<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-0103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_0103">
        <num>8-0103</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and declaration</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 8-0103. Legislative findings and declaration.\n  The legislature finds and declares that:\n  1. The maintenance of a quality environment for the people of this\nstate that at all times is healthful and pleasing to the senses and\nintellect of man now and in the future is a matter of statewide concern.\n  2. Every citizen has a responsibility to contribute to the\npreservation and enhancement of the quality of the environment.\n  3. There is a need to understand the relationship between the\nmaintenance of high-quality ecological systems and the general welfare\nof the people of the state, including their enjoyment of the natural\nresources of the state.\n  4. Enhancement of human and community resources depends on a quality\nphysical environment.\n  5. The capacity of the environment is limited, and it is the intent of\nthe legislature that the government of the state take immediate steps to\nidentify any critical thresholds for the health and safety of the people\nof the state and take all coordinated actions necessary to prevent such\nthresholds from being reached.\n  6. It is the intent of the legislature that to the fullest extent\npossible the policies, statutes, regulations, and ordinances of the\nstate and its political subdivisions should be interpreted and\nadministered in accordance with the policies set forth in this article.\nHowever, the provisions of this article do not change the jurisdiction\nbetween or among state agencies and public corporations.\n  7. It is the intent of the legislature that the protection and\nenhancement of the environment, human and community resources shall be\ngiven appropriate weight with social and economic considerations in\npublic policy. Social, economic, and environmental factors shall be\nconsidered together in reaching decisions on proposed activities.\n  8. It is the intent of the legislature that all agencies conduct their\naffairs with an awareness that they are stewards of the air, water,\nland, and living resources, and that they have an obligation to protect\nthe environment for the use and enjoyment of this and all future\ngenerations.\n  9. It is the intent of the legislature that all agencies which\nregulate activities of individuals, corporations, and public agencies\nwhich are found to affect the quality of the environment shall regulate\nsuch activities so that due consideration is given to preventing\nenvironmental damage.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>