<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0111"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0111"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-05-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8-0111"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0111/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-8-0111/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8_0111">
        <num>8-0111</num>
        <heading>Coordination of reporting; limitations; lead agency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_0111__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Actions undertaken or approved prior to the effective date of this\narticle, except:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_0111__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the case of an action where it is still practicable either to\nmodify the action in such a way as to mitigate potentially adverse\nenvironmental effects or to choose a feasible and less environmentally\ndamaging alternative, in which case the commissioner may, at the request\nof any person or on his own motion, in a particular case, or generally\nin one or more classes of cases specified in rules and regulations,\nrequire the preparation of an environmental impact statement pursuant to\nthis article; or\n  (ii) In the case of an action where the responsible agency proposes a\nmodification of the action and the modification may result in a\nsignificant adverse effect on the environment, in which case an\nenvironmental impact statement shall be prepared with respect to such\nmodification.\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_0111__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Actions subject to the provisions requiring a certificate of\nenvironmental compatibility and public need in articles seven and ten of\nthe public service law or requiring a major renewable energy facility or\na major electric transmission facility siting permit under article eight\nof the public service law; or\n  * NB Effective until December 31, 2040\n  *</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_0111__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Actions subject to the provisions requiring a certificate of\nenvironmental compatibility and public need in articles seven, ten and\nthe former article eight of the public service law or requiring a siting\npermit under section ninety-four-c of the executive law; or\n  * NB Effective December 31, 2040\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8_0111__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Actions subject to the class A or class B regional project\njurisdiction of the Adirondack park agency or a local government\npursuant to section eight hundred seven, eight hundred eight or eight\nhundred nine of the executive law, except class B regional projects\nsubject to review by local government pursuant to section eight hundred\nseven of the executive law located within the Lake George park as\ndefined by subdivision one of section 43-0103 of this chapter.\n  6. Lead Agency. When an action is to be carried out or approved by two\nor more agencies, the determination of whether the action may have a\nsignificant effect on the environment shall be made by the lead agency\nhaving principal responsibility for carrying out or approving such\naction and such agency shall prepare, or cause to be prepared by\ncontract or otherwise, the environmental impact statement for the action\nif such a statement is required by this article. In the event that there\nis a question as to which is the lead agency, any agency may submit the\nquestion to the commissioner and the commissioner shall designate the\nlead agency, giving due consideration to the capacity of such agency to\nfulfill adequately the requirements of this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>