<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0107"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0107"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0107"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0107/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0107/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0107">
        <num>9-0107</num>
        <heading>Acceptance by department of lands for parks and for silvicultural research</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0107. Acceptance by department of lands for parks and for\n            silvicultural research.\n  Notwithstanding any other provisions of this article, the department\nis hereby authorized to accept, for the state, grants or deeds of gift\nof any lands, upon approval of the title thereto by the Attorney\nGeneral, as follows:\n  1. a. Lands, located in any county named in subdivision 2 of section\n9-0105, or in subdivision 6 of section 9-0101 of this article, which the\ndepartment may deem suitable for park or reservation purposes. The grant\nor deed must recite that it is given for acceptance under the provisions\nof this subdivision of this section.\n  b. Property so accepted shall forever be under the jurisdiction of the\ncommissioner and his successors in office and, by virtue of the\nacceptance thereof, shall be irrevocably dedicated to be used for the\npurposes of a public park or reservation under the care, custody,\ncontrol and management of the department and shall not become a part of\nthe forest preserve. Such property shall forever remain open to the\npublic for the enjoyment of the scenic and natural beauties of the\npremises, and receive such improvement or development, by the erection\nof buildings, roads, highways, railroads and other structures, including\nthe improvement, alteration and maintenance of the structures now on\nsuch premises as the legislature may from time to time determine. The\ndepartment may, in its discretion, lease a part or all of such premises\nupon such terms and conditions as it may determine not inconsistent with\nthe reasonable use of such premises by the public, provided that any\nsuch lease shall first have been approved by the Attorney General as to\nform.\n  2. a. Lands, located in any county named in subdivision 6 of section\n9-0101 of this article, which the department may deem suitable for use\nfor the purposes of silvicultural research and experimentation in the\nscience of forestry to the end that forest practices most beneficial to\nthe economy of the state and the health, welfare and comfort of the\npeople of the state may be ascertained and demonstrated. The grant or\ndeed to the state of any such lands must recite that it is given for\nacceptance under the provisions of this subdivision of this section.\n  b. Property so accepted shall be under the jurisdiction of the\ncommissioner and his successors in office and, until otherwise provided\nby law, shall be dedicated for use only for the purposes of\nsilvicultural research and experimentation in the science of forestry,\nincluding purposes incidental thereto, under the care, custody, control\nand management of the department and its successors in office and shall\nnot become a part of the forest preserve. Under such conditions as it\nmay deem consistent with the purposes aforesaid, and upon such terms as\nit may deem to be for the best interests of the state, the department\nmay sell trees, timber and other products on any such lands. All trees,\ntimber or other products to be sold shall be plainly marked or otherwise\ndesignated prior to cutting and no such material shall be removed from\nsuch land until paid for. No such material shall be sold at less than\nthe fair market value in the county or counties in which it is located,\nwhich value shall be the value fixed by a department forester or other\ncompetent appraiser in a report made after an examination of the\nmaterials to be sold, provided such appraisal is approved by the\ndepartment. The department may sell any such materials at not less than\nthe fair market value so fixed and under such conditions as it may\nprescribe, provided, however, that no sale of such materials appraised\nat five hundred dollars or more shall be made without public notice of\nsale, and after receipt of sealed bids. The award shall be made only to\nthe highest bidder. Such notice of sale and bids, the awarding of the\ncontract and the execution and filing of the contract shall otherwise be\nin accordance with the procedure specified in sections 9-0501 through\n9-0505 of this article for the sale after public notice, of trees,\ntimber, and other forest products on reforestation areas. All moneys\nreceived from any such sale shall be paid over to the State Comptroller\nand shall be deposited by him in the forest preserve expansion fund\nestablished by section 97-e of the State Finance Law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>