<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-0503"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-0503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_0503">
        <num>9-0503</num>
        <heading>Certificate of purchase; exemption from taxation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-0503. Certificate of purchase; exemption from taxation.\n  Immediately upon acquiring by gift, purchase or appropriation lands\nfor a reforestation area the commissioner shall transmit to the state\nagency authorized by law to approve assessments of state lands and to\nthe Department of Audit and Control, respectively, a certificate which\nshall set forth, with respect to each parcel of such lands so acquired,\na description thereof, the area in acres, from whom acquired, whether\nacquired by gift, purchase or appropriation, the price paid for such\nparcel in the case of a purchase (except as hereinafter provided), the\ndate of the recording of the deed, if acquired by deed, the effective\ndate of the devise, if acquired by devise, and the assessed valuation of\nsuch parcels as shown by the assessment rolls of the town in which such\nparcel is located two years prior to the gift, if acquired by gift and\nseparately assessed. If such a purchase shall include more than one\nparcel of such lands and it is impossible for the commissioner to\ndetermine the price paid for such parcel included in such purchase, he\nshall specify in such certificate the price paid for the entire tract\npurchased. Such lands shall be exempt from taxation only as provided in\nthe Real Property Tax Law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>