<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1123"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1123"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-1123"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1123/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1123/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1123/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1123/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_1123">
        <num>9-1123</num>
        <heading>Northeastern Interstate Forest Fire Protection Compact</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-1123.  Northeastern Interstate Forest Fire Protection Compact.\n  The Northeastern Interstate Forest Fire Protection Compact as first\nenacted by chapter seven hundred forty-four of the laws of nineteen\nhundred forty-nine, and as re-enacted by chapter two hundred sixty-three\nof the laws of nineteen hundred sixty-three, is hereby continued as\nfollows:\n         NORTHEASTERN INTERSTATE FOREST FIRE PROTECTION COMPACT\n                                Article I\n  The purpose of this compact is to promote effective prevention and\ncontrol of forest fires in the northeastern region of the United States\nand adjacent areas in Canada by the development of integrated forest\nfire plans, by the maintenance of adequate forest fire fighting services\nby the member states, by providing for mutual aid in fighting forest\nfires among the states of the region and for procedures that will\nfacilitate such aid, and by the establishment of a central agency to\ncoordinate the services of member states and perform such common\nservices as member states may deem desirable.\n                               Article II\n  This agreement shall become operative immediately as to those states\nratifying it whenever any two or more of the states of Maine, New\nHampshire, Vermont, Rhode Island, Connecticut, New York and the\nCommonwealth of Massachusetts have ratified it and the congress has\ngiven its consent. Any state not mentioned in this article which is\ncontiguous with any member state may become a party to this compact.\nSubject to the consent of the congress of the United States, any\nprovince of the Dominion of Canada which is contiguous with any member\nstate may become a party to this compact by taking such action as its\nlaws and the laws of the Dominion of Canada may prescribe for\nratification. In this event, the term "state" in this compact shall\ninclude within its meaning the term "province" and the procedures\nprescribed shall be applied in the instance of such provinces, in\naccordance with the forms and practices of the Canadian government.\n                               Article III\n  Each state joining herein shall appoint three representatives to a\ncommission hereby designated as the Northeastern Forest Fire Protection\nCommission. One shall be the state forester or officer holding an\nequivalent position in such state who is responsible for forest fire\ncontrol. The second shall be a member of the legislature of such state\ndesignated by the commission or committee on interstate cooperation of\nsuch state, or if there be none, or if said commission on interstate\ncooperation cannot constitutionally designate the said member, such\nlegislator shall be designated by the governor thereof; provided that if\nit is constitutionally impossible to appoint a legislator as a\ncommissioner from such state, the second member shall be appointed by\nthe governor of said state in his discretion. The third member shall be\na person designated by the governor as the responsible representative of\nthe governor. In the event that any province of the Dominion of Canada\nshall become a member of this commission, it shall designate three\nmembers who will approximate this pattern of representation to the\nextent possible under the law and practices of such province. This\ncommission shall be a body corporate with the powers and duties set\nforth herein.\n                               Article IV\n  It shall be the duty of the commission to make inquiry and ascertain\nfrom time to time such methods, practices, circumstances and conditions\nas may be disclosed for bringing about the prevention and control of\nforest fires in the area comprising the member states, to coordinate the\nforest fire plans and the work of the appropriate agencies of the member\nstates and to facilitate the rendering of aid by the member states to\neach other in fighting forest fires.\n  The commission shall formulate and, in accordance with need, from time\nto time, revise a regional forest fire plan for the entire region\ncovered by the compact which shall serve as a common forest fire plan\nfor that area.\n  The commission shall, more than one month prior to any regular meeting\nof the legislature in any signatory state, present to the governor and\nto the legislature of the state its recommendations relating to\nenactments to be made by the legislature of that state in furthering the\ninterests and purposes of this compact.\n  The commission shall consult with and advise the appropriate\nadministrative agencies of the states party hereto with regard to\nproblems connected with the prevention and control of forest fires and\nrecommend the adoption of such regulations as it deems advisable.\n  The commission shall have power to recommend to the signatory states\nany and all measures that will effectuate the prevention and control of\nforest fires.\n                                Article V\n  Any two or more member states may designate the Northeastern Forest\nFire Protection Commission as a joint agency to maintain such common\nservices as those states deem desirable for the prevention and control\nof forest fires. Except in those cases where all member states join in\nsuch designation for common services, the representatives of any group\nof such designating states in the Northeastern Forest Fire Protection\nCommission shall constitute a separate section of such commission for\nthe performance of the common service or services so designated provided\nthat, if any additional expense is involved, the states so acting shall\nappropriate the necessary funds for this purpose. The creation of such a\nsection as a joint agency shall not affect the privileges, powers,\nresponsibilities or duties of the states participating therein as\nembodied in the other articles of this compact.\n                               Article VI\n  The commission may request the United States forest service to act as\nthe primary research and coordinating agency of the Northeastern Forest\nFire Protection Commission, in cooperation with the appropriate agencies\nin each state and the United States forest service may accept the intial\nresponsibility in preparing and presenting to the commission its\nrecommendations with respect to the regional fire plan. Representatives\nof the United States forest service may attend meetings of the\ncommission and of groups of member states.\n                               Article VII\n  The commission shall annually elect from its members a chairman and a\nvice-chairman. The commission shall appoint such officers or employees\nas may be required to carry the provisions of this compact into effect,\nshall fix and determine their duties, qualifications and compensation,\nand may at its pleasure, remove or discharge any such officer or\nemployee. The commission shall adopt rules and regulations for the\nconduct of its business. It may establish and maintain one or more\noffices for the transaction of its business and may meet at any time or\nplace but must meet at least once a year.\n  A majority of the members of the commission representing a majority of\nthe signatory states shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of\nits general business, but no action of the commission imposing any\nobligation on any signatory state shall be binding unless a majority of\nthe members from such signatory state shall have voted in favor thereof.\nFor the purpose of conducting its general business, voting shall be by\nstate units.\n  The representatives of any two or more member states, upon notice to\nthe chairman as to the time and purpose of the meeting, may meet as a\nsection for the discussion of problems common to those states.\n  Sections established by groups of member states shall have the same\npowers with respect to officers, employees and the maintenance of\noffices as are granted by this article to the commission. Sections may\nadopt such rules, regulations and procedures as may be necessary for the\nconduct of their business.\n                              Article VIII\n  It shall be the duty of each member state to formulate and put in\neffect a forest fire plan for that state and to take such measures as\nmay be recommended by the commission to integrate such forest fire plan\nwith the regional forest fire plan.\n  Whenever the state forest fire control agency of a member state\nrequests aid from the state forest fire control agency of any other\nmember state in combatting, controlling or preventing forest fires, it\nshall be the duty of the state forest fire control agency of that state\nto render all possible aid to the requesting agency which is consonant\nwith the maintenance of protection at home.\n  Each signatory state agrees to render aid to the forest service or\nother agencies of the government of the United States in combatting,\ncontrolling or preventing forest fires in areas under their jurisdiction\nlocated within the member state or a contiguous member state.\n                               Article IX\n  Whenever the forces of any member state are rendering outside aid\npursuant to the request of another member state under this compact, the\nemployees of such state shall, under the direction of the officers of\nthe state to which they are rendering aid, have the same powers (except\nthe power of arrest), duties, rights, privileges and immunities as\ncomparable employees of the state to which they are rendering aid.\n  No member state or its officers or employees rendering outside aid\npursuant to this compact shall be liable on account of any act or\nomission on the part of such forces while so engaged, or on account of\nthe maintenance or use of any equipment or supplies in connection\ntherewith.\n  All liability that may arise either under the laws of the requesting\nstate or under the laws of the aiding state or under the laws of a third\nstate on account of or in connection with a request for aid, shall be\nassumed and born</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>