<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-1103"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1103/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1103/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_1103">
        <num>9-1103</num>
        <heading>Additional powers of the department</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-1103. Additional powers of the department.\n  In addition to the powers provided in section 9-0105 and in connection\nwith the control of fire, the department shall have the power to:\n  1. Maintain a system of forest fire protection in such areas of the\nstate as the department determines necessary.\n  2. Purchase necessary equipment, tools or supplies, employ men or\nincur other expenses as may be necessary to furnish adequate forest fire\nprotection.\n  3. Establish, maintain, equip and operate forest fire observation\nstations, telephone lines or other structures therefor as the public\ninterest requires.\n  4. Make contracts, agreements or purchases either for construction,\noperation or maintenance of telephone lines for fire protection\npurposes. Any telephone company may grant the state a preferred rate.\n  5. With consent of owner build or improve fire roads, ditches, trails\nor fire lines. No action for trespass shall lie on account of injury to\nprivate property on such account, if the act is performed in the\nprotection of the forests from fire.\n  6. Appoint necessary employees to perform such duties as are required\nby this title 11.\n  7. Order removed from service, on forty-eight hours' notice, any\nrailroad locomotive, operating in the fire towns, not properly equipped\nwith fire protection devices.\n  8. Grant an extension of time in which owners may comply with section\n9-1113 when the department is satisfied that such an extension of time\nwill not endanger the forests to fire, but in no case shall an extension\nbe granted for a period of more than six weeks from the time of cutting,\nexcept in connection with operations for the clearing of a reservoir\nsite under the authority of section 15-1507.\n  9. Relieve railroads from maintaining railroad fire patrol, or\nclearing right of way when in the judgment of the department the absence\nof such patrol or clearing will not subject the forests to fire menace.\n  10. Request the Public Service Commission to hear and determine\nwhether any railroad, person or company operating railroad locomotives\nthrough forest land is using such devices and precautions against the\nsetting of forest fires, as the public interest requires.\n  11. Designate persons who shall have authority to issue permits as\nrequired by subdivision 5 of section 9-1105.\n  12. Enter into working agreements with land owners for the purpose of\nsecuring better forest fire protection in the fire towns.\n  13. Make rules and regulations to secure better fire protection within\nall or any portion of those areas designated as fire districts under\nsubdivision 2 of section 9-1109 or defined as fire towns by section\n9-1107.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>