<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="ENV">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-1701"/>
          <FRBRname value="ENV"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/env/section-9-1701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_1701">
        <num>9-1701</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 9-1701. Legislative findings.\n  The legislature finds that invasive plant and animal species pose an\nunacceptable risk to New York state's environment and economy and that\nthis risk is increasing through time as more invasive species become\nestablished within the state. The legislature additionally finds that\ninvasive species are having a detrimental effect upon the state's fresh\nand tidal wetlands, water bodies and waterways, forests, agricultural\nlands, meadows and grasslands, and other natural communities and systems\nby out-competing native species, diminishing biological diversity,\naltering community structure and, in some cases, changing ecosystem\nprocesses. Moreover, the legislature recognizes that the ecological\nintegrity of an increasing number of publicly and privately-owned parks\nand preserves is being adversely affected by invasive plants and\nanimals, challenging the ability of land management agencies to\neffectively manage these sites. The legislature further recognizes that\nnearly half (forty-six percent; fifty-seven percent of the plants,\nthirty-nine percent of the animals) of the species on the federal list\nof endangered species are declining, at least in part, due to invasive\nspecies. The legislature additionally finds that invasive species have\nan adverse impact on the New York state economy. Particularly affected\nby these species are the water supply, agricultural, and recreational\nsectors of the state economy. The economic impact to the national\neconomy has been estimated to be as high as one hundred thirty-seven\nbillion dollars annually.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>