<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-100"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-100"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-08-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="100"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-100/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-100/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_100">
        <num>100</num>
        <heading>Fiduciary powers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As guardian, receiver, trustee, committee or conservator of the\nestate of any minor, person with a mental disability, or conservatee or\nin any other fiduciary capacity;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_100__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As receiver, trustee, or committee of the property or estate of\nany person in insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings.\n  4. To be appointed and to accept the appointment of executor or of\ntrustee under the last will and testament or administrator with or\nwithout the will annexed of the estate of any deceased person.\n  5. To take, accept and execute any and all such trusts, duties and\npowers of whatever nature or description as may be conferred upon or\nentrusted or committed to it by any person or persons, or any body\npolitic, corporation, domestic or foreign, or other authority by grant,\nassignment, transfer, devise, bequest or otherwise, or which may be\nentrusted or committed or transferred to it or vested in it by order of\nany court of competent jurisdiction, or any surrogate, and to receive,\ntake, manage, hold and dispose of according to the terms of such trust,\nduty or power, any property or estate, real or personal, which may be\nthe subject of any such trust, duty or power.\n  Provided that no trust company shall have any right or power to make\nany contract, or to accept or execute any trust whatever, which it would\nnot be lawful for any individual to make, accept or execute.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>