<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-1004"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-1004"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1004"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-1004/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-1004/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-1004/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-1004/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1004">
        <num>1004</num>
        <heading>Certificates; corrections</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1004. Certificates; corrections. Any certificate or other instrument\nrelating to a corporation or foreign corporation filed by the\nsuperintendent under this chapter may be corrected with respect to any\ninformality or error apparent on the face or defect in the execution\nthereof including the deletion of any matter not permitted to be stated\ntherein. A certificate, entitled "Certificate of correction of\n............. (correct title of certificate and name of corporation or\nforeign corporation)" shall be signed, verified or acknowledged as\nprovided in this chapter with respect to the instrument being corrected\nand delivered to the superintendent. It shall set forth the name of the\ncorporation or foreign corporation, the date the instrument to be\ncorrected was filed by the superintendent, the provision in the\ninstrument as corrected or eliminated and if the execution was\ndefective, the proper execution. The filing of the certificate by the\nsuperintendent shall not alter the effective time of the instrument\nbeing corrected, which shall remain as its original effective date, and\nshall not affect any right or liability accrued or incurred before such\nfiling. The name of the corporation or foreign corporation may not be\nchanged or corrected under this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>