<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-109"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-109"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="109"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-109/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-109/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_109">
        <num>109</num>
        <heading>Closing of books; profits; how to be computed</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All income received or properly accrued, provided that no interest\nshall be accrued upon interest-bearing assets upon which a default of\nprincipal or interest has existed for a period which shall be determined\nby the superintendent except interest-bearing assets secured by\ncollateral the ascertained value of which is at least equal to the\namount at which the asset plus all interest accrued thereon is carried\non its books.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Realizable profits resulting from a revaluation to ascertained\ncurrent market of a foreign exchange position, provided that a\nconsistent practice is followed in the deduction from gross income of\nlosses so resulting.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Amounts added to cost or charged to amortization reserve for the\npurpose of amortizing discounts on securities purchased for less than\npar, provided that no discount shall be amortized on securities upon\nwhich a default exists.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any profits actually realized from the sale or other disposition\nof securities, real estate or other property.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Amounts recovered on assets previously charged off, including\namounts allowed by the superintendent on account of assets previously\ndisallowed by him and other amounts allowed by the board of directors on\naccount of assets previously disallowed by it. For the purpose of this\nparagraph amounts transferred to valuation reserves shall be considered\nas amounts charged off.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provided the superintendent shall have approved, and only to the\nextent of such approval, any increase in the book value of the real\nestate and building or buildings thereon used by it as its place or\nplaces of business.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such other items as the superintendent, in his discretion, may\npermit to be included.\n  3. To determine the amount of net profits for such period, the\nfollowing items shall be deducted from gross income:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All expenses paid or properly accrued in the transaction of its\nbusiness and the management of its affairs.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Interest paid or properly accrued upon debts owing by it.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Amounts deducted from cost or credited to amortization reserve for\nthe purpose of amortizing premiums on securities purchased for more than\npar.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_109__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All losses sustained, including assets, or portions thereof,\ndisallowed by the superintendent, and other assets, or portions thereof,\ndisallowed by the board of directors. With the approval of the\nsuperintendent, any items referred to in this paragraph may be excluded.\nFor the purposes of this paragraph, provision for disallowances may be\neffected by charge off or by establishment of valuation reserve and any\nexisting valuation reserve may be deducted from the related asset in\ndetermining the amount of loss sustained.\n  4. The balance thus obtained shall constitute the net profits of such\nbank or trust company for such period.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>