<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-125"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-125"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="125"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-125/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-125/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_125">
        <num>125</num>
        <heading>Reports to superintendent; penalty for failure to make</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 125. Reports to superintendent; penalty for failure to make. 1.\nWithin fifteen days after service upon it of the notice provided for by\nsection thirty-seven of this chapter, every bank and every trust company\nshall make a written report of its financial condition to the\nsuperintendent, which report shall be in such form and contain such\ninformation as the superintendent of financial services may prescribe.\n  2. Every bank and every trust company shall also make such other\nspecial reports to the superintendent as he may from time to time\nrequire, in such form and at such date as may be prescribed by him and\nsuch reports shall, if required by him, be subscribed and affirmed as\ntrue under the penalties of perjury.\n  3. If any bank or trust company shall fail to make any report required\nby or pursuant to this section, on or before the day designated for the\nmaking thereof, or shall fail to include therein any prescribed matter,\nsuch bank or trust company shall forfeit to the people of the state an\namount as determined pursuant to section forty-four-a of this chapter\nfor every day that such report shall be delayed or withheld, and for\nevery day that it shall fail to report any such omitted matter, unless\nthe time therefor shall have been extended by the superintendent as\nprovided in article two of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>