<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-14-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-14-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-02-28" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="14-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-14-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-14-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-14-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-14-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_14_F">
        <num>14-F</num>
        <heading>Power of the superintendent of financial services to require the provision of basic banking services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the maximum amount which a banking institution may require as an\ninitial deposit, if any;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the maximum amount a banking institution may require as a minimum\nbalance, if any, to maintain such account;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>eight withdrawal transactions for account holders under sixty-five\nyears of age, and twelve withdrawal transactions for account holders\nsixty-five years of age or older, including those conducted at\nelectronic facilities, during any periodic cycle at no additional charge\nto the account holder; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the maximum amount a banking institution may charge per periodic\ncycle for the use of such account.\n  3. With respect to any transactions in excess of the number specified\nin accordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of this section,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\na banking institution may impose a reasonable per-transaction charge, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it may impose the fees and charges normally applied to other\nconsumer transaction accounts available at that banking institution\nprovided that any charge per periodic cycle imposed hereunder must be\nreduced by the charge imposed under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of\nthis section; provided however, that at no time shall the fees and\ncharges on the basic banking account exceed the amount that is normally\napplied to other consumer transaction accounts available at that banking\ninstitution.\n  4. A banking institution may require as a condition for opening or\nmaintaining a basic banking account,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the holder of a basic\nbanking account be a resident of this state; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the direct deposit\nto the banking institution of recurring payments such as, but not\nlimited to, social security, wage, or pension payments where direct\ndeposit is available to both the consumer and the banking institution.\n  5. Except as provided in this section and any rules and regulations\npromulgated hereunder, a basic banking account may be offered subject to\nthe same rules, conditions and terms normally applicable to other\nconsumer transaction accounts offered by the banking institution;\nprovided that the fees and charges for specific services other than\nthose otherwise provided in this section shall not exceed those imposed\nby the banking institution for the same services in connection with\nother consumer transaction accounts offered by the banking institution.\n  6. No banking institution shall be required to permit any person to\nopen or maintain a basic banking account pursuant to this section if\nsuch person maintains another consumer transaction account either at\nthat banking institution or any other banking institution.\n  7. In lieu of the basic banking account required by this section, a\nbanking institution may make available an alternative account or other\nbanking services determined by the superintendent to be at least as\nadvantageous to consumers as the basic banking account.\n  8.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a banking institution posts in the public area of its\noffices notice of the availability of its other consumer transaction\naccounts, it shall also post equally conspicuous notice in such public\nareas and in the same manner the availability of its basic banking\naccounts. Where a banking institution makes available in such public\nareas material describing the terms of its other consumer transaction\naccounts, it shall also make comparable descriptive material available\nin the same such areas and in the same manner for its basic banking\naccount.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where a banking institution posts in the public area of its\noffices the notices for information required in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, it shall also post equally conspicuous notice in such\npublic areas and in the same manner, of the department's toll free\nconsumer's hotline telephone number, where consumers can file complaints\nif a consumer is not satisfied with the services a banking institution\nprovides.\n  9. For purposes of this section:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"banking institution" means any bank, trust company, savings bank,\nsavings and loan association, or credit union, or branch of a foreign\nbanking corporation the deposits of which are insured by the Federal\nDeposit Insurance Corporation, which is incorporated, chartered,\norganized or licensed under the laws of this state or any other state or\nthe United States, and, in the ordinary course of its business, offers\nconsumer transaction accounts to the general public or, in the case of a\ncredit union, to its members;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_14_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"consumer transaction account" means a demand deposit account,\nnegotiable order of withdrawal account, share draft account or similar\naccount used primarily for personal, family or household purposes.\n  10. For purposes of this section, any banking insititution which\noffers share draft accounts shall use the term "basic share draft\naccount" instead of "basic banking account".\n  11. If any provision of this section, or the application of such\nprovision to any person or circumstance shall be held invalid, the\nremainder of this section, and the application of such provisions\nthereof to persons or circumstances other than those as to which it is\nheld invalid, shall not be affected thereby.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>