<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-175"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-175"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="175"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-175/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-175/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-175/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-175/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_175">
        <num>175</num>
        <heading>Books and records</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 175. Books and records. 1. Every private banker shall keep separate\nand complete books of account in which shall be promptly entered the\ndetails of all business transacted by him as a private banker including\nstatements in detail of the liabilities incurred by him as a private\nbanker and of the securities or property in which funds held by him as a\nprivate banker have been invested.\n  2. Every private banker shall conform his or her methods of keeping\nhis or her books and records to such orders in respect thereto as shall\nhave been made and promulgated by the superintendent pursuant to article\ntwo of this chapter. Any private banker who refuses or neglects to obey\nany such order shall be subject to a penalty of an amount as determined\npursuant to section forty-four of this chapter for each day that such\nrefusal or neglect continues.\n  3. Every private banker shall preserve all his records of final entry,\nincluding cards used under the card system and deposit tickets, for a\nperiod of at least six years from the date of making the same or from\nthe date of the last entry thereon; provided, however, that preservation\nof photographic reproduction thereof or records in photographic form\nshall constitute compliance with the requirements of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>