<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2">
        <num>2</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such company is organized under or\nsubject to the provisions of article twelve-A of this chapter; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nall of the stock and shares, other than stock or shares required by law\nto qualify directors of such investment company, are or are to be owned\nby trust companies or national banks having trust powers and having\ntheir principal offices within the state of New York or their nominees\nor the nominees of such corporate fiduciaries and individual\nco-fiduciaries.\n  11. Banking organizations. The term, "banking organizations," when\nused in this chapter, means and includes all banks, trust companies,\nprivate bankers, savings banks, safe deposit companies, savings and loan\nassociations, credit unions and investment companies.\n  12. Time deposits. The term, "time deposits," when used in this\nchapter, and except as provided otherwise by regulation of the\nsuperintendent of financial services, means all deposits the payment of\nwhich cannot legally be required within fourteen days.\n  13. Demand deposits. The term, "demand deposits," when used in this\nchapter, and except as provided otherwise by regulation of the\nsuperintendent of financial services, means deposits payment of which\ncan legally be required within fourteen days.\n  14. Net demand deposits. The term, "net demand deposits," when used in\nthis chapter, means the total of all deposits, and of all amounts due to\nbanking corporations and private bankers and of all amounts due on\ncertified and officers' checks, letters of credit and travelers' checks\nsold for cash, and for unpaid dividends, less the following items:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Time deposits;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Amounts due on demand from banking corporations organized under\nthe laws of the United States or any state of the United States and\nprivate bankers other than a federal reserve bank and reserve\ndepositaries.\n  15. Reserves on hand. The term, "reserves on hand," when used in this\nchapter, means the reserves against deposits kept in the vault of any\nbanking organization.\n  16. Reserves on deposit. The term, "reserves on deposit," when used in\nthis chapter, means the reserves against deposits maintained with a\nfederal reserve bank located in this state and with reserve depositaries\nby any banking organization, pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.\n  17. Total reserves. The term, "total reserves," when used in this\nchapter, means the aggregate of reserves on hand and reserves on deposit\nmaintained pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.\n  18. Reserve depositary. The term, "reserve depositary," when used in\nthis chapter, means a banking corporation or private banker designated\nby the superintendent as a depositary for reserves on deposit.\n  19. Stockholder. The term, "stockholder," when used in this chapter,\nunless otherwise qualified, means a person who appears by the books of a\nstock corporation to be the owner and holder of one or more shares of\nthe stock of such corporation.\n  20. Shareholder. The term, "shareholder," when used in this chapter,\nmeans a member of a mutual savings and loan association or a member of a\ncredit union.\n  21. Population. The term, "population," when used in this chapter,\nmeans population as determined by the latest federal census; or when\nused in connection with the words "unincorporated village," as\ndetermined by the superintendent from the best available sources of\ninformation.\n  22. Capital stock. The term, "capital stock," when used in this\nchapter in connection with any stock corporation subject to this\nchapter, means the aggregate par value of all outstanding shares of\nevery class.\n  24. Deed...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2__subsec_b__subsec_28">
            <num>(28)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Department. The term "department" means the department of\nfinancial services of this state.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2__subsec_b__subsec_29">
            <num>(29)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Superintendent. The term "superintendent" means the\nsuperintendent of financial services of this state.\n  30. Consummation of a mortgage loan. The term "consummation of a\nmortgage loan" means, for purposes of the act of congress entitled Truth\nin Lending Act and the regulations thereunder and the Real Estate\nSettlement Procedures Act of 1974, as amended, and the regulations\nthereunder, when the applicant for the mortgage loan executes the\npromissory note and mortgage including by electronic signature, in\naccordance with applicable federal and state laws, rules, and\nregulations.\n  31. Members of a borrower's social network. The term "members of a\nborrower's social network" means a group of individuals authorized by a\nborrower to be part of his or her social media communications and\nnetwork.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>