<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2001"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-2001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2001">
        <num>2001</num>
        <heading>General corporate powers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To sue and be sued in all courts and to participate in actions and\nproceedings, whether judicial, administrative, arbitrative or otherwise,\nin like cases as natural persons.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To have a corporate seal, and to alter such seal at pleasure, and\nto use it by causing it or a facsimile to be affixed or impressed or\nreproduced in any other manner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To adopt, amend or repeal by-laws, including emergency by-laws\nmade pursuant to subdivision sixteen of section twelve of the state\nemergency defense act, relating to the business of the corporation, the\nconduct of its affairs, its rights or powers or the rights or powers of\nits stockholders, directors or officers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To make donations, irrespective of corporate benefit, for the\npublic welfare or for community fund, hospital, charitable, educational,\nscientific, civic or similar purposes, and in time of war or other\nnational emergency in aid thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To pay pensions, establish and carry out pension, profit-sharing,\nsavings, thrift and other retirement, incentive and benefit plans,\ntrusts and provisions for any or all of its directors, officers and\nemployees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To have perpetual existence.\n  2. Every corporation, subject to any limitations or other specific\nprovisions contained in this chapter or any other statute of this state\nor its organization certificate, shall have such of the following powers\nas shall be appropriate in conducting the business of the corporation:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To purchase, receive, take by grant, gift, devise, bequest or\notherwise, lease, or otherwise acquire, own, hold, improve, employ, use\nand otherwise deal in and with, real or personal property, or any\ninterest therein, wherever situated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To sell, convey, lease, exchange, transfer or otherwise dispose\nof, all or any of its property or any interest therein, wherever\nsituated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To make contracts, give guarantees and incur liabilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To do business, carry on its operations, and have offices and\nexercise the powers granted by this chapter in any jurisdiction within\nor without the United States.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To elect or appoint officers, employees and other agents of the\ncorporation, define their duties, fix their compensation and the\ncompensation of directors, and to indemnify corporate personnel.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To be a promoter, partner, member, associate or manager of other\nbusiness enterprises or ventures, or to the extent permitted in any\nother jurisdiction to be an incorporator of other corporations of any\ntype or kind; provided, however, that nothing contained in this\nparagraph shall authorize a banking organization to engage in any\nactivity not otherwise authorized by the laws of New York or by\nregulations of the superintendent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2001__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To have and exercise all other powers necessary or appropriate in\nconducting the business of the corporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>