<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-207"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-207"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="207"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-207/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-207/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_207">
        <num>207</num>
        <heading>Service of process on unlicensed corporation formed under laws other than the statutes of this state</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_207__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Delivered personally without this state to such foreign banking\ncorporation by a person and in the manner authorized to serve process by\nlaw in the jurisdiction in which service is made, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_207__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sent by or on behalf of the plaintiff to such foreign banking\ncorporation by registered mail with return receipt requested, at the\npost office address specified for the purpose of mailing process, on\nfile in the department of financial services, or with any official or\nbody performing the equivalent function, in the jurisdiction of its\nincorporation, or if no such address is there specified, to its\nregistered or other office there specified, or if no such office is\nthere specified, to the last address of such foreign banking corporation\nknown to the plaintiff.\n  3. Proof of service shall be by affidavit of compliance with this\nsection filed, together with the process, within thirty days after such\nservice, with the clerk of the court in which the action or special\nproceeding is pending. If a copy of the process is mailed in accordance\nwith this section, there shall be filed with the affidavit of compliance\neither the return receipt signed by such foreign banking corporation or\nother official proof of delivery or, if acceptance was refused by it,\nthe original envelope with a notation by the postal authorities that\nacceptance was refused. If acceptance was refused, a copy of the notice\nand process together with notice of the mailing by registered mail and\nrefusal to accept shall be promptly sent to such foreign banking\ncorporation at the same address by ordinary mail and the affidavit of\ncompliance shall so state. Service of process shall be complete ten days\nafter such papers are filed with the clerk of the court. The refusal to\naccept delivery of the registered mail or to sign the return receipt\nshall not affect the validity of the service and such foreign banking\ncorporation refusing to accept such registered mail shall be charged\nwith knowledge of the contents thereof.\n  4. Service made as provided in this section shall have the same force\nas personal service made within this state.\n  5. Nothing in this section shall affect the right t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>