<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-208"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-208"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="208"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-208/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-208/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_208">
        <num>208</num>
        <heading>Nondiscriminatory treatment of insured state banks and national banks</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 208. Nondiscriminatory treatment of insured state banks and national\nbanks. Notwithstanding any other laws of this state, a state bank, which\nis incorporated in another state and whose deposits are insured by\nFederal Deposit Insurance Corporation, shall have the same protection,\nprivileges and immunities, including the right to sue, collect debts,\nrealize on collateral security, enforce liens, claims and obligations,\nand protect its property in this state, as a national bank whose\nprincipal office is located in the same state as such state bank, and\nsuch state bank and its shares, securities and evidences of indebtedness\nshall enjoy the same privileges, protections and immunities as those of\nsuch a national bank and shall not be subject to any disability,\nincapacity, restriction, regulation, penalty, fee, fine or taxation\nwhich is not imposed by this state in the case of such a national bank,\nprovided however that this section shall not apply with respect to any\nstate bank and its shares, securities and evidences of indebtedness\nunless such state bank's state of incorporation has a statute with\nprovisions substantially similar to this section which is applicable to\na state bank incorporated in this state. As used in this section the\nterm "state bank" shall mean any commercial bank or trust company.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>