<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-209"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-209"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="209"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-209/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-209/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_209">
        <num>209</num>
        <heading>Restrictions on executive officers of foreign banking corporations and national banks</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_209__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an executive officer and (ii) a director of the bank holding\ncompany of which such foreign banking corporation is a subsidiary, and\nof one or more of the banking institutions which are subsidiaries of\nsuch bank holding company.\n  2. No executive officer of a national bank, federal savings bank or\nfederal savings association, the principal office of which institution\nis located in this state, may be an executive officer, director or\ntrustee of a bank or trust company, savings bank, savings and loan\nassociation, bank holding company or foreign banking corporation\nmaintaining a branch in this state, unless permission therefor has been\ngranted by the superintendent pursuant to the provisions of subdivision\nthree of this section, except that</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_209__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>an executive officer of a\nnational bank located in this state, which is a subsidiary of a bank\nholding company may be</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_209__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an executive officer and (ii) a director of\nthe bank holding company and of one or more banking institutions which\nare subsidiaries of such bank holding company.\n  3. The superintendent shall have the power to determine by regulation\nwho shall be considered, under the provisions of this subdivision, to be\nan executive officer, and by regulation, to grant permission to an\nexecutive officer of a foreign banking corporation maintaining a branch\nin this state and to an executive officer of a national bank located in\nthis state, to be at the same time an executive officer, trustee or\ndirector or both an executive officer and a trustee or director of a\nbank or trust company, savings bank, savings and loan association,\nnational bank, federal savings bank or federal savings association, the\nprincipal office of which is located in this state, bank holding\ncompany, and foreign banking corporation maintaining a branch in this\nstate. Such permission may be granted only if in the judgment of the\nsuperintendent such service by the executive officer will be consistent\nwith the policy of the state of New York as declared in section ten of\nthis chapter. The superintendent shall have the power to revoke such\npermission whenever the superintendent finds, after reasonable notice\nand an opportunity to be heard, that the public interest requires such\nrevocation.\n  4. For the purposes of this subdivision, the terms "subsidiary",\n"banking institution" and "bank holding company" shall each be given the\nsame meaning as is contained in their respective definition in section\none hundred forty-one of this chapter, except that the definition of the\nterm "banking institution" is modified to include a national bank,\nfederal savings bank or federal savings association, the principal\noffice of which institution is located in this state, and a foreign\nbanking corporation maintaining a branch in this state.\n  5. All other restrictions and limitations imposed by this chapte...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>