<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-213"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-213"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="213"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-213/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-213/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_213">
        <num>213</num>
        <heading>Board of directors</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 213. Board of directors. 1. All the corporate powers of such\ncorporation shall be exercised by a board of directors consisting of a\nmaximum of thirty persons, all of whom shall be of full age, residents\nof the state and at least one-half of whom shall be citizens of the\nUnited States.\n  2. The president of such corporation, who shall be appointed by the\nboard, shall serve as a director.\n  3. At each annual meeting of such corporation, the members of such\ncorporation shall elect up to ten directors for a term of one year, who\nshall, to the extent possible, represent different economic regions as\ndefined in section two hundred eleven of this article. The exact number\nshall be established in the by-laws by the board of directors. In such\nelections, members of such corporation shall have one vote each.\n  4. At such annual meetings the stockholders of such corporation shall\nelect up to seven directors for a term of one year each. The exact\nnumber shall be established in the by-laws by the board of directors.\n  5. One director shall be appointed by any of the entities that are\nmembers or stockholders of such corporation and whose membership or\nstockholder interest meets a minimum commitment as established in the\nby-laws by the board of directors.\n  6. The directors elected by the members and the stockholders shall\nelect three additional directors: one representing minority interests,\none representing women's interests, and one representing regional or\nlocal development corporations' interests.\n  7.  The state commissioner of the department of economic development\nshall be a director exofficio.\n  7-a. Two directors shall be appointed by the governor, who shall serve\nat the pleasure of the governor; one director shall be appointed by the\ntemporary president of the senate, who shall serve at the pleasure of\nthe temporary president; one director shall be appointed by the senate\nminority leader, who shall serve at the pleasure of the minority leader;\nand one appointed by the assembly minority leader, who shall serve at\nthe pleasure of the minority leader; and one director shall be appointed\nby the speaker of the assembly, who shall serve at the pleasure of the\nspeaker.\n  8. If any director shall lose his citizenship or shall cease to be a\nresident of the state, he shall immediately vacate his position as a\ndirector and such position shall thereupon be deemed vacant.\n  9. If any vacancy occurs in the elected membership of the board of\ndirectors through death, resignation or otherwise, the remaining\ndirectors shall elect a person to fill such vacancy for the unexpired\nterm.\n  10. Upon the expiration of their terms, the elected directors shall\ncontinue as such until their successors have been elected and have\nqualified.\n  11. The board of directors shall elect one of its members as chairman\nand one of its members as vice-chairman of such board, shall adopt\nby-laws for such corporation, and may appoint such officers and\nemployees as it deems advisable.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>