<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-23"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-23"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="23"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-23/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-23/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_23">
        <num>23</num>
        <heading>Acceptance or rejection of certificate; investigation fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 23. Acceptance or rejection of certificate; investigation fees.\nWithin twenty days after the receipt by the superintendent of any\norganization certificate of a corporation proposed to be organized under\nthis chapter, or any private banker's certificate together with such\ndocuments as are required to be filed therewith, the superintendent\nshall, if such certificate and such accompanying documents comply in\nform and substance with the requirements of this chapter, file such\ncertificate for examination and note thereon the date of such filing. If\nsuch certificate or such accompanying documents do not comply in all\nrespects with the requirements of this chapter, the superintendent\nshall, within twenty days after receipt thereof, return them to the\npersons from whom they were received, calling attention to the defect or\ndefects therein.\n  At the time of submission of the certificate and accompanying\ndocuments an investigation fee as prescribed pursuant to section\neighteen-a of this article shall be paid to the superintendent, to be\nretained by him or her if the certificate and accompanying documents are\nfiled. If the certificate and accompanying documents are not filed\nbecause of defects therein, the investigation fee is to be returned with\nsuch papers to the persons from whom they were received.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>