<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-235-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-235-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="235-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-235-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-235-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-235-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-235-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_235_B">
        <num>235-B</num>
        <heading>Effect of usury</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 235-b. Effect of usury. The knowingly taking, receiving, reserving,\nor charging by a savings bank of interest at a rate greater than six per\ncentum per annum, as computed pursuant to this section, or in excess of\nsuch greater rate of interest as may be authorized by law, shall be held\nand adjudged a forfeiture of the entire interest which the note or other\nevidence of debt carries with it, or which has been agreed to be paid\nthereon. If such greater rate of interest has been paid, the person\npaying the same or his legal representatives may recover from the\nsavings bank twice the entire amount of the interest thus paid. Nothing\nin this section shall be deemed to affect the powers of any savings bank\nwith respect to loans or investments it is authorized to make.\n  * ยง 235-b. Effect of usury. The knowingly taking, receiving,\nreserving, or charging by a savings bank of interest at a rate greater\nthan such rate of interest as may be authorized by law shall be held and\nadjudged a forfeiture of the entire interest which the note or other\nevidence of debt carries with it, or which has been agreed to be paid\nthereon. If such greater rate of interest has been paid, the person\npaying the same or his legal representatives may recover from the\nsavings bank twice the entire amount of the interest thus paid, if\naction therefor is brought within two years from the time the excess of\ninterest is taken. Nothing in this section shall be deemed to affect the\npowers of any savings bank with respect to loans or investments it is\nauthorized to make.\n  * NB Effectiveness of amendments made by chapter 349/1989 ยง7 expired\nSeptember 1, 1971 per ยง13 of such chapter\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>