<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-248"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-248"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="248"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-248/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-248/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-248/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-248/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_248">
        <num>248</num>
        <heading>Removal and forfeiture of office of trustee</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall fail to comply with any of the provisions of this article\nrelating to his official oath and declaration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall become disqualified for any of the reasons specified in this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall have failed to attend the regular meetings of the board of\ntrustees and also of any committee of the board of which he is a member,\nfor a period of six successive months, unless excused by the board for\nsuch failure by resolution adopted at the first or second regular\nmeeting of the board after expiration of such six months period and\nentered upon its minutes; provided, however, that a trustee who has\nforfeited or vacated his office by reason of such failure to attend\nmeetings shall not be eligible for re-election until the expiration of\none year from the date of the first regular meeting of the board at\nwhich a resolution could have been adopted by it, as herein provided, to\nexcuse such failure. A copy of such resolution shall be transmitted to\nthe superintendent by the savings bank within five days after its\nadoption.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall violate any of the provisions of this article imposing\nrestrictions upon trustees and officers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Shall reach the mandatory retirement age, if any, prescribed in\nthe by-laws of the savings bank.\n  3. A trustee who has forfeited or vacated his office shall not be\neligible for re-election, except when the forfeiture or vacancy occurred\nsolely by reason of his\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Failure to comply with the provisions of this article relating to\nhis official oath and declaration; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Failure to attend the regular meetings of the board of trustees or\nneglect of his official duties as prescribed in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision two of this section; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Disqualification through becoming a non-resident, or becoming a\ntrustee, officer or employee of another savings bank, or becoming a\ndirector or trustee of a bank, trust company, national bank, mortgage or\ntitle company and such disqualification shall have been removed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_248__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Resignation while free of any of the disqualifications specified\nin this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>