<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-28-BB"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-28-BB"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-11-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="28-BB"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-28-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-28-BB/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-28-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-28-BB/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_28_BB">
        <num>28-BB</num>
        <heading>Credit needs of local communities; mortgage bankers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Activities conducted by the mortgage banker to ascertain credit\nneeds of its community, including the extent of the mortgage banker's\nefforts to communicate with members of its community regarding the\nservices being provided by the mortgage banker;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The extent of the mortgage banker's marketing and special programs\nto make members of the community aware of the services offered by the\nmortgage banker;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The extent of the mortgage banker's participation in community\noutreach, community development or redevelopment, and educational\nprograms;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The extent of participation by the mortgage banker's board of\ndirectors, advisory committee, managing members or executive management\nor equivalent body or person, in formulating the mortgage banker's\npolicies and reviewing its performance with respect to the purposes of\nthis section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any practices intended to discourage application for types of\ncredit offered by the mortgage banker;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The geographic distribution of the mortgage banker's credit\nextensions, credit applications, and credit denials;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Evidence of prohibited discriminatory or other illegal credit\npractices;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The mortgage banker's record of opening and closing offices and\nproviding services at offices;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The mortgage banker's participation in governmentally-insured,\nguaranteed or subsidized loan programs for housing;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The mortgage banker's ability to meet various community credit\nneeds based on its financial condition, size, legal impediments, local\neconomic condition and other factors; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Other factors that, in the judgment of the superintendent,\nreasonably bear upon the extent to which a mortgage banker is helping to\nmeet the credit needs of its entire community.\n  2. In assessing the record of performance of a mortgage banker\npursuant to the provisions of subdivision one of this section, the\nsuperintendent may, where he or she deems it appropriate, provide for\npublic hearings when an objection to the mortgage banker's application\nor notice has been submitted.\n  3. An assessment of a mortgage banker's record of performance under\nsubdivision one of this section may be the basis for denying an\napplication under the provisions of this section.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or other law to\nthe contrary, the term mortgage banker when used in this section shall\nmean and include mortgage bankers licensed pursuant to section five\nhundred ninety-one of this chapter that originate a minimum number of\nloans annually, such number to be set by regulation promulgated by the\nsuperintendent.\n  5. The superintendent is hereby authorized and empowered to promulgate\nrules and regulations effectuating the provisions of this section,\nincluding any rules and regulations providing that the assessment of\nmortgage bankers shall be made on a graduated numerical basis.\n  6. If any clause, sentence, paragraph, subdivision or part of this\nsection or the application thereof to any person, firm, or corporation,\nor circumstance shall be adjudged by any court of competent jurisdiction\nto be invalid or unconstitutional, such judgment shall not affect,\nimpair or invalidate the remainder thereof, but shall be confined</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_BB__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in\nits operation to the clause, sentence, paragraph, subdivision, or part\nof this section or (ii) in its application to the person, firm or\ncorporation, or circumstance, directly involved in the controversy in\nwhich such judgment shall have been rendered.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>