<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-29"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-29"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="29"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-29/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-29/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-29/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-29/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_29">
        <num>29</num>
        <heading>Branch offices; public accommodation offices; approval or refusal; certificate; investigation fee</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 29. Branch offices; public accommodation offices; approval or\nrefusal; certificate; investigation fee. When a banking organization\nseeks to open a branch office or public accommodation office, it shall\nsubmit a written application to the superintendent. The application\nshall contain such information as the superintendent deems necessary. At\nthe time of making such application, an investigation fee as prescribed\npursuant to section eighteen-a of this article shall be paid to the\nsuperintendent for each branch office or public accommodation office for\nwhich leave to open is sought. If the superintendent finds that the\nopening of the branch office or public accommodation office is\nconsistent with the declaration of policy set forth in section ten of\nthis article and that the applicant is in compliance with section\ntwenty-eight-b of this article, he or she shall issue a certificate in\ntriplicate under his or her hand and the official seal of the department\nauthorizing the opening and occupation of such branch office or public\naccommodation office and specifying the date on or after which and the\nconditions under which it may be opened and the place where it shall be\nlocated. The superintendent shall cause one of such triplicate\ncertificates to be transmitted to the applicant, another to be filed in\nthe office of the department and the third to be filed in the office of\nthe clerk of the county in which the principal office of the applicant\nis located. If the superintendent shall not find that the opening of the\nbranch or public accommodation office is consistent with the declaration\nof policy set forth in section ten of this article or that the applicant\nis in compliance with section twenty-eight-b of this article, he or she\nshall notify the applicant that the application has been denied.\n  No investigation fee for branch applications shall be collected from\napplicants if such branch applications are filed in conjunction with\nproceedings under section one hundred thirty-six, four hundred ten or\nsubdivision eight of section six hundred five of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>