<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="31"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-31/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-31/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-31/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-31/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_31">
        <num>31</num>
        <heading>Index of persons entitled to unclaimed amounts; payment to persons entitled; deduction of service charge</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 31. Index of persons entitled to unclaimed amounts; payment to\npersons entitled; deduction of service charge. An index shall be kept in\nthe office of the department of the names of all persons for whom the\nsuperintendent holds in trust any unclaimed amounts. The superintendent\nmay pay over any such amount which he holds in trust amounting to over\nthree dollars to any person who shall show by evidence satisfactory to\nthe superintendent that he is lawfully entitled to receive it. In cases\nof doubt or conflicting claims, he may require of the claimant an order\nof the supreme court authorizing and directing the payment thereof. The\nsuperintendent shall be held harmless and shall not be liable to any\nsubsequent claimant for any payment made by him in good faith.  The\nsuperintendent shall deduct from the amount of any claim of fifty\ndollars or more allowed by him or ordered by the court to be paid a\nservice charge of one percentum of the amount thereof, but in no event\nless than one dollar and, in addition, any costs, disbursements and\nlegal fees which the court may allow. The amount so deducted shall be\npaid into the state treasury in accordance with the provisions of\nsection seventeen of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>