<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-321"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-321"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="321"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-321/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-321/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-321/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-321/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_321">
        <num>321</num>
        <heading>Change of location; change of designation of principal office</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 321. Change of location; change of designation of principal office.\nAny safe deposit company may make a written application to the\nsuperintendent for leave to change its place or one of its places of\nbusiness to any place at which it could be authorized, under the\nprovisions of this chapter, to open and maintain a branch office or for\nleave to change the designation of its principal office to a branch\noffice and to change the designation of one of its branch offices to its\nprincipal office. The application shall state the reasons for such\nproposed change, and shall be accompanied by a copy of a resolution\nauthorizing the making of the application, certified by a principal\nofficer of the safe deposit company to have been adopted by vote of a\nmajority of its entire board of directors at a meeting of such board,\nduly convened and held, as well as by a fee as prescribed pursuant to\nsection eighteen-a of this chapter. If the proposed place of business is\nwithin the limits of the village, borough or city if in a city not\ndivided into boroughs, in which the place of business sought to be\nchanged is located, such change may be made upon the written approval of\nthe superintendent. If the proposed place of business is beyond such\nlimits, notice of intention to make such application, signed by a\nprincipal officer of the safe deposit company shall be published once a\nweek for two successive weeks in a newspaper to be designated by the\nsuperintendent for the purpose, in accordance with the provisions of\narticle two of this chapter. If the superintendent shall grant his\ncertificate authorizing the change of location, as provided in article\ntwo of this chapter, the safe deposit company may, upon or after the day\nspecified in the certificate, remove its property and effects to the\nlocation designated therein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>