<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-329"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-329"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="329"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-329/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-329/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-329/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-329/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_329">
        <num>329</num>
        <heading>Reports to superintendent; penalty for failure to make</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 329. Reports to superintendent; penalty for failure to make. On or\nbefore the first day of February in each year, every safe deposit\ncompany shall make a written report to the superintendent of financial\nservices which shall contain a statement of its condition on the morning\nof the first day of January in said year. Every such report shall be\nsubscribed and affirmed as true under the penalties of perjury,\naccording to the best of their knowledge and belief, by the two\nprincipal officers in charge of the affairs of the safe deposit company\nat the time of such subscription and shall state that the usual business\nof the safe deposit company has been transacted at the location required\nby this article and not elsewhere.\n  Every safe deposit company shall also make such other special reports\nto the superintendent as he may from time to time require, which shall\nbe in such form and filed at such date as may be prescribed by the\nsuperintendent and shall, if required by him, be subscribed and affirmed\nas true under the penalties of perjury.\n  If any safe deposit company shall fail to make any report required by\nthis section on or before the day designated for the making thereof, or\nshall fail to include therein any matter required by the superintendent,\nit shall forfeit to the people of the state an amount as determined\npursuant to section forty-four-a of this chapter for every day that such\nreport shall be delayed or withheld, and for every day that it shall\nfail to report any such omitted matter, unless the time therefor shall\nhave been extended by the superintendent as provided in article two of\nthis chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>