<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-341"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-341"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="341"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-341/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-341/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_341">
        <num>341</num>
        <heading>Application for license; fees; capital requirements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_341__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As\nused in this article, the term master license shall mean an original\nlicense granted to a person or entity.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_341__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As used in this article, the term supplemental license shall mean\nthe license granted to a person or entity having a master license for\nadditional licensed locations.\n  2. An application for a master license shall be in writing, under\noath, and in the form prescribed by the superintendent and shall contain\nsuch information as the superintendent may require by regulations. The\napplication shall set forth all of the locations at which the applicant\nseeks to conduct business hereunder. At the time of making the\napplication for a master license, the applicant shall pay to the\nsuperintendent a fee as prescribed pursuant to section eighteen-a of\nthis chapter for each proposed location for investigating the\napplication.\n  3. In addition to the investigation fee and annual license fee every\nlicensee hereunder shall pay to the superintendent the sums provided to\nbe paid under the provisions of section seventeen of the banking law.\n  4. In connection with an application for a master license, the\napplicant shall submit an affidavit of financial solvency noting such\ncapitalization requirements and access to such credit as may be\nprescribed by the regulations of the superintendent.\n  5. The applicant shall also prove, in form satisfactory to the\nsuperintendent, that the applicant has available for the operation of\nsuch business at the location or locations specified in the application\nliquid assets of at least fifty thousand dollars. This amount shall be\nmaintained for the period within which the licensee makes loans in the\namounts prescribed in section three hundred forty of this article at\nsuch location.\n  6. If a person or entity holding a master license seeks to open\nanother location for the conduct of activities licensable under this\narticle, the licensee shall first submit written notification of this\nfact to the superintendent. The notification shall contain the address\nof the new location and the master license number. An investigation fee\n...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>