<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-345"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-345"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="345"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-345/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-345/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-345/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-345/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_345">
        <num>345</num>
        <heading>Application for acquisition of control of licensed lender by purchase of stock</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_345__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "person" includes an\nindividual, partnership, corporation, association or any other\norganization and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_345__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "control" means the possession, directly\nor indirectly, of the power to direct or cause the direction of the\nmanagement and policies of a person, whether by means of the ownership\nof the voting stock or equity interests of such person or of one or more\npersons controlling such person, by means of a contractual arrangement,\nor otherwise. Control shall be presumed to exist if any person directly\nor indirectly owns, controls or holds with the power to vote ten per\ncentum or more of the voting stock or equity interests of the person\ndesirous of continuing to maintain and operate a licensee's place of\nbusiness or of any entity which directly or indirectly controls such\nperson. The superintendent may, upon the application of a licensee or\nany such person or entity, determine whether or not the ownership,\ncontrol or holding of such voting stock or equity interests constitutes\nor would constitute control for purposes of this subdivision.\n  2. For a period of six months from the date of qualification thereof\nand for such additional period of time as the superintendent may\nprescribe in writing, the provisions of subdivision one of this section\nshall not apply to a transfer of control by operation of law to the\nlegal representative, as hereinafter defined, of one who has control of\na licensee. Thereafter, such legal representative shall comply with the\nprovisions of subdivision one of this section. The provisions of\nsubdivision one of this section shall be applicable to an application\nmade under such section by a legal representative.\n  The term "legal representative," for the purposes of this section,\nshall mean one duly appointed by a court of competent jurisdiction to\nact as executor, administrator, trustee, committee, conservator or\nreceiver, including one who succeeds a legal representative and one\nacting in an ancillary capacity thereto in accordance with the\nprovisions of such court appointment.\n  If any provision of this section, o...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>