<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-350"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-350"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="350"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-350/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-350/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-350/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-350/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_350">
        <num>350</num>
        <heading>Restrictions concerning advertising, liens on real estate, and places where loans made</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_350__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No licensee or other entity shall\nadvertise, print, display, publish, distribute, or broadcast or cause or\npermit to be advertised, printed, displayed, published, distributed, or\nbroadcasted, in any manner whatsoever any statement or representation\nwith regard to the rates, terms, or conditions for the loaning of money,\ncredit, goods, or things in action which is false, misleading or\ndeceptive, or in violation of chapter three of the act of congress\nentitled "Truth in Lending Act" and the regulations thereunder, as such\nact and regulations may from time to time be amended.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_350__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No licensee shall make, directly or indirectly, orally or in\nwriting, by any method, practice or device, any representation that it\nis licensed under this chapter, except a representation that such\nlicensee is licensed as a licensed lender by the New York state\ndepartment of financial services.\n  2. No licensee shall take a lien upon real estate as security for any\nloan under the provisions of this article, except such lien as is\ncreated by law upon the recording of a judgment.\n  3. No licensee shall conduct the business of making loans under the\nprovisions of this article within any office, room, or place of business\nin which any other business is solicited or engaged in, or in\nassociation or conjunction therewith, except</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_350__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a licensee may, after\nobtaining any required license, conduct on its premises businesses\nauthorized under articles eleven-B, twelve-B, twelve-D and thirteen-B of\nthis chapter, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_350__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as may be authorized in writing by the\nsuperintendent upon a finding that such other business would not result\nin evasions of this article or of the rules and regulations lawfully\nmade hereunder.\n  4. No licensee shall transact such business or make any loan provided\nfor by this article under any other name or at any other place of\nbusiness than that named in the license, except as may be authorized by\nthe superintendent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>