<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-357"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-357"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="357"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-357/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-357/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-357/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-357/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_357">
        <num>357</num>
        <heading>Insurance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_357__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of section three hundred\nfifty-one of this article, in the event of prepayment by cash, a new\nloan, refinancing or otherwise. Only one such amount may be collected in\nconnection with any loan contract irrespective of the number of obligors\nand only one obligor need be insured.\n  4. The insurance authorized by this section, with the exception of\ninsurance provided under group insurance policies, may be written by or\narranged through the licensee or an affiliate, associate or employee of\nthe licensee only if such licensee, affiliate, associate or employee is\na duly licensed insurance agent or broker, provided, however, no\nlicensee shall decline new or existing insurance which meets or exceeds\nthe standards set forth in this section, nor prevent any borrower from\nobtaining such insurance coverage from other sources.\n  5. If a borrower procures such insurance by or through a licensee, the\nstatement required by section three hundred fifty-two of this article\nshall disclose the cost or rate of charge to the borrower and the type\nof insurance, and the licensee shall cause to be delivered to the\nborrower a copy of the policy, certificate, or other evidence therefor\nwithin a reasonable time.\n  6. The insurance authorized by this section and all benefits or\nreturns therefrom accruing to the licensee or to any affiliate,\nassociate or employee of the licensee shall not be prohibited by any\nother provision of this article.\n  7. No insurance shall be required, requested, sold or offered for sale\nin connection with any loan made under this article, except as and to\nthe extent authorized by this section or as provided in subdivision six\nof section three hundred fifty-one of this article.\n  If the borrowers on any loan are husband and wife, joint credit life\ninsurance and joint credit accident and health insurance may be issued\non such loan pursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>