<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-369"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-369"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="369"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-369/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-369/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-369/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-369/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_369">
        <num>369</num>
        <heading>Conditions precedent to issuing license; issuance and filing of license; posting license</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_369__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has been convicted of a crime in any jurisdiction or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_369__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nis associating or consorting with any person who has, or persons who\nhave, been convicted of a crime or crimes in any jurisdiction or\njurisdictions. For the purposes of this article, a person shall be\ndeemed to have been convicted of a crime if such person shall have\npleaded guilty to a charge thereof before a court or magistrate, or\nshall have been found guilty thereof by the decision or judgment of a\ncourt or magistrate or by the verdict of a jury, irrespective of the\npronouncement of sentence or the suspension thereof. The term\n"substantial stockholder," as used in this subdivision, shall be deemed\nto refer to a person owning or controlling ten per centum or more of the\ntotal outstanding stock of the corporation in which such person is a\nstockholder. In making a determination pursuant to this subdivision, the\nsuperintendent shall require fingerprinting of the applicant. Such\nfingerprints shall be submitted to the division of criminal justice\nservices for a state criminal history record check, as defined in\nsubdivision one of section three thousand thirty-five of the education\nlaw, and may be submitted to the federal bureau of investigation for a\nnational criminal history record check.\n  7. No license pursuant to this article shall be issued to any\napplicant to do business at the place specified in the application as\nthe place where the business is to be conducted if, within the twelve\nmonths preceding such application, a license to engage in business\npursuant to this article at such place shall have been revoked.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>