<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-37"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-37"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="37"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-37/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-37/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-37/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-37/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_37">
        <num>37</num>
        <heading>Reports to superintendent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  § 37. Reports to superintendent. 1. The superintendent shall at least\ntwo times in each year designate a past day as of which every bank,\ntrust company, private banker and, in the discretion of the\nsuperintendent, a bank holding company and any non-banking subsidiary\nthereof shall render a periodical report of condition to him. He shall\ndeliver or mail a notice designating such day to such bank, trust\ncompany, private banker, bank holding company or any non-banking\nsubsidiary thereof at its principal office.\n  * 3. In addition to any reports expressly required by this chapter to\nbe made, the superintendent may require any banking organization,\nlicensed lender, licensed casher of checks, licensed mortgage banker,\nforeign banking corporation licensed by the superintendent to do\nbusiness in this state, bank holding company and any non-banking\nsubsidiary thereof, corporate affiliate of a corporate banking\norganization within the meaning of subdivision six of section thirty-six\nof this article and any non-banking subsidiary of a corporation which is\nan affiliate of a corporate banking organization within the meaning of\nsubdivision six-a of section thirty-six of this article to make special\nreports to him at such times as he may prescribe.\n  * NB Effective until certain provisions are met (see Ch. 58 of 2025,\nPart Y, § 13)\n  * 3. In addition to any reports expressly required by this chapter to\nbe made, the superintendent may require any banking organization,\nlicensed lender, licensed buy-now-pay-later lender, licensed casher of\nchecks, licensed mortgage banker, foreign banking corporation licensed\nby the superintendent to do business in this state, bank holding company\nand any non-banking subsidiary thereof, corporate affiliate of a\ncorporate banking organization within the meaning of subdivision six of\nsection thirty-six of this article and any non-banking subsidiary of a\ncorporation which is an affiliate of a corporate banking organization\nwithin the meaning of subdivision six-a of section thirty-six of this\narticle to make special reports to the superintendent at such times as\nthe superintendent may prescribe.\n  * NB Effective upon the one hundred eightieth day after the\npromulgation of rules and/or regulations by the department of financial\nservices to effectuate certain provisions (see Ch. 58 of 2025, Part Y, §\n13)\n  4. The superintendent, except as otherwise expressly provided in this\nchapter, may prescribe the form and contents of all periodical and all\nspecial reports.\n  * 5. The superintendent may extend at his discretion the time within\nwhich a banking organization, foreign banking corporation licensed by\nthe superintendent to do business in this state, bank holding company or\nany non-banking subsidiary thereof, licensed casher of checks, licensed\nmortgage banker, private banker or licensed lender is required to make\nand file any report to the superintendent.\n  * NB Effective until certain provisions are met (see Ch. 58 of 2025,\nPart Y, § 13)\n  * 5. The superintendent may extend at the superintendent's discretion\nthe time within which a banking organization, foreign banking\ncorporation licensed by the superintendent to do business in this state,\nbank holding company or any non-banking subsidiary thereof, licensed\ncasher of checks, licensed mortgage banker, private banker, licensed\nbuy-now-pay-later lender or licensed lender is required to make and file\nany report to the superintendent.\n  * NB Effective upon the one hundred eightieth day after the\npromulgation of rules and/or regulations by the department of financial\nservices to effectuate certain provisions (see Ch. 58 of 2025, Part Y, §\n13)\n  6. For purposes of this section thirty-seven the terms "bank holding\ncompany" and "non-banking subsidiary" shall be defined as such terms are\ndefined in article three-A of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>