<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-376"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-376"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="376"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-376/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-376/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-376/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-376/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_376">
        <num>376</num>
        <heading>Proposed by-laws</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The dates\nof regular meetings of shareholders; the notice, if any, to be given;\nthe qualifications of voters and the manner of voting; the manner of\ncalling special meetings; and the number of members which shall\nconstitute a quorum.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The number of directors, and their qualifications, other than\nthose specified in this article; their terms of office, which shall not\nbe less than one year nor more than three years, and if the terms of\noffice be more than one year, the method of division into classes for\nthe purpose of electing, as nearly as may be, an equal number of\ndirectors each year; and the removal or suspension of directors.  The\nby-laws may provide that the number of directors shall be not less than\nseven nor more than fifteen, in which event the by-laws shall also\nprovide the manner in which the number of directors shall be fixed\nwithin the minimum and maximum limits.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The meetings of the board of directors, of which there shall be no\nless than ten regular monthly meetings per year, provided, however, that\nduring any three consecutive calendar months the board of directors\nshall meet at least twice; its powers and duties; the appointment or\nelection of auditors and their compensation; the establishment of\npolicies governing the appointment of appraisers and their compensation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The officers; the manner of their election; their terms of office,\nduties and compensation; and the bonds which shall be required of\nofficers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The classes of shares which may be issued; whether they shall be\nissued in series or otherwise; the times when they may be issued; and\ntheir matured value.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The manner in which evidence of share ownership shall be issued to\nmembers.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The dues that shall be paid upon shares and the time of their\npayment; the time and manner of apportioning, crediting and paying\ndividends.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The conditions upon which shares may be transferred, matured,\nwithdrawn, retired or suspended and forfeited.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a member thereof, the voting of shares in the Savings and Loan\nBank of the State of New York and the nomination of a director of such\nbank.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The manner and conditions under which the by-laws may be altered\nor amended.\n  2. Such by-laws may make provision for the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fees that may be charged, which shall be only an entrance fee\nat a rate not exceeding twenty-five cents a share with a maximum amount\nof five dollars, or in lieu thereof a membership fee not exceeding one\ndollar; a transfer fee not exceeding twenty-five cents a share, or in\nlieu thereof a total fee not exceeding one dollar on each transfer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Loans and investments; the security to be taken for loans, and the\nconditions under which loans may be repaid.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fines and penalties which may be imposed for failure promptly\nto make payments when due.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prohibiting or further limiting proxies for members, and their\nduration, pursuant to subdivision two of section three hundred\nseventy-eight.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_376__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The receipt of time and demand deposits.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>