<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-378"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-378"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="378"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-378/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-378/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-378/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-378/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_378">
        <num>378</num>
        <heading>Power to issue shares; dues thereon</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Instalment shares, class one, upon which regular payments\nof dues shall be made as provided in the by-laws of the association,\nuntil such shares reach their matured value or are withdrawn, retired or\nforfeited; and instalment shares, class two, which shall have no\nparticipation in dividends and upon which the dues payable in regularly\nincreasing amounts are applied in reduction of a debt due to the\nassociation from the holder of such shares in accordance with a\ndirection given by him.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Savings shares, upon which dues shall be paid in such sums, at\nsuch times and for such purposes as the holder thereof may elect, until\nthe shares are withdrawn or retired. Upon the request of the holder\nthereof, such savings shares may be converted by the issuing association\ninto special savings shares authorized for issuance by paragraph (bb) of\nthis subdivision. The association may enter such conversion in its\nrecords and on the evidence of ownership of the savings shares as an\nalternative to withdrawal or retirement of the savings shares and\nissuance of special savings shares.\n  (bb) Subject to such limitations and restrictions as may be prescribed\nby regulation of the superintendent of financial services, special\nsavings shares, upon which dues shall be paid in such sums, at such\ntimes and for such purposes as the holder thereof may elect, and which\nshall provide that dividends shall be credited from the date of actual\nreceipt of such dues to the date they are withdrawn or retired.\nDividends on special savings shares shall be credited and shall be made\navailable no later than the end of a regular dividend period, or at the\ntime such special savings shares are withdrawn or retired if in the\nopinion of a majority of the board of directors it appears the savings\nand loan association will have sufficient profit available at the end of\nsuch regular dividend period to pay dividends and if the board of\ndirectors chooses payment of dividends at withdrawal as an option to\nperiodic payment of dividends. Any savings and loan association which\ndoes not make dividends available pursuant to the provisions of this\nparagraph shall promptly notify the superintendent of financial services\nof such decision. Withdrawals or retirements of special savings shares\nduring the last three business days of any regular dividend period or,\nin the event that any one of such last three business days is a\nSaturday, withdrawals of such shares upon one of the last four...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Accumulative prepaid shares upon which a single payment of dues to\nthe amount of fifty per centum or more of the matured value thereof\nshall be paid at the time when such shares are issued. The whole or a\npart of the dividends apportioned to such shares shall be credited\nthereto until such shares are matured, withdrawn or retired. Any balance\nof such dividends not so credited shall be paid in cash.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Income shares, upon which a single payment of dues amounting to\none hundred dollars per share shall be paid at the time when such shares\nare issued. The dividends on such shares shall be paid in cash or, in\naccordance with the written order of the holder, applied to the purchase\nof other shares in the association. Income shares may be issued which\nshall not be withdrawable without the consent of the board of directors,\nuntil the expiration of a fixed period, which shall be not more than ten\nyears. Whenever income shares are issued which are not withdrawable\nuntil the expiration of a fixed period, a statement that they are not\nwithdrawable until the expiration of such fixed period shall be printed\nupon the face of the certificate of shares or other evidence of\nownership in such manner as to be clearly legible. Whenever any\nassociation is unable to locate the holder of income shares and\ndividends shall have been apportioned which cannot be paid to the holder\nthereof by reason of the inability of such association to locate such\nholder, such association may credit such dividends as dues upon another\nclass of shares in the name of holder of such income shares and shall\ncarry such other shares and any accumulations thereon for the benefit of\nsuch shareholder. Income shares which are not withdrawable until the\nexpiration of a fixed period shall be termed "income shares, class two."\nOther income shares shall be termed "income shares, class one."\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_378__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cumulative income shares upon which a single payment of dues of\nnot less than one hundred dollars shall be paid at the time such shares\nare issued. The dividends on such shares may be credited thereto until\nsuch shares are matured, withdrawn or retired. Cumulative income shares\nmay be issued which shall not be withdrawable without the consent of the\nboard of directors, until the expiration of a fixed period, which shall\nbe not more than ten years nor less than ninety days. Whenever\ncumulative income shares are issued which are not withdrawable until the\nexpiration of a fixed period, a statement that they are not withdrawable\nuntil the expiration of such fixed period shall be printed upon the face\nof the certificate of shares or other evidence of ownership in such\nmanner as to be clearly legible. Cumulative income shares which are not\nwithdrawable until the expiration of a fixed period shall be termed\n"cumulative income shares, class two." Other cumulative income shares\nshall be termed "cumulative income shares, class one."\n  5. All shares hereafter issued by any savings and loan association\nshall have a matured value of one hundred dollars, except that\ninstalment shares may be issued having a matured value of not less than\none hundred nor more than two hundred fifty dollars.\n  6. Shares issued in the name of more than one person shall confer no\ngreater voting rights than if issued in the name of one person.\n  7. Persons who hold shares in a fiduciary capacity shall have all the\nrights and privileges of membership, except to hold office.\n  8. A savings and loan association shall have a lien upon the shares of\nits members to the extent of any lawful fines or other obligations due\nto it, whether or not such shares are specifically transferred or\npledged to it, and may, at its option, after five days' notice to the\nmember, apply such shares toward the payment of any matured obligations\ndue it.\n  9. A savings and loan association may in its d...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>