<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-390"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-390"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="390"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-390/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-390/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-390/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-390/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_390">
        <num>390</num>
        <heading>Withdrawal of unpledged shares; provisions for dividends</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_390__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>charge a fee to shareholders\nmaking such withdrawals,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>place a limitation upon the amount of such\nwithdrawal requests, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pay a fee to the disbursing association. A\nsavings and loan association may also act as the disbursing association\nin a similar withdrawal transaction from such accumulations on shares in\nanother association that is a member of the federal deposit insurance\ncorporation, and may collect a fee for its services. This subdivision\none-a shall not apply to time deposits received by an association\npursuant to section three hundred seventy-eight-a of this chapter.\n  2. If a member shall not apply for the withdrawal within fifteen days\nafter the expiration of the thirty days' notice of intention no\nwithdrawal shall be payable under such notice or by reason thereof.\nWhile any withdrawal application made pursuant to the required notice of\nintention remains in effect and unpaid, no withdrawal application made\npursuant to a notice of intention subsequently filed shall be paid and\nno loan may be made secured by transfer or pledge of shares, nor shall\nshares be retired or applied by the association, or by the member toward\nthe payment of fines and obligations due to the association, nor shall\ndividends be declared or paid.\n  3. Upon the withdrawal of instalment or accumulative prepaid shares\nprior to their maturity, or upon the withdrawal of income shares issued\nfor a fixed term prior to the expiration of such fixed term, a portion\nof the dividends credited to such shares may be retained by the\nassociation as its own property, in accordance with a schedule, clearly\nand fully set forth in the by-laws. Such schedule shall make proper\nprovision with respect to each class of share, and in the case of\ninstalment shares shall take into account the period such shares have\nbeen in force, provided, however, that the portion of such dividends\nthat may be retained by the association upon the withdrawal of a share\nshall in no case exceed forty per centum of the dividends apportioned\nand credited upon such share.\n  4. The board of directors may permit a member to w...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>