<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-399"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-399"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="399"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-399/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-399/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-399/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-399/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_399">
        <num>399</num>
        <heading>Restrictions on directors and officers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No executive officer of a savings and loan association may be\nan executive officer, director or trustee of another savings and loan\nassociation, bank or trust company, savings bank, national bank, federal\nsavings bank or federal savings association, the principal office of\nwhich institution is located in this state, bank holding company or\nforeign banking corporation maintaining a branch in this state unless\npermission therefor has been granted by the superintendent of financial\nservices pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The superintendent shall have the power to determine by regulation\nwho shall be considered, under the provisions of this subdivision, to be\nan executive officer, and by regulation,, to grant permission to an\nexecutive officer of a savings and loan association to be an executive\nofficer, director or trustee or both an executive officer and a director\nor a trustee of another savings and loan association, bank or trust\ncompany, savings bank, national bank, federal savings bank or federal\nsavings association, the principal office of which is located in this\nstate, bank holding company or foreign banking corporation maintaining a\nbranch in this state. Such permission may be granted only if in the\njudgment of the superintendent such service by the executive officer\nwill be consistent with the policy of the state of New York as declared\nin section ten of this chapter. The superintendent shall have the power\nto revoke such permission whenever the superintendent finds, after\nreasonable notice and an opportunity to be heard, that the public\ninterest requires such revocation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the purposes of this subdivision, the term "bank holding\ncompany" shall be given the same meaning as is contained in section one\nhundred forty-one of this chapter, and the definition of the term\n"banking institution" is modified to include a national bank, federal\nsavings bank or federal savings association, the principal office of\nwhich institution is located in this state, and a foreign banking\ncorporation maintaining a branch in this state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_399__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All other restrictions and limitations imposed by this chapter on\nexecutive officers and directors of savings and loan associations shall\ncontinue in effect.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>