<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4001"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4001">
        <num>4001</num>
        <heading>Incorporation; organization certificate; amount of capital stock</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_4001__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of capital stock the corporation\nexpects to sell in its initial offering of shares and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4001__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such\nadditional amount as may be approved by the superintendent of financial\nservices.\n  4. If the shares are to be classified:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4001__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The number of shares to be included in each class and the par\nvalue of the shares;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4001__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The designation of each class and the relative rights, preferences\nand limitations of the shares of each class;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_4001__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The number of shares of common stock, if any, which are to be\nreserved for issuance in exchange for preferred shares or otherwise to\nreplace any capital stock represented by preferred shares.\n  5. The names and places of residence of the incorporators and, in the\ncase of banks, trust companies and safe deposit companies, the\ncitizenship of the incorporators.\n  6. Its duration if other than perpetual.\n  7. The number of its directors or that the number of directors shall\nnot be less than a stated minimum nor more than a stated maximum. Such\nnumber, or the minimum and the maximum stated, shall be within the\nlimitations prescribed by section seven thousand two of this article.\n  8. The names of the incorporators who shall be its directors until the\nfirst annual meeting of stockholders. The incorporators named as\ndirectors must possess the qualifications of directors as to citizenship\nand residence specified in section seven thousand one of this article;\nand the certificate of a safe deposit company shall recite that such\nqualifications are possessed by such incorporators.\n  9. In the case of a trust company, that the proposed corporation is to\nexercise the powers conferred by section one hundred of this chapter, if\nthe proposed corporation desires to exercise such powers in addition to\nthe other powers conferred upon banks and trust companies in article\nthree of this chapter.\n  No corporation shall be authorized to exercise the powers set forth in\nsection one hundred of this chapter unless its capital stock shall\namount to not less than the amounts prescribed by the superintendent of\nfinancial services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>