<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4005"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4005"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="4005"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4005/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4005/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4005/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-4005/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_4005">
        <num>4005</num>
        <heading>Organization meeting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 4005. Organization meeting. 1. After the corporate existence has\nbegun, an organization meeting of the incorporators shall be held within\nthis state, for the purpose of adopting by-laws and the transaction of\nsuch other business relating to organization as may come before the\nmeeting. The meeting may be held at the call of any incorporator, who\nshall give at least five days' notice thereof by mail to each other\nincorporator, which notice shall set forth the time and place of the\nmeeting. Notice need not be given to any incorporator who attends the\nmeeting or submits a signed waiver of notice before or after the\nmeeting. A majority shall constitute a quorum and the act of the\nmajority of the incorporators present at a meeting at which a quorum is\npresent shall be the act of the incorporators.\n  2. Any action permitted to be taken at the organization meeting may be\ntaken without a meeting if each incorporator signs an instrument setting\nforth the action so taken.\n  3. If an incorporator dies or is for any reason unable to act, action\nmay be taken as provided in such event in subdivision three of section\nsix thousand fifteen.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>