<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="404"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-404/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-404/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_404">
        <num>404</num>
        <heading>Reports to the superintendent; penalty for failure to make</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 404. Reports to the superintendent; penalty for failure to make. 1.\nOn or before the first day in February in each year, every savings and\nloan association shall make a written report to the superintendent which\nshall contain a statement of its condition as of the morning of the\nfirst day of January in such year. Such report shall contain such\ninformation and be in such form as the superintendent may prescribe and\nshall be subscribed and affirmed as true under the penalties of perjury\nby the president or a vice-president and another principal officer.\n  2. Every such association shall also make such other special reports\nto the superintendent as he may from time to time require, in such form\nand at such date as may be prescribed by him and such reports shall, if\nrequired by him, be subscribed and affirmed as true under the penalties\nof perjury.\n  3. If any such association shall fail to make any report required by\nor pursuant to this section on or before the day designated for the\nmaking thereof, or shall fail to include therein any information\nrequired by the superintendent to be included, such association shall\nforfeit to the people of the state an amount as determined pursuant to\nsection forty-four-a of this chapter for every day that such report\nshall be delayed or withheld, and for every day that it shall fail to\nreport any such omitted information, unless the time therefor shall have\nbeen extended by the superintendent.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>