<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-410"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-410"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="410"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-410/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-410/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_410">
        <num>410</num>
        <heading>Conversion of a federal savings and loan association into a state savings and loan association</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at least sixty-six and two-thirds per\ncentum in amount of the book value of all outstanding shares, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at\nleast seventy-five per centum in amount of the book value of the\noutstanding shares represented at the meeting, authorize the conversion\nof such federal savings and loan association into a state savings and\nloan association. A copy of the minutes of such meeting, verified by the\npresiding officer and by the secretary of the meeting, shall be filed in\nthe office of the superintendent within thirty days after the date of\nsuch meeting.\n  3. There shall be filed with such copy of the minutes, the\norganization certificate required by section three hundred seventy-five\nof this article, executed by a majority of the directors, and proposed\nby-laws as required by section three hundred seventy-six of this\narticle. The federal savings and loan association shall also submit a\nwritten plan of conversion to the superintendent, together with an\ninvestigation fee as described pursuant to section eighteen-a of this\nchapter.\n  4. Within sixty days after such filing, the federal savings and loan\nassociation shall take the action prescribed or authorized by the laws\nof the United States to effect such conversion and there shall thereupon\nbe filed in the office of the superintendent a copy of any consent or\nauthorization required of such federal savings and loan association\npursuant to the laws of the United States to effect such conversion.\n  5. When the superintendent shall have approved the organization\ncertificate and the proposed by-laws and shall have issued the\nauthorization certificate, provided in article two of this chapter, the\nassociation shall cease to be a federal savings and loan association and\nshall thereupon be converted into a state savings and loan association,\nbut such federal savings and loan association shall be deemed to be\ncontinued for the purpose of prosecuting or defending suits and of\nenabling it to wind up its affairs as a federal savings and loan\nassociation, and to dispose of and convey its property.\n  At the time when s...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_410__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are\nor have been officers or employees of the converting federal savings and\nloan association, and (ii) have acquired a right or interest in such\nplan or program which has vested in such officers or employees by\ncontractual arrangement in effect not less than six months prior to such\nconversion or by reason of such officers or employees becoming eligible\nand qualified under such plan or program. Notwithstanding the foregoing\nprovisions of this subdivision, the superintendent is authorized to\nwithhold his approval of the conversion of a federal savings and loan\nassociation if in his opinion the benefits under such plans or programs\nare unduly excessive.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>