<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-453"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-453"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="453"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-453/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-453/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_453">
        <num>453</num>
        <heading>Corporate credit unions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>accumulate and prudently manage the liquidity of its member credit\nunions through interlending and investment services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>act as an intermediary for credit union funds between members and\nother corporate credit unions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>obtain liquid funds from other credit union organizations,\nfinancial intermediaries and other sources;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>foster and promote in cooperation with other state, regional and\nnational corporate credit unions and credit union organizations or\nassociations the economic security, growth and development of member\ncredit unions; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>perform such other financial services of benefit to its members\nwhich are authorized by the superintendent.\n  5. A corporate credit union shall enjoy the powers and privileges of\nany other credit union incorporated under this chapter in addition to\nthose powers enumerated in this article, notwithstanding any limitation\nor restrictions found elsewhere in this article. The superintendent of\nfinancial services may promulgate such regulations concerning the\nestablishment and operations of corporate credit unions as in its\ndiscretion are necessary and proper. Subject to such regulations, a\ncorporate credit union may:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>accept shares or deposits in any form from its members, other\nstate, regional or national corporate credit unions, and credit union\norganizations or associations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>make loans to its members and other credit unions and other state,\nregional, or national corporate credit unions, organizations and\nassociations of credit unions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish lines of credit for members and participate with other\ncredit unions in making loans to its members under the terms and\nconditions determined by the board of directors;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>invest in the shares of or make deposits in credit unions;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>buy and sell any form of marketable debt obligations of domestic\nor foreign corporations or of federal, state or local government units;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>borrow money, accept demand deposits and issue notes or\ndebentures;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>acquire or sell the assets and assume the liabilities of a member;\nand\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_453__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>enter into agreements with credit unions to discount or purchase\nloans made pursuant to government-guaranteed loan programs, real estate\nloans made by members or any obligations of the United States or any\nagency thereof held by members.\n  6. A corporate credit union shall be exempt from the reserve\nrequirements of section four hundred fifty-eight-a of this article, but\nshall be required to accumulate and maintain reserves in accordance with\nthe requirements of the National Credit Union Administration.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>