<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-454"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-454"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-10-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="454"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-454/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-454/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-454/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-454/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_454">
        <num>454</num>
        <heading>General powers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To lend money to its members at the rate or rates agreed to by\nthe credit union and the borrower upon such terms and conditions as are\nestablished by its board of directors and subject to such regulations\nand restrictions as the superintendent of financial services finds\nnecessary and proper.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The knowingly taking, receiving, reserving, or charging a greater\nrate of interest than permitted by law shall be held and adjudged a\nforfeiture of the entire interest which the note or other evidence of\ndebt carries with it, or which has been agreed to be paid thereon. If\nsuch greater rate of interest has been paid, the person paying the same\nor his legal representatives may recover twice the entire amount of the\ninterest thus paid from the credit union.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No credit union may make any member business loan that would\nresult in a total amount of such loans outstanding at that credit union\nat any one time equal to more than the lesser of 1.75 times the actual\nnet worth of the credit union, or 1.75 times the minimum net worth\nrequired under 12 U.S.C. 1790d</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_454__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(A) for a credit union to be well\ncapitalized.\n  (ii) Subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph does not apply in the case of:\n(A) a credit union chartered for the purpose of making, or that has a\nhistory of primarily making, member business loans to its members, as\ndetermined by the superintendent; or (B) a credit union that serves\npredominantly low-income members, as defined by the superintendent, or\nwhich is a community development financial institution as defined in 12\nU.S.C. 4702; or (C) a credit union excepted from the requirements of\nsuch subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by the superintendent where such credit union is\nseeking an exception from any federal limits on member business loans to\nthe same extent as permitted to federally-insured state credit unions\npursuant to the Federal Credit Union Act and regulations related\nthereto, provided that such credit union demonstrates to the\nsatisfaction of the superintendent that such exception would be\nconsistent with the declaration of policy as set forth in section ten of\nthis chapter.\n  (iii) For purposes of this paragraph the term "member business loan"\nand the term "net worth" shall have the same meaning as such terms are\ndefined in 12 U.S.C. 1757a.\n  7.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To issue credit cards, debit cards, and similar devices to\nallow members to make purchases and to access their loans, lines of\ncredit, shares and deposits;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To collect, receive and disburse funds in connection with the\nissuance of negotiable checks, money orders, travelers checks and other\npayment instruments to members, and to charge a fee for such services;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To rent safe deposit boxes to members; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To provide any related financial services to members which are not\nexpressly authorized pursuant to this article, including but not limited\nto electronic funds transfers and correspondent services; provided,\nhowever, that any credit union which seeks to offer any such related\nfinancial services which it has not offered prior to June twentieth, two\nthousand three shall, not less than sixty days prior to offering such\nservices, notify the superintendent in writing of its intention to offer\nsuch services. If the superintendent does not object in writing to the\noffering of such services within sixty days after the receipt of the\nnotice, the credit union may offer such services to its members.\n  8. To deposit any moneys received by it, and not lent to members, in\none or more state or federally chartered banking organizations or\nbranches of foreign banking corporations which are insured by the\nFederal Deposit Insurance Corporation, by the National Credit Union\nShare Insurance Fund, or by another agency of the United States\ngovernment.\n  9. To borrow money subject to such regulations and restrictions as the\nsuperintendent of financial services finds necessary and proper from any\nsource in an aggregate amount not exceeding fifty percent of assets\nwithout the written approval of the superintendent.\n  10. To impose financing charges and late charges in the event of late\npayment or default on loans and recover reasonable costs and expenses,\nincluding collection costs and reasonable attorneys' fees incurred both\nbefore and after judgment.\n  11. To suspend or expel members, as provided in section four hundred\nsixty-four of this article.\n  12. To impress and enforce a lien upon the shares, share accounts,\nshare certificates, deposits, dividends, and accumulation of interest on\nthe shares, accounts, certificates, and deposits of any member to the\nextent of any sums owed the credit union by said member and any loans\nmade to him or her directly or indir...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To invest its funds in:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Those securities authorized as\npermissible investments for savings banks by subdivisions one, two,\nthree, four, twelve, paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision twelve-a, and\nsubdivisions fifteen, seventeen, twenty-seven and twenty-eight-a of\nsection two hundred thirty-five of this chapter and such other\ninvestments as the superintendent deems permissible.\n  (ii) Advances of federal funds as authorized for savings banks by\nsubdivision twelve-b of section two hundred thirty-five of this chapter.\n  (iii) Common trust units of a credit union investment pool organized\nfor the purchase of:\n  (A) obligations of the United States of America, or securities fully\nguaranteed as to principal and interest thereby;\n  (B) obligations issued by banks for cooperatives, federal land banks,\nfederal intermediate credit banks, federal home loan banks, the Federal\nHome Loan Bank Board, or any corporation designated in section 846 of\nTitle 31 of the United States Code as a wholly owned government\ncorporation, or in obligations, participations, or other instruments of\nor issued by, or fully guaranteed as to principal and interest by, the\nFederal National Mortgage Association or the Government National\nMortgage Association, or in mortgages, obligations, or other securities\nwhich are or ever have been sold by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage\nCorporation pursuant to section 1454 or 1455 of Title 12 of the United\nStates Code, or in obligations or other instruments or securities of the\nStudent Loan Marketing Association;\n  (C) participation certificates evidencing beneficial interests in\nobligations, or in the right to receive interest and principal\ncollections therefrom, which obligations have been subjected by one or\nmore government agencies to a trust or trusts for which any executive\ndepartment, agency, or instrumentality of the United States (or the head\nthereof) has been named to act as trustee; provided that such investment\npool has been approved by the superintendent; or\n  (D) securities, obligations or other instruments of, or issued by, any\nagency of the United States.\n  (iv) Where the assets of a ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All such securities, except those purchased in a common trust unit\npursuant to subparagraph (iii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision,\nmust be registered in the name of the credit union; provided that where\nany such securities are non-registerable, except those purchased in a\ncommon trust investment pool, as hereinbefore provided, they shall be\nplaced in the custody of a bank, trust company, national bank, or state\nor federal corporate credit union in the name of the credit union, and\nshall be retained by such bank, trust company, national bank, or state\nor federal corporate credit union until such securities are liquidated\nat maturity or sold, in either of which events the proceeds of such\nsecurities shall be deposited in the name of the credit union in any\ninstitution specified in subdivision eight of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_454__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of this subdivision, a credit union\nmay invest the lesser of ten percent of its capital or net worth, but at\nleast ten thousand dollars, in the shares of investment companies;\nprovided that the portfolio of such investment company consists solely\nof securities in which credit unions are permitted to invest directly.\nThe term "investment companies" means open-end and close-end investment\ncompanies and unit investment trusts as these terms are used in an Act\nof Congress entitled "Investment Company Act of 1940."\n  19. Subject to regulations and restrictions of the superintendent of\nfinancial services, a credit union may invest its funds in and make\nloans to credit union organizations; provided that such loans or\ninvestments shall be approved by the board of directors. No such loan or\ninvestment shall be made by a credit union pursuant to this subdivision\nif the amount of such loan or investment exceeds three per centum of the\ntotal sum due to the members on shares and deposits. For the purpose of\nthis subdivision, a credit union organization is any organization\nestablished primarily to serve the needs of its member state and federal\ncredit unions, and whose business relates to the daily operations of the\ncredit unions it serves.\n  20. To purchase, sell, service, pledge or discount, or otherwise\nreceive or dispose of, eligible obligations to the same extent as\nauthorized pursuant to Title 12 U.S.C. section 1757</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_454__subsec_c__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <content>
              <p>and any\nregulations promulgated thereunder, as such laws or regulations may be\namended from time to time.\n  21. To purchase, hold, lease and convey a plot whereon there is or may\nbe erected a building suitable for the transaction of its business, from\nportions of which not required for its own use a revenue may be derived,\nand a plot whereon parking accommodations are or are to be provided,\nwith or without charge, primarily for its members or employees or both;\nprovided that the net aggregate of all investments of any credit union\nin such plots and building shall be limited to six per centum of the\ncapital and retained earnings of such credit union, except with the\napproval of the superintendent.\n  22. To enter into contracts.\n  23. To sue and to be sued in all courts and to participate in actions\nand proceedings, whether judicial, arbitrative, or otherwise, in like\ncases as natural persons.\n  24. To have a corporate seal, and to alter such seal at pleasure, and\nto use...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_454__subsec_c__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>(B)) and any\nregulations related thereto, as amended.\n  37. To engage in a "savings promotion" in accordance with section\nnine-v of this chapter and subject to any regulations promulgated by the\nsuperintendent. The superintendent shall consult with the state gaming\ncommission before proposing any such regulations or any amendments\nthereto. Such regulations shall ensure that:\n  a. no participant in a savings promotion is charged any fee that would\nconstitute, directly or indirectly, consideration for participation in\nsuch savings promotion; and\n  b. no participant in a savings promotion foregoes, directly or\nindirectly, any interest that would constitute consideration for\nparticipation in such savings promotion.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>