<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-464"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-464"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="464"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-464/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-464/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-464/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-464/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_464">
        <num>464</num>
        <heading>Manner of withdrawal; expulsion or suspension of members; effect upon liabilities to credit unions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_464__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_464__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, a member\nshall not be expelled or suspended unless he or she has been informed in\nwriting of the charges against him or her and has been provided the\nopportunity to be heard within thirty days of the date of the mailing or\ndelivery of such written notice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_464__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the case of a member who has been physically abusive or who has\nmade threats of physical harm or violence, such member may be suspended\nor expelled from the date of the mailing or delivery of a written notice\nof such action and the reasons for the suspension or expulsion. As part\nof such notice, the member shall be advised of the opportunity to\nrequest reinstatement and to be heard within thirty days of the date of\nthe mailing or delivery of such notice.\n  3. Any member of a credit union who withdraws or is suspended or\nexpelled shall not be relieved of any liability to the corporation. The\namounts paid in on shares or deposited by such members, together with\nany dividends credited to their shares and any interest which has\naccrued on their deposits, shall be repaid to them in the order of their\nwithdrawal, suspension or expulsion, as funds become available therefor,\nbut the credit union may deduct from such payments any sums due it from\nsuch members.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>