<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-487-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-487-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="487-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-487-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-487-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-487-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-487-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_487_A">
        <num>487-A</num>
        <heading>Conversion of a credit union into a mutual savings bank</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_487_A__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, 12 U.S.C. 1831i</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_487_A__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n  6. The member vote concerning charter conversion under this section\nshall be verified by the superintendent. If the superintendent\ndisapproves of the methods by which the member vote was taken or\nprocedures applicable to the member vote, the member vote shall be taken\nagain, as directed by the superintendent.\n  7. Upon completion of a conversion described in this section, the\ncredit union shall no longer be subject to any of the provisions of this\narticle.\n  When the superintendent shall have approved the organization\ncertificate and the proposed bylaws and shall have issued the\nauthorization certificate, as provided in article six of this chapter,\nthe credit union shall cease to be a credit union and shall thereupon be\nconverted into a mutual savings bank; provided, however, that such\ncredit union shall be deemed to be continued for the purpose of\nprosecuting or defending suits and of enabling it to wind up its affairs\nas a credit union and to dispose of and convey its property.\n  At the time when such conversion becomes effective, all the property\nof the credit union shall immediately by act of law and without any\nconveyance or transfer become the property of the mutual savings bank\nand the mutual savings bank shall succeed to all the rights, obligations\nand relations of the credit union.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>