<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-494"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-494"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="494"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-494/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-494/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-494/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-494/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_494">
        <num>494</num>
        <heading>License form; posting; limitations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 494. License form; posting; limitations. 1. Each license issued\nunder this article shall state the address at which the licensed\nbusiness is to be conducted and shall state fully the name of the\nlicensee and, if the licensee is a copartnership or association, the\nnames of the members thereof, and if a corporation, the date and place\nof its incorporation and the address of its principal place of business.\nSuch license shall be kept conspicuously posted in the licensee's\nspecified place of business and shall not be transferable or assignable.\n  2. Whenever any licensee hereunder changes its place of business to\nanother location, it shall give immediate written notice thereof to the\nsuperintendent, who shall without charge attach to the license or\nendorse on it in writing a record of the change and the date thereof,\nwhich shall be authority for the operation of the business under such\nlicense at such new location.\n  3. No person, except a licensee, may make any representation, directly\nor indirectly, orally or in writing, that he is licensed under this\narticle, and a licensee may make such a representation only in\nconnection with the licensee's business as a sales finance company and\nin accordance with any rules and regulations of the superintendent.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>