<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-498"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-498"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="498"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-498/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-498/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-498/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-498/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_498">
        <num>498</num>
        <heading>Complaints</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 498. Complaints. 1. Any buyer having reason to believe that this\narticle, or any other law regulating retail instalment sales, contracts,\nobligations or credit agreements, has been violated by any person may\nfile with the superintendent a written complaint setting forth the\ndetails of such alleged violation. Upon receipt of such complaint, the\nsuperintendent, or any person duly designated by him, may inspect the\npertinent books, records, letters and contracts of any licensee, and of\nany retail seller or other person involved, relating to such specific\nwritten complaint.\n  2. The superintendent or any person duly designated by him, shall have\nthe power to hold hearings upon such complaints and to determine the\ntime and place in this state, reasonably convenient to the parties\ninvolved, where they shall be held.\n  3. The superintendent shall make findings on any complaint on which a\nhearing has been held. The investigation, notice and hearing shall be in\naccordance with the provisions of this article and one copy of the\nfindings shall be given to each such person involved in the complaint.\n  4. No licensee or other person shall be subject to examination or\ninvestigation by the superintendent except as provided in this article.\nThe superintendent shall have only such powers as are expressly\ndelegated to him by this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>