<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-5016"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-5016"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="5016"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-5016/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-5016/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-5016/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-5016/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_5016">
        <num>5016</num>
        <heading>Convertible shares, capital notes and debentures</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_5016__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A sufficient number of authorized but unissued shares of the\nappropriate class or series are reserved by the board to be issued only\nin satisfaction of the conversion privileges of such convertible capital\nnotes, debentures or shares when issued; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5016__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The aggregate conversion privileges of such convertible capital\nnotes, debentures or shares when issued do not exceed the aggregate of\nany shares reserved under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_5016__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and any additional shares which\nmay be authorized by the board under subdivision three of this section.\n  5. No privilege of conversion may be conferred upon, or altered in\nrespect to, any shares or capital notes or debentures that would result\nin the receipt by the corporation of less than the minimum consideration\nrequired to be received upon the issue of new shares.  The consideration\nfor shares issued upon the exercise of a conversion privilege shall be\nthat provided in subdivision six of section five thousand four.\n  6. Within ninety days after any capital notes or debentures are\nconverted into shares of the corporation, a certificate of the\ncorporation shall be signed, verified and filed as provided in section\none thousand three stating the amount of capital notes or debentures so\nconverted, the number of shares of each class or series into which the\nsame were converted, and such other information with respect thereto as\nthe superintendent may require.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>