<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-513"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-513"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="513"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-513/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-513/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_513">
        <num>513</num>
        <heading>Reports to superintendent</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 513. Reports to superintendent. On or before the first day of April\nin each year, every investment company shall make a written report to\nthe superintendent of financial services which shall contain a statement\nof its condition on the morning of the first day of January in said year\nand shall be in the form and contain the matters prescribed by the\nsuperintendent. The superintendent may, however, in his discretion\naccept from an investment company which has branches in a foreign\ncountry or countries, a report containing a statement of its condition\nas of a date not later than the first day of January and not earlier\nthan the first day of November in the preceding year. Every such report\nshall be subscribed and affirmed as true under the penalties of perjury,\naccording to the best of their knowledge and belief, by the two\nprincipal officers of the investment company at the time of such\nsubscription, and shall state that the usual business of the investment\ncompany has been transacted at the location or locations required by\nthis article and not elsewhere.\n  Every such investment company shall also make such other special\nreports to the superintendent as he may from time to time require, which\nshall be in such form and filed at such date as may be prescribed by the\nsuperintendent and shall, if required by him, be subscribed and affirmed\nas true under the penalties of perjury.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>