<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-565"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-565"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="565"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-565/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-565/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-565/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-565/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_565">
        <num>565</num>
        <heading>Licensee's books and records; reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 565. Licensee's books and records; reports. 1. The licensee shall\nkeep and use in his business such books, accounts and records as will\nenable the superintendent to determine whether such licensee is\ncomplying with the provisions of this article and with the rules and\nregulations lawfully made by the superintendent hereunder. Every\nlicensee shall preserve such books, accounts and records, including\ncards used in a card system, if any, for at least six years after making\nthe final entry in respect to any premium finance agreement recorded\ntherein; provided, however, the preservation of photographic\nreproductions thereof or records in photographic form shall constitute\ncompliance with this requirement.\n  2. Each licensee shall annually on or before the first day of February\nfile a report with the superintendent giving such information as the\nsuperintendent may require concerning the business and operations during\nthe preceding calendar year of each licensed place of business conducted\nby the licensee within the state under the authority of this article.\nUpon good cause shown by a licensee, the superintendent may extend the\ntime for filing such report for a period not in excess of sixty days.\nSuch report shall be subscribed and affirmed as true by the licensee\nunder the penalties of perjury and be in the form prescribed by the\nsuperintendent who may make and publish annually an analysis and\nrecapitulation of such reports. In addition to such annual reports, the\nsuperintendent may require of licensees such additional regular or\nspecial reports as he may deem necessary to the proper supervision of\nlicensees under this article.  Such additional reports shall be in the\nform prescribed by the superintendent and shall be subscribed and\naffirmed as true under the penalties of perjury.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>