<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-567"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-567"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="567"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-567/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-567/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-567/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-567/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_567">
        <num>567</num>
        <heading>Form and content of premium finance agreements</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_567__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At its top, the words PREMIUM FINANCE AGREEMENT in at least ten\npoint bold type; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_567__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A notice in at least eight point bold type, reading as follows:\nNOTICE: 1. Do not sign this agreement before you read it or if it\ncontains any blank space. 2. You are entitled to a completely filled in\ncopy of this agreement. 3. Under the law, you have the right to pay off\nin advance the full amount due and under certain conditions to obtain a\npartial refund of the service charge.\n  3. A premium finance agreement shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_567__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contain the name and place of business of the insurance agent or\nbroker, if any, negotiating the related insurance contract, the name and\nresidence or the place of business of the insured as specified by him,\nthe name and place of business of the premium finance agency which is to\nhold or acquire the agreement and to which instalment or other payments\nare to be made, a description of the insurance contract, the premiums\nfor which are advanced or to be advanced under the agreement, and the\namount of the premiums for such insurance contract; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_567__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Set forth the items required to be disclosed by the act of\ncongress entitled "Truth in Lending Act" and the regulations thereunder,\nas such act and regulations may from time to time be amended.\n  4. No premium finance agreement shall be signed by an insured when it\ncontains any blank space to be filled in after it has been signed;\nhowever, if any insurance contract, the premiums for which are advanced\nor to be advanced under the agreement, has not been issued at the time\nof its signature by the insured and it so provides, the name of the\nauthorized insurer by whom such insurance contract is issued and the\npolicy number and the due date of the first instalment may be left blank\nand later inserted in the original of the agreement after it has been\nsigned by the insured.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>