<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-581"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-581"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="581"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-581/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-581/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-581/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-581/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_581">
        <num>581</num>
        <heading>Conditions for issuance of a license; procedure where application denied</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 581. Conditions for issuance of a license; procedure where\napplication denied. 1. Upon the filing of an application for a license,\nif the superintendent shall find that the financial responsibility,\nexperience, character, and general fitness of the applicant, and of the\nofficers and directors thereof are such as to command the confidence of\nthe community and to warrant belief that the business will be operated\nhonestly, fairly, and efficiently within the purposes of this article,\nhe or she shall thereupon issue a license in duplicate to engage in\nbudget planning in accordance with the provisions of this article. The\nsuperintendent shall transmit one copy of such license to the applicant\nand file another in the office of the department of financial services.\nSuch license shall remain in full force and effect until it is\nsurrendered by the licensee or revoked or suspended as hereinafter\nprovided; if the superintendent shall not so find he or she shall not\nissue such license and he or she shall notify the applicant of the\ndenial. The superintendent shall approve or deny every application for\nlicense hereunder within ninety days from the filing thereof.\n  2. The superintendent shall not issue a license unless an applicant\nagrees to provide, either directly or indirectly, budgeting, educational\nand/or counseling services, acceptable to the superintendent, to the\ndebtors with whom such licensee has a contract to engage in budget\nplanning, as defined by section four hundred fifty-five of the general\nbusiness law. Failure of a licensee to provide, directly or indirectly,\nsuch budgeting, educational and/or counseling services acceptable to the\nsuperintendent shall be a basis for suspension and revocation of the\nlicense.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>