<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-591"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-591"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="591"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-591/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-591/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-591/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-591/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_591">
        <num>591</num>
        <heading>Application for a mortgage banker's license; fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_591__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An affirmation of financial solvency noting such capitalization\nrequirements as may be required by the superintendent, and access to\nsuch credit as may be required by the superintendent;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_591__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The fingerprints of the applicant, which may be submitted to the\ndivision of criminal justice services and the federal bureau of\ninvestigation for state and national criminal history record checks;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_591__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An affirmation that the applicant, or its members, directors or\nprincipals as may be appropriate, are at least twenty-one years of age;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_591__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Information as to the character, fitness, financial and business\nresponsibility, background and experiences of the applicant.\n  2. An application shall be accompanied by an investigation fee as\nprescribed pursuant to section eighteen-a of this chapter payable to the\nsuperintendent.\n  3. A licensee may apply for authority to open and maintain a branch\noffice by giving the superintendent prior notice of its intention in\nsuch form as shall be prescribed by the superintendent. Unless the\nsuperintendent denies the application within thirty days of publication\nof notice of receipt of a completed application, the licensee shall be\npermitted to open and maintain such branch office. An application to\nopen and maintain a branch office shall be accompanied by an\ninvestigation fee as prescribed pursuant to section eighteen-a of this\nchapter.\n  4. As a condition for the issuance and retention of a mortgage\nbanker's license, and subject to such regulations as the superintendent\nshall prescribe, applicants for a license shall file with the\nsuperintendent a surety bond in form satisfactory to him or her issued\nby a bonding company or insurance company authorized to do business in\nthis state.  The principal amount of such bond shall be in an amount and\nform prescribed by regulations of the superintendent. Such regulations\nshall provide for a varying bond amount based upon a licensee's volume\nof business and any other relevant factors as determined by the\nsuperintendent, but in no case shall such bond be less than fifty\nthousand dollars nor more than five hundred thousand dollars; provided,\nhowever, that if the superintendent determines, in his or her sole\ndiscretion, that a licensee has engaged in a pattern of conduct\nresulting in bona fide consumer complaints of misconduct, the\nsuperintendent may require such licensee to post a surety bond, or keep\non deposit as provided in this subdivision, twice the amount of such\nbond or deposit as is required consi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>