<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-593-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-593-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="593-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-593-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-593-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-593-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-593-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_593_A">
        <num>593-A</num>
        <heading>Registration provisions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 593-a. Registration provisions. 1. Each certificate issued to a\nregistered mortgage broker under this article shall state the address or\naddresses at which the business is to be conducted and shall state fully\nthe name of the registrant, and the date and place of its incorporation\nif applicable. A copy of such certificate shall be prominently posted in\neach place of business of the registrant. Such certificate shall not be\ntransferable or assignable. In the event the location at which the\nbusiness is to be conducted shall be changed, the registrant shall\nforthwith notify the superintendent who shall thereupon without charge\nattach to the certificate an amendment certificate setting forth such\nchanged location.\n  2. In addition to the display of such certificate, each registered\nmortgage broker shall prominently display a notice printed in the\nEnglish language, each letter to be at least two inches in height,\nindicating that the mortgage broker is not empowered to make mortgage\nloans, and such other notices as required by the superintendent of\nfinancial services.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>