<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-595-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-595-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="595-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-595-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-595-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-595-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-595-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_595_C">
        <num>595-C</num>
        <heading>Regulation of dealings of mortgage brokers and home improvement contractors</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_595_C__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of the National Housing Act,\n12 U.S.C. 1709</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_595_C__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, or to amounts added to a federal housing\nadministration insured mortgage under the energy efficiency mortgage\nprogram originally established under section 106 of the Energy Policy\nAct of 1992, as from time to time amended.\n  3. A mortgage broker shall not permit a home improvement contractor to\nbe a cosigner or to act as a guarantor for a mortgage loan for home\nimprovement.\n  4. For the purpose of this section, "home improvement contractor",\nmeans, with respect to any home improvement, a person, firm or\ncorporation which owns or operates a home improvement business or who\nundertakes, offers to undertake or agrees to perform any home\nimprovement for a fee and for whom the total price for all labor,\nmaterials and other items is equal to or greater than two hundred\ndollars. Home improvement contractor does not include a person, firm,\ncorporation, landlord, cooperative corporation, condominium board of\nmanagers, joint tenant or co-tenant that owns, in whole or in part, the\nproperty to be improved.\n  5. This section shall not annul, alter, affect or exempt any person\nsubject to the provisions of this section from complying with the laws,\nordinances, rules or regulations of any locality or other governmental\nbody, relating to home improvement contracts, except to the extent that\nsuch laws, ordinances, rules or regulations are inconsistent with any\nprovision of this section, but no such law, ordinance, rule or\nregulation shall be considered inconsistent, if it affords greater\nprotection to the homeowner from persons subject to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>