<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="599-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_599_C">
        <num>599-C</num>
        <heading>License required</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each individual, other than an individual described in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, shall be licensed pursuant to subdivision one\nof this section not later than July thirty-first, two thousand ten, or\nsuch later date approved for mortgage loan originators in this state by\nthe Secretary of the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development,\npursuant to the authority granted under Public Law 110-289, Section\n1508</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and approved by the superintendent;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each individual authorized as a mortgage loan originator under\nprior law not later than July thirty-first, two thousand nine, shall be\nlicensed pursuant to subdivision one of this section not later than\nJanuary first, two thousand eleven, or such later date approved for\nmortgage loan originators in this state by the Secretary of the U.S.\nDepartment of Housing and Urban Development, pursuant to the authority\ngranted under Public Law 110-289, Section 1508</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and approved by the\nsuperintendent.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, after\nthe effective date of this article, no individual shall act as a\nmortgage loan originator if such individual has been convicted of, or\npled guilty or nolo contendere to, a felony of the types and during the\ntime periods described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section\nfive hundred ninety-nine-e of this article, in a domestic, foreign or\nmilitary court, unless expressly authorized to act as a mortgage loan\noriginator by the superintendent.\n  3. Exemption from licensing requirements. The following persons are\nexempt from the licensing requirements otherwise applicable under this\narticle:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Registered mortgage loan originators, when acting for an entity\ndescribed in subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, (ii) and (iii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision thirteen of section five hundred ninety-nine-b of this\narticle.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any individual who offers or negotiates the terms of a residential\nmortgage loan with or on behalf of an immediate family member of the\nindividual.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any individual who offers or negotiates terms of a residential\nmortgage loan secured by a dwelling or residential real property that\nserved as the individual's own residence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A licensed attorney who negotiates the terms of a residential\nmortgage loan on behalf of a client as an ancillary matter to the\nattorney's representation of the client, unless the attorney is\ncompensated by a lender, a mortgage broker, or other mortgage loan\noriginator or by any agent of such lender, mortgage broker, or other\nmortgage loan originator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any individual employed by a mortgage loan servicer registered\nunder article twelve-D of this chapter, who negotiates any modification\nof an existing residential mortgage loan on behalf of such servicer, and\ndoes not otherwise act as a mortgage loan originator, unless licensing\nis required by a rule, regulation, guideline or interpretation issued by\nthe U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development under Public Law\n110-289.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_599_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any individual involved in the sale of manufactured homes if\nexempted from licensing by a rule, regulation, guideline or\ninterpretation issued by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban\nDevelopment under Public Law 110-289.\n  4. Independent contractor loan processors or underwriters. A loan\nprocessor or underwriter who is an independent contractor of an\noriginating entity may not engage in residential mortgage loan\norigination activities unless such independent contractor loan processor\nor underwriter obtains and maintains a license under this article. Each\nindependent contractor loan processor or underwriter licensed as a\nmortgage loan originator must have and maintain a valid unique\nidentifier issued by the NMLSR.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>