<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="599-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-599-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_599_Q">
        <num>599-Q</num>
        <heading>Confidentiality</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 599-q. Confidentiality. In order to promote more effective\nregulation and reduce regulatory burden through supervisory information\nsharing, information provided to the superintendent by an MLO shall be\nsubject to the following:\n  1. Except as otherwise provided in public law 110-289, section 1512,\nthe requirements under any federal law, the freedom of information law\n("FOIL") or other law of this state regarding the privacy or\nconfidentiality of any information or material provided to the NMLSR,\nand any privilege arising under federal or state law (including the\nrules of any federal or state court) with respect to such information or\nmaterial, shall continue to apply to such information or material after\nthe information or material has been disclosed to the NMLSR. Such\ninformation and material may be shared with all state and federal\nregulatory officials with mortgage industry oversight authority without\nthe loss of privilege of the loss of confidentiality protections\nprovided by federal law, FOIL or this chapter.\n  2. For these purposes, the superintendent is authorized to enter into\nagreements or sharing arrangements with other governmental agencies, the\nConference of State Bank Supervisors, the American Association of\nResidential Mortgage Regulators or other associations representing\ngovernmental agencies as established by rule, regulation or order of the\nsuperintendent.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>