<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6_C">
        <num>6-C</num>
        <heading>Application forms to be made available; certain cases</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6-c. Application forms to be made available; certain cases. 1.\nEvery banking organization which originates loans secured by real\nproperty located in this state shall provide at its principal place of\nbusiness and at all its branches except automated teller machines,\npoint-of-sale terminals or other similar facilities, application forms\nfor such loans which forms shall be made available upon request.\n  2. Every such organization shall be required, in such manner as the\nsuperintendent shall determine, to maintain a record of such application\nforms returned substantially completed and the last activity had with\nrespect thereto.\n  3. Every such organization shall inform any person making inquiry\nregarding the origination of loans secured by real property located in\nthis state that written loan application forms are available at its\nprincipal place of business and at all its branches except automated\nteller machines, point-of-sale terminals or other similar facilities.\n  4. For purposes of this section "a loan secured by real property"\nshall include any loan secured by a mortgage or other lien upon real\nproperty including a leasehold estate and any cooperative apartment loan\nsubject to the provisions of subdivision five of section one hundred\nthree, subdivision eight-a of section two hundred thirty-five or\nsubdivision two-a of section three hundred eighty of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>