<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6002"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6002"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6002"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6002/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6002/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6002">
        <num>6002</num>
        <heading>Meetings of stockholders</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6002. Meetings of stockholders. 1. Meetings of stockholders may be\nheld at such place, within or without this state, as may be fixed by or\nunder the by-laws, or if not so fixed, at the office of the corporation\nin this state except that the annual meetings of stockholders of banks\nand trust companies, stock-form savings banks, and stock-form savings\nand loan associations shall be held in the city or village in which the\noffice of the bank or trust company, stock-form savings bank, or\nstock-form savings and loan association is located.\n  2. A meeting of stockholders shall be held annually for the election\nof directors and the transaction of other business within the first four\nmonths of each institution's fiscal year in the case of banks, trust\ncompanies, stock-form savings banks, stock-form savings and loan\nassociations, and safe deposit companies and on a date fixed by or under\nthe by-laws in the case of investment companies. A failure to hold the\nannual meeting on the date so fixed or to elect a sufficient number of\ndirectors to conduct the business of the corporation shall not work a\nforfeiture or give cause for dissolution of the corporation.\n  3. Special meetings of the stockholders may be called by the board and\nby such person or persons as may be so authorized by the organization\ncertificate or the by-laws.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>