<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6011"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6011"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6011"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6011/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6011/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6011/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6011/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6011">
        <num>6011</num>
        <heading>Duties of inspectors at stockholders' meetings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 6011. Duties of inspectors at stockholders' meetings. The inspectors\nshall determine the number of shares outstanding and the voting power of\neach, the shares represented at the meeting, the existence of a quorum,\nthe validity and effect of proxies, and shall receive votes, ballots or\nconsents, hear and determine all challenges and questions arising in\nconnection with the right to vote, count and tabulate all votes, ballots\nor consents, determine the result, and do such acts as are proper to\nconduct the election or vote with fairness to all stockholders. On\nrequest of the person presiding at the meeting or any stockholder\nentitled to vote thereat, the inspectors shall make a report in writing\nof any challenge, question or matter determined by them and execute a\ncertificate of any fact found by them. Any report or certificate made by\nthem shall be prima facie evidence of the facts stated and of the vote\nas certified by them. Each inspector shall be entitled to a reasonable\ncompensation for his services, to be paid by the corporation.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>