<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6022"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6022"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="6022"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6022/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6022/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6022/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-6022/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_6022">
        <num>6022</num>
        <heading>Procedure to enforce stockholder's right to receive payment for shares</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_6022__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The corporation or, in the case of a merger, the receiving\ncorporation shall, within twenty days after the expiration of whichever\nis applicable of the two periods last mentioned, institute a special\nproceeding in the supreme court in the judicial district in which the\noffice of the corporation is located to determine the rights of\ndissenting stockholders and to fix the fair value of their shares.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6022__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the corporation fails to institute such proceeding within such\nperiod of twenty days, any dissenting stockholder may institute such\nproceeding for the same purpose not later than thirty days after the\nexpiration of such twenty day period. If such proceeding is not\ninstituted within such thirty day period, all dissenter's rights shall\nbe lost unless the supreme court, for good cause shown, shall otherwise\ndirect.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6022__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All dissenting stockholders, excepting those who, as provided in\nsubdivision seven, have agreed with the corporation upon the price to be\npaid for their shares, shall be made parties to such proceeding, which\nshall have the effect of an action quasi in rem against their shares.\nThe corporation shall serve a copy of the petition in such proceeding\nupon each dissenting stockholder who is a resident of this state in the\nmanner provided by law for the service of a summons, and upon each\nnonresident dissenting stockholder either by registered mail and\npublication, or in such other manner as is permitted by law. The\njurisdiction of the court shall be plenary and exclusive.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6022__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The court shall determine whether each dissenting stockholder, as\nto whom the corporation requests the court to make such determination,\nis entitled to receive payment for his shares. If the corporation does\nnot request any such determination or if the court finds that any\ndissenting stockholder is so entitled, it shall proceed to fix the value\nof the shares, which, for the purposes of this section, shall be the\nfair value as of the close of business on the day prior to the\nstockholders' authorization date, excluding any appreciation or\ndepreciation directly or indirectly induced by such corporate action or\nits proposal. The court may, if it so elects, appoint an appraiser to\nreceive evidence and recommend a decision on the question of fair value.\nSuch appraiser shall have the power, authority and duties specified in\nthe order appointing him, or any amendment thereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6022__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The final order in the proceeding shall be entered against the\ncorporation in favor of each dissenting stockholder who is a party to\nthe proceeding and is entitled thereto for the value of his shares so\ndetermined.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6022__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The final order shall include an allowance for interest at such\nrate as the court finds to be equitable, from the stockholders'\nauthorization date to the date of payment. If the court finds that the\nrefusal of any stockholder to accept the corporate offer of payment for\nhis shares was arbitrary, vexatious or otherwise not in good faith, no\ninterest shall be allowed to him.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6022__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The costs and expenses of such proceeding shall be determined by\nthe court and shall be assessed against the corporation, or, in the case\nof a merger, the receiving corporation, except that all or any part of\nsuch costs and expenses may be apportioned and assessed, as the court\nmay determine, against any or all of the dissenting stockholders who are\nparties to the proceeding if the court finds that their refusal to\naccept the corporate offer was arbitrary, vexatious or otherwise not in\ngood faith. Such expenses shall include reasonable compensation for and\nthe reasonable expenses of the appraiser, but shall exclude the fees and\nexpenses of counsel for and experts employed by any party unless the\ncourt, in its discretion, awards such fees and expenses. In exercising\nsuch discretion, the court shall consider any of the following:  (A)\nthat the fair value of the shares as determined materially exceeds the\namount which such corporation offered to pay; (B) that no offer was made\nby such corporation; and (C) that such corporation failed to institute\nthe special proceeding within the period specified therefor.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_6022__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within sixty days after final determination of the proceeding, the\ncorporation or, in the case of a merger, the receiving corporation shall\npay to each dissenting stockholder the amount found to be due him, upon\nsurrender of the certificates representing his shares.\n  9. Shares acquired by the corporation upon the payment of the agreed\nvalue therefor or of the amount due under the final order, as provided\nin this section, shall be dealt with as provided in section five\nthousand fourteen, except that, in the case of a merger, they shall be\ndisposed of as provided in the plan of merger or consolidation.\n  10. The enforcement by a stockholder of his right to receive payment\nfor his shares in the manner provided herein shall exclude the\nenforcement by such stockholder of any other right to which he might\notherwise be entitled by virtue of share ownership, except as provided\nin subdivision five, and except that this section shall not exclude the\nright of such stockholder to bring or maintain an appropriate action to\nobtain relief on the ground that such corporate action will be or is\nillegal or fraudulent as to him.\n  11. Except as otherwise expressly provided in this section, any notice\nto be given by a corporation to a stockholder under this section shall\nbe given in the manner provided in section six thousand five.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>