<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-611"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-611"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="611"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-611/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-611/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-611/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-611/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_611">
        <num>611</num>
        <heading>Special deputies; assistants; counsel and other employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 611. Special deputies; assistants; counsel and other employees. The\nsuperintendent may, by certificate, under his hand and the official seal\nof the department, appoint one or more special deputy superintendents as\nagent or agents to assist him in liquidating the business and affairs of\nany banking organization in his possession.  The superintendent shall\nfile such certificate in his office and shall cause a certified copy\nthereof to be filed with the supreme court in the judicial district in\nwhich the principal office of such banking organization is located. He\nmay delegate such special deputy superintendents to perform such duties\nconnected with such liquidation as he may deem proper.  The\nsuperintendent may employ such counsel and expert assistants, without\nbeing subject to the requirements of section one hundred twelve of the\nstate finance law or to the prior approval of any other state agency,\nunder such titles as he shall assign to them and may retain such of the\nofficers or employees of such banking organization as he may deem\nnecessary in the liquidation and distribution of its assets. He shall\nrequire such security as he may deem proper from his agents and\nassistants appointed pursuant to the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>