<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-612"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-612"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="612"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-612/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-612/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-612/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-612/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_612">
        <num>612</num>
        <heading>Certificates to be recorded and received in evidence</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 612. Certificates to be recorded and received in evidence. The\nsuperintendent, deputy superintendents, and the special deputy\nsuperintendents designated under the provisions of section six hundred\neleven of this chapter, are hereby authorized to subscribe and\nacknowledge written statements reciting determinations made or acts\nperformed pursuant to the powers vested in and duties imposed upon the\nsuperintendent pursuant to the terms and provisions of this chapter.\nEvery paper so executed and acknowledged by the superintendent or a\ndeputy superintendent or a special deputy superintendent may be recorded\nin any proper recording office in the same manner and with the same\neffect as a deed regularly acknowledged and, whether or not so recorded,\nshall be received in evidence in any action or proceeding now pending or\nhereafter commenced, and shall be presumptive evidence of the facts\ntherein stated.\n  Any statement, similarly executed and acknowledged, setting forth an\nextract from a book, record or document of any banking organization in\nthe possession of the superintendent or any other book, record or\ndocument relating to the liquidation thereof, shall be received in\nevidence in any action or proceeding now pending or hereafter commenced\nwith the same effect as the original book, record or document.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>