<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-614"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-614"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="614"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-614/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-614/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-614/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-614/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_614">
        <num>614</num>
        <heading>Obtaining possession of pleadings, et cetera, in actions against which attorneys' liens are asserted</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 614. Obtaining possession of pleadings, et cetera, in actions\nagainst which attorneys' liens are asserted. When the superintendent is\nin possession of any banking organization, and attorneys' liens are\nasserted by attorneys of such banking organization against any causes of\naction to which such banking organization is a party, or against\npleadings or other papers in the possession of such attorneys relating\nto such causes of action, or if such liens are asserted against any\nevidences of title to any assets or against any of the assets of such\nbanking organization then in the possession of such attorneys, the\nsuperintendent may institute special proceedings and petition the court\nto fix and determine the amount of such liens. Such proceedings shall be\ninstituted in the county in which the principal office of such banking\norganization is located. Upon application of the superintendent and upon\nnotice to such attorneys to be prescribed by the court, the court may by\norder prior to final order in such proceeding direct such attorneys to\ndeliver to the superintendent all property of such banking organization,\nagainst which such liens are asserted, together with such consents to\nsubstitution of attorneys as the court may direct, upon the\nsuperintendent furnishing security to such attorneys in the manner and\nto an amount that may be fixed by the court.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>