<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-680-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-680-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="680-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-680-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-680-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-680-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-680-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_680_A">
        <num>680-A</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is in a record between a bank and one or more depositors;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>may have one or more beneficiaries as additional parties; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>states the intention of the parties to establish a special deposit\ngoverned by this article.\n  2. "Bank" means a person engaged in the business of banking and\nincludes a savings bank, savings and loan association, credit union,\ntrust company, and a bank as defined in section two of this chapter.\nEach branch or separate office of a bank is a separate bank for the\npurpose of this article.\n  3. "Beneficiary" means a person that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is identified as a beneficiary in an account agreement; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if not identified as a beneficiary in an account agreement, may be\nentitled to payment from a special deposit:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>under the account agreement; or\n  (ii) on termination of the special deposit.\n  4. "Contingency" means an event or circumstance stated in an account\nagreement that is not certain to occur but must occur before the bank is\nobligated to pay a beneficiary.\n  5. "Creditor process" means attachment, garnishment, levy, notice of\nlien, sequestration, or similar process issued by or on behalf of a\ncreditor or other claimant.\n  6. "Depositor" means a person that establishes or funds a special\ndeposit.\n  7. "Good faith" means honesty in fact and observance of reasonable\ncommercial standards of fair dealing.\n  8. "Knowledge" means:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>with respect to a beneficiary, actual knowledge of the fact; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>with respect to a bank holding a special deposit:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if the bank:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_680_A__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>has established a reasonable routine for communicating material\ninformation to an individual to whom the bank has assigned\nresponsibility for the special deposit; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_680_A__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>maintains reasonable compliance with the routine, actual knowledge\nof the fact by that individual; or\n  (ii) if the bank has not established and maintained reasonable\ncompliance with a routine described in subparagraph</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nparagraph or otherwise exercised due diligence, implied knowledge of the\nfact that would have come to the attention of an individual to whom the\nbank has assigned responsibility for the special deposit.\n  9. "Obligated to pay a beneficiary" or "obligation to pay a\nbeneficiary" means a beneficiary is entitled under the account agreement\nto receive from the bank a payment when:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a contingency has occurred; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the bank has knowledge the contingency has occurred.\n  10. "Permissible purpose" means a governmental, regulatory,\ncommercial, charitable, or testamentary objective of the parties stated\nin an account agreement. The term includes an objective to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hold funds:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in escrow, including for a purchase and sale, lease, buyback, or\nother transaction;\n  (ii) as a security deposit of a tenant;\n  (iii) that may be distributed to a person as remuneration, retirement\nor other benefit, or compensation under a judgment, consent decree,\ncourt order, or other decision of a tribunal; or\n  (iv) for distribution to a defined class of persons after\nidentification of the class members and their interest in the funds;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide assurance with respect to an obligation created by\ncontract, such as earnest money to ensure a transaction closes;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>settle an obligation that arises in the operation of a payment\nsystem, securities settlement system, or other financial market\ninfrastructure;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide assurance with respect to an obligation that arises in the\noperation of a payment system, securities settlement system, or other\nfinancial market infrastructure; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hold margin, other cash collateral, or funds that support the\norderly functioning of financial market infrastructure or the\nperformance of an obligation with respect to the infrastructure.\n  11. "Person" means an individual, estate, business or nonprofit\nentity, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or\ninstrumentality, or other legal entity. The term includes a protected\nseries, however denominated, of an entity if the protected series is\nestablished under law that limits, or limits if conditions specified\nunder law are satisfied, the ability of a creditor of the entity or of\nany other protected series of the entity to satisfy a claim from assets\nof the protected series.\n  12. "Record" means information:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>inscribed on a tangible medium; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_680_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>stored in an electronic or other medium and retrievable in\nperceivable form.\n  13. "Special deposit" means a deposit that satisfies section six\nhundred eighty-d of this article.\n  14. "State" means a state of the United States, the District of\nColumbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any other\nterritory or possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United\nStates. The term includes an agency or instrumentality of the state.\n  * NB Effective January 1, 2026\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>