<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7">
        <num>7</num>
        <heading>Payment of dividends or interest upon unclaimed deposits or shares; limitation of charges in connection with savings accounts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7. Payment of dividends or interest upon unclaimed deposits or\nshares; limitation of charges in connection with savings accounts. 1. No\nbanking organization or foreign banking corporation transacting business\nin this state shall discontinue the payment of dividends or interest on\nany deposit made with such organization or corporation, or reduce the\nrate at which dividends or interest is paid, solely because such deposit\nis inactive or unclaimed, except that payment of dividends or interest\nmay be discontinued for the period following June thirtieth of the year\nin which the deposit is paid to the state comptroller pursuant to\nsection three hundred three of the abandoned property law. A share\nissued by a savings and loan association or by a credit union shall be\ndeemed a deposit for the purposes of this section.\n  2. No banking organization or foreign banking corporation transacting\nbusiness in this state shall impose any service charge on an inactive\nsavings account which is higher than the service charge imposed by such\norganization or corporation on an active savings account; provided,\nhowever, that a banking organization or foreign banking corporation may\nimpose a reasonable charge on an inactive savings account for costs\nrelated to or incurred as a result of the payment or delivery of\nabandoned property to the state comptroller pursuant to the abandoned\nproperty law.\n  3. The superintendent of financial services may promulgate such\nregulations as he or she deems necessary and proper to implement and\ndefine the provisions of this section.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>