<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7011"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7011"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="7011"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7011/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7011/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7011/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-7011/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_7011">
        <num>7011</num>
        <heading>Notice of board meetings; waiver; adjournment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 7011. Notice of board meetings; waiver; adjournment. 1.  Unless\notherwise provided by the by-laws, regular meetings of the board may be\nheld without notice if the time and place of such meetings are fixed by\nthe by-laws or the board. Special meetings of the board shall be held\nupon notice to the directors.\n  2. The by-laws may prescribe what shall constitute notice of meeting\nof the board. A notice, or waiver of notice, need not specify the\npurpose of any regular or special meeting of the board, unless required\nby the by-laws.\n  3. Notice of a meeting need not be given to any director who submits a\nsigned waiver of notice whether before or after the meeting, or who\nattends the meeting without protesting, prior thereto or at its\ncommencement, the lack of notice to him.\n  4. A majority of the directors present, whether or not a quorum is\npresent, may adjourn any meeting to another time and place. If the\nby-laws so provide, notice of any adjournment of a meeting of the board\nto another time or place shall be given to the directors who were not\npresent at the time of the adjournment and, unless such time and place\nare announced at the meeting, to the other directors.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>