<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-719"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-719"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="719"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-719/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-719/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-719/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-719/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_719">
        <num>719</num>
        <heading>Prohibited practices</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 719. Prohibited practices. No student loan servicer shall:\n  1. Employ any scheme, device or artifice to defraud or mislead a\nborrower;\n  2. Engage in any unfair, deceptive or predatory act or practice toward\nany person or misrepresent or omit any material information in\nconnection with the servicing of a student loan, including, but not\nlimited to, misrepresenting the amount, nature or terms of any fee or\npayment due or claimed to be due on a student loan, the terms and\nconditions of the loan agreement or the borrower's obligations under the\nloan;\n  3. Misapply payments to the outstanding balance of any student loan or\nto any related interest or fees;\n  4. Provide inaccurate information to a consumer reporting agency;\n  5. Refuse to communicate with an authorized representative of the\nborrower who provides a written authorization signed by the borrower,\nprovided that the servicer may adopt procedures reasonably related to\nverifying that the representative is in fact authorized to act on behalf\nof the borrower;\n  6. Make any false statement or make any omission of a material fact in\nconnection with any information or reports filed with a governmental\nagency or in connection with any investigation conducted by the\nsuperintendent or another governmental agency;\n  7. Fail to respond within fifteen calendar days to communications from\nthe department, or within such shorter, reasonable time as the\ndepartment may request in his or her communication; or\n  8. Fail to provide a response within fifteen calendar days to a\nconsumer complaint submitted to the servicer by the department. If\nnecessary, a student loan servicer may request additional time up to a\nmaximum of forty-five calendar days, provided that such request is\naccompanied by an explanation why such additional time is reasonable and\nnecessary.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>