<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-742"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-742"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="742"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-742/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-742/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-742/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-742/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_742">
        <num>742</num>
        <heading>Superintendent authorized to examine</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 742. Superintendent authorized to examine. 1. The superintendent\nshall have the power to make such investigations as the superintendent\nshall deem necessary to determine whether any buy-now-pay-later lender\nor any other person has violated any of the provisions of this article\nor any other applicable law, or whether any licensee has conducted\nitself in such manner as would justify the revocation of its license,\nand to the extent necessary therefor, the superintendent may require the\nattendance of and examine any person under oath, and shall have the\npower to compel the production of all relevant books, records, accounts,\nand documents.\n  2. The superintendent shall have the power to make such examinations\nof the books, records, accounts and documents used in the business of\nany licensee as the superintendent shall deem necessary to determine\nwhether any such licensee has violated any of the provisions of this\nchapter or any other applicable law or to secure information lawfully\nrequired by the superintendent.\n  * NB Effective upon the one hundred eightieth day after the\npromulgation of rules and/or regulations by the department of financial\nservices to effectuate certain provisions (see Ch. 58 of 2025, Part Y, ยง\n13)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>