<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-743"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-743"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="743"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-743/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-743/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-743/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-743/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_743">
        <num>743</num>
        <heading>Licensee's books and records; reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 743. Licensee's books and records; reports. 1. A buy-now-pay-later\nlender shall keep and use in its business such books, accounts and\nrecords as will enable the superintendent to determine whether such\nbuy-now-pay-later lender is complying with the provisions of this\narticle and with the rules and regulations promulgated by the\nsuperintendent thereunder. Every buy-now-pay-later lender shall preserve\nsuch books, accounts and records for at least six years after making the\nfinal entry in respect to any buy-now-pay-later loan recorded therein;\nprovided, however, the preservation of photographic or digital\nreproductions thereof or records in photographic or digital form shall\nconstitute compliance with this requirement.\n  2. By a date to be set by the superintendent, each licensee shall\nannually file a report with the superintendent giving such information\nas the superintendent may require concerning the licensee's business and\noperations during the preceding calendar year within the state under the\nauthority of this article. Such report shall be subscribed and affirmed\nas true by the licensee under the penalties of perjury and be in the\nform prescribed by the superintendent. In addition to such annual\nreports, the superintendent may require of licensees such additional\nregular or special reports as the superintendent may deem necessary to\nthe proper supervision of licensees under this article. Such additional\nreports shall be in the form prescribed by the superintendent and shall\nbe subscribed and affirmed as true under the penalties of perjury.\n  * NB Effective upon the one hundred eightieth day after the\npromulgation of rules and/or regulations by the department of financial\nservices to effectuate certain provisions (see Ch. 58 of 2025, Part Y, ยง\n13)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>