<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-75-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-75-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="75-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-75-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-75-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-75-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-75-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_75_G">
        <num>75-G</num>
        <heading>Report of compliance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 75-g. Report of compliance. 1. By the fifteenth day of January and\nJuly of each year (or the following business day if such day is not a\nbusiness day), every banking institution which had an automated teller\nmachine facility which was in operation on the fifteenth day of the\npreceding month shall submit a written compliance report to the\ndepartment on a form prescribed by the superintendent, certifying that\nsuch automated teller machine facility is in compliance with the\nprovisions of this article or any variance or exemption that has been\ngranted, or if such facility is not in compliance with such provisions,\nstating the manner in which such facility fails to meet such\nrequirements. Notwithstanding article three of the state technology law\nor any other law to the contrary, the superintendent may require that\nsuch reports and any other reports required by this section shall be\nmade by electronic means, unless the superintendent, in his or her sole\ndiscretion, grants a waiver of such electronic filing requirements, upon\ngood cause shown.\n  2. If any compliance report required by subdivision one of this\nsection indicates any failure to meet the requirements of this article,\nsuch banking institution shall submit a written report to the\ndepartment, on a form prescribed by the superintendent, no later than\nthe eleventh business day following such compliance report, indicating\nwhether each such failure has been corrected and, for any failure that\nhas not been corrected, the reason for such failure and the expected\ncorrection date.  If any such failure shall not have been corrected\nwithin ten business days of the filing date of the applicable compliance\nreport, such banking institution shall, promptly after correcting such\nfailure, submit a written report to the department with the date or\ndates of each such correction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>