<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-78"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-78"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="78"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-78/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-78/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-78/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-78/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_78">
        <num>78</num>
        <heading>Powers with respect to certain crimes and frauds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 78. Powers with respect to certain crimes and frauds. If the\nsuperintendent has a reasonable suspicion that a person or entity is\nengaging in or has engaged in fraud (as interpreted under this chapter,\nthe insurance law or the financial services law) or a misdemeanor or\nfelony under this chapter or one of the articles of the penal law\nenumerated in this section in connection with activities regulated by\nthe superintendent pursuant to this chapter or involving a product\nregulated pursuant to this chapter, the superintendent may undertake\nsuch investigation as is deemed necessary, and in the enforcement of\nthis chapter, determine whether any such person or entity has violated\nor is about to violate this chapter or any such enumerated articles. The\napplicable articles of the penal law are article one hundred fifty-five,\none hundred seventy, one hundred seventy-five, one hundred seventy-six,\none hundred eighty, one hundred eighty-five, one hundred eighty-seven,\none hundred ninety, two hundred, two hundred ten or four hundred\nseventy. Notwithstanding the above-referenced laws or articles, the\nscope of authority set forth in this section shall not be deemed to\notherwise limit or impair the ability of the department to assist any\nother entity in an investigation involving a violation of law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>