<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-8001"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-8001"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="8001"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-8001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-8001/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-8001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-8001/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_8001">
        <num>8001</num>
        <heading>Right to amend organization certificate</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To change its corporate name.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the case of a bank or trust company, to change its corporate\npowers in accordance with section ninety-four.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To extend the duration of the corporation or, if the corporation\nceased to exist because of the expiration of the duration specified in\nits organization certificate, to revive its existence.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To increase or decrease the number of its directors, or to provide\nthat the number of its directors shall be not less than a stated minimum\nnor more than a stated maximum; provided that in either case the number\nof directors shall not be less than the minimum prescribed in this\nchapter, and provided further that the number of the directors may be\nincreased notwithstanding any maximum number prescribed by any special\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To increase or decrease the aggregate number of shares, or shares\nof any class or series, which the corporation shall have authority to\nissue.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To eliminate from authorized shares any class of shares, or any\nshares of any class, whether issued or unissued.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To increase the par value of any authorized shares of any class,\nwhether issued or unissued.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To reduce the par value of any authorized shares of any class,\nwhether issued or unissued.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To change any authorized shares, whether issued or unissued, into\na different number of shares of the same class or into the same or a\ndifferent number of shares of any one or more classes or any series\nthereof.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To fix, change or abolish the designation of any authorized class\nor any series thereof, or any of the relative rights, preferences and\nlimitations of any shares of any authorized class or any series thereof,\nwhether issued or unissued, including any provisions in respect of any\nundeclared dividends, whether or not cumulative or accrued, or the\nredemption of any shares, or any preemptive right to acquire shares or\nother securities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>As to the shares of any preferred class, then or theretofore\nauthorized, which may be issued in series, to grant authority to the\nboard or to change or revoke the authority of the board to establish and\ndesignate series and to fix the number of shares and the relative\nrights, preferences and limitations as between series.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_8001__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To strike out, change or add any provision, not inconsistent with\nthis chapter or any other statute, relating to the business of the\ncorporation, its affairs, its rights or powers, or the rights or powers\nof its stockholders, directors or officers, including any provision\nwhich under this chapter is required or permitted to be set forth in the\nby-laws.\n  3. A corporation created by special act may accomplish any or all\namendments permitted in this title, in the manner and subject to the\nconditions provided in this subarticle.\n  4. A corporation may not change the location of its office under this\nsection.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>