<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9-V"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9-V"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-09-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9-V"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9_V">
        <num>9-V</num>
        <heading>Savings promotion prize giveaway</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9_V__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe interest rate associated with any such qualifying account is not\nreduced when compared with other comparable non-qualifying accounts\noffered by any banking organization, federal credit union, federal\nsavings bank, federal savings and loan association or national bank\nassociation, to account for the possibility of depositors winning\nspecified prizes; and (ii) no banking organization, federal credit\nunion, federal savings bank, federal savings and loan association, or\nnational bank association may charge a fee for entry. All fees charged\nin connection with such qualifying account shall be comparable with all\nfees charged in connection with other comparable non-qualifying\naccounts, if any, offered by any banking organization, federal credit\nunion, federal savings bank, federal savings and loan association, or\nnational bank association.\n  b. A savings promotion shall be conducted such that each entry in the\nsavings promotion has an equal chance of being drawn.\n  c. Participants in a savings promotion shall not be required to be\npresent at a prize drawing in order to win.\n  d. The offering of a savings promotion shall be subject to section\nthree hundred sixty-nine-e of the general business law in the same\nmanner as other promotions regulated thereunder. For purposes of the\ngeneral business law and the penal law, a savings promotion offered in\naccordance with this chapter shall not be deemed to entail consideration\nor the promotion of gambling or a lottery.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>