<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9008"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9008"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="9008"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9008/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9008/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9008/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-9008/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_9008">
        <num>9008</num>
        <heading>Indemnification of directors and officers by a court</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_9008__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the civil action or proceeding in which the expenses were\nincurred or other amounts were paid, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_9008__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To the supreme court in a separate proceeding, in which case the\napplication shall set forth the disposition of any previous application\nmade to any court for the same or similar relief and also reasonable\ncause for the failure to make application for such relief in the action\nor proceeding in which the expenses were incurred or other amounts were\npaid.\n  2. The application shall be made in such manner and form as may be\nrequired by the applicable rules of court, or in the absence thereof, by\ndirection of a court to which it is made. Such application shall be upon\nnotice to the corporation. The court may also direct that notice be\ngiven at the expense of the corporation to the shareholders and such\nother persons as it may designate in such manner as it may require.\n  3. Where indemnification is sought by judicial action, the court may\nallow a person such reasonable expenses, including attorneys' fees,\nduring the pendency of the litigation as are necessary in connection\nwith his defense therein, if the court shall find that the defendant has\nby his pleadings or during the course of the litigation raised genuine\nissues of fact or law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>