<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="BNK">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-96"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-96"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-09-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="96"/>
          <FRBRname value="BNK"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-96/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-96/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-96/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/bnk/section-96/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96">
        <num>96</num>
        <heading>General powers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To receive upon deposit for safe-keeping for hire upon terms\nand conditions to be prescribed by the bank or trust company, money,\nsecurities, papers of any kind and any other personal property;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To engage in the safe deposit business by renting vaults, safe\ndeposit boxes and other receptacles upon premises occupied by the bank\nor trust company, upon such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by\nthe bank or trust company.\n  4. To issue by its board of directors capital notes or debentures,\nwhen so specifically authorized by the superintendent, and, when so\nspecifically authorized by the superintendent, to receive in payment\ntherefor, in whole or in part, mortgages, interests therein or other\nproperty and to retain, unrecorded or unregistered, assignments or\nconveyances of such mortgages, interests therein or other property,\nprovided that the superintendent shall not approve the retention of any\nassignment of mortgage or interest therein or any conveyance of other\nproperty, which may be recorded or registered, without record or\nregistration thereof, except where such mortgage, interest therein or\nother property is assigned or conveyed by a corporation organized under\nthe banking law or by a corporation wholly owned by not less than twenty\nsavings banks of this state.\n  5. To become a member of a federal reserve bank, and to have and\nexercise all powers, not in conflict with the laws of this state, which\nare conferred upon any such member by the federal reserve act. Such bank\nor trust company and its directors, officers and stockholders shall\ncontinue to be subject, however, to all liabilities and duties imposed\nupon them by any law of this state and to all the provisions of this\nchapter relating to banks and trust companies.\n  6. To assume and discharge such obligations to Federal Deposit\nInsurance Corporation as may be necessary or required for the purpose of\nmaintaining deposit insurance in such corporation.\n  7.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To act as financial agent of the United States Government and\nas depositary of public money of the United States (including, without\nbeing limited to, revenues and funds of the United States, and any funds\nthe deposit of which is subject to the control or regulation of the\nUnited States or any of its officers, agents, or employees, and Postal\nSavings funds); and to perform all such reasonable duties as depositary\nof such public money and as financial agent of the United States\nGovernment as may be required of it; and to pledge assets or furnish\nother security, satisfactory in form and amount to the Secretary of the\nTreasury of the United States, for the safekeeping and prompt payment of\nsuch public money deposited with it and for the faithful performance of\nits duties as financial agent of the United States Government.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To pledge assets or furnish other security, satisfactory in form\nand amount to judges of courts of bankruptcy, for the repayment of\ndeposits of the money of estates under the national bankruptcy act.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_96__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To pledge assets or furnish other security, satisfactory in form\nand amount to the depositor, for the repayment of moneys held in the\nname of any state (which term shall include every territory of the\nUnited States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto\nRico), or of any foreign nation, or of any Indian nation or tribe, or of\nany political subdivision or instrumentality or authority of any of\nthem, when required to be secured by applicable law, decree, regulation\nor resolution, and to pledge assets or furnish other security for the\nrepayment of moneys held as fiduciary, or in the name of a fiduciary, of\nany trust created by any such state, foreign nation, Indian nation or\ntribe, political subdivision, instrumentality or authority as required\nby the terms of such trust; provided, however, that before any pledge or\nsecurity is made or furnished to any depositor other than this state or\na political subdivision, instrumentality or authority of this state, the\nbank or trust company shall obtain a certified or official copy of such\nlaw, decree, regulation, or resolution or trust requiring such pledge or\nother security, and an opinion of counsel that such pledge or security\nis required by such law, decree, regulation, or resolution or by the\nterms of such trust.\n  9. To execute and deliver such guaranties as may be incidental to\ncarrying on the business of a bank or trust company.\n  10. To exercise, subject to such regulations as may be issued from\ntime to time by the superintendent, through any foreign branch office\n(other than one opened or occupied in another state of the United\nStates, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States,\nGuam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Northern\nMariana Islands) opened and occupied with the approval of the\nsuperintendent as provided in section one hundred five of this article,\nsuch further powers as may be usual in connection with the transaction\nof ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>