<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-120.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-120.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="120.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-120.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-120.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-120.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-120.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_120_30">
        <num>120.30</num>
        <heading>Warrant of arrest; by what courts issuable and in what courts returnable</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 120.30 Warrant of arrest; by what courts issuable and in what courts\n           returnable.\n  1. A warrant of arrest may be issued only by the local criminal court\nor youth part of the superior court with which the underlying accusatory\ninstrument has been filed, and it may be made returnable in such issuing\ncourt only.\n  2. The particular local criminal court or courts or youth part of the\nsuperior court with which any particular local criminal court or youth\npart of the superior court accusatory instrument may be filed for the\npurpose of obtaining a warrant of arrest are determined, generally, by\nthe provisions of section 100.55 or 100.60 of this title. If, however, a\nparticular accusatory instrument may pursuant to said section 100.55 be\nfiled with a particular town court and such town court is not available\nat the time such instrument is sought to be filed and a warrant\nobtained, such accusatory instrument may be filed with the town court of\nany adjoining town of the same county. If such instrument may be filed\npursuant to said section 100.55 with a particular village court and such\nvillage court is not available at the time, it may be filed with the\ntown court of the town embracing such village, or if such town court is\nnot available either, with the town court of any adjoining town of the\nsame county.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>