<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.55"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.55"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="140.55"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.55/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.55/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_140_55">
        <num>140.55</num>
        <heading>Arrest without a warrant; by peace officers of other states for offense committed outside state; uniform close pursuit act</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 140.55 Arrest without a warrant; by peace officers of other states for\n             offense committed outside state; uniform close pursuit act.\n  1.  As used in this section, the word "state" shall include the\nDistrict of Columbia.\n  2.  Any peace officer of another state of the United States, who\nenters this state in close pursuit and continues within this state in\nsuch close pursuit of a person in order to arrest him, shall have the\nsame authority to arrest and hold in custody such person on the ground\nthat he has committed a crime in another state which is a crime under\nthe laws of the state of New York, as police officers of this state have\nto arrest and hold in custody a person on the ground that he has\ncommitted a crime in this state.\n  3.  If an arrest is made in this state by an officer of another state\nin accordance with the provisions of subdivision two, he shall without\nunnecessary delay take the person arrested before a local criminal court\nwhich shall conduct a hearing for the sole purpose of determining if the\narrest was in accordance with the provisions of subdivision two, and not\nof determining the guilt or innocence of the arrested person.  If such\ncourt determines that the arrest was in accordance with such\nsubdivision, it shall commit the person arrested to the custody of the\nofficer making the arrest, who shall without unnecessary delay take him\nto the state from which he fled.  If such court determines that the\narrest was unlawful, it shall discharge the person arrested.\n  4.  This section shall not be construed so as to make unlawful any\narrest in this state which would otherwise be lawful.\n  5.  Upon the taking effect of this section it shall be the duty of the\nsecretary of state to certify a copy of this section to the executive\ndepartment of each of the states of the United States.\n  6.  This section shall apply only to peace officers of a state which\nby its laws has made similar provision for the arrest and custody of\npersons closely pursued within the territory thereof.\n  7.  If any part of this section is for any reason declared void, it is\ndeclared to be the intent of this section that such invalidity shall not\naffect the validity of the remaining portions of this section.\n  8.  This section may be cited as the uniform act on close pursuit.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>