<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.25"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.25"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="140.25"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_140_25">
        <num>140.25</num>
        <heading>Arrest without a warrant; by peace officer</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any offense when he has reasonable cause to believe that such\nperson has committed such offense in his presence; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A crime when he has reasonable cause to believe that such person\nhas committed such crime, whether in his presence or otherwise.\n  2.  A peace officer acts "pursuant to his special duties" in making an\narrest only when the arrest is for:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An offense defined by a statute which such peace officer, by\nreason of the specialized nature of his particular employment or by\nexpress provision of law, is required or authorized to enforce; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An offense committed or reasonably believed by him to have been\ncommitted in such manner or place as to render arrest of the offender by\nsuch peace officer under the particular circumstances an integral part\nof his specialized duties.\n  3.  A peace officer, whether or not he is acting pursuant to his\nspecial duties, may arrest a person for an offense committed or believed\nby him to have been committed within the geographical area of such peace\nofficer's employment, as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>He may arrest such person for any offense when such person has in\nfact committed such offense in his presence; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>He may arrest such person for a felony when he has reasonable\ncause to believe that such person has committed such felony, whether in\nhis presence or otherwise.\n  4.  A peace officer, when outside the geographical area of his\nemployment, may, anywhere in the state, arrest a person for a felony\nwhen he has reasonable cause to believe that such person has there\ncommitted such felony in his presence, provided that such arrest is made\nduring or immediately after the allegedly criminal conduct or during the\nalleged perpetrator's immediate flight therefrom.\n  5.  For the purposes of this section, the "geographical area of\nemployment" of a peace officer is as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The "geographical area of employment" of any peace officer\nemployed as such by any agency of the state consists of the entire\nstate;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The "geographical area of employment" of any peace officer\nemployed as such by an agency of a county, city, town or village\nconsists of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such county, city, town or village, as the case may be,\nand (ii) any other place where he is, at a particular time, acting in\nthe course of his particular duties or employment;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_25__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The "geographical area of employment" of any peace officer\nemployed as such by any private organization consists of any place in\nthe state where he is, at a particular time, acting in the course of his\nparticular duties or employment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>