<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.40"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.40"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-09-06" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="140.40"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-140.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_140_40">
        <num>140.40</num>
        <heading>Arrest without a warrant; by person acting other than as a police officer or a peace officer; procedure after arrest</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the arrest is for an offense other than a class A, B, C or D\nfelony or a violation of section 130.25, former section 130.40, section\n205.10, 205.17, 205.19 or 215.56 of the penal law and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>owing to\nunavailability of a local criminal court the appropriate police officer\nhaving custody of the arrested person is unable to bring him before such\na court with reasonable promptness, the arrested person must be dealt\nwith in the manner prescribed in subdivision three of section 140.20, as\nif he had been arrested by a police officer.\n  3. If the arrest is for an offense other than a class A, B, C or D\nfelony or a violation of section 130.25, former section 130.40, section\n205.10, 205.17, 205.19 or 215.56 of the penal law, the arrested person\nneed not be brought before a local criminal court, as provided in\nsubdivision one, and the procedure may instead be as follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An appropriate police officer may issue and serve an appearance\nticket upon the arrested person and release him from custody, as\nprescribed in subdivision two of section 150.20; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The desk officer in charge at the appropriate police officer's\nstation, county jail or police headquarters, or any of his superior\nofficers, may, in such place, fix pre-arraignment bail and, upon deposit\nthereof, issue and serve an appearance ticket upon the arrested person\nand release him from custody, as prescribed in section 150.30.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a police\nofficer is not required to take an arrested person into custody or to\ntake any other action prescribed in this section on behalf of the\narresting person if he has reasonable cause to believe that the arrested\nperson did not commit the alleged offense or that the arrest was\notherwise unauthorized.\n  5. If a police officer takes an arrested juvenile offender or a person\nsixteen or commencing October first, two thosuand nineteen, seventeen\nyears of age into custody, the police officer shall immediately notify\nthe parent or other person legally responsible for his or her care or\nthe person with whom he or she is domiciled, that such offender or\nperson has been arrested, and the location of the facility where he or\nshe is being detained. If the officer determines that it is necessary to\nquestion a juvenile offender or such person the officer must take him or\nher to a facility designated by the chief administrator of the courts as\na suitable place for the questioning of children or, upon the consent of\na parent or other person legally responsible for the care of the\njuvenile offender or such person, to his or her residence and there\nquestion him or her for a reasonable period of time. A juvenile offender\nor such person shall not be questioned pursuant to this section unless\nhe or she and a person required to be notified pursuant to this\nsubdivision, if present, have been advised:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of his or her right to remain silent;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the statements made by the juvenile offender or such person\nmay be used in a court of law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of his or her right to have an attorney present at such\nquestioning; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of his or her right to have an attorney provided for him or her\nwithout charge if he or she is unable to afford counsel.\n  In determining the suitability of questioning and determining the\nreasonable period of time for questioning such a juvenile offender or\nsuch person, his or her age, the presence or absence of his or her\nparents or other persons legally responsible for his or her care and\nnotification pursuant to this subdivision shall be included among\nrelevant considerations.\n  6. As used in this section:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An "appropriate police officer" means one who would himself be\nauthorized to make the arrest in question as a police officer pursuant\nto section 140.10;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_140_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An "appropriate local criminal court" means one with which an\naccusatory instrument charging the offense in question may properly be\nfiled pursuant to the provisions of section 100.55.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>