<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-150.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-150.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-01-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="150.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-150.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-150.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-150.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-150.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_150_10">
        <num>150.10</num>
        <heading>Appearance ticket; definition, form and content</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 150.10 Appearance ticket; definition, form and content.\n  1. An appearance ticket is a written notice issued and subscribed by a\npolice officer or other public servant authorized by state law or local\nlaw enacted pursuant to the provisions of the municipal home rule law to\nissue the same, directing a designated person to appear in a designated\nlocal criminal court at a designated future time in connection with his\nalleged commission of a designated offense. A notice conforming to such\ndefinition constitutes an appearance ticket regardless of whether it is\nreferred to in some other provision of law as a summons or by any other\nname or title.\n  2. When an appearance ticket as defined in subdivision one of this\nsection is issued to a person in conjunction with an offense charged in\na simplified information, said appearance ticket shall contain the\nlanguage, set forth in subdivision four of section 100.25, notifying the\ndefendant of his right to receive a supporting deposition.\n  3. Before issuing an appearance ticket a police officer or other\npublic servant must inform the arrestee that they may provide their\ncontact information for the purposes of receiving a court notification\nto remind them of their court appearance date from the court or a\ncertified pretrial services agency. Such contact information may include\none or more phone numbers, a residential address or address at which the\narrestee receives mail, or an email address. The contact information\nshall be recorded and be transmitted to the local criminal court as\nrequired by section 150.80 of this article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>