<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.25"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.25"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="170.25"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_170_25">
        <num>170.25</num>
        <heading>Divestiture of jurisdiction by indictment; removal of case to superior court at defendant's instance</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_25__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a motion in a superior court is not made by the defendant\nwithin the designated period, the proceedings in the local criminal\ncourt must continue.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_25__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If a motion in a superior court is made by the defendant within\nthe designated period, such motion stays the proceedings in the local\ncriminal court until the entry of an order determining such motion.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_25__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the superior court enters an order granting the motion, such\norder stays the proceedings in the local criminal court as provided in\nsubdivision two; and upon a subsequent indictment or dismissal of such\ncharge by the grand jury, the proceedings in the local criminal court\nterminate as provided in subdivision two.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_25__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the superior court enters an order denying the motion, the\nproceedings in the local criminal court must continue.\n  4.  Upon application of a defendant who on the basis of an order\nissued by a superior court pursuant to subdivision one is awaiting grand\njury action, and who, at the time of such order or subsequent thereto,\nhas been committed to the custody of the sheriff pending grand jury\naction, and who has been confined in such custody for a period of more\nthan forty-five days without the occurrence of any grand jury action or\ndisposition, the superior court which issued such order must release him\non his own recognizance unless:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_25__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The lack of a grand jury disposition during such period of\nconfinement was due to the defendant's request, action or condition, or\noccurred with his consent; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_25__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The people have shown good cause why such order of release should\nnot be issued.  Such good cause must consist of some compelling fact or\ncircumstance which precluded grand jury action within the prescribed\nperiod or rendered the same against the interest of justice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>