<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.50"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.50"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="170.50"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-170.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_170_50">
        <num>170.50</num>
        <heading>Motion in superior court to dismiss prosecutor's information</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_50__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The evidence before the grand jury was not legally sufficient to\nsupport the charge; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_170_50__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The grand jury proceeding resulting in the filing of such\nprosecutor's information was defective.\n  2.  The criteria and procedures for consideration and disposition of\nsuch motion are the same as those prescribed in sections 210.30 and\n210.35, governing consideration and disposition of a motion to dismiss\nan indictment on the ground of insufficiency of grand jury evidence or\nof a defective grand jury proceeding; and, where appropriate, the\ngeneral procedural rules prescribed in section 210.45 for consideration\nand disposition of a motion to dismiss an indictment are also\napplicable.\n  3.  Upon dismissing a prosecutor's information or a count thereof\npursuant to this section, the court may, upon application of the people,\nin its discretion authorize the people to resubmit the charge or charges\nto the same or another grand jury.  In the absence of such\nauthorization, such charge or charges may not be resubmitted to a grand\njury.  The rules prescribed in subdivisions eight and nine of section\n210.45 concerning the discharge of a defendant from custody or\nexoneration of bail in the absence of an authorization to resubmit an\nindictment to a grand jury, and concerning the issuance of a securing\norder and the effective period thereof where such an authorization is\nissued, apply equally where a prosecutor's information is dismissed\npursuant to this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>