<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-2.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-2.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-2.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-2.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-2.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-2.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2_10">
        <num>2.10</num>
        <heading>Persons designated as peace officers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the enforcement of\nany of the criminal or seizure and forfeiture provisions of the tax law\nrelating to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>taxes imposed under or pursuant to the authority of\narticle twelve-A of the tax law and administered by the commissioner,\n(ii) taxes imposed under or pursuant to the authority of article\neighteen of the tax law and administered by the commissioner, (iii)\ntaxes imposed under article twenty of the tax law, or (iv) sales or\ncompensating use taxes relating to petroleum products or cigarettes\nimposed under article twenty-eight or pursuant to the authority of\narticle twenty-nine of the tax law and administered by the commissioner\nor\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the enforcement of any provision of the penal law relating to\nany of the taxes described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision and\nrelating to crimes effected through the use of a statement or document\nfiled with the department in connection with the administration of such\ntaxes or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as revenue crimes specialist and assigned to the enforcement of\nany of the criminal provisions of the tax law relating to taxes\nadministered by the commissioner of taxation and finance other than\nthose taxes set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision or any\nprovision of the penal law relating to such taxes, and those provisions\nof the penal law</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>relating to any of the foregoing taxes and (ii)\nrelating to crimes effected through the use of a statement or document\nfiled with the department in connection with the administration of such\nforegoing taxes or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to the enforcement of any provision of law which is subject to\nenforcement by criminal penalties and which relates to the performance\nby persons employed by the department of taxation and finance of the\nduties of their employment.\n  Provided, however, that nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed to\nauthorize any such employee designated as a peace officer after November\nfirst, nineteen hundred eighty-five to carry, possess, repair or dispose\nof a firearm unless the appropriate license therefor has been issued\npursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law, and further provided that,\nprior to such designation by the commissioner each such employee shall\nhave successfully completed the training requirements specified in\nsection 2.30 of this article. Provided, further, that any license issued\nto such employee pursuant to such peace officer designation by the\ncommissioner shall relate only to the firearm issued to such employee by\nthe department of taxation and finance and such permit shall not cover\nany other firearms. The foregoing sentence shall not be deemed to\nprohibit such peace officer from applying for a separate permit relating\nto non-departmental firearms.\n  5. Employees of the New York city department of finance assigned to\nenforcement of the tax on cigarettes imposed by title D of chapter\nforty-six of the administrative code of the city of New York by the\ncommissioner of finance.\n  6. Confidential investigators and inspectors, as designated by the\ncommissioner, of the department of agriculture and markets, pursuant to\nrules of the department.\n  7. Officers or agents of a duly incorporated society for the\nprevention of cruelty to animals.\n  * 7-a. Officers or agents of a duly incorporated society for the\nprevention of cruelty to children in Rockland county; provided, however,\nthat nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed to authorize such\nofficer or agent to carry, possess, repair, or dispose of a firearm\nunless the appropri...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Marshalls or deputy marshalls of a city court, provided, however,\nthat nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed to authorize such\nofficer to carry, possess, repair or dispose of a firearm unless the\nappropriate license therefor has been issued pursuant to section 400.00\nof the penal law.\n  e. Uniformed court officers of the city of Mount Vernon.\n  f. Uniformed court officers of the city of Jamestown.\n  22. Patrolmen appointed by the Lake George park commission; provided\nhowever that nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed to authorize\nsuch officer to carry, possess, repair or dispose of a firearm unless\nthe appropriate license therefor has been issued pursuant to section\n400.00 of the penal law.\n  23. Parole officers or warrant officers in the department of\ncorrections and community supervision.\n  23-a. Parole revocation specialists in the department of corrections\nand community supervision; provided, however, that nothing in this\nsubdivision shall be deemed to authorize such employee to carry,\npossess, repair or dispose of a firearm unless the appropriate license\ntherefor has been issued pursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n  24. Probation officers.\n  25. Officials, as designated by the commissioner of the department of\ncorrections and community supervision pursuant to rules of the\ndepartment, and correction officers of any state correctional facility\nor of any penal correctional institution.\n  26. Peace officers designated pursuant to the provisions of the New\nYork state defense emergency act, as set forth in chapter seven hundred\neighty-four of the laws of nineteen hundred fifty-one, as amended, when\nacting pursuant to their special duties during a period of attack or\nimminent attack by enemy forces, or during official drills called to\ncombat natural or man-made disasters, or during official drills in\npreparation for an attack by enemy forces or in preparation for a\nnatural or man-made disaster; provided, however, tha...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Syracuse University peace officers appointed by the chief\nlaw enforcement officer of the city of Syracuse pursuant to paragraphs\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, who shall be authorized to issue\nappearance tickets and simplified traffic informations; provided,\nhowever, that nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed to authorize\nany such officer to carry, possess, repair or dispose of a firearm\nunless the appropriate license therefor has been issued pursuant to\nsection 400.00 of the penal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the protection of the grounds, buildings and property of\nSyracuse University, the prevention of crime and the enforcement of law\nand order, and for the enforcement of such rules and regulations as\nSyracuse University shall from time to time establish, the chief law\nenforcement officer of the city of Syracuse may appoint and remove,\nfollowing consultations with Syracuse University; such number of\nSyracuse University peace officers as is determined by the chief law\nenforcement officer of the city of Syracuse to be necessary for the\nmaintenance of public order at such university, such appointments to be\nmade from persons nominated by the chancellor of Syracuse University.\nSuch peace officers shall comply with such requirements as shall be\nestablished by the chief law enforcement officer of the city of\nSyracuse. Such Syracuse University peace officers so appointed shall be\nemployees of such university, and subject to its supervision and control\nand the terms and conditions to be mutually agreed upon between the\nchief law enforcement officer of the city of Syracuse and Syracuse\nUniversity. Nothing in this paragraph shall limit the authority of\nSyracuse University to remove such peace officers. Such Syracuse\nUniversity peace officers shall have the powers of peace officers within\nthe geographical area of employment of the grounds or premises owned,\ncontrolled or administrated by Syracuse University within the county of\nOnondaga, except in those situations when requested by the chief law\nenforcement officer of the city of Syracuse or his or her designee,\nincluding by means of written protocols agreed to by the chief law\nenforcement officer of the city of Syracuse and Syracuse University, to\nprovide assistance on any public highway which crosses or adjoins such\ngrounds or premises. Syracuse University shall provide legal defense and\nindemnification, and hold harmless the city of Syracuse, and its\nofficers and employees from all claims arising...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Every Syracuse University peace officer so appointed shall, before\nentering upon the duties of his or her office, take and subscribe the\noath of office prescribed by article thirteen of the state constitution,\nwhich oath shall be filed in the office of the county clerk of the\ncounty of Onondaga. Every such peace officer appointed pursuant to this\nsubdivision when on regular duty shall conspicuously wear a metallic\nshield with a designating number and the words "Syracuse University\nPeace Officer" engraved thereon.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To become eligible for appointment as a Syracuse University peace\nofficer a candidate shall, in addition to the training requirements as\nset forth in section 2.30 of this article, complete the course of\ninstruction in public and private law enforcement established pursuant\nto paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of section sixty-four hundred fifty\nof the education law.\n  * NB There are 2 sub 77's\n  * 77. Chief fire marshal, assistant chief fire marshal, and fire\nmarshals, all of whom are full-time employees of the town of East\nHampton, when acting pursuant to their special duties in matters arising\nunder the laws relating to fires, the extinguishment thereof and fire\nperils; provided, however, that nothing in this subdivision shall be\ndeemed to authorize such officer to carry, possess, repair or dispose of\na firearm unless the appropriate license therefor has been issued\npursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n  * NB There are 2 sub 77's\n  78. A security officer employed by a community college who is\nspecifically designated as a peace officer by the board of trustees of a\ncommunity college pursuant to subdivision five-a of section sixty-three\nhundred six of the education law, or by a community college regional\nboard of trustees pursuant to subdivision four-a of section sixty-three\nhundred ten of the education law; provided, however, that nothing in\nthis subdivision shall be deemed to authorize such officer to carry,\npossess, repair or dispose of a firearm unless the appropriate license\ntherefor has been issued pursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n  * 79. Court security officers employed by the Wayne county sheriff's\noffice; provided however, that nothing in this subdivision shall be\ndeemed to authorize such officer to carry, possess, repair or dispose of\na firearm unless the appropriate license therefor has been issued\npursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n  * NB There are 4 sub 79's\n  * 79. Supervisors and members of the arson investigation bureau and\nfire inspection bureau of the office of fire prevention and control when\nacting pursuant to their special duties in matters arising under the\nlaws relating to fires, their prevention, extinguishment, investigation\nthereof, and fire perils; provided, howeve...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section 2.20 of this article, as\nwell as the power to detain an individual for a reasonable period of\ntime while awaiting the arrival of law enforcement, provided that the\nofficer has actual knowledge, or probable cause to believe, that such\nindividual has committed an offense; provided however, that nothing in\nthis subdivision shall be deemed to authorize such officer to carry,\npossess, repair or dispose of a firearm unless the appropriate license\ntherefor has been issued pursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n  84.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Public safety officers employed by the University of Rochester\nwho are designated as peace officers by the board of trustees of the\nUniversity of Rochester pursuant to paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision; provided, however, that nothing in this subdivision shall\nbe deemed to authorize any such officer to carry, possess, repair or\ndispose of a firearm unless the appropriate license therefor has been\nissued pursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For the protection of the grounds, buildings and property of the\nUniversity of Rochester, the prevention of crime and the enforcement of\nlaw and order, the board of trustees of the University of Rochester may\nappoint and remove such number of public safety officers designated as\npeace officers as is determined by the board of trustees to be necessary\nfor the maintenance of public order consistent with this subdivision.\nSuch peace officers shall comply with such requirements as shall be\nmutually agreed upon between the chief law enforcement officers of the\napplicable local law enforcement jurisdictions and the University of\nRochester. Such University of Rochester peace officers so appointed\nshall be employees of the University of Rochester and subject to its\nsupervision and control. Such University of Rochester peace officers\nshall have the powers of peace officers within the geographic area of\nemployment of the grounds or premises owned, controlled or administered\nby the University of Rochester within the county of Monroe, on any\npublic street and sidewalk that abuts the grounds, buildings or property\nof such university, and beyond such geographic area upon the request of\nthe chief law enforcement officer of the local law enforcement\njurisdiction or his or her designee, for the purpose of transporting an\nindividual who has been arrested in accordance with section 140.27 of\nthis chapter and when no local law enforcement officer is available for\ntransporting such individual in a timely manner.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The University of Rochester shall provide legal defense and\nindemnification to applicable municipality and its officers and\nemployees, and hold them harmless, against all claims arising out of\nconduct by or injury to such peace officers while carrying out their\nspecial duties, except in those situations when they are acting as\nagents of the chief law enforcement officer of the applicable local law\nenforcement jurisdiction or his or her designee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To become eligible for designation as a University of Rochester\npeace officer, a candidate shall, in addition to the training\nrequirements as set forth in section 2.30 of this article, complete the\ncourse of instruction in public and private law enforcement established\npursuant to subdivision three of section sixty-four hundred thirty-five\nof the education law.\n  85. Uniformed members of the bureau of fire prevention of the town of\nIslip, when acting pursuant to their special duties in matters arising\nunder laws relating to fires, the extinguishment thereof and fire\nperils; provided, however, that nothing in this subdivision shall be\ndeemed to authorize such members to carry, possess, repair or dispose of\na firearm unless the appropriate license therefor has been issued\npursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n  86. Investigators appointed by the cannabis control board, pursuant to\nsection ten of the cannabis law; provided, however, that nothing in this\nsubdivision shall be deemed to authorize such officer to carry, possess,\nrepair, or dispose of a firearm unless the appropriate license therefor\nhas been issued pursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n  87. Officers and members of the security force employed by Rochester\nRegional Health, within the grounds or premises owned or under the\nsupervision, administration, or control of Rochester Regional Health\nlocated on the campuses and at the facilities of Rochester General\nHospital and Unity Hospital, shall have the powers of peace officers,\nand beyond such geographic area upon the request of the chief law\nenforcement officer of the local law enforcement jurisdiction or such\nchief law enforcement officer's designee, for the purpose of\ntransporting an individual who has been arrested in accordance with\nsection 140.27 of this chapter and where no local law enforcement\nofficer is available for transporting such individual in a timely\nmanner. Such peace officers shall only have the powe...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2_10__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of\nsection 2.20 of this article, and the power to detain an individual for\na reasonable period of time while awaiting the arrival of law\nenforcement, provided that such peace officer has actual knowledge, or\nprobable cause to believe, that such individual has committed an\noffense; provided however, that nothing in this subdivision shall be\ndeemed to authorize such officer to carry, possess, repair or dispose of\na firearm unless the appropriate license therefor has been issued\npursuant to section 400.00 of the penal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>