<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-220.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-220.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="220.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-220.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-220.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-220.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-220.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_220_15">
        <num>220.15</num>
        <heading>Plea; plea of not responsible by reason of mental disease or defect</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The nature of the charge to which the plea is offered, and the\nconsequences of such plea;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That he has the right to plead not guilty or to persist in that\nplea if it has already been entered;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That he has the right to be tried by a jury, the right to the\nassistance of counsel, the right to confront and cross-examine witnesses\nagainst him, and the right not to be compelled to incriminate himself;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That if he pleads not responsible by reason of mental disease or\ndefect there will be no trial with respect to the charges contained in\nthe indictment, so that by offering such plea he waives the right to\nsuch trial;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That if he pleads not responsible by reason of mental disease or\ndefect the court will ask him questions about the offense or offenses\ncharged in the indictment and that he will thereby waive his right not\nto be compelled to incriminate himself; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That the acceptance of a plea of not responsible by reason of\nmental disease or defect is the equivalent of a verdict of not\nresponsible by reason of mental disease or defect after trial.\n  4.  The court shall not accept a plea of not responsible by reason of\nmental disease or defect without first determining that there is a\nfactual basis for such plea.  The court must address the defendant\npersonally in open court and determine that the plea is voluntary,\nknowingly made, and not the result of force, threats, or promises.  The\ncourt must inquire whether the defendant's willingness to plead results\nfrom prior discussions between the district attorney and counsel for the\ndefendant.  The court must be satisfied that the defendant understands\nthe proceedings against him, has sufficient capacity to assist in his\nown defense and understands the consequences of a plea of not\nresponsible by reason of mental disease or defect.  The court may make\nsuch inquiry as it deems necessary or appropriate for the purpose of\nmaking the determinations required by this section.\n  5.  Before accepting a plea of not responsible by reason of mental\ndisease or defect, the court must find and state each of the following\non the record in detail and not in conclusory terms:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That it is satisfied that each element of the offense or offenses\ncharged in the indictment would be established beyond a reasonable doubt\nat a trial;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That the affirmative defense of lack of criminal responsibility\nby reason of mental disease or defect would be proven by the defendant\nat a trial by a preponderance of the evidence;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That the defendant has the capacity to understand the proceedings\nagainst him and to assist in his own defense;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That such plea by the defendant is knowingly and voluntarily made\nand that there is a factual basis for the plea;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_220_15__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That the acceptance of such plea is required in the interest of\nthe public in the effective administration of justice.\n  6.  When a plea of not responsible by reason of mental disease or\ndefect is accepted by the court and recorded upon the minutes, the\nprovisions of section 330.20 of this chapter shall govern all subsequent\nproceedings against the defendant.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>