<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-230.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-230.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="230.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-230.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-230.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-230.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-230.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_230_20">
        <num>230.20</num>
        <heading>Removal of action; removal from county court to supreme court and change of venue; upon motion of party</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_230_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the indictment and action be removed from such superior court\nto a designated superior court of or located in another county; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_230_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the commissioner of jurors of such county, in consultation\nwith the appropriate administrative judge of the judicial district in\nwhich the county is located, expand the pool of jurors to encompass\nprospective jurors from the jury lists of counties that are within the\njudicial district in which, and that are geographically contiguous with\nthe county in which, such superior court is located.\n  In making such determination the appellate division shall consider,\namong other factors, the hardship on potential jurors and the potential\ndepletion of a county's qualified juror list that may result from an\norder expanding the jury pool. An order of removal under paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_230_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nherein must, if the defendant is in custody at the time, include a\nprovision for transfer of custody by the sheriff or other appropriate\npublic servant of the county of confinement to the sheriff or other\nappropriate public servant of the county to which the action has been\nremoved. If the order is issued upon motion of the people, the appellate\ndivision may impose such conditions as it deems equitable and\nappropriate to insure that the removal does not subject the defendant to\nan unreasonable burden in making his defense. Any additional cost to the\npeople incurred in complying with the order must be borne by the county\nfrom which the action originated.\n  3. Any motion made pursuant to this section must be based upon papers\nstating the grounds therefor, and must be made within the period\nprovided by section 255.20 and upon five days notice thereof together\nwith service of the moving papers upon, as the case may be,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_230_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\ndistrict attorney or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_230_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>either the defendant or his counsel. In any\ncase, the motion must be made returnable either during the appellate\ndivision term during which such moving papers are served or during the\nnext term thereof.\n  4. If the appellate division grants the motion and orders a removal of\nthe action, a certified copy of such order must be filed with the clerk\nof the superior court in which the indictment is pending. Such clerk\nmust thereupon transmit such instrument, together with the pertinent\npapers and proceedings of the action, including all undertakings for\nappearances of the defendant and of the witnesses, or a certified copy\nor copies of the same, to the term of the superior court to which the\naction has been removed. Such latter court must then proceed to conduct\nthe action to judgment or other final disposition.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>