<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.70"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.70"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="245.70"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.70/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.70/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.70/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-245.70/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_245_70">
        <num>245.70</num>
        <heading>Protective orders</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_70__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A party that has\nunsuccessfully sought, or unsuccessfully opposed the granting of, a\nprotective order under this section relating to the name, address,\ncontact information or statements of a person may obtain expedited\nreview of that ruling by an individual justice of the intermediate\nappellate court to which an appeal from a judgment of conviction in the\ncase would be taken.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_70__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such review shall be sought within two business days of the\nadverse or partially adverse ruling, by order to show cause filed with\nthe intermediate appellate court. The order to show cause shall in\naddition be timely served on the lower court and on the opposing party,\nand shall be accompanied by a sworn affirmation stating in good faith\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_70__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the ruling affects substantial interests, and (ii) that\ndiligent efforts to reach an accommodation of the underlying discovery\ndispute with opposing counsel failed or that no accommodation was\nfeasible; except that service on the opposing party, and a statement\nregarding efforts to reach an accommodation, are unnecessary where the\nopposing party was not made aware of the application for a protective\norder and good cause is shown for omitting service of the order to show\ncause on the opposing party. The lower court's order subject to review\nshall be stayed until the appellate justice renders a determination.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_70__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The assignment of the individual appellate justice, and the mode\nof and procedure for the review, shall be determined by rules of the\nindividual appellate courts. The appellate justice may consider any\nrelevant and reliable information bearing on the issue, and may dispense\nwith written briefs other than supporting and opposing materials\npreviously submitted to the lower court. The appellate justice may\ndispense with the issuance of a written opinion in rendering his or her\ndecision, and when practicable shall render decision and order\nexpeditiously. Such review, decision and order shall not affect the\nright of a defendant, in a subsequent appeal from a judgment of\nconviction, to claim as error the ruling reviewed.\n  7. Compliance with protective order. Any protective order issued under\nthis article is a mandate of the court for purposes of the offense of\ncriminal contempt in subdivision three of section 215.50 of the penal\nlaw.\n  8. A motion filed in good faith pursuant to subdivision one or two of\nthis section shall be deemed a pre-trial motion for the purposes of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_245_70__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of section 30.30 of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>