<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-250.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-250.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="250.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-250.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-250.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-250.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-250.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_250_30">
        <num>250.30</num>
        <heading>Notice of defenses in offenses involving computers</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 250.30 Notice of defenses in offenses involving computers.\n  1. In any prosecution in which the defendant seeks to invoke any of\nthe defenses specified in section 156.50 of the penal law, the defendant\nmust within forty-five days after arraignment and not less than twenty\ndays before the commencement of the trial serve upon the people and file\nwith the court a written notice of his intention to present such\ndefense. For good cause shown, the court may extend the period for\nservice of the notice.\n  2. The notice served must specify the subdivision or subdivisions upon\nwhich the defendant relies and must also state the reasonable grounds\nthat led the defendant to believe that he had the authorization required\nby the statute or the right required by the statute to engage in such\nconduct.\n  3. If at the trial the defendant seeks to invoke any of the defenses\nspecified in section 156.50 of the penal law without having served the\nnotice as required, or seeks to invoke a subdivision or a ground not\nspecified in the notice, the court may exclude any testimony or evidence\nin regard to the defense, or any subdivision or ground, not noticed. The\ncourt may in its discretion, for good cause shown, receive such\ntestimony or evidence, but before doing so, it may, upon application of\nthe people, grant an adjournment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>