<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.16"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.16"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="270.16"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.16/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.16/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.16/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-270.16/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_270_16">
        <num>270.16</num>
        <heading>Capital cases; individual questioning for racial bias</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 270.16 Capital cases; individual questioning for racial bias.\n  1. In any case in which the crime charged may be punishable by death,\nthe court shall, upon motion of either party, permit the parties,\ncommencing with the people, to examine the prospective jurors\nindividually and outside the presence of the other prospective jurors\nregarding their qualifications to serve as jurors. Each party shall be\nafforded a fair opportunity to question a prospective juror as to any\nunexplored matter affecting his or her qualifications, including without\nlimitation the possibility of racial bias on the part of the prospective\njuror, but the court shall not permit questioning that is repetitious or\nirrelevant, or questions as to a prospective juror's knowledge of rules\nof law. If necessary to prevent improper questioning as to any matter,\nthe court shall personally examine the prospective jurors as to that\nmatter. The scope of such examination shall be within the discretion of\nthe court. After the parties have concluded their examinations of a\nprospective juror, the court may ask such further questions as it deems\nproper regarding the qualifications of the prospective juror.\n  2.  The proceedings provided for in this section shall be conducted on\nthe record; provided, however, that upon motion of either party, and for\ngood cause shown, the court may direct that all or a portion of the\nrecord of such proceedings be sealed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>