<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-360.25"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-360.25"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="360.25"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-360.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-360.25/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-360.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-360.25/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_360_25">
        <num>360.25</num>
        <heading>Trial jury; challenge for cause of an individual juror</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_360_25__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>He does not have the qualifications required by the judiciary law;\nor\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_360_25__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>He has a state of mind that is likely to preclude him from\nrendering an impartial verdict based upon the evidence adduced at the\ntrial; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_360_25__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>He is related within the sixth degree by consanguinity or affinity\nto the defendant, or to the person allegedly injured by the crime\ncharged, or to a prospective witness at the trial, or to counsel for the\npeople or for the defendant; or that he is or was a party adverse to any\nsuch person in a civil action; or that he has complained against or been\naccused by any such person in a criminal action; or that he bears some\nother relationship to any such person of such nature that it is likely\nto preclude him from rendering an impartial verdict; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_360_25__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>He is to be a witness at the trial; or where a prosecutor's\ninformation was filed at the direction of a grand jury, he was a witness\nbefore the grand jury or at the preliminary hearing; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_360_25__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>He or she served on a trial jury in a prior civil or criminal\naction involving the same incident charged; or where a prosecutor's\ninformation was filed at the direction of a grand jury, he or she served\non the grand jury which directed such filing.\n  2. All issues of fact or questions of law arising on the challenge\nmust be tried and determined by the court. The provisions of subdivision\ntwo of section 270.20 with respect to challenges are also applicable to\nthe selection of a trial jury in a local criminal court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>