<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="390.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_390_20">
        <num>390.20</num>
        <heading>Requirement of pre-sentence report</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A sentence of probation except where the provisions of\nsubparagraph (ii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four of this section\napply;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A sentence of imprisonment for a term in excess of one hundred\neighty days;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Consecutive sentences of imprisonment with terms aggregating more\nthan ninety days.\n  3. Permissible in any case. For purposes of sentence, the court may,\nin its discretion, order a pre-sentence investigation and report in any\ncase, irrespective of whether such investigation and report is required\nby subdivision one or two.\n  4. Waiver.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one or\ntwo of this section, a pre-sentence investigation of the defendant and a\nwritten report thereon may be waived by the mutual consent of the\nparties and with consent of the judge, stated on the record or in\nwriting, whenever:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A sentence of imprisonment has been agreed upon by the parties and\nwill be satisfied by the time served, or\n  (ii) A sentence of probation or conditional discharge has been agreed\nupon by the parties and will be imposed, or\n  (iii) A report has been prepared in the preceding twelve months, or\n  (iv) A sentence of probation is revoked.\n  * Provided, however, a pre-sentence investigation of the defendant and\na written report thereon shall not be waived if an indeterminate or\ndeterminate sentence of imprisonment is to be imposed.\n  * NB Effective until September 1, 2027\n  * Provided, however, a pre-sentence investigation of the defendant and\na written report thereon shall not be waived if an indeterminate\nsentence of imprisonment is to be imposed.\n  * NB Effective September 1, 2027\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a pre-sentence investigation and report has been waived\npursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, (ii) or (iii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_390_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision and the court determines that such information would be\nrelevant to the court disposition, a victim impact statement shall be\nprovided in accordance with this section.\n  5. Negotiated sentence of imprisonment. In any city having a\npopulation of one million or more and notwithstanding the provisions of\nsubdivision one or two of this section, a pre-sentence investigation and\nwritten report thereon shall not be required where a negotiated sentence\nof imprisonment for a term of three hundred sixty-five days or less has\nbeen mutually agreed upon by the parties with consent of the judge, as a\nresult of a conviction or revocation of a sentence of probation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>