<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="390.60"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-390.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_390_60">
        <num>390.60</num>
        <heading>Copy of reports to accompany defendant sentenced to imprisonment</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 390.60 Copy of reports to accompany defendant sentenced to\n             imprisonment.\n  1. Cases where copy of report is required.  Whenever a person is\nsentenced to a term of imprisonment, a copy of any pre-sentence report\nprepared, a copy of any pre-sentence memorandum filed by the defendant\nand a copy of any medical, psychiatric or social agency report submitted\nto the court or to the probation department in connection with the\nquestion of sentence must be delivered to the person in charge of the\ncorrectional or division for youth facility to which the defendant is\ncommitted at the time the defendant is delivered thereto.  When a person\nis committed to any hospital operated by the office of mental health or\nreferred to any program established pursuant to section four hundred one\nof the correction law, from a correctional facility or division for\nyouth facility, the person in charge of the correctional facility or\ndivision for youth facility shall ensure that a copy of any pre-sentence\nreport concerning such person, a copy of any pre-sentence memorandum\nfiled by such person, and a copy of any medical, psychiatric or social\nagency report submitted to the court or to the probation department in\nconnection with the question of sentence is provided to such hospital or\nprogram.\n  2. Effect of failure to deliver required report.  A commitment is not\nvoid by reason of failure to comply with the provisions of subdivision\none, but the person in charge of the correctional facility to which the\ndefendant has been delivered in execution of the sentence is authorized\nto refuse to accept custody of such person until the required report is\ndelivered.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>