<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-400.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-400.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="400.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-400.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-400.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-400.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-400.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_400_20">
        <num>400.20</num>
        <heading>Procedure for determining whether defendant should be sentenced as a persistent felony offender</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_400_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nhas found that the defendant is a persistent felony offender as defined\nin subdivision one of section 70.10 of the penal law, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_400_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is of the\nopinion that the history and character of the defendant and the nature\nand circumstances of his criminal conduct are such that extended\nincarceration and lifetime supervision of the defendant are warranted to\nbest serve the public interest.\n  2.  Authorization for hearing.  When information available to the\ncourt prior to sentencing indicates that the defendant is a persistent\nfelony offender, and when, in the opinion of the court, the available\ninformation shows that a persistent felony offender sentence may be\nwarranted, the court may order a hearing to determine</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_400_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the\ndefendant is in fact a persistent felony offender, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_400_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if so,\nwhether a persistent felony offender sentence should be imposed.\n  3.  Order directing a hearing.  An order directing a hearing to\ndetermine whether the defendant should be sentenced as a persistent\nfelony offender must be filed with the clerk of the court and must\nspecify a date for the hearing not less than twenty days from the date\nthe order is filed.  The court must annex to and file with the order a\nstatement setting forth the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_400_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The dates and places of the previous convictions which render the\ndefendant a persistent felony offender as defined in subdivision one of\nsection 70.10 of the penal law; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_400_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The factors in the defendant's background and prior criminal\nconduct which the court deems relevant for the purpose of sentencing the\ndefendant as a persistent felony offender.\n  4.  Notice of hearing.  Upon receipt of the order and statement of the\ncourt, the clerk of the court must send a notice of hearing to the\ndefendant, his counsel and the district attorney.  Such notice must\nspecify the time and place of the hearing and the fact that the purpose\nof the hearing is to determine whether or not the defendant should be\nsentenced as a persistent felony offender.  Each notice required to be\nsent hereunder must be accompanied by a copy of the statement of the\ncourt.\n  5.  Burden and standard of proof; evidence.  Upon any hearing held\npursuant to this section the burden of proof is upon the people.  A\nfinding that the defendant is a persistent felony offender, as defined\nin subdivision one of section 70.10 of the penal law, must be based upon\nproof beyond a reasonable doubt by evidence admissible under the rules\napplicable to the trial of the issue of guilt.  Matters pertaining to\nthe defendant's history and character and the nature and circumstances\nof his criminal conduct may be established by any relevant evidence, not\nlegally privileged, regardless of admissibility under the exclusionary\nrules of evidence, and the standard of proof with respect to such\nmatters shall be a preponderance of the evidence.\n  6.  Constitutionality of prior convictions.  A previous conviction in\nthis or any other jurisdiction which was obtained in violation of the\nrights of the defendant under the applicable provisions of the\nConstitution of the United States may not be counted in determining\nwhether the defendant is a persistent felony offender.  The defendant\nmay, at any time during the course of the hearing hereunder controvert\nan allegation with respect to such conviction in the statement of the\ncourt on the grounds that the conviction was unconstitutiona...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_400_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the uncontroverted allegations with\nrespect to the defendant's background and the nature of his prior\ncriminal conduct warrant sentencing the defendant as a persistent felony\noffender, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_400_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant either has no relevant evidence to\npresent or the facts which could be established through the evidence\noffered by the defendant would not affect the court's decision, the\ncourt may enter a finding that the defendant is a persistent felony\noffender and sentence him in accordance with the provisions of\nsubdivision two of section 70.10 of the penal law.\n  9.  Cases where further hearing is required.  Where the defendant\ncontroverts an allegation in the statement of the court and the\nuncontroverted allegations in such statement are not sufficient to\nsupport a finding that the defendant is a persistent felony offender as\ndefined in subdivision one of section 70.10 of the penal law, or where\nthe uncontroverted allegations with respect to the defendant's history\nand the nature of his prior criminal conduct do not warrant sentencing\nhim as a persistent felony offender, or where the defendant has offered\nto present evidence to establish facts that would affect the court's\ndecision on the question of whether a persistent felony offender\nsentence is warranted, the court may fix a date for a further hearing.\nSuch hearing shall be before the court without a jury and either party\nmay introduce evidence with respect to the controverted allegations or\nany other matter relevant to the issue of whether or not the defendant\nshould be sentenced as a persistent felony offender.  At the conclusion\nof the hearing the court must make a finding as to whether or not the\ndefendant is a persistent felony offender and, upon a finding that he is\nsuch, must then make such findings of fact as it deems relevant to the\nquestion of whether a persistent felony offender sentence is warranted.\nIf the court both finds that the defendant is a persistent felony\noffender and is of the opinion that a persistent felony offender\nsentence is warranted, it may sentence the defendant in accordance with\nthe provisions of subdivision two of section 70.10 of the penal law.\...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>