<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.45"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.45"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-12-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="420.45"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.45/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.45/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.45/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.45/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_420_45">
        <num>420.45</num>
        <heading>Post-trial motion relating to certain instruments affecting residential real property</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_45__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of rule sixty-five hundred eleven\nof the civil practice law and rules for a notice of pendency of action\nand shall have the same effect as such notice.\n  3. The supreme court must conduct a hearing and make findings of fact\nessential to the determination whether to declare the instrument\ndescribed in subdivision one of this section void ab initio. There will\nbe a rebuttable presumption that where a party is convicted after a\ntrial or a guilty plea to any crime that affects the title to,\nencumbrance of, or the possession of, real property and where there is\nan instrument that encumbers or is material to the transfer or sale of\nreal property, that such instrument is void ab initio.\n  4. Upon the defendant's conviction of or guilty plea as described in\nsubdivision one of this section, and after conducting a hearing pursuant\nto subdivision three of this section, a court shall make a determination\nand if appropriate shall order that the instrument described in\nsubdivision one of this section be declared void ab initio or grant\nother appropriate relief to the victim. The order of the court shall\ndescribe the nature of the false statement or false information\ncontained in such instrument. A copy of such instrument shall be\nattached to the order of the court.\n  5. If the order relates to an instrument that has been filed with,\nregistered, or recorded in a public office, a certified copy of such\norder shall be recorded in the office of the recording officer of the\ncounty in which such property is situated.\n  6. For purposes of this section, "all persons who have an interest in\nthe property affected by such instrument" shall mean all parties who\nhave recorded an instrument affecting the real property that is the\nsubject of the instrument described in subdivision one of this section,\nany last record owner and anyone in residence during the pendency of the\nprosecution and any party with a lien against the property that is\nunsatisfied, or any other ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_45__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nrelief otherwise provided by law, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_45__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a party's right to appeal such\norder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>