<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.35"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.35"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-02-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="420.35"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.35/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-420.35/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_420_35">
        <num>420.35</num>
        <heading>Mandatory surcharge and crime victim assistance fee; applicability to sentences mandating payment of fines</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_35__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant\nis convicted of prostitution under section 230.00 of the penal law; (ii)\nthe defendant is convicted of a violation in the event such conviction\nis in lieu of a plea to or conviction for prostitution under section\n230.00 of the penal law; (iii) the court finds that a defendant is a\nvictim of sex trafficking under section 230.34 of the penal law or a\nvictim of trafficking in persons under the trafficking victims\nprotection act (United States Code, Title 22, Chapter 78); or (iv) the\ncourt finds that the defendant is a victim of sex trafficking of a child\nunder section 230.34-a of the penal law.\n  2-a. A court may waive any mandatory surcharge, additional surcharge,\ntown or village surcharge, the crime victim assistance fee, DNA databank\nfee, sex offender registration fee and/or supplemental sex offender\nvictim fee when the court finds that the defendant was under the age of\ntwenty-one at the time the offense was committed and:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_35__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the imposition of such surcharge or fee would work an unreasonable\nhardship on the defendant, his or her immediate family, or any other\nperson who is dependent on such defendant for financial support; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_35__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>after considering the goal of promoting successful and productive\nreentry and reintegration as set forth in subdivision six of section\n1.05 of the penal law, the imposition of such surcharge or fee would\nadversely impact the defendant's reintegration into society; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_420_35__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the interests of justice.\n  3. It shall be the duty of a court of record or administrative\ntribunal to report to the division of criminal justice services on the\ndisposition and collection of mandatory surcharges, sex offender\nregistration fees or DNA databank fees and crime victim assistance fees.\nSuch report shall include, for all cases, whether the surcharge, sex\noffender registration fee, DNA databank fee or crime victim assistance\nfee levied pursuant to subdivision one of section 60.35 of the penal law\nor section eighteen hundred nine of the vehicle and traffic law has been\nimposed pursuant to law, collected, or is to be collected by probation\nor corrections or other officials. The form, manner and frequency of\nsuch reports shall be determined by the commissioner of the division of\ncriminal justice services after consultation with the chief\nadministrator of the courts and the commissioner of the department of\nmotor vehicles.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>