<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.70"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.70"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-10-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="460.70"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.70/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.70/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.70/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.70/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_460_70">
        <num>460.70</num>
        <heading>Appeal; how perfected</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_70__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After the local criminal court has, pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_70__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of section 460.10, filed its return with the clerk of\nthe appellate court and delivered a copy thereof to the appellant, the\nappellant must file with such clerk, and serve a copy thereof upon the\nrespondent, a notice of argument, noticing the appeal for argument at\nthe term of such appellate court immediately following the term being\nheld at the time of the appellant's receipt of the return. Upon motion\nof the appellant, however, such appellate court may for good cause shown\nenlarge the time to a subsequent term, in which case the appellant must\nnotice the appeal for argument at such subsequent term;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_70__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The appellant must further comply with all court rules applicable\nto the mode of perfecting such appeals;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_70__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the appellant does not file a notice of argument as provided in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_70__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or does not comply with all applicable court rules as\nprovided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_70__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, the appellate court may, either upon motion\nof the respondent or upon its own motion, dismiss the appeal.\n  3. The mode of and time for perfecting any appeal which has been taken\nto the court of appeals are determined by the rules of the court of\nappeals. Among the matters to be determined by such court rules are the\ntimes when the appeal must be noticed for and brought to argument, the\ncontent, form and number of the records and briefs and copies thereof to\nbe served and filed, and the times when such records and briefs must be\nserved and filed.\n  When an appeal is taken by a defendant pursuant to section 450.70, the\ndefendant shall cause to be prepared and printed or otherwise duplicated\npursuant to rules of the court of appeals the record on appeal and the\nrequired number of copies thereof. If the defendant is granted\npermission to appeal as a poor person, the expense thereof shall be a\nstate charge payable out of funds appropriated to the office of court\nadministration for that purpose.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>