<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="460.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-460.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_460_20">
        <num>460.20</num>
        <heading>Certificate granting leave to appeal to court of appeals</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where the appeal sought is from an order of the appellate\ndivision, the certificate may be issued by</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_20__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a judge of the court of\nappeals or (ii) a justice of the appellate division of the department\nwhich entered the order sought to be appealed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where the appeal sought is from an order of an intermediate\nappellate court other than the appellate division, the certificate may\nbe issued only by a judge of the court of appeals.\n  3.  An application for such a certificate must be made in the\nfollowing manner:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An application to a justice of the appellate division must be\nmade upon reasonable notice to the respondent;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_460_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An application seeking such a certificate from a judge of the\ncourt of appeals must be made to the chief judge of such court by\nsubmission thereof, either in writing or first orally and then in\nwriting, to the clerk of the court of appeals.  The chief judge must\nthen designate a judge of such court to determine the application.  The\nclerk must then notify the respondent of the application and must inform\nboth parties of such designation.\n  4.  A justice of the appellate division to whom such an application\nhas been made, or a judge of the court of appeals designated to\ndetermine such an application, may in his discretion determine it upon\nsuch papers as he may request the parties to submit, or upon oral\nargument, or upon both.\n  5.  Every judge or justice acting pursuant to this section shall file\nwith the clerk of the court of appeals, immediately upon issuance, a\ncopy of every certificate granting or denying leave to appeal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>