<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-470.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-470.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="470.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-470.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-470.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-470.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-470.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_470_30">
        <num>470.30</num>
        <heading>Determination by court of appeals of appeals taken directly thereto from judgments and orders of criminal courts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_470_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the sentence of death was imposed under the influence of\npassion, prejudice, or any other arbitrary or legally impermissible\nfactor including whether the imposition of the verdict or sentence was\nbased upon the race of the defendant or a victim of the crime for which\nthe defendant was convicted;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the sentence of death is excessive or disproportionate to\nthe penalty imposed in similar cases considering both the crime and the\ndefendant. In conducting such review the court, upon request of the\ndefendant, in addition to any other determination, shall review whether\nthe sentence of death is excessive or disproportionate to the penalty\nimposed in similar cases by virtue of the race of the defendant or a\nvictim of the crime for which the defendant was convicted; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470_30__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>whether the decision to impose the sentence of death was against\nthe weight of the evidence.\n  4. The court shall include in its decision:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the aggravating and mitigating factors established in the record\non appeal; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>those similar cases it took into consideration.\n  5. In addition to exercising any other corrective action pursuant to\nsubdivision one of this section, the court, with regard to review of a\nsentence of death, shall be authorized to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470_30__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>affirm the sentence of death; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470_30__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>set the sentence aside and remand the case for resentencing\npursuant to the procedures set forth in section 400.27 for a\ndetermination as to whether the defendant shall be sentenced to death,\nlife imprisonment without parole or to a term of imprisonment for the\nclass A-I felony of murder in the first degree other than a sentence of\nlife imprisonment without parole; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_470_30__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>set the sentence aside and remand the case for resentencing by the\ncourt for a determination as to whether the defendant shall be sentenced\nto life imprisonment without parole or to a term of imprisonment for the\nclass A-I felony of murder in the first degree other than a sentence of\nlife imprisonment without parole.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>