<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-06-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="510.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_510_20">
        <num>510.20</num>
        <heading>Application for a change in securing order</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The principal is entitled to representation by counsel in the\nmaking and presentation of such application. If the principal is\nfinancially unable to obtain counsel, counsel shall be assigned to the\nprincipal.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon such application, the principal must be accorded an\nopportunity to be heard, present evidence and to contend that an order\nof recognizance, release under non-monetary conditions or, where\nauthorized, bail, a reduction of bail, or imposition of non-monetary\nconditions in conjunction with bail or a reduction of bail, must or\nshould issue, that the court should release the principal on the\nprincipal's own recognizance or under non-monetary conditions rather\nthan fix bail, or where bail has been imposed, reduce the amount of bail\nand impose non-monetary conditions, where authorized under this title,\nand that if bail is authorized and fixed it should be in a suggested\namount and form.\n  3. When an application for a change in securing order is brought under\nthis section and one or more of the charge or charges on which such\nsecuring order was based have been dismissed and/or reduced such that\nthe securing order is no longer supported by the provisions of section\n510.10 of this article, the court shall impose a new securing order in\naccordance with such section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>