<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.30"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.30"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-06-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="510.30"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.30/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.30/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_510_30">
        <num>510.30</num>
        <heading>Application for securing order; rules of law and criteria controlling determination</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 510.30 Application for securing order; rules of law and criteria\n           controlling determination.\n  1. With respect to any principal, the court in all cases, unless\notherwise provided by law, must impose a securing order in accordance\nwith section 510.10 of this article, and shall explain the basis for its\ndetermination and choice of securing order on the record or in writing.\n  2. Where the principal is a defendant-appellant in a pending appeal\nfrom a judgment of conviction, the court must also consider the\nlikelihood of ultimate reversal of the judgment. A determination that\nthe appeal is palpably without merit alone justifies, but does not\nrequire, a denial of the application, regardless of any determination\nmade with respect to the factors specified in subdivision one of this\nsection.\n  3. When bail or recognizance is ordered, the court shall inform the\nprincipal, if the principal is a defendant charged with the commission\nof a felony, that the release is conditional and that the court may\nrevoke the order of release and may be authorized to commit the\nprincipal to the custody of the sheriff in accordance with the\nprovisions of subdivision two of section 530.60 of this chapter if the\nprincipal commits a subsequent felony while at liberty upon such order.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>