<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.40"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.40"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-06-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="510.40"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-510.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_510_40">
        <num>510.40</num>
        <heading>Court notification to principal of conditions of release and of alleged violations of conditions of release</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Electronic monitoring of a principal's location may be ordered\nonly if the court finds, after notice, an opportunity to be heard and an\nindividualized determination explained on the record or in writing, that\nthe defendant qualifies for electronic monitoring in accordance with\nsubdivision twenty-one of section 500.10 of this title, and no other\nrealistic non-monetary condition or set of non-monetary conditions will\nsuffice to reasonably assure a principal's return to court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The specific method of electronic monitoring of the principal's\nlocation must be approved by the court. The procedure and method of such\nelectronic monitoring shall reflect the findings of the individualized\ndetermination warranting such imposition of electronic monitoring to\nreasonably assure the principal's return to court, and shall be\nunobtrusive to the greatest extent practicable.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_40__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Electronic monitoring of the location of a principal may be\nconducted only by a public entity under the supervision and control of a\ncounty or municipality or a non-profit entity under contract to the\ncounty, municipality or the state. A county or municipality shall be\nauthorized to enter into a contract with another county or municipality\nin the state to monitor principals under non-monetary conditions of\nrelease in its county, but counties, municipalities and the state shall\nnot contract with any private for-profit entity for such purposes.\nCounties, municipalities and the state may contract with a private\nfor-profit entity to supply electronic monitoring devices or other\nitems, provided that any interaction with persons under electronic\nmonitoring or the data produced by such monitoring shall be conducted\nsolely by employees of a county, municipality, the state, or a\nnon-profit entity under contract with such county, municipality or the\nstate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_40__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Electronic monitoring of a principal's location may be for a\nmaximum period of sixty days, and may be renewed for such period, after\nnotice, an opportunity to be heard and a de novo, individualized\ndetermination in accordance with this subdivision, which shall be\nexplained on the record or in writing.\n  A defendant subject to electronic location monitoring under this\nsubdivision shall be considered held or confined in custody for purposes\nof section 180.80 of this chapter and shall be considered committed to\nthe custody of the sheriff for purposes of section 170.70 of the\nchapter, as applicable.\n  5. If a principal is released under non-monetary conditions, the court\nshall, on the record and in an individualized written document provided\nto the principal, notify the principal, in plain language and a manner\nsufficiently clear and specific:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of any conditions to which the principal is subject, to serve as a\nguide for the principal's conduct; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_510_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that the possible consequences for violation of such a condition\nmay include revocation of the securing order and the ordering of a more\nrestrictive securing order.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>