<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.40"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.40"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="520.40"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-520.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_520_40">
        <num>520.40</num>
        <heading>Transfer of cash bail from local criminal court to superior court</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 520.40  Transfer of cash bail from local criminal court to superior\n             court.\n  When a local criminal court acquires control over the person of an\naccused and such court designates the amount of bail that the accused\nmay post and such bail is posted in cash and subsequently the accused is\narraigned in superior court where bail is fixed by such court, the\naccused may request that the cash bail posted in the local criminal\ncourt be transferred to the superior court. Notice of such request must\nbe given to the person who posted cash bail. Upon such a request the\nsuperior court shall make an order directing the local criminal court to\ntransfer the cash bail that it holds to the superior court for use in\nthe superior court.  If there is an overage, the superior court shall\norder it be paid over to the person who posted the cash bail in the\nlocal criminal court.  If there is a deficiency, the accused shall post\nadditional bail as directed by the superior court.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>