<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.13"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.13"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-10-24" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="530.13"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.13/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.13/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.13/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.13/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_530_13">
        <num>530.13</num>
        <heading>Protection of victims of crimes, other than family offenses</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>stay away from the home, school, business or place of employment\nof the victims of, or designated witnesses to, the alleged offense;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>refrain from harassing, intimidating, threatening or otherwise\ninterfering with the victims of the alleged offense and such members of\nthe family or household of such victims or designated witnesses as shall\nbe specifically named by the court in such order;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>1. to refrain from intentionally injuring or killing, without\njustification, any companion animal the defendant knows to be owned,\npossessed, leased, kept or held by such victim or victims or a minor\nchild residing in such victim's or victims' household.\n  2. "Companion animal", as used in this section, shall have the same\nmeaning as in subdivision five of section three hundred fifty of the\nagriculture and markets law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>1. to refrain from remotely controlling any connected devices\naffecting the home, vehicle or property of the person protected by the\norder.\n  2. For purposes of this paragraph, "connected device" shall mean any\ndevice, or other physical object that is capable of connecting to the\ninternet, directly or indirectly, and that is assigned an internet\nprotocol address or bluetooth address.\n  In addition to the foregoing provisions, the court may issue an order,\npursuant to section two hundred twenty-seven-c of the real property law,\nauthorizing the party for whose benefit any order of protection has been\nissued to terminate a lease or rental agreement pursuant to section two\nhundred twenty-seven-c of the real property law.\n  2. The court may issue a temporary order of protection under this\nsection ex parte upon the filing of an accusatory instrument and for\ngood cause shown.\n  3. The court may issue or extend a temporary order of protection under\nthis section ex parte simultaneously with the issuance of a warrant for\nthe arrest of the defendant. Such temporary order of protection may\ncontinue in effect until the day the defendant subsequently appears in\ncourt pursuant to such warrant or voluntarily or otherwise.\n  4. * Upon sentencing on a conviction for any offense, where the court\nhas not issued an order of protection pursuant to section 530.12 of this\narticle, the court may, in addition to any other disposition, including\na conditional discharge or youthful offender adjudication, enter an\norder of protection. Where a temporary order of protection was issued,\nthe court shall state on the record the reasons for issuing or not\nissuing an order of protection. The duration of such an order shall be\nfixed by the court and; (A) in the case of a felony conviction, shall\nnot exceed the greater of:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>eight years from the date of such\nsentencing, except where the sentence is or includes a sentence of\nprobation on a conviction for a felony sexual assault, as provided in\nsubparagraph (iii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision three of section\n65.00 of the penal law, in which case, ten years from the date of such\nsentencing, or (ii) eight years from the date of the expiration of the\nmaximum term of an indeterminate or the term of a determinate sentence\nof imprisonment actually imposed; or (B) in the case of a conviction for\na class A misdemeanor, shall not exceed the greater of:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>five years\nfrom the date of such sentencing, except where the sentence is or\nincludes a sentence of probation on a conviction for a misdemeanor\nsexual assault, as provided in subparagraph (ii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of section 65.00 of the penal law, in which case, six\nyears from the date of such sentencing or (ii) five years from the date\nof the expiration of the maximum term of a definite or intermittent term\nactually imposed; or (C) in the case of a conviction for any other\noffense, shall not exceed the greater of:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>two years from the date of\nsentencing, or (ii) two years from the date of the expiration of the\nmaximum term of a definite or intermittent term actually imposed. For\npurposes of determining the duration of an order of protection entered\npursuant to this subdivision, a conviction shall be deemed to include a\nconviction that has been replaced by a youthful offender adjudication.\nIn addition to any other conditions such an order may require that the\ndefendant:\n  * NB Effective until September 1, 2027\n  * Upon sentencing on a conviction for any offense, where the court has\nnot issued an order of protection pursuant to section 530.12 of this\narticle, the court may, in addition to any other disposition, including\na conditional discharge or youthful offender adjudication, enter an\norder of protection. Where a temporary order of protection was issued,\nthe court shall state on the record the reasons for issuing or not\nissuing an order of protection. The duration of such an order shall be\nfixed by the court and, in the case of a felony conviction, shall not\nexceed the greater of:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>five years from the date of such sentencing,\nor (ii) three years from the date of the expiration of the maximum term\nof an indeterminate sentence of imprisonment actually imposed; or in the\ncase of a conviction for a class A misdemeanor, shall not exceed three\nyears from the date of such sentencing; or in the case of a conviction\nfor any other offense, shall not exceed one year from the date of\nsentencing. For purposes of determining the duration of an order of\nprotection entered pursuant to this subdivision, a conviction shall be\ndeemed to include a conviction that has been replaced by a youthful\noffender adjudication. In addition to any other conditions such an order\nmay require that the defendant:\n  * NB Effective September 1, 2027\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>stay away from the home, school, business or place of employment\nof the victim or victims, or of any witness designated by the court, of\nsuch offense;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>refrain from harassing, intimidating, threatening or otherwise\ninterfering with the victim or victims of the offense and such members\nof the family or household of such victim or victims as shall be\nspecifically named by the court in such order;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>1. to refrain from intentionally injuring or killing, without\njustification, any companion animal the defendant knows to be owned,\npossessed, leased, kept or held by such victim or victims or a minor\nchild residing in such victim's or victims' household.\n  2. "Companion animal", as used in this section, shall have the same\nmeaning as in subdivision five of section three hundred fifty of the\nagriculture and markets law;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>1. to refrain from remotely controlling any connected devices\naffecting the home, vehicle or property of the person protected by the\norder.\n  2. For purposes of this paragraph, "connected device" shall mean any\ndevice, or other physical object that is capable of connecting to the\ninternet, directly or indirectly, and that is assigned an internet\nprotocol address or bluetooth address.\n  * 5. The court shall inquire as to the existence of any other orders\nof protection between the defendant and the person or persons for whom\nthe order of protection is sought. An order of protection issued under\nthis section shall plainly state the date that such order expires.\nOrders of protection issued to protect victims of domestic violence, as\ndefined in section four hundred fifty-nine-a of the social services law,\nshall be on uniform statewide forms that shall be promulgated by the\nchief administrator of the courts in a manner to ensure the\ncompatibility of such forms with the statewide registry of orders of\nprotection and warrants established pursuant to section two hundred\ntwenty-one-a of the executive law. A copy of an order of protection or a\ntemporary order of protection issued pursuant to subdivision one, two,\nthree, or four of this section shall be filed by the clerk of the court\nwith the sheriff's office in the county in which such victim or victims\nreside, or, if the victim or victims reside within a city, with the\npolice department of such city. A copy of such order of protection or\ntemporary order of protection may from time to time be filed by the\nclerk of the court with any other police department or sheriff's office\nhaving jurisdiction of the residence, work place, and school of anyone\nintended to be protected by such order. A copy of the order may also be\nfiled by the victim or victims at the appropriate police department or\nsheriff's office having jurisdiction. Any subsequent amendment or\nrevocation of such order shall be filed in the ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>revoke an order of recognizance, release under non-monetary\nconditions or bail and commit the defendant to custody; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>restore the case to the calendar when there has been an\nadjournment in contemplation of dismissal and commit the defendant to\ncustody or impose or increase bail pending a trial of the original crime\nor violation; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>revoke a conditional discharge in accordance with section 410.70\nof this chapter and impose probation supervision or impose a sentence of\nimprisonment in accordance with the penal law based on the original\nconviction; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_13__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>revoke probation in accordance with section 410.70 of this chapter\nand impose a sentence of imprisonment in accordance with the penal law\nbased on the original conviction. In addition, if the act which\nconstitutes the violation of the order of protection or temporary order\nof protection is a crime or a violation the defendant may be charged\nwith and tried for that crime or violation.\n  9. The chief administrator of the courts shall promulgate appropriate\nuniform temporary order of protection and order of protection forms to\nbe used throughout the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>