<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.11"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.11"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="530.11"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.11/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-530.11/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_530_11">
        <num>530.11</num>
        <heading>Procedures for family offense matters</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons related by consanguinity or affinity;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons legally married to one another;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons formerly married to one another regardless of whether they\nstill reside in the same household;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons who have a child in common, regardless of whether such\npersons have been married or have lived together at any time;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons who are not related by consanguinity or affinity and who\nare or have been in an intimate relationship regardless of whether such\npersons have lived together at any time. Factors the court may consider\nin determining whether a relationship is an "intimate relationship"\ninclude but are not limited to: the nature or type of relationship,\nregardless of whether the relationship is sexual in nature; the\nfrequency of interaction between the persons; and the duration of the\nrelationship. Neither a casual acquaintance nor ordinary fraternization\nbetween two individuals in business or social contexts shall be deemed\nto constitute an "intimate relationship"; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>persons who are related by consanguinity or affinity to parties\nwho are or have been in an intimate relationship as defined in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n  2. Information to petitioner or complainant. The chief administrator\nof the courts shall designate the appropriate probation officers,\nwarrant officers, sheriffs, police officers, district attorneys or any\nother law enforcement officials, to inform any petitioner or complainant\nbringing a proceeding under this section before such proceeding is\ncommenced, of the procedures available for the institution of family\noffense proceedings, including but not limited to the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That there is concurrent jurisdiction with respect to family\noffenses in both family court and the criminal courts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That a family court proceeding is a civil proceeding and is for\nthe purpose of attempting to stop the violence, end family disruption\nand obtain protection. That referrals for counseling, or counseling\nservices, are available through probation for this purpose;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That a proceeding in the criminal courts is for the purpose of\nprosecution of the offender and can result in a criminal conviction of\nthe offender;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That a proceeding or action subject to the provisions of this\nsection is initiated at the time of the filing of an accusatory\ninstrument or family court petition, not at the time of arrest, or\nrequest for arrest, if any;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>That an arrest may precede the commencement of a family court or a\ncriminal court proceeding, but an arrest is not a requirement for\ncommencing either proceeding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At such time as the complainant first appears before the court on\na complaint or information, the court shall advise the complainant that\nthe complainant may: continue with the proceeding in criminal court; or\nhave the allegations contained therein heard in a family court\nproceeding; or proceed concurrently in both criminal and family court.\nNotwithstanding a complainant's election to proceed in family court, the\ncriminal court shall not be divested of jurisdiction to hear a family\noffense proceeding pursuant to this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing herein shall be deemed to limit or restrict complainant's\nrights to proceed directly and without court referral in either a\ncriminal or family court, or both, as provided for in section one\nhundred fifteen of the family court act and section 100.07 of this\nchapter;\n  2-a. Upon the filing of an accusatory instrument charging a crime or\nviolation described in subdivision one of this section between members\nof the same family or household, as such terms are defined in this\nsection, or as soon as the complainant first appears before the court,\nwhichever is sooner, the court shall advise the complainant of the right\nto proceed in both the criminal and family courts, pursuant to section\n100.07 of this chapter.\n  3. Official responsibility. No official or other person designated\npursuant to subdivision two of this section shall discourage or prevent\nany person who wishes to file a petition or sign a complaint from having\naccess to any court for that purpose.\n  4. When a person is arrested for an alleged family offense or an\nalleged violation of an order of protection or temporary order of\nprotection or arrested pursuant to a warrant issued by the supreme or\nfamily court, and the supreme or family court, as applicable, is not in\nsession, such person shall be brought before a local criminal court in\nthe county of arrest or in the county in which such warrant is\nreturnable pursuant to article one hundred twenty of this chapter. Such\nlocal criminal court may issue any order authorized under subdivision\neleven of section 530.12 of this article, section one hundred\nfifty-four-d or one hundred fifty-five of the family court act or\nsubdivision three-b of section two hundred forty or subdivision two-a of\nsection two hundred fifty-two of the domestic relations law, in addition\nto discharging other arraignment responsibilities as set forth in this\nchapter. In making such order, the local criminal court shall consider\nde novo the recommendation an...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An order issued by a court of competent jurisdiction in another\nstate, territorial or tribal jurisdiction shall be deemed valid if:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the issuing court had personal jurisdiction over the parties and\nover the subject matter under the law of the issuing jurisdiction;\n  (ii) the person against whom the order was issued had reasonable\nnotice and an opportunity to be heard prior to issuance of the order;\nprovided, however, that if the order was a temporary order of protection\nissued in the absence of such person, that notice had been given and\nthat an opportunity to be heard had been provided within a reasonable\nperiod of time after the issuance of the order; and\n  (iii) in the case of orders of protection or temporary orders of\nprotection issued against both a petitioner, plaintiff or complainant\nand respondent or defendant, the order or portion thereof sought to be\nenforced was supported by: (A) a pleading requesting such order,\nincluding, but not limited to, a petition, cross-petition or\ncounterclaim; and (B) a judicial finding that the requesting party is\nentitled to the issuance of the order which may result from a judicial\nfinding of fact, judicial acceptance of an admission by the party\nagainst whom the order was issued or judicial finding that the party\nagainst whom the order was issued had given knowing, intelligent and\nvoluntary consent to its issuance.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of article fifty-four of the civil\npractice law and rules, an order of protection or temporary order of\nprotection issued by a court of competent jurisdiction in another state,\nterritorial or tribal jurisdiction, accompanied by a sworn affidavit\nthat upon information and belief such order is in effect as written and\nhas not been vacated or modified, may be filed without fee with the\nclerk of the court, who shall transmit information regarding such order\nto the statewide registry of orders of protection and warrants\nestablished pursuant to section two hundred twenty-one-a of the\nexecutive law; provided, however, that such filing and registry entry\nshall not be required for enforcement of the order.\n  6. Notice. Every police officer, peace officer or district attorney\ninvestigating a family offense under this article shall advise the\nvictim of the availability of a shelter or other services in the\ncommunity, and shall immediately give the victim written notice of the\nlegal rights and remedies available to a victim of a family offense\nunder the relevant provisions of this chapter and the family court act.\nSuch notice shall be prepared, at minimum, in plain English, Spanish,\nChinese and Russian and if necessary, shall be delivered orally, and\nshall include but not be limited to the information contained in the\nfollowing statement:\n  "Are you the victim of domestic violence? If you need help now, you\ncan call 911 for the police to come to you. You can also call a domestic\nviolence hotline. You can have a confidential talk with an advocate at\nthe hotline about help you can get in your community including: where\nyou can get treatment for injuries, where you can get shelter, where you\ncan get support, and what you can do to be safe. The New York State\n24-hour Domestic &amp; Sexual Violence Hotline number is (insert the\nstatewide multilingual 800 number). They can give you information in\nmany languages. If you are deaf ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_530_11__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision\ntwo of section two hundred twelve of the judiciary law, shall promulgate\nrules to facilitate record sharing and other communication between the\ncriminal and family courts, subject to applicable provisions of this\nchapter and the family court act pertaining to the confidentiality,\nexpungement and sealing of records, when such courts exercise concurrent\njurisdiction over family offense proceedings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>