<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-570.56"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-570.56"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="570.56"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-570.56/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-570.56/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-570.56/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-570.56/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_570_56">
        <num>570.56</num>
        <heading>Expense of extradition</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 570.56 Expense of extradition.\n  The expenses of extradition must be borne by the county from which the\napplication for a requisition comes or, where the application is made by\nthe attorney general, by the county in which the offense was committed.\nIn the case of extradition of a person who has been convicted of a crime\nin this state and has escaped from a state prison or reformatory, the\nexpense of extradition shall be borne by the department of corrections\nand community supervision. Where a person has broken the terms of his or\nher parole from a state prison or reformatory, the expense of\nextradition shall be borne by the state department of corrections and\ncommunity supervision. Where a person has broken the terms of his or her\nbail or probation, the expense of extradition shall be borne by the\ncounty. Where a person has been convicted but not yet confined to a\nprison, or has been sentenced for a felony to a county jail or\npenitentiary and escapes, the expenses of extradition shall be charged\nto the county from whose custody the escape is effected. Nothing in this\nsection shall preclude a county or the department of corrections and\ncommunity supervision, as the case may be, from collecting the expenses\ninvolved in extradition from the person who was extradited.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>