<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.10"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.10"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="690.10"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.10/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.10/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_690_10">
        <num>690.10</num>
        <heading>Search warrants; property subject to seizure thereunder</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 690.10 Search warrants; property subject to seizure thereunder.\n  Personal property is subject to seizure pursuant to a search warrant\nif there is reasonable cause to believe that it:\n  1. Is stolen; or\n  2. Is unlawfully possessed; or\n  3. Has been used, or is possessed for the purpose of being used, to\ncommit or conceal the commission of an offense against the laws of this\nstate or another state, provided however, that if such offense was\nagainst the laws of another state, the court shall only issue a warrant\nif the conduct comprising such offense would, if occurring in this\nstate, constitute a felony against the laws of this state; or\n  4. Constitutes evidence or tends to demonstrate that an offense was\ncommitted in this state or another state, or that a particular person\nparticipated in the commission of an offense in this state or another\nstate, provided however, that if such offense was against the laws of\nanother state, the court shall only issue a warrant if the conduct\ncomprising such offense would, if occurring in this state, constitute a\nfelony against the laws of this state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>