<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.50"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.50"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="690.50"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.50/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-690.50/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_690_50">
        <num>690.50</num>
        <heading>Search warrants; execution thereof</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_690_50__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such premises or vehicle are at the time unoccupied or reasonably\nbelieved by the officer to be unoccupied; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_690_50__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The search warrant expressly authorizes entry without notice.\n  3.  In executing a search warrant directing or authorizing a search of\na person, a police officer must give, or make reasonable effort to give,\nsuch person notice of his authority and purpose and show him the warrant\nor a copy thereof upon request.  If such person, or another, thereafter\nresists or refuses to permit the search, the officer may use as much\nphysical force, other than deadly physical force, as is necessary to\nexecute the warrant; and he may use deadly physical force if he\nreasonably believes such to be necessary to defend himself or a third\nperson from what he reasonably believes to be the use or imminent use of\ndeadly physical force.\n  4.  Upon seizing property pursuant to a search warrant, a police\nofficer must write and subscribe a receipt itemizing the property taken\nand containing the name of the court by which the warrant was issued. If\nproperty is taken from a person, such receipt must be given to such\nperson.  If property is taken from premises or a vehicle, such receipt\nmust be given to the owner, tenant or other person in possession thereof\nif he is present; or if he is not, the officer must leave such a receipt\nin the premises or vehicle from which the property was taken.\n  5.  Upon seizing property pursuant to a search warrant, a police\nofficer must without unnecessary delay return to the court the warrant\nand the property, and must file therewith a written inventory of such\nproperty, subscribed and sworn to by such officer.\n  6. Upon arresting a person during a search for him or her pursuant to\na search warrant as defined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_690_50__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of\nsection 690.05, a police officer shall comply with the terms of the\nwarrant of arrest, superior court warrant of arrest, or bench warrant\nfor a felony, and shall proceed in the manner directed by this chapter.\nUpon arresting such person, the police officer shall also, without\nunnecessary delay, file a written statement with the court which issued\nthe search warrant, subscribed and sworn to by such officer, setting\nforth that the person has been arrested and duly brought before the\nappropriate court, return to the court the warrant and the property\nseized in the course of its execution, and file therewith a written\ninventory of any such property, subscribed and sworn to by such officer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>