<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="700.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-700.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_700_15">
        <num>700.15</num>
        <heading>Eavesdropping and video surveillance warrants; when issuable</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 700.15  Eavesdropping and video surveillance warrants; when issuable.\n  An eavesdropping or video surveillance warrant may issue only:\n  1.  Upon an appropriate application made in conformity with this\narticle; and\n  2.  Upon probable cause to believe that a particularly described\nperson is committing, has committed, or is about to commit a particular\ndesignated offense; and\n  3.  Upon probable cause to believe that particular communications\nconcerning such offense will be obtained through eavesdropping, or upon\nprobable cause to believe that particular observations concerning such\noffense will be obtained through video surveillance; and\n  4.  Upon a showing that normal investigative procedures have been\ntried and have failed, or reasonably appear to be unlikely to succeed if\ntried, or to be too dangerous to employ; and\n  5.  Upon probable cause to believe that the facilities from which, or\nthe place where, the communications are to be intercepted or the video\nsurveillance is to be conducted, are being used, or are about to be\nused, in connection with the commission of such offense, or are leased\nto, listed in the name of, or commonly used by such person.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>