<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-705.15"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-705.15"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="705.15"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-705.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-705.15/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-705.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-705.15/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_705_15">
        <num>705.15</num>
        <heading>Application for an order authorizing the use of a pen register or a trap and trace device</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_705_15__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The identity of the applicant and the identity of the law\nenforcement agency conducting the investigation; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_705_15__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement of facts and circumstances sufficient to justify the\napplicant's belief that an order authorizing the use of a pen register\nor a trap and trace device should be issued, including</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_705_15__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement\nof the specific facts on the basis of which the applicant reasonably\nsuspects that the designated crime has been, is being, or is about to be\ncommitted and demonstrating that the information likely to be obtained\nby use of a pen register or a trap and trace device is or will be\nrelevant to an ongoing criminal investigation of such designated\noffense, (ii) the identity, if known, of the person to whom is leased or\nin whose name is listed the telephone line to which the pen register or\ntrap and trace device is to be attached, (iii) the identity, if known,\nof the person who is the subject of the criminal investigation, (iv) the\nnumber and, if known, the physical location of the telephone line to\nwhich the pen register or trap and trace device is to be attached and,\nin the case of a trap and trace device, the geographic limits of the\ntrap and trace order, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_705_15__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement of the designated crime or\ncrimes to which the information likely to be obtained by the use of the\npen register or trap and trace device relates; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_705_15__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement of the period of time for which the authorization for\nthe use of a pen register or a trap and trace device is required; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_705_15__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A statement of the facts concerning all previous applications,\nknown to the applicant, for an order authorizing the use of a pen\nregister or a trap and trace device involving any of the same persons or\nfacilities specified in the application, and the action taken by the\njustice on each such application.\n  3. Allegations of fact in the application may be based either upon the\npersonal knowledge of the applicant or upon information and belief. If\nthe applicant personally knows the facts alleged, it must be so stated.\nIf the facts stated in the application are derived in whole or in part\nfrom the statements of persons other than the applicant, the sources of\nsuch facts must be either disclosed or described.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>