<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.00"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.00"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="722.00"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.00/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-722.00/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_722_00">
        <num>722.00</num>
        <heading>Probation case plans</heading>
        <content>
          <p>ยง 722.00 Probation case plans.\n  1. All juvenile offenders and adolescent offenders shall be notified\nof the availability of services through the local probation department.\nSuch services shall include the ability of the probation department to\nconduct a risk and needs assessment, utilizing a validated risk\nassessment tool, in order to help determine suitable and individualized\nprogramming and referrals. Participation in such risk and needs\nassessment shall be voluntary and the adolescent offender or juvenile\noffender may be accompanied by counsel during any such assessment. Based\nupon the assessment findings, the probation department shall refer the\nadolescent offender or juvenile offender to available and appropriate\nservices.\n  2. Nothing shall preclude the probation department and the adolescent\noffender or juvenile offender from entering into a voluntary service\nplan which may include alcohol, substance use and mental health\ntreatment and services. To the extent practicable, such services shall\ncontinue through the pendency of the action and shall further continue\nwhere such action is removed in accordance with this article.\n  3. When preparing a pre-sentence investigation report of any such\nadolescent offender or juvenile offender, the probation department shall\nincorporate a summary of any assessment findings, referrals and progress\nwith respect to mitigating risk and addressing any identified needs.\n  4. The probation service shall not transmit or otherwise communicate\nto the district attorney or the youth part any statement made by the\njuvenile or adolescent offender to a probation officer. However, the\nprobation service may make a recommendation regarding the completion of\nhis or her case plan to the youth part and provide such information as\nit shall deem relevant.\n  5. No statement made to the probation service may be admitted into\nevidence at a fact-finding hearing at any time prior to a conviction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>