<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.20"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.20"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-10-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="725.20"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.20/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.20/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_725_20">
        <num>725.20</num>
        <heading>Record of certain actions removed</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_725_20__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of section 220.10 of this chapter, or\nsection 330.25 of this chapter.\n  2. When such an action is removed the court that directed the removal\nmust cause the following additional records to be filed with the clerk\nof the county court or in the city of New York with the clerk of the\nsupreme court of the county wherein the action was pending and with the\ndivision of criminal justice services:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_725_20__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A certified copy of the order of removal;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_725_20__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Where the direction is one authorized by subparagraph (iii) of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_725_20__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of section 220.10 or section 330.25 of\nthis chapter, a copy of the minutes of the plea of guilty, including the\nminutes of the memorandum submitted by the district attorney and the\ncourt; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_725_20__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the records specified in this subdivision, such\nfurther statement or submission of additional information pertaining to\nthe proceeding in criminal court in accordance with standards\nestablished by the commissioner of the division of criminal justice\nservices, subject to the provisions of subdivision three of this\nsection.\n  3. It shall be the duty of said clerk to maintain a separate file for\ncopies of orders and minutes filed pursuant to this section. Upon\nreceipt of such orders and minutes the clerk must promptly delete such\nportions as would identify the defendant, but the clerk shall\nnevertheless maintain a separate confidential system to enable\ncorrelation of the documents so filed with identification of the\ndefendant. After making such deletions the orders and minutes shall be\nplaced within the file and must be available for public inspection.\nInformation permitting correlation of any such record with the identity\nof any defendant shall not be divulged to any person except upon order\nof a justice of the supreme court based upon a finding that the public\ninterest or the interests of justice warrant disclosure in a particular\ncause for a particular case or for a particular purpose or use.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>