<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.05"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.05"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-03-25" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="725.05"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.05/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-725.05/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_725_05">
        <num>725.05</num>
        <heading>Order of removal</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_725_05__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision three of sections 722.20 or 722.21 of this title, it must\nspecify the act or acts it found reasonable cause to believe the\ndefendant did.\n  3. Where the direction is authorized pursuant to subdivision four of\nsection 722.20 or section 722.21 of this title, it must specify the act\nor acts it found reasonable cause to allege.\n  4. Where the direction is authorized pursuant to section 190.71 of\nthis chapter, the court shall annex to the order as part thereof a\ncertified copy of the grand jury request.\n  4-a. Where the direction is authorized pursuant to subdivision seven\nof section 210.30 of this chapter, it must specify the act or acts for\nwhich there was sufficient evidence to believe that defendant did.\n  5. Where the direction is authorized pursuant to section 220.10,\n310.85 or 330.25 of this chapter, it must specify the act or acts for\nwhich a plea or verdict of guilty was rendered or accepted and entered.\n  6. Where a securing order has not been made, the order of removal must\nprovide that the police officer or peace officer who made the arrest or\nsome other proper officer forthwith and with all reasonable speed take\nthe juvenile to the designated family court or, where that cannot be\ndone, it must provide for release or detention in the same manner as\nprovided for a family court proceeding pursuant to section 320.5 of the\nfamily court act.\n  7. Whether or not a securing order has been made, the order of removal\nmust specify a date certain within ten days from the date of the order\nof removal for the defendant's appearance in the family court and where\nthe defendant is in detention or in the custody of the sheriff that date\nmust be not later than the next day the family court is in session.\nUnless the defendant is in detention or is in the custody of the sheriff\nor unless the order of removal specifies a juvenile or adolescent\noffense for which the defendant is not eligible for consideration for\nadjustment under subdi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>