<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.40"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.40"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-26" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="730.40"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.40/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.40/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_730_40">
        <num>730.40</num>
        <heading>Fitness to proceed; local criminal court accusatory instrument</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision six of section\n730.60 of this article.  When the defendant is in the custody of the\ncommissioner at the expiration of the period prescribed in a temporary\norder of observation, the proceedings in the local criminal court that\nissued such order shall terminate for all purposes and the commissioner\nmust promptly certify to such court and to the appropriate district\nattorney that the defendant was in his or her custody on such expiration\ndate. Upon receipt of such certification, the court must dismiss the\nfelony complaint filed against the defendant.\n  * NB Effective until March 19, 2026\n  * 2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_730_40__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>When a local criminal court has issued a final order of\nobservation, it must:\n  (A) order the institution in which the defendant is confined to make a\nsingle point of access referral for the defendant with the appropriate\nagency closest to the defendant's last known county of residence prior\nto discharge; and\n  (B) dismiss the accusatory instrument filed in such court against the\ndefendant and such dismissal constitutes a bar to any further\nprosecution of the charge or charges contained in such accusatory\ninstrument.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_730_40__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Each appropriate institution shall maintain records compiling all\ndischarge planning and single point of access referrals completed\npursuant to subparagraph one of this paragraph and submit de-identified\nbiannual reports on such records to the commissioner and chief\nadministrative judge of the courts.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_40__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>When the defendant is in the custody of the commissioner pursuant\nto a final order of observation, the commissioner or such commissioner's\ndesignee, which may include the director of an appropriate institution,\nimmediately upon the discharge of the defendant, must certify to such\ncourt that the commissioner or such commissioner's designee has complied\nwith the notice provisions set forth in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision six\nof section 730.60 of this article and the referral provisions set forth\nin paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_40__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. When the defendant is in the\ncustody of the commissioner at the expiration of the period prescribed\nin a temporary order of observation, the proceedings in the local\ncriminal court that issued such order shall terminate for all purposes\nand the commissioner must promptly certify to such court and to the\nappropriate district attorney that the defendant was in the\ncommissioner's custody on such expiration date. Upon receipt of such\ncertification, the court must dismiss the felony complaint filed against\nthe defendant.\n  * NB Effective March 19, 2026\n  3. When a local criminal court has issued an order of examination or a\ntemporary order of observation, and when the charge or charges contained\nin the accusatory instrument are subsequently presented to a grand jury,\nsuch grand jury need not hear the defendant pursuant to section 190.50\nunless, upon application by defendant to the superior court that\nimpaneled such grand jury, the superior court determines that the\ndefendant is not an incapacitated person.\n  4. When an indictment is filed against a defendant after a local\ncriminal court has issued an order of examination and before it has\nissued a final or temporary order of observation, the defendant must be\npromptly arraigned upon the indictment, and the proceedings in the local\ncriminal court shall thereupon terminate for all purposes. The district\nattorney must notify the local criminal court of such arraignment, and\nsuch court must thereupon dismiss the accusatory instrument filed in\nsuch court against the defendant. If the director has submitted the\nexamination reports to the local criminal court, such court must forward\nthem to the superior court in which the indictment was filed. If the\ndirector has not submitted such reports to the local criminal court, he\nmust submit them to the superior court in which the indictment was\nfiled.\n  5. When an indictment is timely filed against the defendant after the\nissuance of...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>