<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="CPL">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.60"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.60"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="730.60"/>
          <FRBRname value="CPL"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.60/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/cpl/section-730.60/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_730_60">
        <num>730.60</num>
        <heading>Fitness to proceed; procedure following custody by commissioner</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_60__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant is a resident or citizen of another\nstate or country and that he will be removed thereto upon dismissal of\nthe indictment, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_60__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the defendant has been continuously confined in\nthe custody of the commissioner for a period of more than two years.\nBefore granting a motion under this subdivision, the court must be\nfurther satisfied that dismissal of the indictment is consistent with\nthe ends of justice and that custody of the defendant by the\ncommissioner pursuant to an order of commitment or an order of retention\nis not necessary for the protection of the public and that care and\ntreatment can be effectively administered to the defendant without the\nnecessity of such order. If the court enters an order of dismissal under\nthis subdivision, it must set forth in the record the reasons for such\naction, and must direct that such order of dismissal be served upon the\ncommissioner. The dismissal of an indictment pursuant to this\nsubdivision constitutes a bar to any further prosecution of the charge\nor charges contained in such indictment.\n  6.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_60__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no person committed\nto the custody of the commissioner pursuant to this article, or\ncontinuously thereafter retained in such custody, shall be discharged,\nreleased on condition or placed in any less secure facility or on any\nless restrictive status, including, but not limited to vacations,\nfurloughs and temporary passes, unless the commissioner or his or her\ndesignee, which may include the director of an appropriate institution,\nshall deliver written notice, at least four days, excluding Saturdays,\nSundays and holidays, in advance of the change of such committed\nperson's facility or status, or in the case of a person committed\npursuant to a final order of observation written notice upon discharge\nof such committed person, to all of the following:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_730_60__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The district attorney of the county from which such person was\ncommitted;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_730_60__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The superintendent of state police;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_730_60__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The sheriff of the county where the facility is located;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_730_60__subsec_a__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The police department having jurisdiction of the area where the\nfacility is located;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_730_60__subsec_a__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any person who may reasonably be expected to be the victim of any\nassault or any violent felony offense, as defined in the penal law, or\nany offense listed in section 530.11 of this part which would be carried\nout by the committed person; provided that the person who reasonably may\nbe expected to be a victim does not need to be a member of the same\nfamily or household as the committed person; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_730_60__subsec_a__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Any other person the court may designate.\n  Said notice may be given by any means reasonably calculated to give\nprompt actual notice.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_60__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The notice required by this subdivision shall also be given\nimmediately upon the departure of such committed person from the actual\ncustody of the commissioner or an appropriate institution, without\nproper authorization. Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to\nimpair any other right or duty regarding any notice or hearing contained\nin any other provision of law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_60__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever a district attorney has received the notice described in\nthis subdivision, and the defendant is in the custody of the\ncommissioner pursuant to a final order of observation or an order of\ncommitment, he may apply within three days of receipt of such notice to\na superior court, for an order directing a hearing to be held to\ndetermine whether such committed person is a danger to himself or\nothers. Such hearing shall be held within ten days following the\nissuance of such order. Such order may provide that there shall be no\nfurther change in the committed person's facility or status until the\nhearing. Upon a finding that the committed person is a danger to himself\nor others, the court shall issue an order to the commissioner\nauthorizing retention of the committed person in the status existing at\nthe time notice was given hereunder, for a specified period, not to\nexceed six months. The district attorney and the committed person's\nattorney shall be entitled to the committed person's clinical records in\nthe commissioner's custody, upon the issuance of an order directing a\nhearing to be held.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_730_60__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to impair any other\nright or duty regarding any notice or hearing contained in any other\nprovision of law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>