<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1008"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1008"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1008"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1008/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1008/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1008/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1008/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1008">
        <num>1008</num>
        <heading>Consent of state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1008. Consent of state. The state of New York hereby consents to the\noccupation and use by the authority of any and all property of the state\nof whatever kind or character on the Niagara river or within the\ninternational rapids section of the Saint Lawrence river, and hereby\nvests the authority with and delegates to it the right to exercise any\nand every right and power of the state in connection therewith, whether\nproprietary or sovereign in character, which the state itself might\nexercise, provided that such consent and delegation of power shall not\npermit the impairment or limit or prevent the future improvement of the\nnavigability of the Niagara river or the international rapids section of\nthe Saint Lawrence river, consistent with the maintenance of such\nprojects, but on the contrary the projects shall be such as will improve\nand benefit commerce and navigation therein and provided further that\nthe authority shall have no power to limit, waive or surrender any right\nor interest of the state of New York in such rivers or the use thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>