<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-Y"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-Y"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1020-Y"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-Y/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-Y/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1020_Y">
        <num>1020-Y</num>
        <heading>Court proceedings; preferences; venue</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1020-y. Court proceedings; preferences; venue. 1. Any action, suit\nor proceeding to which the authority may be a party in which any\nquestion arises as to the validity of this title or the valuation of\nstock or assets acquired by the authority by the exercise of the power\nof eminent domain shall be preferred over all other civil causes in all\ncourts of the state, except election matters, and shall be heard and\ndetermined in preference to all other civil business pending therein,\nexcept election matters, irrespective of position on the calendar. The\nsame preference shall be granted upon application of counsel to the\nauthority in any action or proceeding questioning the validity of this\ntitle or the valuation of stock or assets acquired by the authority by\nthe exercise of the power of eminent domain in which such counsel may be\nallowed to intervene. The venue of any action or proceeding questioning\nthe validity of this title shall be laid in the county in which the\nprincipal office of the authority is located.\n  2. In the event any party shall appeal an award of compensation for\nthe taking by the authority of stock or assets, such party shall post a\nbond in such amount, if any, as the supreme court shall deem appropriate\nto adequately protect the interests of the other party under all the\ncircumstances.\n  3. Except in an action for wrongful death, an action against the\nauthority founded on tort shall not be commenced more than one year and\nninety days after the cause of action therefor shall have accrued, nor\nunless a notice of claim shall have been served on the authority within\nthe time limited by, and in compliance with all the requirements of\nsection fifty-e of the general municipal law. An action against the\nauthority for wrongful death shall be commenced in accordance with the\nnotice of claim and time limitation provisions of title eleven of\narticle nine of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>