<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1020-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1020_B">
        <num>1020-B</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by the highest court of competent jurisdiction, or (ii) by\na court of competent jurisdiction from which no appeal has been taken\nand the time within which to appeal has expired.\n  9. "Governing body" means, with respect to any municipality, the body\nhaving charge of the fiscal affairs of such municipality.\n  10. "LILCO" means the Long Island lighting company, its subsidiaries\nand their successors and assigns, other than the authority.\n  11. "Municipality" means any city, town, village, county, municipal\ncorporation, district corporation, district or other political\nsubdivision of the state.\n  12. "OCLD" means the original cost of assets, less depreciation.\n  12-a. "Project" means an action undertaken by the authority that:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Causes the authority to issue bonds, notes or other obligations,\nor shares in any subsidiary corporation, or\n  (ii) Significantly modifies the use of an asset valued at more than\none million dollars owned by the authority or involves the sale, lease\nor other disposition of such an asset, or\n  (iii) Commits the authority to a contract or agreement with a total\nconsideration of greater than one million dollars and does not involve\nthe day to day operations of the authority.\n  13. "Prudent utility practices" at a particular time means any of the\npractices, methods, and acts, which, in the exercise of reasonable\njudgment in light of the facts (including but not limited to the\npractices, methods and acts engaged in or approved by a significant\nportion of the gas or the electrical utility industry, as the case may\nbe, prior thereto) known at the time the decision was made, would have\nbeen expected to accomplish the desired result at the lowest reasonable\ncost consistent with reliability, safety and expedition. Prudent utility\npractice is not intended to be limited to the optimum practice, method\nor act, to the exclusion of all others, but rather to be a spectrum of\npossible practices, methods or acts. In evaluating whether any matter\nconforms to prudent utility practice, the parties shall take into\naccount the fact that the authority is a corporate municipality of the\nstate with the statutory duties and responsibilities thereof.\n  14. "Real property" means lands, structures, franchises and interests\nin land, including lands under water and riparian rights, and any and\nall other things and rights usually included within such term, and\nincludes also any and all interests in such property less than full\ntitle, such as easements, rights of way, uses, leases, licenses and all\nother incorporeal hereditaments and every estate, interest or right,\nlegal or equitable, including terms for years and liens thereon by way\nof judgments, mortgages or otherwis...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the effective date of this title, (ii)\nthe date of the taking of the stock or assets pursuant to this title or\n(iii) such earlier or later date or, in the case of equity or debt\nsecurities, such period of trading days in the primary established\nmarket in which such securities are traded, as may be determined to be\nnecessary to exclude from the determination of the market value thereof\nany enhancement or depreciation in value arising from the announcement,\nexpectation or accomplishment of the taking by the exercise of the power\nof eminent domain or otherwise, or speculative market activity intended\nto cause or having the effect of causing an increase or decrease in such\nmarket value.\n  23. "Service provider" means the entity under contract with the\nauthority to provide management and operation services associated with\nthe authority's electric transmission and distribution system and any\nsubsidiary of such entity that provides such services under contract.\n  24. "Operations services agreement" means an agreement and any\namendments thereto between the Long Island lighting company dba LIPA or\nthe authority and the service provider to provide management and\noperation services associated with the authority's electric transmission\nand distribution system.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1020-b's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>