<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-V"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-V"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1020-V"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1020_V">
        <num>1020-V</num>
        <heading>Equal employment opportunity and minority and women owned business enterprise programs</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_V__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The contractor will not discriminate against employees or\napplicants for employment because of race, creed, color, national\norigin, sex, age, disability, or marital status, and will undertake or\ncontinue existing programs of affirmative action to ensure that minority\ngroup persons and women are afforded equal opportunity without\ndiscrimination. Such programs shall include, but not be limited to,\nrecruitment, employment, job assignment, promotion, upgrading, demotion,\ntransfer, layoff, termination, rates of pay or other forms of\ncompensation, and selection for training and retraining, including\napprenticeship and on-the-job training.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_V__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>At the request of the authority, the contractor shall request each\nemployment agency, labor union, or authorized representative of workers\nwith which it has a collective bargaining or other agreement or\nunderstanding and which is involved in the performance of the contract\nwith the authority to furnish a written statement that such employment\nagency, labor union or representative shall not discriminate because of\nrace, creed, color, national origin, sex, age, disability or marital\nstatus and that such union or representative will cooperate in the\nimplementation of the contractor's obligations hereunder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_V__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The contractor shall state, in all solicitations or advertisements\nfor employees placed by or on behalf of the contractor in the\nperformance of the contract with the authority that all qualified\napplicants will be afforded equal employment opportunity without\ndiscrimination because of race, creed, color, national origin, sex, age,\ndisability or marital status.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_V__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The contractor will include the provisions of paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_V__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthrough</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_V__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision in every subcontract or purchase order\nin such a manner that such provisions will be binding upon each\nsubcontractor or vendor as to its work in connection with the contract\nwith the authority.\n  2. The authority shall establish measures, procedures and guidelines\nto ensure that contractors and subcontractors undertake meaningful\nprograms to employ and promote qualified minority group members and\nwomen. Such procedures may require after notice in a bid solicitation,\nthe submission of a minority and women workforce utilization program\nprior to the award of any contract, or at any time thereafter, and may\nrequire the submission of compliance reports relating to the operation\nand implementation of any workforce utilization program adopted\nhereunder.  The authority may take appropriate action, including the\nimpositions of sanctions for non-compliance to effectuate the provisions\nof this section and shall be responsible for monitoring compliance with\nthis title.\n  3. In the performance of projects pursuant to this title, minority and\nwomen-owned business enterprises shall be given the opportunity for\nmeaningful participation. The authority shall establish quantifiable\nstandards and measures and procedures to secure meaningful participation\nand identify those contracts and items of work for which minority and\nwomen-owned business enterprises may best bid to actively and\naffirmatively promote and assist their participation in projects, so as\nto facilitate the award of a fair share of contracts to such\nenterprises; provided, however, that nothing in this title shall be\nconstrued to limit the ability of the authority to assure that qualified\nminority and women-owned business enterprises may participate in the\nprogram. For purposes hereof, minority business enterprise shall mean\nany business enterprise which is at least fifty-one per centum owned by,\nor in the case of a publicly owned business, at least fifty-one per\ncentum of...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>