<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1020-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1020_D">
        <num>1020-D</num>
        <heading>Board of trustees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1020-d. Board of trustees. 1. Starting on January first, two\nthousand fourteen, the board of the authority shall be constituted and\nconsist of nine trustees all of whom shall be residents of the service\narea, five of whom shall be appointed by the governor, one of whom the\ngovernor shall designate as chair, and serve at his or her pleasure, two\nof whom shall be appointed by the temporary president of the senate, and\ntwo of whom shall be appointed by the speaker of the assembly. One of\nthe governor's appointees shall serve an initial term of two years; one\nof the governor's appointees shall serve an initial term of three years;\nand three of the governor's appointees shall serve an initial term of\nfour years. One of the appointees of the temporary president of the\nsenate and one of the appointees of the speaker of the assembly shall\nserve initial terms of two years; and one appointee of the temporary\npresident of the senate and one appointee of the speaker of the assembly\nshall serve initial terms of three years. Thereafter, all terms shall be\nfor a period of four years. In the event of a vacancy occurring in the\noffice of trustee by death, resignation or otherwise, the respective\nappointing officer shall appoint a successor who shall hold office for\nthe unexpired portion of the term.\n  2. No trustee shall receive a salary, but each shall be entitled to\nreimbursement for reasonable expenses in the performance of duties\nassigned hereunder.\n  3. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, no trustee,\nofficer or employee of the state, any state agency or municipality\nappointed a trustee shall be deemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit\nhis or her office or employment by reason of his or her acceptance of a\ntrusteeship on the authority, his or her service thereon or his or her\nemployment therewith.\n  4. All trustees appointed under this section shall have relevant\nutility, corporate board or financial experience.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1020-d's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>