<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1020-A*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1020_A*2">
        <num>1020-A*2</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1020-a. Definitions. As used or referred to in this title, unless\na different meaning clearly appears from the context:\n  1. The term "authority" shall mean the corporation created by section\none thousand twenty-c of this title.\n  2. The term "bonds" shall mean bonds, notes or other evidences of\nindebtedness issued by the authority pursuant to this title.\n  3. The term "comptroller" shall mean the comptroller of the state.\n  4. The term "civil service commission" shall mean the civil service\ncommission of the county of Albany.\n  5. The term "district" shall mean the Green Island power district\ncreated by section one thousand twenty-b of this title.\n  6. The term "board of trustees" shall mean the board of trustees of\nthe village of Green Island.\n  7. The term "mayor" shall mean the mayor of the village of Green\nIsland.\n  8. The term "properties" shall mean the power distribution system or\nsystems of the authority, whether situated within or without the\nterritorial limits of the district, including the plants, works,\nstructures, poles, lines, conduits, mains, systems, instrumentalities or\npart thereof and appurtenances thereto, lands, easements, rights in land\nand water rights, rights-of-way, contract rights, franchises,\ntransmission facilities and distribution facilities, or any other\nproperty incidental to and included in such system or part thereof, and\nany improvements, extensions or betterments.\n  9. The term "municipalities" shall mean any county, city, town,\nvillage, school district, and any other political subdivision of the\nstate.\n  10. The term "revenues" shall mean all rates, rents, fees, charges,\npayments and other income and receipts derived from the operation of the\nproperties of the authority including, but not limited to, investment\nproceeds and proceeds of insurance, condemnation, and sales or other\ndisposition of assets, together with all federal, state or municipal\naid.\n  11. The term "state" shall mean the state of New York.\n  12. The term "village" shall mean the village of Green Island.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1020-a's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>