<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1020-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1020-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1020_A">
        <num>1020-A</num>
        <heading>Declaration of legislative findings and declarations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1020_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three of\narticle nine of the state constitution.\n  Such matters of state concern best can be dealt with by replacing such\ninvestor owned utility with a publicly owned power authority. Such an\nauthority can best accomplish the purposes and objectives of this title\nby implementing, if it then appears appropriate, the results of\nnegotiations between the state and LILCO. In such circumstances, such an\nauthority will provide safe and adequate service at rates which will be\nlower than the rates which would otherwise result and will facilitate\nthe shifting of investment into more beneficial energy demand/energy\nsupply management alternatives, realizing savings for the ratepayers and\ntaxpayers in the service area and otherwise restoring the confidence and\nprotecting the interests of ratepayers and the economy in the service\narea. Moreover, in such circumstances the replacement of such investor\nowned utilities by such an authority will result in an improved system\nand reduction of future costs and a safer, more efficient, reliable and\neconomical supply of electric energy. The legislature further finds that\nsuch an authority shall utilize to the fullest extent practicable, all\neconomical means of conservation, and technologies that rely on\nrenewable energy resources, cogeneration and improvements in energy\nefficiency which will benefit the interests of the ratepayers of the\nservice area.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1020-a's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>