<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1021-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1021_M">
        <num>1021-M</num>
        <heading>Actions against the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1021-m. Actions against the authority. 1. Any action, suit or\nproceeding to which the authority may be a party in which any question\narises as to the validity of this title or the valuation of stock or\nassets acquired by the authority by the exercise of the power of eminent\ndomain shall be preferred over all other civil causes in all courts of\nthe state, except election matters, and shall be heard and determined in\npreference to all other civil business pending therein, except election\nmatters, irrespective of position on the calendar. The same preference\nshall be granted upon application of counsel to the authority in any\naction or proceeding questioning the validity of this title or the\nvaluation of stock or assets acquired by the authority by the exercise\nof the power of eminent domain in which such counsel may be allowed to\nintervene. The venue of any such action or proceeding shall be laid in\nthe supreme court pursuant to article five of the civil practice law and\nrules.\n  2. In the event any party shall appeal an award of compensation for\nthe taking by the authority of stock or assets, such party shall post a\nbond in such amount, if any, as the supreme court shall deem appropriate\nto adequately protect the interests of the other party under all the\ncircumstances.\n  3. An action against the authority founded on tort shall be commenced\nin compliance with all the requirements of section fifty-e of the\ngeneral municipal law, except that an action against the authority for\nwrongful death shall be commenced in accordance with the provisions of\ntitle eleven of article nine of this chapter. Except in an action for\nwrongful death, an action against the authority for damages for injuries\nto real or personal property, or for the destruction thereof, or for\npersonal injuries, alleged to have been sustained, shall not be\ncommenced more than one year and ninety days after the cause of action\ntherefor shall have accrued.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>