<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1021-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1021_C">
        <num>1021-C</num>
        <heading>North Country power authority service area; extension of service area</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1021-c. North Country power authority service area; extension of\nservice area. 1. The service area of the North Country power authority\nshall include all the territory located within so much of the county of\nFranklin as constitutes the Towns of Bombay, Fort Covington, Moira and\nWestville, and so much of the county of St. Lawrence as constitutes the\nTowns of Brasher, Canton, Colton, DeKalb, Edwards, Fowler, Gouverneur,\nHermon, Lisbon, Louisville, Madrid, Norfolk, Pierrepont, Potsdam,\nRussell, Stockholm, and Waddington and the Villages of Canton, Norwood,\nand Potsdam or such portions thereof as shall be determined by the\ndirectors, but the service area shall exclude the portions of said\nmunicipalities in Franklin and St. Lawrence counties which are served as\nof the effective date of this title by another existing non-profit\nmunicipal electric utility. The service area of the North Country power\nauthority shall include such other territories, as shall be determined\nby the directors, wholly within Franklin or St. Lawrence county, and\nadjacent to one or more of the above-referenced municipalities, in which\nrate payers rely on uninterrupted electric service from power facilities\nof the authority located within said municipalities. A map of the\nservice area shall be filed in the offices of the county clerks of\nFranklin and St. Lawrence counties.\n  2. The service area of the North Country power authority may be\nextended at any time to include additional territory within Franklin or\nSt.  Lawrence counties by the directors in accordance with the following\nprocedure, provided however, the procedure does not conflict with any\nrule or regulation of the public service commission or any other law.\nWhenever the directors determine that the territory included within the\nservice area should be extended, consistent with the provisions of this\ntitle, the directors shall adopt a resolution proposing the additional\nterritory, wholly within Franklin or St. Lawrence county, to be\nincluded, which may be all the territory within one or more named\nmunicipalities or, by adequate description, a portion of any such\nmunicipality or municipalities. The directors shall fix the dates, hours\nand places for three public hearings before such directors upon the\nquestion of such extension and cause notice thereof and of the\nadditional territory to be included within the service area to be\npublished in two newspapers of general circulation in the county not\nless than twenty nor more than thirty days before such date. At least\none of such hearing shall be held within the bounds of the proposed\nadditional territory. At such time the directors shall hear all persons,\ntaxpayers or officials who may wish to be heard and shall finally\ndetermine the additional territory, if any, to be included in such\nextension. Such determination shall be made by resolution of the\ndirectors adopted by a two-thirds vote of all directors then in office.\nA map of the service area, as extended, shall thereupon be filed in the\noffices of the county clerks of Franklin and St. Lawrence counties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>