<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1021-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1021-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1021_B">
        <num>1021-B</num>
        <heading>North Country power authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1021_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The directors shall from time to time select such officers and\nemployees, including a chief executive officer and such engineering,\nmanagement and legal officers, and other professional employees,\nincluding but not limited to accounting, planning, construction,\nfinance, appraisal, banking and trustee services, as the directors may\nrequire for the performance of their duties and shall prescribe the\nduties and compensation of each such officer and employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1021_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any employees are hired as a consequence of an acquisition of\nthe assets of National Grid, they shall be hired subject and be entitled\nto all applicable provisions of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1021_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any existing contract or contracts\nwith labor unions and (ii) all existing pension or other retirement\nplans.  Notwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local\nlaw, the board may determine that such class of employees of the\nauthority may elect to become members of the New York state employees'\nretirement system on the basis of compensation payable to them by the\nauthority.\n  7.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1021_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall be subject in all respects to the general\nsupervision and jurisdiction of the public service commission in the\nsame manner as a municipal electric utility is subject to the\njurisdiction of the public service commission under the public service\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1021_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall not make any commitment, enter into any\nagreement nor incur any indebtedness unless prior approval has been\nreceived from the New York state public authorities control board\npursuant to article one-A of this chapter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1021_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to all of the powers of the public service commission,\nprior to acquiring any property and commencing operations, the authority\nshall secure an order from the commission authorizing such acquisition\nand commencement. The commission shall have the power to deny the\nauthority's application to acquire property and commence operations. The\nauthority shall comply with any and all requests for documents,\nmaterials, and testimony that the commission may seek. The commission\nshall consider, including but not limited to, the following factors\nbefore issuing an order: ratepayer impacts; system reliability;\nenvironmental impacts, conservation of energy resources; preservation or\ncreation of economic opportunities; power efficiency and availability;\npublic health and welfare; and any other factor it deems relevant. The\nauthority granted pursuant to this paragraph shall terminate upon\ncommencement of distribution of power.\n  8. The authority and its corporate existence shall continue until\nterminated by law, provided, however, that no such law shall take effect\nso long as the authority shall have securities outstanding, unless\nadequate provision has been made for the payment thereof.\n  9. In the event that the authority does not commence delivering\nelectric power within ten years of the effective date of this title, the\nauthority shall cease to exist and the provisions of this title shall be\nof no further force and effect, subject to the terms of any bonds, notes\nor other debt obligations then outstanding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>