<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1026"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1026"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1026"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1026/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1026/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1026/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1026/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1026">
        <num>1026</num>
        <heading>Albany Light, Heat and Power Authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1026. Albany Light, Heat and Power Authority. There is hereby\ndefined and established an area in the county of Albany to be known as\nthe "Albany light, heat and power district," which shall embrace all the\nterritory comprised within the cities of Albany, Cohoes and Watervliet,\nthe villages of Ravena, Green Island, Colonie, Menands, Voorheesville\nand Altamont, and the towns of Bethlehem, Coeymans, Colonie, Green\nIsland, Guilderland and New Scotland, within such county. Such district\nmay be extended at any time to include additional territory within such\ncounty, in the manner provided in section one thousand twenty-eight.\n  There is also hereby created and established a public corporation, to\nbe known as "Albany Light, Heat and Power Authority," hereinafter in\nthis title referred to as "the authority." The authority shall be a body\ncorporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation, the\nobjects of which in the judgment of the legislature cannot be attained\nunder general laws. It shall have the power to acquire by the exercise\nof the right of eminent domain or otherwise such real estate and other\nproperty as may be necessary, to sue and be sued, to incur debts,\nliabilities and obligations, to issue bonds and other evidences of\nindebtedness, to have a seal, and to exercise all powers authorized by\nthis title and reasonably necessary for accomplishing its purposes, or\nproperly incidental thereto, subject to the provisions herein contained\nand to the constitution and laws of the United States and of New York\nstate. Such powers shall be exercised in the name of the authority. Such\nauthority shall continue only until July first, nineteen hundred\nsixty-three, and thereafter until all its liabilities have been met and\nits bonds have been paid in full or such liabilities or bonds have\notherwise been discharged; provided, however, that no appropriation made\nto the authority by the state of New York or by any political\nsubdivision thereof, shall be deemed a liability for the purposes of\nthis section.\n  * NB Terminated July 1, 1963\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>