<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1027"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1027"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1027"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1027/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1027/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1027/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1027/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1027">
        <num>1027</num>
        <heading>Members of authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1027. Members of authority. The members, constituting the board of\ndirectors of the authority, shall consist of not exceeding five persons,\nto be appointed by the board of supervisors of Albany county. Three\nmembers shall when appointed be residents of the city of Albany and\nshall be appointed by such board on designation of the mayor of such\ncity. The term of office of a member shall be five years, but in the\nfirst instance such members shall be appointed to hold office, one for\none year, one for two years, one for three years, one for four years and\none for five years, the term of each to be fixed by the resolution\nmaking the appointment. Upon resignation of a member, or a vacancy\noccurring in any other manner, it shall be filled by appointment for the\nunexpired term. In other respects all vacancies shall be filled in\nmanner corresponding to the original appointment. Each member before\nentering upon the duties of his office shall take the constitutional\noath of office, which shall be filed in the office of the secretary of\nstate. Three directors shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of\nbusiness and the concurrence of three directors at a meeting shall be\nnecessary to the validity of any resolution, order or determination. Any\nmember may be removed by the board of supervisors for inefficiency,\nneglect of duty or misconduct in office, after a hearing upon charges\nand an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel upon not less\nthan ten days' notice. The members shall receive such salary as shall be\ndetermined by the board of supervisors of the county. They shall receive\nno reimbursement for the ordinary expenses of attending meetings, but\nmay by resolution of the board of directors be allowed their expenses of\na special or extraordinary nature. A member may receive additional\ncompensation to be fixed by the board of directors, if appointed an\nofficer of the authority. The directors of the authority may appoint an\nexecutive committee of not less than three members and may delegate full\npowers to such committee. They may appoint such other committees of not\nless than three members each with such powers as they may provide. They\nmay elect one of the members as a president and may elect or appoint\nother officers and determine their powers. They may by a vote of a\nmajority of members adopt by-laws and provide for their annual and\nregular meetings and for the calling of special meetings. The treasurer\nof the county of Albany shall be ex-officio treasurer of the authority\nand his compensation as such treasurer shall be fixed by the board of\nsupervisors.\n  * NB Terminated July 1, 1963\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>