<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1028"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1028"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1028"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1028/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1028/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1028/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1028/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1028">
        <num>1028</num>
        <heading>Enlargement of district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1028. Enlargement of district. Whenever it shall appear to the\nboard of supervisors that the area included within the district should\nbe extended it shall adopt a resolution stating the additional territory\nto be included which may be all the territory within one or more named\nmunicipalities or by adequate description a part of any such territory.\nIt shall fix the date and hour for a hearing upon the question of such\nextension and cause notice thereof and of the additional territory to be\nincluded within the district to be published in two newspapers of\ngeneral circulation in the county not less than twenty nor more than\nthirty days before such date. At such time the board shall hear all\npersons, taxpayers or officials who may wish to be heard and shall\nfinally determine the additional territory, if any, to be included in\nsuch extension. Such determination shall be made by resolution of the\nboard adopted by a two-thirds vote thereof. A map of the district as\nextended shall thereupon be filed in the office of the county clerk.\n  * NB Terminated July 1, 1963\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>