<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1032"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1032"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1032"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1032/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1032/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1032/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1032/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1032">
        <num>1032</num>
        <heading>Power to furnish service within district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1032. Power to furnish service within district. The authority\nshall have power to construct or acquire, by purchase or condemnation,\nor to lease, and to equip, own and operate, within or without the\nterritorial limits of the county, any plant, works, structures, poles,\nlines, wires, conduits, mains, systems, waterpower, franchises, and any\nand all other real and personal property, used, connected with or\nappertaining to the manufacture, conveying, transportation and\nfurnishing of gas, whether natural or manufactured or a mixture of both,\nfor light, heat and power and in the generation, furnishing and\ntransmission of electric current for light, heat and power, for the\npurpose of furnishing such service to the county and to any municipality\nor district and to persons in such district, including the state capitol\nand the branches, departments and offices of the state government; and\nalso, for such purpose, to purchase gas or electrical energy from the\nstate of New York, or from any state agency, or from any municipality\nwithin or outside of the county, or from any private or public\ncorporation.\n  * NB Terminated July 1, 1963\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>