<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1033"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1033"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1033"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1033/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1033/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1033/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1033/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1033">
        <num>1033</num>
        <heading>Power to contract with municipalities within district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1033. Power to contract with municipalities within district. The\nauthority shall also have power to contract with the governing body of\nany municipality within the district with a view to the construction,\nacquisition, maintenance and operation of any such service for or within\nsuch municipality and except in the case of towns when so authorized by\nthe board of supervisors it shall not have power to furnish any such\nservice within any municipality except by agreement with the governing\nbody thereof. In any such contract with a municipality the authority may\nagree with respect to the rates for services and any other matters\nnecessary or incidental to construction, acquisition, maintenance and\noperation therein. It may, if it seems to it necessary or proper,\nprovide for the collection of its revenue by the municipality and for an\naccounting between it and the municipality, and for compensation to the\nmunicipality for its services. It may likewise, with the approval of the\nboard of supervisors, agree upon a basis by which all or any part of its\nproperties, rights and interests in such municipality, including any\nproperties taken or held in the name of the county, may thereafter be\nacquired by and transferred to such municipality. In any agreement as to\nrates, the power shall be deemed to be reserved, whether or not\nexpressed, to charge adequate rates to properly operate and maintain any\nsuch service and to pay any bonds and other obligations of the\nauthority, including any obligation to the county under this title.\n  * NB Terminated July 1, 1963\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>