<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1036"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1036"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1036"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1036/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1036/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1036/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1036/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1036">
        <num>1036</num>
        <heading>Referendum</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1036. Referendum. No bonds shall be issued under this title by the\nauthority in an aggregate amount at any time outstanding exceeding ten\nmillion dollars. No such bonds shall be issued by the authority without\nthe approval of a majority of the electors of the district voting on the\nquestion of such approval. Such question may be submitted by the board\nof supervisors either at a general election or a special election called\nfor such purpose. The question submitted to the electors of the district\nshall be: "Shall the authority issue not exceeding (filling in the\namount) dollars bonds under the Albany Light, Heat and Power Authority\nAct?" If such proposition is adopted, the authority may issue bonds\nunder the power so given. The submission of such question and the\nconduct of and canvass of the votes cast at such election in the\ndistrict shall be provided for by the board of supervisors as nearly as\nmay be in accordance with the provisions of the election law. Notice of\nthe submission of such question and a general statement of the purposes\nto which the proceeds of the bonds are to be applied shall be published\nin the official newspapers of the county, designated by the board of\nsupervisors, once a week for six weeks immediately preceding such\nelection. At any time prior to the election at which such question is to\nbe submitted to the electors for approval, the board of supervisors may,\nnot later than fifteen days prior to such election, rescind its action\nin submitting the same whereupon such question shall not be submitted at\nsuch election, or, if submitted, the vote of the electors thereon shall\nbe without effect. Neither the submission of such question nor the\nvalidity or result of such election shall be questioned in any court or\nelsewhere except in an action or proceeding commenced not later than\ntwenty days after the determination of such result by the county board\nof canvassers has been filed in the office of the county board of\nelections.\n  * NB Terminated July 1, 1963\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>