<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1045-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1045_C">
        <num>1045-C</num>
        <heading>New York city municipal water finance authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1045-c. New York city municipal water finance authority. 1. A\ncorporation known as the New York city municipal water finance authority\nis hereby created for public purposes and charged with the duties and\nhaving the powers provided in this title. The authority shall be a body\ncorporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation. It\nshall be administered by a board of directors consisting of seven\nmembers as follows: the commissioner of environmental protection of the\ncity, the state commissioner of environmental conservation, the director\nof management and budget of the city, the commissioner of finance of the\ncity, two public members to be appointed by the mayor and one public\nmember to be appointed by the governor. One public member appointed by\nthe mayor shall serve for a term of one year, one public member\nappointed by the mayor shall serve for a term of two years, and the\npublic member appointed by the governor shall serve for a term of two\nyears from January first next succeeding the date of their appointment.\nTheir successors shall serve for terms of two years each. Members shall\ncontinue in office until their successors have been appointed and\nqualified. The mayor or the governor shall fill any vacancy which may\noccur by reason of death, resignation or otherwise in a manner\nconsistent with the original appointment. A public member may be removed\nby the mayor or the governor, whichever appointed him, for cause, but\nnot without an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel, in his\ndefense, upon not less than ten days' notice. The mayor shall select a\nchairman from among the directors appointed by him who shall serve in\nsuch capacity at his pleasure. The chairman shall preside over all\nmeetings of the board of directors and shall have such other duties as\nmay be prescribed by the board.\n  2. Each director who is a public member shall be entitled to\nreimbursement for his actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of his official duties and a per diem allowance of one\nhundred fifty dollars when rendering service as such director, provided\nthat the aggregate of such per diem allowance to any one director in any\none fiscal year of the authority shall not exceed the sum of five\nthousand dollars.\n  3. Such public members may engage in private employment, or in a\nprofession or business, subject to the limitations contained in sections\ntwenty-six hundred four, twenty-six hundred five, twenty-six hundred six\nand twenty-six hundred seven of the New York city charter for members\nappointed by the mayor, and subject to the limitations contained in\nsections seventy-three and seventy-four of the public officers law for\nmembers appointed by the governor. The authority shall, for the purposes\nof such sections be a "city agency" or a "state agency," as the case may\nbe and such directors shall be "officers" of the authority for the\npurposes of such sections.\n  4. Four directors of the authority of whom at least three members\nshall be ex officio shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any\nbusiness or the exercise of any power of the authority. Resolutions\nauthorizing the issuance of bonds or notes of the authority and\nresolutions authorizing any loan, lease, sale or other agreement in\nrespect to a water project shall be approved by not less than four\nmembers of the authority at a meeting duly called for such purposes at\nwhich a quorum is in attendance, but for the transaction of any other\nbusiness or the performance of any other power or function of the\nauthority, the authority may act by a majority of the members present at\nany meeting at which a quorum is in attendance. The authority may\ndelegate to one or more of its directors, or its officers, agents and\nemployees, such powers and duties as it may deem proper. The\ncommissioner of environmental protection of the city, the state\ncommissioner of environmental conservation, the director of management\nand budget of the city, and the commissioner of finance of the city may\neach, by written instrument, filed with and approved as to form by the\nauthority, designate a deputy or assistant in their respective\ndepartments or offices, to perform, in their absence, their respective\nduties under this title. The term "director" as used in this subdivision\nshall include such persons so designated as provided herein. The\ndesignation of such persons shall be deemed temporary only and shall not\naffect the civil service or retirement rights of any persons so\ndesignated.\n  5. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of this or any other\nlaw, general, special or local, or of any charter, no officer or\nemployee of the city or the state, shall be deemed to have forfeited or\nshall forfeit his office or employment or any benefits provided under\nthe retirement and social security law by reason of his acceptance of\nmembership on the authority, provided, however, that a director who\nholds such other public office or employment shall receive no additional\ncompensation for services rendered pursuant to this title, but shall be\nentitled to reimbursement for his actual and necessary expenses incurred\nin the performance of such services.\n  6. The authority and its corporate existence shall continue until\nterminated by law, provided, however, that no such law shall take effect\nso long as the authority shall have bonds or other obligations\noutstanding unless adequate provision has been made for the payment or\nsatisfaction thereof. Upon termination of the existence of the\nauthority, all of the rights and properties of the authority then\nremaining shall pass to and vest in the city except as otherwise may be\nspecified in such law.\n  7. It is hereby determined and declared that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers and duties are in all respects for the\nbenefit of the people of the city and the state for the improvement of\ntheir health, welfare and prosperity and that such purposes are public\npurposes and that the authority is and will be performing an essential\ngovernmental function in the exercise of the powers conferred upon it by\nthis title.\n  8. Nothing in this title shall be construed to obligate the state in\nany way in connection with the operations or obligations of the\nauthority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>