<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1045-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1045-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1045_N">
        <num>1045-N</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees to and from city and state agencies; retirement rights of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1045-n. Transfer of officers and employees to and from city and\nstate agencies; retirement rights of officers and employees.  Officers\nand employees of city and state agencies may be transferred to the\nauthority or water board and officers and employees of the authority or\nwater board may be transferred to appropriate city and state agencies\nwithout examination and without loss of any civil service or retirement\nstatus or rights. Any officer or employee of the authority or water\nboard who heretofore acquired or shall hereafter acquire such position\nstatus by transfer and who at the time of such transfer was a member of\nthe New York city employees' retirement system shall continue to be a\nmember of such system as long as he or she continues in such service,\nand shall continue to have all the rights, privileges and obligations of\nmembership in such system. Employment by the authority or water board\nshall constitute city-service for the purposes of chapter one of title\nthirteen of the administrative code of the city of New York. Transfers\nshall be in accordance with section seventy of the civil service law or\nthe rules of the civil service commission of the city, as the case may\nbe. No such transfer shall be made except with the approval of the head\nof the agency involved, the director of the division of the budget or\nthe director of management and budget of the city, as the case may be,\nand the chairman of the authority or water board, as applicable, and in\ncompliance with the rules and regulations of the civil service\ncommission of the city or the state, as the case may be.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>