<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1063"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1063"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1063"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1063/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1063/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1063/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1063/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1063">
        <num>1063</num>
        <heading>Exemption from taxes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1063. Exemption from taxes. 1. It is hereby determined that the\ncreation of the authority and the carrying out of its corporate purposes\nis in all respects for the benefit of the people of the county of Erie\nand its environs, and is a public purpose, and the authority shall be\nregarded as performing a governmental function in the exercise of the\npowers conferred upon it by this title and shall not be required to pay\nany taxes, special ad valorem levies or special assessments upon any\nproperty owned by it or under its jurisdiction, control or supervision\nor upon its activities, or any filing, recording or transfer taxes in\nrelation to instruments filed, recorded or transferred by it or on its\nbehalf.\n  2. Any bonds or notes issued pursuant to this title, together with the\nincome therefrom shall be exempt from taxation, except for transfer and\nestate taxes. The revenues, monies and other properties and the\nactivities of the authority shall be exempt from taxes and governmental\nfees or charges, whether imposed by the state or any municipality,\nincluding real estate taxes, franchise taxes or other excise taxes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>