<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1075"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1075"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1075"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1075/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1075/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1075/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1075/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1075">
        <num>1075</num>
        <heading>Statement of purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1075. Statement of purpose. Prior to the enactment of section five\nof article ten of the constitution (effective on January first, nineteen\nhundred thirty-nine) public benefit corporations could be created\npursuant to general law and chapter eight hundred forty-seven of the\nlaws of nineteen hundred thirty-four, as amended, authorized the\ncreation of county water authorities. On the twenty-ninth day of March,\nnineteen hundred thirty-seven, the board of supervisors of Suffolk\ncounty pursuant to such chapter created the Suffolk county water\nauthority, which since such date has been in continuous existence as a\nbody corporate and politic, constituting a public benefit corporation.\nThereafter the provisions of such chapter were reenacted and continued\nas article seven of the county law by chapter one hundred ninety-five of\nthe laws of nineteen hundred forty. The Suffolk county water authority\nis the only county water authority created pursuant to such chapter\neight hundred forty-seven of the laws of nineteen hundred thirty-four,\nas amended, or pursuant to such article seven of the county law. Since\nthe enactment of section five of article ten of the constitution public\nbenefit corporations may be created only by special act of the\nlegislature and, to the extent that the provisions of article seven of\nthe county law purport to authorize the creation of county water\nauthorities pursuant to its provisions subsequent to January first,\nnineteen hundred thirty-nine, such provisions of the county law are\nobsolete. The purpose of this title is to continue the existence of the\nSuffolk county water authority, to place the statutory provisions of law\napplicable thereto in the public authorities law where they\nappropriately belong, to provide for the powers and duties of the\nauthority, and to repeal the provisions of present article seven of the\ncounty law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>