<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1077"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1077"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1077"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1077/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1077/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1077/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1077/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1077">
        <num>1077</num>
        <heading>Suffolk county water authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1077. Suffolk county water authority. 1. The corporate existence of\nthe Suffolk county water authority, heretofore created pursuant to the\nprovisions of chapter eight hundred forty-seven of the laws of nineteen\nhundred thirty-four and thereafter continued pursuant to the provisions\nof article seven of the county law, is hereby continued for the purposes\nand charged with the duties and having the powers provided in this\ntitle. The authority shall be a body corporate and politic, constituting\na public benefit corporation. It shall consist of five members all of\nwhom shall be residents of the county of Suffolk. The present members of\nthe authority shall continue in office until the expiration of their\nseveral terms of office and the board of supervisors shall appoint two\nadditional members whose terms of office shall in the first instance be\nfixed by such board of supervisors in such manner and for such periods\nof time that the office of one member of the authority shall expire each\nyear. Their successors shall be appointed one member annually by the\ncounty board of supervisors for a term of five years. Vacancies in the\nmembership of such authority, other than by expiration of term, shall be\nfilled by the board of supervisors by appointment for the unexpired\nterm. The chairman in office at the effective date of this title shall\ncontinue in such office until the expiration of his term of office.\nThereafter the chairman of such authority shall be appointed by the\ncounty board of supervisors. The members of such authority shall receive\nsuch compensation for their services as shall be fixed by the board of\nsupervisors and shall be reimbursed for all necessary and actual\nexpenses incurred in connection with their duties as such members and in\nconnection with the carrying out of the purposes of this title. The\npower of such authority shall be vested in and exercised by a majority\nof the members of the authority then in office. Said authority may\ndelegate to one or more of its members, or its agents, or employees,\nsuch powers and duties as it may deem proper. The corporate existence of\nsuch authority shall continue until its liabilities have been met and\nits bonds have been paid in full. Upon ceasing to exist, all its rights\nand property shall pass to the county of Suffolk.\n  2. Neither the public service commission nor any other board or\ncommission of like character, shall have jurisdiction over the authority\nin the management and control of its properties or operations or any\npower over the regulation of rates fixed or charges collected by the\nauthority.\n  3. It is hereby determined and declared that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers, purposes and duties are in all respects for\nthe benefit of the people of the county of Suffolk and the state of New\nYork, for the improvement of their health, welfare and prosperity and\nthat the said purposes are public purposes and that the authority is and\nwill be performing an essential governmental function in the exercise of\nthe powers conferred upon it by this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>