<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1078-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1078_D">
        <num>1078-D</num>
        <heading>Additional powers of the county of Suffolk and towns and villages within Suffolk county</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1078-d. Additional powers of the county of Suffolk and towns and\nvillages within Suffolk county. 1. a. In addition to any powers granted\nby any general or special law, the board of supervisors of the county of\nSuffolk, acting on behalf of the county, and any town board or village\nboard of trustees of any town or village within the county of Suffolk,\nacting on behalf of such town or village, either separately or pursuant\nto agreements among themselves, may, from time to time, appropriate by\nresolution sums of money to defray costs and expenses of the authority\nassociated with the extension of authority mains to areas in the county\nwithin which the county department of health services has documented\nthat private wells providing water to home owners have become\ncontaminated with pollutants in concentrations greater than recommended\nby any drinking water guidelines or standard established by the federal\ngovernment or this state, and may enter into a contract or contracts\nwith the authority to so extend authority mains.\n  b. In areas of documented groundwater contamination where potable\nwater may be more economically supplied by a municipal water authority,\nspecial district or improvement area established to provide a water\nimprovement, or by a village, than by the Suffolk county water\nauthority, the county board of supervisors and any town board or village\nboard of trustees within Suffolk county may appropriate sums of money to\nsaid municipal water authority, special district or improvement area or\nvillage, and enter into a contract or contracts, in accordance with this\nsubdivision.\n  2. Persons wishing to connect to mains that have been extended to\nareas of documented groundwater contamination with financial assistance\nby the county, or any town or village as provided herein, shall be\nsolely responsible for costs and expenses associated with connecting to\nsaid mains.\n  3. Appropriations of money by the county board of supervisors and any\ntown board or village board of trustees in the county of Suffolk to the\nauthority or to a municipal water authority, special district or\nimprovement area or village within Suffolk county, and any contract or\ncontracts entered into with said authority or municipal water authority,\nspecial district or improvement area or village prior to the effective\ndate of this section that are consistent with the authorization in\nsubdivision one of this section are hereby legalized, validated,\nratified and confirmed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>