<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1078"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1078/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1078">
        <num>1078</num>
        <heading>Powers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1078__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To purchase, in the name of the authority, any water supply\nsystem, water distribution system, including plants, works,\ninstrumentalities or parts thereof and appurtenances thereto, lands,\neasements, rights in land and water rights, rights-of-way, contract\nrights, franchises, approaches, connections, dams, reservoirs, water\nmains and pipe lines, pumping stations and equipment, or any other\nproperty incidental to and included in such system or part thereof, and\nany improvements, extensions and betterments, situated wholly within the\ncounty for the purpose of supplying water for domestic, commercial and\npublic purposes at retail to individual consumers within the county of\nSuffolk or at wholesale in the manner provided by subdivision seven of\nthis section as a means of so acquiring for such purposes, and subject\nto the approval of the public service commission, the authority may\npurchase all of the stock of any existing privately owned water\ncorporation or company, and thereafter, within a reasonable time, such\nwater corporation or company shall be dissolved.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1078__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To condemn in the name of the authority, except where located in\nanother county, any water supply system, water distribution system,\nincluding plants, works, instrumentalities, or parts thereof and\nappurtenances thereto, lands, easements, rights in land and water\nrights, rights-of-way, contract rights, franchises, approaches,\nconnections, dams, reservoirs, water mains and pipe lines, pumping\nstations and equipment, or any other property incidental to and included\nin such system or part thereof, and any improvements, extensions and\nbetterments for the purpose of supplying water for domestic, commercial\nand public purposes at retail to individual consumers within the county\nof Suffolk or at wholesale in the manner provided by subdivision seven\nof this section. The authority shall exercise the power of condemnation\nhereby granted in the manner provided either by the condemnation law or\nby the Suffolk county improvement act. In the exercise of such power of\ncondemnation, the property being condemned shall be deemed, when so\ndetermined by the authority, to be for a public use superior to the\npublic use in the hands of any other person, association, or\ncorporation, provided, however, that the authority shall have no power\nto condemn property the legal title to which is vested in a municipality\nunless such municipality shall consent thereto.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1078__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To construct, develop and operate any water supply system, water\ndistribution system, including plants, works, instrumentalities, or\nparts thereof, and appurtenances thereto, dams, reservoirs, water mains,\npipe lines, pumping stations and equipment, or any other property\nincidental to or included in such system or part thereof within the\ncounty of Suffolk, and to acquire, by condemnation in the manner\nprovided by this title, or by purchase, lands, easements, rights in land\nand water rights and rights-of-way in connection therewith within such\ncounty; and to own and operate, maintain, repair, improve, reconstruct,\nenlarge and extend, subject to the provisions of this title, any of its\nproperties acquired or constructed under this title, all of which,\ntogether with the acquisition of such properties are hereby declared to\nbe public purposes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1078__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To acquire, hold, use, lease, sell, transfer and dispose of any\nproperty, real, personal or mixed, or interest therein, for its\ncorporate purposes.\n  5. To purchase water in bulk from any person, private corporation or\nmunicipality when necessary or convenient for the operation of such\nwater supply and distribution system. To sell water in bulk to any\nnot-for-profit corporation, public corporation, private corporation or\nperson at its regular retail rates.\n  6. To fix, alter, charge and collect rates and other charges for the\nuse of water by the inhabitants of the county or other consumers\nthereof, at reasonable rates to be determined by the authority for the\npurpose of providing for the payment of the expenses of the authority,\nthe construction, improvement, repair, maintenance and operation of the\nwater supply and distribution system of the authority, the payment of\nthe principal of and interest on the obligations of the authority, and\nto fulfill the terms and provisions of any agreements made with the\npurchasers or holders of any such obligations.\n  7. To sell water by volume to any or all municipalities or privately\nowned public water supply and distribution systems in such county. The\nfact that any municipality has procured or is about to procure an\nindependent source of water supply shall not prevent such municipality\nfrom purchasing water from the authority. Subject to the approval of the\nboard of supervisors of Suffolk county to sell any water not needed in\nsuch county to any municipality or privately owned public water supply\nand distribution system outside of the county in which created. Not only\nmay the authority sell any surplus water it may have developed, but it\nmay, with the consent of such board of supervisors, develop and provide\na sufficient amount of water so as to supply water outside of the county\nto any municipality or privately owned public water supply and\ndistribution system.\n  8. To make contracts and execute a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>