<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1079"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1079"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1079"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1079/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1079/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1079/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1079/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1079">
        <num>1079</num>
        <heading>Survey of water resources</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1079. Survey of water resources. The board of supervisors of Suffolk\ncounty may, by resolution, appropriate a sum of money to defray the\npreliminary expenses of such authority so created and may thereafter\nappropriate such sums as may be required, for the purpose of making a\nsurvey of the water resources of the said county, and the preparation of\na map or plan for the development thereof. The authority shall, as soon\nas possible, make a survey of the water resources of the county, and\nprepare a map and plan for the development of the same showing in detail\nthe proposed sources of water to be developed, and the municipalities\nand areas which may be served thereby. Application for approval of the\nproject shall then be made to the water power and control commission as\nprovided by article eleven of the conservation law. If so approved, the\nauthority shall enter into such contracts or agreements as may be\nnecessary to carry out the plan of such development. The authority may,\nhowever, acquire by purchase or condemnation any existing water supply\nand distribution system without making such survey and except as to\nproperties to be acquired under condemnation proceedings instituted\nprior to February first, nineteen hundred fifty-two after first\nobtaining the approval of the board of supervisors of the county,\nprovided, however, that the authority shall not acquire any existing\nwater supply and distribution system owned by a municipality unless the\ngoverning board thereof shall adopt a resolution requesting the\nauthority to make such acquisition.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>