<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1096-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1096-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1096-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1096-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1096-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1096-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1096-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1096_A">
        <num>1096-A</num>
        <heading>Additional duties of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1096-a. Additional duties of the authority. 1. The authority shall\nsubmit to the president of the Monroe county legislature a copy of the\nauthority's preliminary budget, annual budget or amended budget,\ncertified by the treasurer of the authority, not later than thirty days\nprior to the date on which the annual budget is adopted or approved by\nthe authority. The authority shall give notice in writing to the\npresident of the Monroe county legislature not later than thirty days\nprior to anticipated final approval of any construction projects to be\nundertaken by the authority involving water mains in excess of twelve\ninches in size, construction of mains in geographical areas theretofore\nundeveloped or not supplied with a public water supply, storage\nfacilities, pumping stations or water treatment facilities utilizing\nfunds of either the authority or funds of the county of Monroe under\nsubdivision sixteen-b of section one thousand ninety-six of this title\nprovided, however, that the foregoing shall not in any event be deemed\nto include: modernization, renewal and replacement, repair, maintenance\nof or improvement in properties or facilities; preliminary undertakings\nsuch as studies, tests, evaluations, reports, preparation of engineering\nplans and specifications, obtaining property rights and obtaining of\nnecessary governmental approvals; construction activities deemed\nnecessary by the authority in an emergency to protect life, property,\nhealth or the public safety; changes during construction which do not\nmaterially change the essential service area affected by a project; and\nconstruction activities within the terms of the last sentence of this\nsubdivision. In the event the Monroe county legislature, by its\nresolution adopted at any time within sixty days after receipt by the\npresident of the county legislature of the notice from the authority\nherein provided for, requests any change in such project, the authority\nshall conduct a public informational meeting upon ten days' notice to be\npublished twice consecutively in a newspaper of general circulation in\nthe county of Monroe prior to the authority granting final approval or\nprior to the commencement of construction of such project. The authority\nshall give written notice to the president of the Monroe county\nlegislature not less than thirty days prior to the date of any final\naction of the authority with respect to any change in the rates of the\nauthority. The authority shall conduct a public informational meeting\nupon ten days' notice to be published twice consecutively in a newspaper\nof general circulation in the county of Monroe relative to any change in\nsuch rates prior to the effective date of such change. The foregoing\nprovisions of this subdivision shall not be construed to or require the\nauthority to in any way violate or impair the rights and remedies of or\ncovenants with the holders of obligations of the authority pursuant to\nany resolution or trust indenture of or binding upon the authority\nadopted or executed authorizing or securing obligations of the authority\nor abrogate the rights and powers of the authority to fulfill its duties\nand obligations to comply with all the terms, covenants or requirements\nrequired or provided by any existing contractual agreement or provided\nor required by statute or the order or direction or approval of a\nfederal, state or local governmental entity having appropriate\njurisdiction or authority.\n  2. The authority shall be empowered to develop and adopt an\nadministrative code, subject to amendment from time to time, concerning\nsuch cooperative interrelationships between the authority and the county\nof Monroe, including the duties of the authority under subdivision one\nof this section. Any such code, or any amendment thereto, shall be\nsubmitted to the president of the county legislature not less than\nninety days prior to its adoption by the authority for approval by such\nlegislature.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>