<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1126"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1126"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1126"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1126/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1126/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1126/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1126/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1126">
        <num>1126</num>
        <heading>Advances on behalf of the authority; transfer of property to authority; acquisition of property by town for authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1126. Advances on behalf of the authority; transfer of property to\nauthority; acquisition of property by town for authority. 1. In addition\nto any powers granted to it by law, the town, from time to time, may\nappropriate sums of money to or on behalf of the authority to defray\nproject costs or any other costs and expenses of the authority. Subject\nto the rights of bondholders, the town may determine if the moneys so\nappropriated shall be subject to repayment by the authority to the town\nand, in such event, the manner and time or times for such repayment.\n  2. The town or any other municipality may give, grant, sell, convey,\nloan, license the use of or lease to the authority any property or\nfacility which is useful to the authority in order to carry out its\npowers under this title. Any such transfer of property shall be upon\nsuch terms and conditions, subject to the rights of the holders of any\nbonds, as the authority and the town or other municipality may agree.\n  3. The town may acquire by purchase or by exercise of the power of\neminent domain real property in the name of the town for any corporate\npurpose of the authority.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, general, special\nor local to the contrary, real property acquired by the authority or the\ntown from the state may be used for any corporate purpose of the\nauthority.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1126's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>