<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1139*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1139*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1139*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1139*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1139*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1139*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1139*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1139*2">
        <num>1139*2</num>
        <heading>Audit, annual report and information</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1139. Audit, annual report and information. In conformity with the\nprovisions of section five of article ten of the constitution, the\naccounts of the authority shall be subject to the supervision of the\ncomptroller. The authority shall annually submit to the governor and\ncomptroller and to the state legislature a detailed report pursuant to\nthe provisions of section two thousand five hundred of title one of\narticle nine of this chapter, and a copy of such report shall be filed\nwith both the county executive and with the county legislature. The\nauthority shall comply with the provisions of sections two thousand five\nhundred one, two thousand five hundred two and two thousand five hundred\nthree of title one of article nine of this chapter.\n  The county executive and the chairman of the county legislature may\neach designate a representative to act as a liaison to the authority.\nEach such liaison shall have the right to attend all meetings of the\nauthority and request, from time to time, such information as the\nliaison may deem reasonably necessary for the purpose of informing the\ncounty executive and the county legislature, respectively, of the\nactivities of the authority.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1139's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>