<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1141*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1141*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1141*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1141*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1141*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1141*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1141*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1141*2">
        <num>1141*2</num>
        <heading>Environmental applications, proceedings, approvals and permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1141. Environmental applications, proceedings, approvals and\npermits. 1. Any application in relation to the purposes of or\ncontemplated by this title heretofore filed, or any proceeding\nheretofore commenced, or any determination or decision heretofore made\nby the county, any municipality within the county or any water district,\nsewer district or district corporation and sent to or filed with the\nstate department of environmental conservation, the department of\ntransportation or any other state agency or instrumentality or with the\nUnited States environmental protection agency or any other federal\nagency or instrumentality shall inure to and for the benefit of the\nauthority to the same extent and in the same manner as if the authority\nhad been a party to such application or proceeding from its inception,\nand the authority shall be deemed a party thereto, to the extent not\nprohibited by any federal law. Any license, approval, permit or decision\nheretofore or hereafter issued or granted pursuant to or as a result of\nany such application or proceeding shall inure to the benefit of and be\nbinding upon the authority and shall be assigned and transferred by the\ncounty or any such municipality to the authority, unless such assignment\nand transfer is prohibited by federal law.\n  2. All such applications, proceedings, licenses, approvals, permits\nand decisions shall further inure to and for the benefit of and be\nbinding upon any person leasing, acquiring, constructing, maintaining,\nusing or occupying any facility financed in whole or in part by the\nauthority.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1141's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>