<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1147-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1147-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1147-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1147-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1147-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1147-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1147-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1147_C">
        <num>1147-C</num>
        <heading>Sewer authority created</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Chairperson. The chairperson shall be the chief executive officer\nof the authority and it shall be the responsibility of the chairperson\nto:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>preside at all meetings of the board of directors and of the\nofficers;\n  (ii) manage the facilities, projects and construction of the authority\nand to effectuate the decisions of the board of directors;\n  (iii) exercise supervision over the conduct of the officers and\nemployees of the authority;\n  (iv) report annually to the residents and businesses within the bounds\nof the authority by publication once in a newspaper having general\ncirculation within the district that a report has been filed in the\noffice of the authority and in the offices of the clerks of the towns of\nAlfred, Almond and Hornellsville and the village of Almond and is\navailable for public inspection; such report shall include but not be\nlimited to the following:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a brief financial account on operations of the sewer system\nincluding, but not limited to, sewer rates, total revenues and sources\nof such revenues, operating and maintenance expenses, outstanding\nindebtedness and interest on bonds and notes;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the number of users of the sewer system by classification in the\nevent users are classified;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the extensions made of the system in the previous year, if any;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any actions taken to make any capital improvements to the system\nincluding any extension of the system;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the types of treatment to which the sewage is subjected before\nleaving the treatment plant or plants;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any compliance activities required by regulations of the\ndepartment of environmental conservation or the department of health or\nany local health department and any instances of noncompliance;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the present condition of the sewer system and any appurtenances\nthereto and any significant actions, as determined by the authority, to\nimprove, extend or maintain the system;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>any special public services the authority provides during the\nyear;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>execute all contracts in the name of the authority;\n  (vi) institute, at the direction of the board of directors, all civil\nactions in the name of the authority;\n  (vii) provide for the enforcement of all rules and regulations of the\nauthority and cause all violations thereof to be prosecuted;\n  (viii) sign orders to pay claims when authorized by the board of\ndirectors;\n  (ix) sign checks in the absence or inability of the treasurer or\ndeputy treasurer, if any, when authorized by the board of directors; and\na certified copy of the resolution of the board of directors to that\neffect shall be notice to the depository of such authorization;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_x">
          <num>(x)</num>
          <content>
            <p>appoint, subject to the approval of the board of directors,\nnon-elected officers, counsel, accountants and other financial advisors,\nengineers and other technical advisors;\n  (xi) employ, promote and discharge managers, supervisors and\nemployees; and\n  (xii) take all other reasonable and necessary actions to carry out his\nor her office as the chief executive officer of the authority. If the\nchairperson has not been appointed as a member of the board of directors\nof the authority pursuant to this section, such chairperson shall be\ndeemed an ex officio member of the board of directors. Such status shall\nnot carry with it the right to vote on matters coming before the board\nof directors nor shall the presence of such chairperson be counted for\nthe purpose of determining a quorum.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Secretary.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The secretary shall be the recording and\ncorresponding officer of the authority and the custodian of the records\nof the authority.\n  (ii) The secretary shall prepare and send required notices of all\nmeetings when directed to do so by the chairperson or by the written\nrequest of four members who have specified the issues to be discussed at\nthe meeting.\n  (iii) In the absence or disability of the secretary, the chairperson\nmay appoint a temporary secretary.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Treasurer.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The treasurer shall have custody of all moneys\nbelonging to the authority and keep accounts of all receipts and\nexpenditures in conformance with a uniform system of accounts formulated\nand prescribed by the comptroller pursuant to section thirty-six of the\ngeneral municipal law.\n  (ii) The treasurer shall execute a bond, conditioned upon the faithful\nperformance of the duties of his or her office, the amount and\nsufficiency of which shall be approved by the board of directors and the\npremium therefor shall be paid by the authority.\n  (iii) The treasurer shall deposit within ten days after receipt\nthereof, in the name of the authority, in one or more banks, and/or\ntrust companies, designated by the board of directors, all moneys\nreceived by him or her.\n  (iv) The treasurer may sign checks with the facsimile signature of the\ntreasurer, as reproduced by a machine or device, when approved and\nauthorized by the board of directors.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The treasurer shall pay out moneys from the authority treasury\nonly as authorized by the board of directors and by law. All such\npayments, except as may be authorized by the board of directors for a\npetty cash account, shall be by check.\n  (vi) The treasurer shall issue a report on the finances of the\nauthority at each regular meeting of the board of directors.\n  (vii) The treasurer shall file in the office of the authority, within\nsixty days after the end of the fiscal year, a statement showing in\ndetail all revenues and expenditures during the previous fiscal year and\nthe outstanding indebtedness of the authority as of the end of the\nfiscal year. The members shall within ten days cause to be published\nonce in a newspaper having general circulation within the district, a\nnotice that the financial statement has been filed and is available for\ninspection or a summary of such statement in a form approved by the\ncomptroller, with an endorsement thereon that details thereof are on\nfile in the office of the authority.\n  6. The officers of the authority, other than members of the board of\ndirectors, shall receive such compensation as may be determined by the\nboard of directors and shall be reimbursed for all necessary and actual\nexpenses incurred in connection with their duties as such officers and\nin connection with carrying out the purposes of this title.\n  7. In addition to any powers granted to it by law, the governing body\nof each of the towns and of the village wholly or partially within the\nbounds of the authority, from time to time, may appropriate sums of\nmoney to defray project costs or any other costs and expenses of the\nauthority. Subject to the rights of bondholders, each governing body may\ndetermine if the moneys so appropriated shall be subject to repayment by\nthe authority to such towns and such village, and in such event, the\nmanner and time for such repayment.\n  8. It is hereby determined and declared that the authority and t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The mayor of the village of Almond and the supervisors of the\ntowns of Alfred, Almond and Hornellsville shall each, pursuant to the\nauthority granted to them by their respective governing boards, file on\nor before March thirty-first of the year following the year in which\nthis title shall take effect, in the office of the secretary of state, a\ncertificate signed by such mayor or supervisor setting forth: the name\nof the authority; the names of the members of the authority appointed by\nthe mayor of that village or by the town board of that town; and the\neffective date of the authority. The authority shall be perpetual in\nduration, except that if any such certificate is not filed with the\nsecretary of state on or before such date, then the corporate existence\nof the authority shall thereupon terminate and shall thereupon be deemed\nto be and shall be dissolved.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1147_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the\nauthority and its corporate existence shall continue until terminated by\nlaw, provided, however, that no such law shall take effect so long as\nthe authority shall have bonds or other obligations outstanding unless\nadequate provision has been made for the payment or satisfaction\nthereof. Upon termination of the authority, all facilities, rights and\nproperty shall be disposed of as shall be agreed upon by all of the\nmembers of the authority. In the event no such agreement can be reached,\nthe issue of the disposition of such facilities, rights and property\nshall be submitted to arbitration in the manner provided by article\nseventy-five of the civil practice law and rules.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>