<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1149-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1149-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-11-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1149-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1149-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1149-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1149-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1149-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1149_F">
        <num>1149-F</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1149-f. Transfer of officers and employees. Any officer or employee\nunder civil service who is selected by the authority and may be\ntransferred to the authority and shall be eligible for such transfer and\nappointment without examination to comparable offices, positions and\nemployment under the authority.\n  The salary or compensation of any such officer or employee, as\ndetermined by the authority, shall after such transfer be paid by the\nauthority.\n  Any such officers or employees so transferred to the authority\npursuant to this section, who are members of or beneficiaries under any\nexisting pension or retirement fund or system, shall continue to have\nall rights, privileges, obligations and status with respect to such fund\nor system as are now prescribed by law, but during the period of their\nemployment by the authority, all contributions to such funds or systems\nto be paid by the employer on account of such officers or employees\nshall be paid by the authority.\n  All such officers and employees so transferred to the authority who\nhave been appointed to positions under the rules and classifications of\nthe civil service commission shall have the same status with respect\nthereto after transfer to the authority as they had under their original\nappointments. The appointment and promotion of all employees of the\nauthority shall be made in accordance with the provisions of the civil\nservice law and such rules as the civil service commission may adopt and\nmake applicable to the authority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>