<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1174-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1174-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1174-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1174-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1174-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1174-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1174-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1174_C">
        <num>1174-C</num>
        <heading>Water authority of Southeastern Nassau county district</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1174-c. Water authority of Southeastern Nassau county district.  1.\nThere is hereby created a district to be known as the "water authority\nof Southeastern Nassau county district" which shall be defined as all\nthat portion of Nassau county serviced by the New York Water service\ncorporation as of January first, nineteen hundred ninety-one.\n  2. If the authority decides to enter into a contract to purchase or\notherwise acquire an interest in the New York Water Service Corporation\nor to initiate a condemnation proceeding pursuant to the eminent domain\nprocedure law, prior to entering into any contract to purchase or\notherwise acquire an interest in the New York Water Service Corporation\nor the initiation of any condemnation proceeding by the authority\npursuant to the eminent domain procedure law the authority shall provide\nratepayers within the area serviced by the New York Water Service\nCorporation and the public with public forums for the expression and\ndiscussion of views regarding such purchase, acquisition or condemnation\nof the New York Water Service Corporation. The authority shall hold at\nleast one forum in each of the towns of Hempstead and Oyster Bay within\nthe portions of the towns of Hempstead and Oyster Bay serviced by the\nNew York Water Service Corporation.\n  3. If the authority decides to enter into a contract to purchase or\notherwise acquire an interest in the New York Water Service Corporation\nor to initiate a condemnation proceeding pursuant to the eminent domain\nprocedure law, the authority is authorized to provide registered voters\nwithin the area serviced by the New York Water Service Corporation prior\nto entering into such contract to purchase or otherwise acquire an\ninterest in the New York Water Service Corporation or the initiation of\nany condemnation proceeding by the authority pursuant to the eminent\ndomain procedure law, with a nonbinding referendum, regarding whether\nthe authority should enter into a contract to purchase or otherwise\nacquire an interest in the New York Water Service Corporation or\ninitiate condemnation proceeding pursuant to the eminent domain\nprocedure law. The proposition shall be placed on the ballot and voted\nupon at a special election or a date to be determined by the Nassau\ncounty board of elections.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>