<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1179"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1179"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1179"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1179/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1179/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1179">
        <num>1179</num>
        <heading>Transfer to authority of city sewer system</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1179. Transfer to authority of city sewer system. Upon the filing by\nthe authority with the common council of the city and the secretary of\nstate of the state of New York, of its certificate signed by its\nchairman or vice-chairman stating that the project has been completed,\nthereupon, and by virtue of this title, the existing sewer system,\ntogether with all contracts, books, maps, plans, papers and records of\nwhatever description pertaining to subjects or matters relating to the\ndesign, construction, operation and affairs of the existing sewer system\nshall be assigned, transferred and dedicated to the use of and be in the\npossession of and under the jurisdiction, control and supervision of the\nauthority and the authority is empowered to take possession thereof for\nits uses and purposes. The authority shall thereafter have complete\njurisdiction, control, possession and supervision of the existing sewer\nsystem and of all the facilities in the city for the disposal of sewage\nand storm water, and shall continue to exercise such power for a period\nof five years and so long thereafter as any of the bonds and liabilities\nof the authority shall remain unpaid or shall not have otherwise been\ndischarged. When all of the bonds and liabilities of the authority shall\nhave been paid in full or shall have otherwise been discharged and the\nauthority shall have ceased to exist, the powers, jurisdiction and duty\nof the board shall cease and the property and assets acquired or held by\nit shall thereafter become the property of, and shall be under the\njurisdiction, control, possession and supervision of, the city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>