<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-DD*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-DD*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1199-DD*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-DD*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-DD*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-DD*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-DD*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1199_DD*2">
        <num>1199-DD*2</num>
        <heading>Orange county water authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1199_DD*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The county executive shall file on or before December\nthirty-first in the year in which this title shall have become a law, in\nthe office of the secretary of state, a certificate signed by the county\nexecutive setting forth:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1199_DD*2__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the name of the authority; (ii) the names\nof the members appointed by the county executive and confirmed by the\ncounty legislature and their terms of office; and (iii) the effective\ndate of this title. If such certificate is not filed with the secretary\nof state on or before such date, then the corporate existence of the\nauthority shall thereupon terminate and it shall thereupon be deemed to\nbe and shall be dissolved.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1199_DD*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority and its corporate existence shall continue until\nterminated by law, provided, however, that no such law shall take effect\nso long as the authority shall have bonds or other obligations\noutstanding unless adequate provision has been made for the payment or\nsatisfaction thereof. Upon termination of the existence of the\nauthority, all of the rights and properties of the authority then\nremaining shall pass to and vest in the county.\n  5. It is hereby determined and declared, that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers and duties are in all respects for the\nbenefit of the people of the county and the state for the improvement of\ntheir health, welfare and prosperity and that such purposes are public\npurposes and that the authority is and will be performing an essential\ngovernmental function in the exercise of the powers conferred upon it by\nthis title.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1199-dd's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>