<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-FFFF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-FFFF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1199-FFFF"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-FFFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-FFFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-FFFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-FFFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1199_FFFF">
        <num>1199-FFFF</num>
        <heading>Advances on behalf of the authority; transfer of property to the authority; acquisition of property by county for authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1199-ffff. Advances on behalf of the authority; transfer of\nproperty to the authority; acquisition of property by county for\nauthority. 1. In addition to any powers granted to it by law, the county\nfrom time to time may appropriate sums of money, after approval by the\ncounty legislature, to or on behalf of the authority to defray project\ncosts or any other costs and expenses of the authority. Subject to the\nrights of bondholders, the county may determine if the moneys so\nappropriated shall be subject to repayment by the authority to the\ncounty and, in such event, the manner and time or times for such\nrepayment.\n  2. The county or any other municipality may give, grant, sell, convey,\nloan, license the use of or lease to the authority any property or\nfacility which is useful to the authority in order to carry out its\npowers under this title. Any such transfer of property shall be upon\nsuch terms and conditions, subject to the rights of the holders of any\nbonds, as the authority and the county or other municipality may agree.\n  3. The county may acquire by purchase or by exercise of the power of\neminent domain real property in the name of the county for any corporate\npurpose of the authority.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, general, special\nor local to the contrary, real property acquired by the authority or the\ncounty from the state may be used for any corporate purpose of the\nauthority.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1199-ffff's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>