<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-UU*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-UU*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1199-UU*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-UU*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-UU*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-UU*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-UU*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1199_UU*2">
        <num>1199-UU*2</num>
        <heading>Environmental applications, proceedings, approvals and permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1199-uu. Environmental applications, proceedings, approvals and\npermits. 1. Any application in relation to the purposes of or\ncontemplated by this title heretofore filed, or any proceeding\nheretofore commenced, by the county with the department of environmental\nconservation, the department of transportation or any other state agency\nor instrumentality or with the United States environmental protection\nagency or any other federal agency or instrumentality shall inure to and\nfor the benefit of the authority to the same extent and in the same\nmanner as if the authority had been a party to such application or\nproceeding from its inception, and the authority shall be deemed a party\nthereto, to the extent not prohibited by any federal law. Any license,\napproval, permit or decision heretofore or hereafter issued or granted\npursuant to or as a result of any such application or proceeding shall\ninure to the benefit of and be binding upon the authority and shall be\nassigned and transferred by the county to the authority, unless such\nassignment and transfer is prohibited by federal law.\n  2. All such applications, proceedings, licenses, approvals, permits\nand decisions shall further inure to and for the benefit of and be\nbinding upon any person leasing, acquiring, constructing, maintaining,\nusing or occupying any facility financed in whole or in part by the\nauthority.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1199-uu's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>