<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-GG"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-GG"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1199-GG"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1199_GG">
        <num>1199-GG</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1199-gg. Transfer of officers and employees. Any public officer or\nemployee under civil service who is selected by the authority may, with\nthe consent of the commission, board, department or municipality by\nwhich he or she has been employed, be transferred to the authority and\nshall be eligible for such transfer and appointment without examination\nto comparable offices, positions and employment under the authority. The\nsalary or compensation of any such officer or employee shall after such\ntransfer be paid by the authority. Any such officers or employees so\ntransferred to the authority, pursuant to the provisions of this\nsection, who are members of or beneficiaries under any existing pension\nor retirement fund or system, shall continue to have all rights,\nprivileges, obligations and status with respect to such fund or system\nas are now prescribed by law, but during the period of their employment\nby the authority, all contributions to any such fund or system to be\npaid by the employer on account of such officers and employees, shall be\npaid by the authority. All such officers and employees so transferred to\nthe authority who have been appointed to positions under the rules and\nclassifications of the civil service commission shall have the same\nstatus with respect thereto after transfer to the authority as they had\nunder their original appointments. The appointment and promotion of all\nemployees of the authority shall be made in accordance with the\nprovisions of the civil service law and such rules as the civil service\ncommission may adopt and make applicable to the authority.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1199-gg's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>