<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-XXXX"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-XXXX"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1199-XXXX"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-XXXX/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-XXXX/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-XXXX/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1199-XXXX/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1199_XXXX">
        <num>1199-XXXX</num>
        <heading>Charges by the authority; method of collection</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1199-xxxx. Charges by the authority; method of collection. 1. The\nauthority may fix and collect, on any equitable basis, rates, fees and\nother charges for the use of its water or sewer facilities or of the\nservices or commodities provided by the authority. Such rates, rentals,\nfees and other charges may be fixed and collected from any person or\ncorporation to which such facilities, services or commodities are\nprovided or made available from the authority. Such rates, rentals, fees\nand other charges may be the same or different for each classification\nof user or service recipient and may, by way of example, reflect the\nsource and composition of the sewage or location of services or system\ncosts and expenses. The authority shall not establish, fix or revise any\nclassification or user or rate, rental or fee or other charge unless and\nuntil the authority has held a public hearing at which interested\npersons shall have an opportunity to be heard concerning the same.\nNotice of any such public hearing shall be published at least ten days\nbefore the date set therefor, in at least one newspaper of general\ncirculation in the boundaries of the authority. Such notice shall set\nforth the date, time and place of such hearing and shall include a brief\ndescription of matters to be considered at such meeting. A copy of such\nnotice shall be available for inspection by the public. At any such\nhearing, any interested persons shall have an opportunity to be heard\nconcerning the matters under consideration. Any decision by the\nauthority at such public hearing or relating to the matters under\nconsideration at such hearing shall be in writing and made available in\nthe office of the authority for public inspection during regular\nbusiness hours.\n  2. All rates, fees and other charges for the use of the facilities or\nservices or commodities provided or made available by the authority and\nbilled directly by the authority to the user or service recipient\npursuant to a classification of users or service recipients adopted by\nthe authority as herein provided shall be a lien upon the real property\nupon which, or in connection with which, services are provided or are\nmade available, as and from the first date fixed for a payment of such\nrates, rentals, fees and other charges. Any such lien shall take\nprecedent over all other liens, or encumbrances, except taxes or\nassessments. The treasurer of the authority shall prepare and transmit\nto the county legislature, on or before the first day of November in\neach year, a list of those properties using such facilities or for which\nsuch services or commodities were provided or made available and from\nwhich the payment of rates, rentals, fees and other charges are in\narrears for a period of thirty days or more after the last day fixed for\npayment of such rates, rentals, fees and other charges without penalty.\nThe list shall contain a brief description of such properties, the names\nof the persons or corporations liable to pay for the same, and the\namount chargeable to each, including penalties and interest, as\napplicable, computed to December thirty-first of that year. The county\nlegislature shall levy such sums against the properties liable and shall\nstate the amount thereof in a separate column in the annual tax rolls of\nthe county under the heading "water charge" or "sewer disposal charge,"\nas applicable. Such amounts, excluding penalties and interest when\ncollected by the county collector or receiver of taxes, shall be paid\nover to the treasurer of the authority. Penalties and interest shall be\nretained by the collector which shall become a part of the general funds\nof the county. All of the provisions of the tax law of the state\ngoverning enforcement and collection of unpaid taxes or assessments for\nspecial improvements not inconsistent herewith shall apply to the\ncollection of such unpaid rates, rentals, fees and other charges.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง1199-xxxx's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>