<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1200"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1200"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1200"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1200/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1200/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1200">
        <num>1200</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1200. Definitions. Unless expressly otherwise provided, whenever\nused in this title, the following terms shall mean or include:  1.\n"Authority." The corporation created by section eighteen hundred one of\nthis title.\n  2. "Board." The members of the authority.\n  3. "Board of estimate." The board of estimate of the city.\n  4. "City." The city of New York.\n  5. "Comptroller." The comptroller of the city.\n  6. "Devices and appurtenances." Devices and appurtenances deemed\nnecessary by the authority, to secure the greatest efficiency, public\nconvenience and safety, including the number, location, description and\nplans and specifications for the stations, suitable supports, turnouts,\nswitches, sidings, connections, landing places, garages, repair shops,\nbuildings, structures, platforms, stairways, elevators, telephone,\ntelegraph and signal devices, facilities for access to the surface, and\nother suitable appliances incidental and requisite to what such\nauthority may approve as the best and most efficient system of rapid\ntransit in view of the public needs and requirements, including in its\ndiscretion, operation of a transit facility or some portion thereof by\nany device or means, other than separate cars or trains, in the\nconstruction of which stationary means for guiding a conveyance in a\ndefinite path and means for propelling such conveyance are necessary\nelements.\n  7. "Equipment." Rolling stock, omnibuses, vehicles, motors, boilers,\nengines, wires, ways, conduits and mechanisms, machinery, tools,\nimplements, materials, supplies and devices of every nature whatsoever\nused for the generation or transmission of motive power and including\nall power houses, and all apparatus and all devices for signalling and\nventilation as may be required for the operation of a transit facility.\n  8. "Facilities." Routes, tracks, extensions, connections, terminals or\nfacilities.\n  9. "Fiscal year." A period commencing the first day of January in each\nyear and ending on the succeeding December thirty-first of such year.\n  10. "Governor." The governor of the state of New York.\n  11. "Mayor." The mayor of the city.\n  12. "Person." A natural person, firm or corporation.\n  13. "Property" or "property rights." Real estate, real property,\nlands, rights, terms, interests, privileges, franchises or easements of\nowners, abutting owners or others.\n  14. "Revenues." All monies received by the authority or its\nsubsidiaries from whatever source, derived directly or indirectly from\nor in connection with their operations.\n  15. "Transit facility." A rapid transit railroad, omnibus line or any\nother facility or any railroad in the city used for local service in the\ntransportation of passengers as common carriers for hire or in the\ntransportation of the United States mail or personal property, and any\nportion thereof and the rights, leaseholds or other interests therein,\ntogether with the devices and appurtenances, facilities and equipment\nthereof and power plants and other instrumentalities used or useful\ntherefor or in connection therewith.\n  16. "Street." A public street, marginal street, avenue, road, bridge,\nviaduct, highway, boulevard, driveway, park, parkway, dock, wharf, pier,\nground, river, water, square, place or land within the city.\n  17. "Metropolitan transportation authority." The corporation created\nby section twelve hundred sixty-three of this chapter.\n  18. "Triborough bridge and tunnel authority." The corporation created\nby section five hundred fifty-two of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>