<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1203"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1203"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1203"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1203/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1203/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1203">
        <num>1203</num>
        <heading>Transfer of transit facilities by the city to the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1203__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such agreement shall provide that capital costs of a nature not\nheretofore charged as operating expenses shall be paid by the city, or\nat the option of the authority may be paid in the first instance by the\nauthority but in such event, the authority shall be entitled to recover\nfrom the city the amount of such costs; provided, however, that the\ntotal amount of such capital costs which the authority may incur without\nthe approval of the mayor in any city fiscal year shall not exceed five\nmillion dollars and that no other such capital costs shall be incurred\nby the authority without such approval. Where the city is required to\nreimburse the authority for the amount of any capital costs pursuant to\nsuch agreement, serial bonds or capital notes may be issued by the city,\npursuant to the local finance law, to finance any such reimbursement in\nthe same manner and to the same extent as if such costs were to be paid\ndirectly by the city.\n  The authority shall submit annually to the city planning commission\nand the mayor of the city on or before October fifteenth in each year an\nestimate of all such capital costs for inclusion in the capital budget\nof the city.\n  (ii) From and after March first, nineteen hundred sixty-eight, the\nauthority shall also have the right to incur capital costs of such\nnature in its own name to the extent that capital funds are available to\nit for expenditures of such nature pursuant to the provisions of section\ntwelve hundred nineteen-a of this chapter or of any other provision of\nlaw, which capital costs shall not be payable by the city; provided,\nhowever, that no project to be financed by the use of such capital funds\nwhich is estimated by the authority to involve an expenditure in excess\nof one million dollars shall be commenced unless the mayor and the board\nof estimate shall each have been notified in writing by the authority of\nthe intent of the authority to undertake such project and of the nature\nthereof. No suc...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1203__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Pension or retirement contributions on behalf of persons who were\nemployed on transit facilities heretofore acquired by the city.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1203__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Contributions to the New York City employees' retirement system on\nbehalf of officers or employees whose compensation has been paid out of\nthe operating revenues of the board of transportation of the city, which\ncontributions have or shall hereafter become due or payable for fiscal\nyears of the city ending on or before June thirtieth, nineteen hundred\nfifty-three.\n  c. All other liabilities of the board of transportation on the date of\nthe conveyance.\n  d. Ten million dollars derived from any funds of the city (but not\nfrom borrowed funds), or from the operating fund of the board of\ntransportation at the time of such transfer, for use by the authority as\ninitial working capital</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1203__subsec_i__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>in partial consideration of the acceptance\nby the authority of the initial transfer, in which case the sum shall\nnot be repaid, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1203__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>as a loan, in which case such sum shall be repaid\nin not less than five nor more than ten equal annual installments,\ncommencing July first, nineteen hundred fifty-four.\n  3. a. Such agreement may contain provisions relating to the use and\noccupancy by the authority of real property (in addition to that\ntransferred pursuant to subdivision one of this section) now or\nhereafter owned or leased by the city, on such terms as may be mutually\nagreed upon by the city and the authority, and may provide for or\nauthorize surrenders to the city of property no longer required by the\nauthority.\n  b. The authority shall be entitled to utilize the officers, employees,\nagents, facilities and services of the city on the same terms and\nconditions as were applicable to or provided to the board of\ntransportation on March fifteenth, nineteen hundred fifty-three.\n  4. The city and the authority are hereby authorized and empowered to\nmake or enter into any contracts, agreements, deeds, leases, ...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>