<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1204-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1204_C">
        <num>1204-C</num>
        <heading>Receipt of line of duty pay</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1204-c. Receipt of line of duty pay. 1. A member of the New York\ncity transit authority police force in the rank of police officer or a\nmember of such force who is detailed or designated as a detective or who\nholds the position of sergeant or any position of higher rank, shall be\nentitled pursuant to this section to the full amount of his or her\nregular salary for the period of any incapacity due to illness or injury\nincurred in the performance and discharge of duty as a member of the\nforce, as determined by the authority, only in the event that a\ncollective bargaining agreement granting such entitlement pursuant to\nthis section has been entered into by the authority and the certified\nemployee organization representing such member. The first entitlement of\nany such member of the New York city transit authority police force to\nthe full amount of regular salary under this section shall commence on\nthe date of execution of the collective bargaining agreement providing\nfor such entitlement with respect to such member.\n  2. Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the rights,\npowers and duties of the authority pursuant to any other provision of\nlaw, including, but not limited to, the right to discipline a police\nofficer by termination, reduction of salary, or any other appropriate\nmeasure; the power to terminate an appointee who has not completed his\nor her probationary term; and the power to apply for ordinary or\naccident disability retirement for a police officer.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require payment of\nsalary to a member of the New York city transit authority police force\nwho has been terminated, retired, suspended or otherwise separated from\nservice by reason of death, retirement or any other cause.\n  4. A decision as to eligibility for benefits pursuant to this section\nshall not be binding on the medical board or the board of trustees of\nany pension fund in the determination of eligibility for an accident\ndisability or accidental death benefit.\n  5. As used in this section the term "incapacity" shall mean the\ninability to perform full, limited, or restricted duty.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>