<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-01-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1204"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1204/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1204">
        <num>1204</num>
        <heading>General powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1204__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirty-four of\nsection 1.20 of the criminal procedure law and shall possess all the\npowers of a police officer of a city in the execution of criminal\nprocess; and criminal process issued by any court or magistrate of a\ncity may be directed to and executed by a member of such force,\nnotwithstanding the provisions of any local or special act, ordinance or\nregulation.\n  The authority may appoint a chief and a deputy chief of the transit\npolice department who, in the discretion of the authority, may be\nselected from the ranks of the transit police force, and assign powers\nand duties to them and fix their compensation. The chief shall be the\nhead of such department. During the absence or disability of the chief,\nthe deputy chief shall possess all the powers and perform all the duties\nof the chief. The transit police force shall consist of captains,\nlieutenants, sergeants and police officers. The authority may detail\npersons in the rank of captain of the transit police force to serve in\nhigher ranks. A captain when so detailed to serve in a higher rank may\nbe granted an increase in salary above the grade established for the\nrank of captain in the uniformed force. The authority may maintain a\ndivision for detective purposes to be known as the detective division\nand may, from time to time, detail to service in said division as many\nmembers of the force as it may deem necessary, and may at any time\nrevoke any such detail. Any member of the force while so detailed may be\ngranted an increase in salary above the grade established for his or her\nrank in the uniformed force, but shall retain his or her rank in the\nforce and shall be eligible for promotion the same as if serving in the\nuniformed force, and the time during which he or she serves in such\ndivision shall count for all purposes as if served in his or her rank or\ngrade in the uniformed force.\n  16-a. The authority shall establish and publish or cause to be\npublished schedules...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>