<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1205"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1205"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1205"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1205">
        <num>1205</num>
        <heading>Rates of fare and levels of service</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any complete or partial closing of a passenger station within\nthe city of New York, or any means of public access to such facility,\nexcept for purposes of repair or renovation or in case of emergency\nshall be accomplished only if approved by resolution of the authority\nadopted by not less than a majority of the whole number of members of\nthe authority then in office, and only after a public hearing. Such\nhearing shall be held not less than thirty days after notice of such\nproposed closing has been given to, and comments solicited from, the\ncommunity board as established pursuant to section eighty-four of the\nNew York city charter whose area of jurisdiction includes the station\nproposed to be closed or otherwise affected.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In the case of a planned complete closure of a passenger station\nfor purposes of repair or renovation, where such station will be out of\nservice for sixty days or longer the MTA board shall adopt a policy,\nwithin ninety days of the effective date of the chapter of the laws of\ntwo thousand nineteen which amended this subdivision, that will ensure\nadequate communication of such work to impacted stakeholders where such\npassenger station is located including but not limited to: elected\nrepresentatives, senate and assembly representatives, and community\nboards at least forty-five days prior to such closure. Such policy shall\nrequire the authority to notify the community board or boards whose\ndistrict contains a passenger station subject to a planned complete\nclosure or is contiguous to a district that contains a passenger station\nsubject to a planned complete closure located on the same line of\nservice as the passenger station subject to closure in writing. Such\nwritten notice shall provide such board or boards with an option to\nrequest a presentation from the authority regarding such planned\ncomplete closure. Upon request from such board or boards the authority\nshall, at a date convenient to such board or boards prior to such\nclosure, present information regarding such closure and related service\nalternatives and also allow for public comment. The policy shall also\nrequire that the authority provide notice to the public at least thirty\ndays prior to such closure by:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>posting notice in the passenger\nstations that are scheduled for closure; and (ii) posting notice on the\nauthority's website and social media accounts; providing information\nabout the planned complete closure, service alternatives, and directions\non how the public can provide comment to the authority regarding such\nclosure. This subdivision shall not apply to emergency station closures\nresulting from unforeseen circumstances where such closure is necessary\nto ensure public health, safety and welfare.\n  6. No acts or activities taken or proposed to be taken by the\nauthority pursuant to the provisions of subdivision one or two of this\nsection shall be deemed to be "actions" for the purposes or within the\nmeaning of article eight of the environmental conservation law.\n  7. Whenever the authority causes notices of hearings on proposed\nchanges in services or fares to be posted pursuant to this section or\nany statute, regulation, or authority policy, or where it voluntarily\nposts such notices, such notices shall:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be written in a clear and\ncoherent manner using words with common and every day meaning;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be\ncaptioned in large point type bold lettering with a title that fairly\nand accurately conveys the basic nature of such change or changes;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nwhere such change involves a proposed change in levels of fare, include\nin its title the range of amounts of fare changes under consideration;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>contain, to the extent practicable, a concise description of the\nspecific nature of the change or changes, including but not limited to a\nconcise description of those changes that affect the largest number of\npassengers;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>where such change involves a change in the nature of a\nroute, contain, to the extent practicable, a clear graphic illustration\nof such change or changes; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1205__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>where such change involves a partial\nor complete station closing, such notice shall be posted at the affected\nstation with a clear graphic illustration depicting the nature of any\nclosing for such station.\n  8. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the authority and any\nof its subsidiary corporations shall establish and implement a half fare\nrate program for persons with serious mental illness who are eligible to\nreceive supplemental security income benefits as defined pursuant to\ntitle sixteen of the federal social security act and section two hundred\nnine of the social services law. The half fare rate program established\nand implemented pursuant to this subdivision shall be in operation\nduring all hours in which such authority provides railroad, subway\nand/or omnibus services, and such program shall not be limited in\noperation to off-peak hours or to any other hours designated by the\nauthority or its subsidiary corporations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>