<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1210"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1210"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1210"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1210/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1210/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1210">
        <num>1210</num>
        <heading>Employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1210. Employees. 1. Employees in the competitive and labor classes\nof the classified service in the employ of the board of transportation\nand performing services in respect to subjects or matters, jurisdiction\nof which was transferred to the authority, with the approval of the\nauthority shall be transferred to comparable positions in the employ of\nthe authority; and, any officers and other employees of such board of\ntransportation may be so transferred and appointed by the authority.\n  2. The appointment, promotion and continuance of employment of all\nemployees of the authority shall be governed by the provisions of the\ncivil service law and the rules of the municipal civil service\ncommission of the city. Employees of any board, commission or department\nof the city may be transferred to positions of employment under the\nauthority in accordance with the provisions of the civil service law and\nshall be eligible for such transfer and appointment without examination\nto such positions of employment. Employees who have been appointed to\npositions in the service of the city under the rules of the municipal\ncivil service commission of the city shall have the same status with\nrespect thereto after transfer to positions of employment under the\nauthority as they had under their original appointments. Employees of\nthe authority shall be subject to the provisions of the civil service\nlaw.\n  3. Officers and employees of the city who are members or beneficiaries\nof any existing pension or retirement system shall continue to have the\nrights, privileges, obligations and status with respect to such system\nor systems as if they had continued in their city offices or\nemployments. Employment by the authority shall constitute city service\nfor the purposes of title B of chapter three of the administrative code\nof such city and the contributions required to be made by the authority\npursuant to section B 3-20.0 of such code shall be an operating expense\nof the authority.\n  4. No assignment of, or power of attorney to collect or other\ninstrument affecting, the whole or any part of his salary or earnings by\nan officer or employee of the authority, shall in any way operate to\nprevent the payment of such salary or earnings directly to such officer\nor employee unless approved in writing by a person duly designated by\nthe authority for such purpose. In the event of the payment of such\nsalary or earnings directly to such officer or employee, notwithstanding\nthe existence of an assignment of, or power of attorney to collect or\nother instrument affecting, the whole or part thereof, not approved by\nsuch designated person, no person shall have any cause of action\ntherefor against such authority for the recovery of any moneys by virtue\nof such unapproved assignment, power of attorney to collect or other\ninstrument. Any such assignment, power of attorney or other instrument\nfiled hereafter with the authority shall contain the name of the officer\nor employee affected thereby and his title or the position in which he\nis employed. The authority shall be entitled to receive a fee of two\ndollars upon the filing of such assignment, power of attorney or other\ninstrument. In the event that such assignment, power of attorney or\nother instrument contains a provision to the effect that the same shall\nbe ineffective unless subsequent written notice is given to the\nauthority to make deductions, the filing fee shall be fifty cents; and\nthe filing fee of any such subsequent written notice to make deductions\nin accordance with the terms of any such assignment, power of attorney\nor other instrument shall be one dollar and fifty cents. The filing fee\nof any other notice or paper relating to any such assignment, power of\nattorney or other instrument shall be one dollar.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>