<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1226-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1226-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1226-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1226-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1226-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1226-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1226-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1226_C">
        <num>1226-C</num>
        <heading>Upper Mohawk valley regional water finance authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1226_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The county executive shall file on or before December\nthirty-first of the year in which this title shall have become a law, in\nthe office of the secretary of state, a certificate signed by the county\nexecutive setting forth:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1226_C__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name of the authority;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1226_C__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the names of\nthe members appointed by the council, the mayor, the county executive,\nand the towns and their terms of office; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1226_C__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the effective date of\nthis title. If such certificate is not filed with the secretary of state\non or before such date, then the corporate existence of the authority\nshall thereupon terminate and it shall thereupon be deemed to be and\nshall be dissolved.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1226_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1226_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the\nauthority and its corporate existence shall continue until terminated by\nlaw, provided, however, that no such law shall take effect so long as\nthe authority shall have bonds or other obligations outstanding unless\nadequate provision has been made for the payment or satisfaction\nthereof. Upon termination of the existence of the authority, all of the\nrights and properties of the authority then remaining shall pass to and\nvest jointly in the city and the towns and villages in the service area\nin such a manner as prescribed by law.\n  5. It is hereby determined and declared that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers and duties are in all respects for the\nbenefit of the people of the service area and the state for the\nimprovement of their health, welfare and prosperity and that such\npurposes are public purposes and that the authority is and will be\nperforming an essential governmental function in the exercise of the\npowers conferred upon it by this title.\n  6. Nothing in this title shall be construed to obligate the state in\nany way in connection with the operations or obligations of the\nauthority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>