<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1230-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1230_H">
        <num>1230-H</num>
        <heading>Transfer of facilities by the city of Niagara Falls or any municipality</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_H__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision five of section twelve hundred thirty-e of\nthis title shall be filed by the mayor and terminating three hundred\nsixty-five days thereafter shall be accepted by the water board in the\nphysical condition in which it then exists. Any such agreement shall\nstate the consideration, if any, for such transfer and shall provide\nthat the authority shall assume the obligation to pay any or all\noutstanding indebtedness of the transferring body relating to the system\nand/or pay all or part of any purchase or acquisition price in cash or\nin installments over such period of years, at such rate of interest, if\nany, and may be subject to such other terms and conditions as the water\nboard, the authority, the city or municipality, as the case may be,\nshall agree to be fair, adequate and reasonable. Notwithstanding the\nprovisions of any general, special or local law or charter to the\ncontrary, any action taken by the city or any municipality pursuant to\nthis subdivision shall not be subject to a permissive or mandatory\nreferendum.\n  2. Any such agreement shall set forth the liabilities of the city or\nof any municipality in which it is contemplated are to be paid by the\nauthority or the water board from moneys available to it.\n  3. Any such agreement may provide for the payment by the city or any\nmunicipality to the water board of any funds, including the remaining\nproceeds of any bonds or notes issued for any facility of the system, to\nbe transferred by the city or municipality to the water board as may be\ndetermined appropriate by the city or such municipality and the water\nboard.\n  4. The city, any municipality, the authority and the water board, or\nany combination thereof, are hereby authorized and empowered to make or\nenter into any contracts, agreements, deeds, leases, conveyances or\nother instruments as may be necessary or appropriate to effectuate the\npurposes of this title, and they shall have power and authority to do so\nand to auth...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>