<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-U"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-U"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1230-U"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1230_U">
        <num>1230-U</num>
        <heading>Contracts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1230-u. Contracts. All contracts for construction or purchase of\nsupplies, materials or equipment shall be let by the water board, shall\nbe made in conformity with the applicable provisions of section one\nhundred three of the general municipal law and section one hundred\nthirty-five of the state finance law. For the purposes of article\nfifteen-A of the executive law only, the authority and the water board\nshall each be deemed a state agency as that term is used in such\narticle, and its contracts for procurement, design, construction,\nservices and materials shall be deemed state contracts within the\nmeaning of that term as set forth in such article. All construction\ncontracts shall be let in accordance with the provisions of state law\npertaining to prevailing wages, labor standards and working hours. The\nwater board may, in its discretion, assign contracts for supervision and\ncoordination to the successful bidder for any subdivision of work for\nwhich the water board receives bids. The water board shall not award any\nconstruction contract except to the lowest bidder who, in its opinion,\nis qualified to perform the work required and who is responsible and\nreliable. The water board may, however, reject any or all bids or waive\nany informality in a bid if it believes that the public interest will be\npromoted thereby. The water board may reject any bid if, in its\njudgment, the business and technical organization, plant, resources,\nfinancial standing, or experience of the bidder justifies such rejection\nin view of the work to be performed. Nothing in this title shall be\nconstrued to limit or diminish the power of the water board to do any\nconstruction directly by the officers, employees or agents of the water\nboard.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>