<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-V"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-V"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1230-V"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1230_V">
        <num>1230-V</num>
        <heading>Code of ethics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No employee shall accept other employment which will impair his or\nher independence of judgment in the exercise of his or her official\nduties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No employee shall accept employment or engage in any business or\nprofessional activity which will require the employee to disclose\nconfidential information which he or she has gained by reason of his or\nher official position or authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No employee shall disclose confidential information acquired by\nthe employee in the course of his or her official duties nor use such\ninformation to further his or her personal interests.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No employee shall use or attempt to use his or her official\nposition to secure unwarranted privileges or exemptions for himself or\nherself or others.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No employee shall engage in any transaction as representative or\nagent of the authority or water board with any person or business entity\nin which he or she has a direct or indirect financial interest that\nmight reasonably tend to conflict with the proper discharge of his or\nher official duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An employee shall not by his or her conduct give reasonable basis\nfor the impression that any person can improperly influence such\nemployee or unduly enjoy his or her favor in the performance of his or\nher official duties, or that he or she is affected by the kinship, rank,\nposition or influence of any party or person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An employee shall abstain from making personal investments in\nenterprises which he or she has reason to believe may be directly\ninvolved in decisions to be made by the employee or which will otherwise\ncreate substantial conflict between his or her duty in the public\ninterest and his or her private interest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An employee shall endeavor to pursue a course of conduct which\nwill not raise suspicion among the public that he or she is likely to be\nengaged in acts that are in violation of his or her trust.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No employee employed on a full-time basis nor any person, firm or\nassociation of which such an employee is a member, nor corporation a\nsubstantial portion of the stock of which is owned or controlled\ndirectly or indirectly by such employee, shall sell goods or services to\nany person, firm, corporation or association which is licensed or whose\nrates are fixed by the water board in which such employee serves or is\nemployed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_V__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any employee shall have a financial interest, direct or\nindirect, having a value of ten thousand dollars or more, in any\nactivity which is subject to the jurisdiction of a regulatory agency, he\nor she shall file with the secretary of state and secretary of the water\nboard a written statement that he or she has such a financial interest\nin such activity which statement shall be open to public inspection.\n  4. In addition to any penalty contained in any other provision of law,\nany such employee who shall knowingly and intentionally violate any of\nthe provisions of this section may be fined, suspended or removed from\noffice or employment in accordance with the rules and regulations of the\nwater board. It shall be a misdemeanor for any such employee to be in\nany way or manner interested, directly or indirectly, in the furnishing\nof work, materials, supplies or labor, in any contract therefor which\nthe authority or the water board is empowered to make by this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>