<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1230-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1230-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1230_K">
        <num>1230-K</num>
        <heading>Appropriations for purposes of the water board or the authority; transfer of property to the water board or authority; acquisition of pro...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring the purchase by any\nmunicipality of specified amounts of water, wastewater or storm water\nservices;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring the use by any municipality of a system\nfacility;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>limiting the right, including a prohibition, of any\nmunicipality to construct a facility which will serve the same, or\nsubstantially the same, function as a system facility constructed or to\nbe constructed by the water board;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring the water board to\nreserve capacity in any system facility to assure the availability to\nany municipality of a specified amount of use of any system facility;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>providing for specified minimum periodic payments whether or not\nwater, wastewater or storm water services are actually taken and used,\nor such system facility is actually used, subject to such limitations,\nexceptions and provisions therein, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring any municipality to\npay to the water board such amounts as shall be necessary to assure the\ncontinued operation of the water board.  All such payments shall be\ndetermined and paid in such manner and at such times as may be provided\nin such contracts.\n  5. No gift, grant, sale, conveyance, loan, contract or lease\nauthorized by this section shall be subject to referendum, permissive or\notherwise.\n  6. Any agreement for the supply of water services, wastewater services\nor storm water services between the city or an agency thereof and any\nother municipality or state agency, or any administrative determination\nby a state agency, or any other arrangement in this regard, in effect at\nthe time the water board shall be established, shall remain in full\nforce and effect and be binding upon the water board as if it were a\nparty to such agreement, determination or other arrangement.\n  7.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, neither the\nauthority nor the water board shall supply, or enter into any agreement\nto supply water to any municipality within the Niagara county water\ndistrict, or any person or entity within the boundaries of the Niagara\ncounty water district without the consent and approval by resolution of\na majority of the members of the Niagara county water district\nadministrative board;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that nothing contained in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1230_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, or elsewhere in this title shall affect in any manner\neither the existing rights of the city, or such rights assumed by the\nauthority or the water board, or the existing rights of any other\nmunicipality with respect to those persons or entities presently\nreceiving water from the city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>