<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1232-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1232_P">
        <num>1232-P</num>
        <heading>Code of ethics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority member shall accept other employment, which will\nimpair his or her independence of judgment in the exercise of his or her\nofficial duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority member shall accept employment or engage in any\nbusiness or professional activity which will require the member to\ndisclose confidential information which he or she has gained by reason\nof his or her official position or authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority member shall disclose confidential information\nacquired by the member in the course of his or her official duties nor\nuse such information to further his or her personal interests.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority member shall use or attempt to use his or her\nofficial position to secure unwarranted privileges or exemptions for him\nor herself or others.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority member shall engage in any transaction as\nrepresentative or agent of the authority with any business entity in\nwhich he or she has a direct or indirect financial interest that might\nreasonably tend to conflict with the proper discharge of his or her\nofficial duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority member shall not by his or her conduct give\nreasonable basis for the impression that any person can improperly\ninfluence such member or unduly enjoy his or her favor in the\nperformance of his or her official duties, or that he or she is affected\nby the kinship, rank, position or influence of any party or person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority member shall abstain from making personal investments\nin enterprises which he or she has reason to believe may be directly\ninvolved in decisions to be made by the member or which will otherwise\ncreate substantial conflict between his or her duty in the public\ninterest and his or her private interest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority member shall endeavor to pursue a course of conduct\nwhich will not raise suspicion among the public that he or she is likely\nto be engaged in acts that are in violation of his or her trust.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority member employed on a full-time basis nor any firm or\nassociation of which such a member is a member nor a corporation a\nsubstantial portion of the stock of which is owned or controlled\ndirectly or indirectly by such member, shall sell goods or services to\nany person, firm, corporation or association which is licensed or whose\nrates are fixed by the authority in which such member serves or is\nemployed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1232_P__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any authority member shall have a financial interest, direct or\nindirect, having a value of ten thousand dollars or more in any activity\nwhich is subject to the jurisdiction of a regulatory agency, he or she\nshall file with the secretary of state a written statement that he or\nshe has such a financial interest in such activity which statement shall\nbe open to public inspection.\n  4. In addition to any penalty contained in any other provision of law,\nany such authority member who shall knowingly and intentionally violate\nany of the provisions of this section may be fined, suspended or removed\nfrom office or employment.\n  5. All members of the authority shall be deemed to be public officers\nand shall, notwithstanding any other ethical requirements established by\nstate or local law, and when not inconsistent with the provisions of\nthis title, comply with sections seventy-three, seventy-three-a and\nseventy-four of the public officers law. Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of law, the filing of a Nassau county financial disclosure\nstatement, pursuant to the Nassau county code of ethics as set forth in\nsection twenty-two hundred eighteen of the county charter, by a member\nof the authority shall constitute and be deemed in compliance with the\nfinancial disclosure requirements imposed by this section and section\nseventy-three-a of the public officers law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>