<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1232-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1232-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1232_S">
        <num>1232-S</num>
        <heading>Environmental application, proceedings, approvals and permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1232-s. Environmental application, proceedings, approvals and\npermits.  1. Any application in relation to the purposes of or\ncontemplated by this title filed prior to the effective date of this\ntitle, or any proceeding commenced prior to the effective date of this\ntitle, by the county with the department of environmental conservation,\nthe department of health, the department of transportation, any other\nstate agency or instrumentality, or with the United States environmental\nprotection agency or any other federal agency or instrumentality shall\ninure to and for the benefit of the authority to the same extent and in\nthe same manner as if the authority had been a party to such application\nor proceeding from its inception, and the authority shall be deemed a\nparty thereto, to the extent not prohibited by any federal law. Any\nlicense, approval, permit or decision issued or granted pursuant to or\nas a result of any such application or proceeding shall inure to the\nbenefit of and be binding upon the authority and shall be assigned and\ntransferred by the county or any agency thereof to the authority, unless\nsuch assignment and transfer is prohibited by federal law.\n  2. All such applications, proceedings, licenses, approvals, permits\nand decisions shall further inure to and for the benefit of and be\nbinding upon any person leasing, acquiring, constructing, maintaining,\nusing or occupying any facility financed in whole or in part by the\nauthority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>