<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1264"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1264"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1264"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1264/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1264/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1264/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1264/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1264">
        <num>1264</num>
        <heading>Purposes of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1264. Purposes of the authority. 1. The purposes of the authority\nshall be the continuance, further development and improvement of\ncommuter transportation and other services related thereto within the\nmetropolitan commuter transportation district, including but not limited\nto such transportation by railroad, omnibus, marine and air, in\naccordance with the provisions of this title. It shall be the further\npurpose of the authority, consistent with its status as the ex officio\nboard of both the New York city transit authority and the triborough\nbridge and tunnel authority, to develop and implement a unified mass\ntransportation policy for such district in an efficient and\ncost-effective manner that includes the use of design-build contracting\non all projects over two hundred million dollars in cost for new\nconstruction and all projects over four hundred million dollars in cost\nfor projects that are predominantly rehabilitation or replacement of\nexisting assets except where a waiver is granted by the New York state\nbudget director pursuant to a request in writing from the metropolitan\ntransportation authority. For purposes of granting a waiver pursuant to\nthis section, such review shall consider whether the design build\ncontracting method is appropriate for the project that such waiver is\nsought for, and the amount of savings and efficiencies that could be\nachieved using such method. The determination for such waiver shall be\nmade in writing within forty-five days from request or shall be deemed\ngranted.\n  2. It is hereby found and declared that such purposes are in all\nrespects for the benefit of the people of the state of New York and the\nauthority shall be regarded as performing an essential governmental\nfunction in carrying out its purposes and in exercising the powers\ngranted by this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>