<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1266-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1266_F">
        <num>1266-F</num>
        <heading>Medical emergency services plan; implementation on Metro-North Commuter Railroad Company</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1266-f. Medical emergency services plan; implementation on\nMetro-North Commuter Railroad Company. 1. The authority is hereby\nauthorized and directed to implement a medical emergency services\nprogram not later than April first, nineteen hundred eighty-six, for the\nbenefit of persons utilizing transportation and other related services\nof the Metro-North Commuter Railroad Company. Such program shall include\nbut not be limited to provision for the following: The training of\nconductors, trainmen and other designated employees in first aid,\nemergency techniques and procedures, handling and positioning of\nstricken commuters, and knowledge of procedures and equipment used for\nrespiratory and cardiac emergencies.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, a designated employee employed upon facilities of the\nMetro-North Commuter Railroad Company who has successfully completed a\ncourse in first aid, including instruction and training in\ncardiopulmonary resuscitation and who voluntarily and without\nexpectation of monetary compensation renders first aid, emergency\ntreatment or cardiopulmonary resuscitation at the scene of an accident\nor other emergency, in the course of his duties as an employee of the\nMetro-North Commuter Railroad Company to a person who is unconscious,\nill or injured, shall not be liable for damages and injuries alleged to\nhave been sustained by such person or for damages for death of such\nperson alleged to have occurred by reason of an act or omission in the\nrendering of such first aid, emergency treatment or cardiopulmonary\nresuscitation unless it is established that such injuries were or such\ndeath was caused by gross negligence on the part of such designated\nemployee.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>