<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1266"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1266">
        <num>1266</num>
        <heading>Special powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any transportation facility\nother than a transit project, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>upon the request of the New York\ncity transit authority, and upon such terms and conditions as shall be\nagreed to by the authority or any transportation facility constituting a\ntransit facility (a "transportation assistance project"), or may provide\nfor such planning, design, acquisition, establishment, construction,\neffectuation, operation, maintenance, renovation, improvement,\nextension, rehabilitation or repair by contract, lease or other\narrangement on such terms as the authority may deem necessary,\nconvenient or desirable with any person, including but not limited to\nany common carrier or freight forwarder, the state, any state agency,\nthe federal government, any other state or agency or instrumentality\nthereof, any public authority of this or any other state, the port of\nNew York authority or any political subdivision or municipality of the\nstate. In connection with the operation of any transportation facility,\nthe authority may plan, design, acquire, establish, construct,\neffectuate, operate, maintain, renovate, improve, extend or repair or\nmay provide by contract, lease or other arrangement for the planning,\ndesign, acquisition, establishment, construction, effectuation,\noperation, maintenance, renovation, improvement, extension or repair of\nany related services and activities it deems necessary, convenient or\ndesirable, including but not limited to the transportation and storage\nof freight and the United States mail, feeder and connecting\ntransportation, parking areas, transportation centers, stations and\nrelated facilities. Upon the completion of any such transportation\nassistance project or any part thereof or the termination of any\ncontract, lease or other arrangement relating to such transportation\nassistance project, the authority shall cause the same to be\ntransferred, leased or subleased to the New York city transit authority\nor its designated subsidiary, as appropriate, with or without\nconsideration.\n  3. The authority ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as the same shall become\ndue, the principal of and interest on the bonds and notes and other\nobligations of the authority and of such subsidiary corporations,\ntogether with the maintenance of proper reserves therefor,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the cost\nand expense of keeping the properties and assets of the authority and\nits subsidiary corporations in good condition and repair, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\ncapital and operating expenses of the authority and its subsidiary\ncorporations. The authority may contract with the holders of bonds and\nnotes with respect to the exercise of the powers authorized by this\nsection. No acts or activities taken or proposed to be taken by the\nauthority or any subsidiary of the authority pursuant to the provisions\nof this subdivision shall be deemed to be "actions" for the purposes or\nwithin the meaning of article eight of the environmental conservation\nlaw.\n  3-a. In furtherance of the authority's mandate to develop and\nimplement a unified mass transportation policy for the metropolitan\ncommuter transportation district and the exercise of its powers,\nincluding the power to issue notes, bonds and other obligations secured\nin whole or in part by the revenues of the authority and its\nsubsidiaries, and New York city transit authority and its subsidiaries,\nthe authority shall join with the New York city transit authority and\nits subsidiaries in connection with any change in the establishment,\nlevy and collection of fares, tolls, rentals, rates, charges and other\nfees for the transportation of passengers on any transportation\nfacilities operated by New York city transit authority and its\nsubsidiaries. Such fares, tolls, rentals, charges and other fees on\ntransit facilities shall be established in accordance with the\nrequirements of sections twelve hundred five and twelve hundred seven-i\nof this article.\n  4. The authority may establish and, in the case of joint service\narrangements, join with others in the establishment of such schedules\nand standards of operations and such other rules and regulations\nincluding but not limited to rules and regulations governing the conduct\nand safety of the public as it may deem necessary, convenient or\ndesirable for the use and operation of any transportation facility and\nrelated services operated by the authority or under contract, lease or\nother arrangement, including jo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the enactment by the state of Connecticut of legislation\nhaving like effect as the provisions of this paragraph and the granting\nof the consent of the congress of the United States of America to the\ninterstate compact thereby created, and (ii) in conformity with\nrecommendations of the New York-Connecticut bi-state bridge study\ncommission, the authority is authorized, in cooperation with any duly\ndesignated agency or agencies of the state of Connecticut, to design,\nconstruct, maintain, operate, improve and reconstruct a highway bridge\ncrossing Long Island sound from a point in the vicinity of the city of\nBridgeport in the state of Connecticut to a point in the vicinity of the\nvillage of Port Jefferson in the state of New York, together with\napproaches to such bridge; and to contract from time to time with such\nagency or agencies of the state of Connecticut with respect to all\nmatters affecting these authorizations, including, without limitation,\nthe sharing of all capital, operational and maintenance expense (except\nthat the capital expense of the original construction of such bridge,\nother than the expense of acquiring the needed real property, shall be\nin the ratio of fifty per-centum for the authority and fifty per-centum\nfor such agency or agencies of the state of Connecticut), the manner and\nby whom the work of design, construction, reconstruction, improvement,\nmaintenance and operation is to be performed or contracted to others for\nperformance, the tolls, fees and other charges to be imposed from time\nto time for the use of such bridge, and the sharing of revenues derived\nfrom the imposition of such tolls, fees and charges (except that net\nrevenues remaining after deduction of operational and maintenance\nexpense of such bridge shall be in the ratio of fifty per-centum for the\nauthority and fifty per-centum for the state of Connecticut or for such\nagency or agencies of the state of Connecticut. Subject to the\nlimitations imposed upon ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If funds are made available by the authority for the payment of\nthe cost and expense of the acquisition thereof, the commissioner of\ntransportation of the state of New York, when requested by the\nauthority, may acquire in the name of the state such real property lying\nwithin the territorial boundaries of the state as may be determined from\ntime to time by the authority to be necessary, convenient or desirable\nto carry out the authorizations set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, may remove the owner or occupant thereof where\nnecessary and obtain possession and, when requested by the authority,\nmay dispose of any real property so acquired, all according to the\nprocedure provided in section thirty of the highway law. The authority\nshall have the right to possess and use for its corporate purposes all\nsuch real property so acquired, all according to the procedure provided\nin section thirty of the highway law. The authority shall have the right\nto possess and use for its corporate purposes all such real property so\nacquired. Claims for the value of the property appropriated and for\nlegal damages caused by any such appropriation shall be adjusted and\ndetermined by the commissioner of transportation with the approval of\nthe authority or by the court of claims as provided in section thirty of\nthe highway law. When a claim has been filed with the court of claims,\nthe claimant shall cause a copy of such claim to be served upon the\nauthority and the authority shall have the right to be represented and\nheard before such court. All awards and judgments arising from such\nclaims shall be paid out of moneys of the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority, acting independently or jointly or in cooperation\nwith such agency or agencies of the state of Connecticut, may also apply\nfor and accept, upon condition or otherwise, from the duly authorized\nagencies of the federal government, and of the governments of the states\nof Connecticut and New York, such underwater and overwater grants of\nreal property, licenses or permits as shall be necessary, convenient or\ndesirable to carry out the authorizations set forth in paragraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The provisions of chapter four hundred forty-two of the laws of\nnineteen hundred sixty-five (and of any agreement entered into in\npursuance thereof) relating to the repayment of a loan made by the state\nto the authority for the purchase of the Long Island railroad shall be\ninapplicable to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the construction of such bridges and their\napproaches, (ii) bonds, notes or other obligations of the authority\nissued for or in connection with the financing of the cost of design,\nconstruction and reconstruction of such bridges and their approaches, or\nthe proceeds realized upon such issuance; and (iii) revenues derived\nfrom the investment of such proceeds or of any part thereof, and from\nthe imposition of tolls, fees or other charges for the use of such\nbridges.\n  10. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, general, special\nor local, or of any agreement entered into in pursuance thereof,\nrelating to the repayment of any loan or advance made by the state to\nthe authority or to the New York city transit authority, neither the\nauthority nor the New York city transit authority shall be required to\nrepay any such loan or advance heretofore made from or by reason of the\nissuance of bonds or notes of either of them or from the proceeds\nrealized upon such issuance or from any other funds received by either\nof them from any source whatever in aid or assistance of the project or\nprojects for the financing of which such bonds or notes are issued.\n  11. No project to be constructed upon real property theretofore used\nfor a transportation purpose, or on an insubstantial addition to such\nproperty contiguous thereto, which will not change in a material respect\nthe general character of such prior transportation use, nor any acts or\nactivities in connection with such project, shall be subject to the\nprovisions of article eight, nineteen, twenty-four or twenty-five of the\nenvironmental conservation law, or to any local law or ordinance adopted\npursuant to any such article. Nor shall any acts or activities taken or\nproposed to be taken by the authority or by any other person or entity,\npublic or private, in connection with the planning, design, acquisition,\nimprovement, construction, reconstruction or rehabilitation of a\ntransportation facility,...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever the authority determines in consultation with the\ncity of New York that it is necessary to obtain the temporary or\npermanent use, occupancy, control or possession of vacant or undeveloped\nor underutilized but replaceable real property, or any interest therein,\nor subsurface real property or any interest therein then owned by the\ncity of New York for a project in the two thousand fifteen to two\nthousand nineteen, two thousand twenty to two thousand twenty-four, or\ntwo thousand twenty-five to two thousand twenty-nine approved capital\nprograms in connection with</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the installation of one or more\nelevators to make one or more subway stations more accessible, (ii) the\nconstruction or reconstruction of an electrical substation to increase\navailable power to the subway system to expand passenger capacity or\nreliability, (iii) the capital project to construct four commuter\nrailroad passenger stations in the borough of the Bronx known as Penn\nStation access, (iv) the Second Avenue Subway capital project,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nInterborough Express capital project, or (vi) the construction or\nreconstruction of signal or communication systems, the authority upon\napproval by the board of the metropolitan transportation authority and\nupon suitable notice and with the consent of the city of New York may\ncause the title to such real property, or any interest therein, to be\ntransferred to the authority by adding it to the agreement of lease\ndated June first, nineteen hundred fifty-three, as amended, renewed and\nsupplemented, authorized by section twelve hundred three of this\narticle, or may itself acquire title to such property from the city of\nNew York, and any such transfer or acquisition of real property shall be\nsubject to the provisions of subdivision five of section twelve hundred\nsixty-six-c of this title. Nothing in this subdivision shall be deemed\nto authorize any temporary or permanent transfer or acquisition of real\nproperty, or interest therein, that is dedicated parkland without\nseparate legislative approval of such alienation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon the execution of any transfer or acquisition pursuant to\nthis subdivision, which shall be final upon the approval by the board of\nthe metropolitan transportation authority and consent of the city of New\nYork, the fair market value shall be determined pursuant to this\nparagraph. The authority shall make a written offer to pay to the city\nof New York the fair market value of the authority's use, occupancy,\ncontrol, possession or acquisition of such property. The offer by the\nauthority shall be based on an appraisal of the value of such property\nand a copy of such appraisal shall be included with the offer. Such\nappraisal shall be done by an independent New York state licensed or\ncertified appraiser, who may not be employed by the authority, selected\nat random from a panel of appraisers maintained by it for such purpose.\nSuch appraisal and a second appraisal, if required pursuant to\nsubparagraph (ii) of this paragraph, shall consider only the reasonably\nanticipated lawful use of the property and its zoning designation under\nthe zoning resolution of the city of New York at the time the authority\nnotified the city of New York of its determination to use, occupy,\ncontrol, possess or acquire such property.\n  (ii) Within thirty days of receipt of the offer by the authority, the\ncity of New York may accept it, agree with the authority on another\namount, or request a second appraisal by an independent New York state\nlicensed or certified appraiser, who may not be employed by the city of\nNew York, selected at random by the city of New York from a panel of\nappraisers maintained by it for such purpose. Such second appraisal\nshall be completed within thirty days. If the second appraisal produces\nan estimate of the fair market value of the property that is greater\nthan that of the first appraisal, the authority shall have ten days to\nincrease its offer to such higher amount, otherwise the two appraisers\nshall reconcile their valuations and agree on...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to affect or limit\nthe authority's power under subdivision twelve of this section.\n  * NB Repealed December 31, 2030\n  13. The authority and each of its subsidiary corporations shall place\non each transformer and substation which contains polychlorinated\nbiphenyls (PCBs) a symbol so indicating the presence of PCBs. Use of a\nPCB mark illustrated in the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant\nto the federal Toxic Substances Control Act shall constitute compliance\nwith the provisions of this subdivision.\n  14. Notwithstanding any other provisions of law or the terms of any\ncontract, the authority, in consultation with the Long Island Rail Road,\nshall establish and implement a no fare program for transportation on\nthe Long Island Rail Road for police officers employed by the city of\nNew York, county of Nassau, Nassau county villages and cities, county of\nSuffolk, Suffolk county villages and towns, the division of state\npolice, the port authority of New York and New Jersey, the Metro-North\nCommuter Railroad Company, the New York city housing authority and the\nNew York city transit authority. In establishing such program, which has\nas its goal increased protection and improved safety for its commuters,\nthe authority and the Long Island Rail Road shall, among other things,\nconsider:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring police officers who ride without cost to\nregister with the Long Island Rail Road as a condition of riding without\ncost;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring such officers to indicate during such registration\nprocess their regular working hours and the Long Island Rail Road trains\nthat such officers expect to ride; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>periodically re-registering\nand re-validating such officers. The authority and the Long Island Rail\nRoad shall also have the power to consider other matters necessary to\ncarry out the goals and objectives of this section.\n  15.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law or the terms of\nany contract, the authority, in consultation with the New York city\ntransit authority, the Long Island Rail Road and the Metro-North\nCommuter Railroad Company, shall establish and implement a no fare\nprogram for transportation on New York city transit authority systems,\nthe Long Island Rail Road and the Metro-North Commuter Railroad Company\nfor individuals serving as personal care attendants accompanying an\nAmericans With Disabilities Act paratransit eligible individual.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to be eligible for such no fare program the personal care\nattendant must show his or her community based personal care attendant\nagency issued identification card.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1266__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In order to be considered accompanying an Americans With\nDisabilities Act paratransit eligible individual the personal care\nattendant shall have the same origin and destination as such paratransit\neligible individual.\n  16. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the authority and any\nof its subsidiary corporations shall establish and implement a half fare\nrate program for persons with serious mental illness who are eligible to\nreceive supplemental security income benefits as defined pursuant to\ntitle sixteen of the federal social security act and section two hundred\nnine of the social services law.\n  17. Notwithstanding any conflicting provisions of general, special or\nlocal law, and pursuant to the authority's 2000-2004 capital program\nplans approved by the metropolitan transportation authority capital\nprogram review board, the authority or any of its subsidiaries, the New\nYork city transit authority or any of its subsidiaries, or Triborough\nbridge and tunnel authority, shall provide, from funds identified in\nsuch approved 2000-2004 capital program plans, up to twelve million\ndollars for the financing of a bus and heavy duty vehicles emission\nresearch and testing facility and related equipment located in the state\nof New York, whether within or outside of the transportation district,\nwhich facility shall be operated by the department of environmental\nconservation and shall be available for use on a non-exclusive basis by\nthe authority and any of its subsidiaries, the New York city transit\nauthority and any of its subsidiaries, and Triborough bridge and tunnel\nauthority.\n  18. The authority shall conduct a campaign of public outreach to\ninform the public of the provisions pertaining to assault on employees\ndescribed in subdivision eleven of section 120.05 of the penal law.\n  19. In connection with their lawful responsibilities or functions, the\nauthority and its subsidiaries, including Metro-North Commuter Railroad,\nthe Long Island...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>