<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-03-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1266-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1266_E">
        <num>1266-E</num>
        <heading>Metro-North rail commuter council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1266-e. Metro-North rail commuter council. 1. There is hereby\ncreated the Metro-North rail commuter council to study, investigate,\nmonitor and make recommendations with respect to the maintenance and\noperation of those portions of, if any, the Hudson, Harlem, New Haven,\nPascack Valley and Port Jervis commuter railroad lines remaining within\nthe metropolitan commuter transportation district. Such council shall\nstudy and investigate all aspects of the day to day operation of such\nrailroad lines, monitor their performance and recommend changes to\nimprove the efficiency of the operation thereof. Such council shall\nstudy and make recommendations in regard to improving bicycle and\npedestrian access at bridges, stations and other facilities operated by\nsuch railroad lines and submit such recommendations to the metropolitan\ntransportation authority on or before June first, two thousand\ntwenty-two and every five years thereafter.\n  2. Such council shall consist of twelve members and shall be commuters\nwho regularly use the transportation services of such railroad lines. At\nleast five of such members shall be residents of the county of\nWestchester. Of the other seven members, at least one of such members\nshall be a resident of each of the counties of Rockland, Putnam,\nDutchess, Orange and Bronx, provided that such county has not withdrawn\nfrom the metropolitan commuter transportation district pursuant to\nsection twelve hundred seventy-nine-b of this title; provided further,\nshould only the county of Putnam remain in the metropolitan commuter\ntransportation district then membership on such council shall consist of\neight members, six of whom reside in the county of Westchester and two\nof whom reside in the county of Putnam. Members shall be appointed by\nthe governor. In making such appointments the governor shall consult\nwith and solicit recommendations from local officials and to the extent\npossible appoint members who represent the ridership of the several\ncommuter railroad lines. Provided, however, that one member shall be\nappointed who has a demonstrated expertise or interest in the promotion\nand development of improved bicycle and pedestrian access at bridges,\nstations and other facilities operated by the authority and its\naffiliates and subsidiaries. Vacancies occurring in the membership of\nthe council shall be filled in the same manner as original appointments.\n  3. The members of the council shall receive no compensation for their\nservices but shall be reimbursed for their expenses actually and\nnecessarily incurred by them in the performance of their duties\nhereunder from funds appropriated to the commissioner of transportation.\n  4. The council may request and shall receive from any department,\ndivision, board, bureau, commission, agency, public authority of the\nstate or any political subdivision thereof such assistance and data as\nit requests and will enable it to properly carry out its activities for\nthe purposes set forth herein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>