<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-03-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1266-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1266_D">
        <num>1266-D</num>
        <heading>Long Island rail road commuter's council</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1266-d. Long Island rail road commuter's council. 1. There is hereby\ncreated the Long Island rail road commuter's council, to study,\ninvestigate, monitor and make recommendations with respect to the\nmaintenance and operation of the Long Island rail road. Such council\nshall study and investigate all aspects of the day to day operations of\nsuch railroad, monitor its performance and recommend changes to improve\nthe efficiency of the operation thereof. Such council shall study and\nmake recommendations in regard to improving bicycle and pedestrian\naccess at bridges, stations and other facilities operated by the Long\nIsland Railroad and submit such recommendations to the metropolitan\ntransportation authority on or before June first, two thousand\ntwenty-two and every five years thereafter.\n  2. Such council shall consist of thirteen members who shall be\ncommuters who regularly use the transportation services of such\nrailroad, and who shall be residents of Nassau, Suffolk, Queens or\nBrooklyn county.  Members shall be appointed by the governor upon the\nrecommendation of the county executive of each such county, provided,\nhowever, that such members shall be chosen from a list of ten names\nsubmitted by each such county executive and provided further however\nthat no more than six members of such council shall be residents of\neither such county.  Provided, however, that one member shall be\nappointed on the recommendation of the borough president of Queens and\none member shall be appointed on the recommendation of the borough\npresident of Brooklyn.  Provided, however, that one member shall be\nappointed who has a demonstrated expertise or interest in the promotion\nand development of improved bicycle and pedestrian access at bridges,\nstations and other facilities operated by the authority and its\naffiliates and subsidiaries. Vacancies occurring in the membership of\nthe council shall be filled in the same manner as original appointments,\nprovided, however, that such vacancy shall be filled from a list of\nthree names submitted by each such county executive.\n  3. The members of the council shall receive no compensation for their\nservices but shall be reimbursed for their expenses actually and\nnecessarily incurred in the performance of their duties hereunder.\n  4. The council may request and shall receive from any department,\ndivision, board, bureau, commission, agency, public authority of the\nstate or any political subdivision thereof such assistance and data as\nwill enable it properly to carry out its activities hereunder and\neffectuate the purposes set forth herein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>