<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1266-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1266-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1266_B">
        <num>1266-B</num>
        <heading>Medical emergency services plan; implementation on Long Island Rail Road</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1266-b. Medical emergency services plan; implementation on Long\nIsland Rail Road. 1. a. The authority in consultation with the Long\nIsland Rail Road is hereby authorized and directed to implement a\ncomprehensive medical emergency services program, including an emergency\nresponse protocol, not later than September first, two thousand five,\nfor the benefit of persons utilizing transportation and other related\nservices of the Long Island Rail Road. Such program shall include but\nnot be limited to provision for the following: The training of\ndesignated employees in first aid, emergency techniques and procedures,\nhandling and positioning of stricken commuters, knowledge of procedures\nand equipment used for respiratory and cardiac emergencies and an\nemergency response protocol for all employees.\n  b. Such program and plan shall be submitted to the temporary president\nof the senate, the speaker of the assembly and the governor on or before\nSeptember first, two thousand five, and shall be updated as necessary.\nThe authority will issue an annual report on or before April first of\neach year beginning April first, two thousand six, which will include\ncurrent updates, descriptions of medical emergencies, responses and\noutcomes since the most recent report, information regarding training of\npersonnel, analysis of the current plan and any recommendations for\nimproving the program.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, a designated employee employed upon facilities of the Long\nIsland Rail Road who has been trained in first aid, emergency techniques\nand procedures, handling and positioning of stricken commuters, and the\napplicable procedures and equipment used for respiratory and cardiac\nemergencies who voluntarily and without the expectation of monetary\ncompensation renders any of the foregoing treatment in an emergency to a\ncommuter upon facilities of the Long Island Rail Road who is\nunconscious, ill or injured shall not be liable for damages for injuries\nalleged to have been sustained by such commuter or for damages for the\ndeath of such commuter alleged to have occurred by reason of an act or\nomission in the rendering of such treatment in an emergency unless it is\nestablished that such injuries were or such death was caused by gross\nnegligence on the part of such designated employee.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>