<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1268"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1268"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1268"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1268/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1268/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1268/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1268/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1268">
        <num>1268</num>
        <heading>Co-operation and assistance of other agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1268. Co-operation and assistance of other agencies. 1. To avoid\nduplication of effort and in the interests of economy, the authority may\nmake use of existing studies, surveys, plans, data and other materials\nin the possession of any state agency or any municipality or political\nsubdivision of the state. Each such agency, municipality or subdivision\nis hereby authorized to make the same available to the authority and\notherwise to assist it in the performance of its functions. At the\nrequest of the authority, each such agency, municipality or subdivision\nwhich is engaged in highway or other transportation activities or in\nland use or development planning, or which is charged with the duty of\nproviding or regulating any transportation facility or any other public\nfacility, is further authorized to provide the authority with\ninformation regarding its plans and programs affecting the\ntransportation district so that the authority may have available to it\ncurrent information with respect thereto. The officers and personnel of\nsuch agencies, municipalities or subdivisions, and of any other\ngovernment or agency whatever, may serve at the request of the authority\nupon such advisory committees as the authority shall determine to create\nand such officers and personnel may serve upon such committees without\nforfeiture of office or employment and with no loss or diminution in the\ncompensation, status, rights and privileges which they otherwise enjoy.\n  2. The authority shall, at the request of any state agency,\nmunicipality or political subdivision of the state, engaged in highway\nor other transportation activities or in land use or development\nplanning, provide said state agency, municipality or political\nsubdivision with all current and relevant information regarding its\nplans or programs, so as to enable said agency, municipality or\nsubdivision to properly effectuate said activities or planning.\n  3. To the extent that the provisions of this title authorize the\nauthority to enter into any agreement or arrangement with, or undertake\nany other activity requiring the participation of, the New York city\ntransit authority or any of its subsidiary corporations in furtherance\nof their respective purposes and powers or the Triborough bridge and\ntunnel authority in furtherance of its purposes and powers, such\nentities are hereby authorized and empowered to enter into and perform\nsuch contract or other arrangement and to undertake such activities.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>