<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1269-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1269_F">
        <num>1269-F</num>
        <heading>Mission statement and measurement report</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1269-f. Mission statement and measurement report. 1. The authority\nshall submit to the governor, the temporary president of the senate and\nthe speaker of the assembly, on or before October thirty-first, two\nthousand nine, a proposed authority mission statement and proposed\nmeasurements. The proposed mission statement and proposed measurements\nshall have the following components: a brief mission statement\nexpressing the purpose and goals of the authority; a description of the\nstakeholders of the authority and their reasonable expectations from the\nauthority, which stakeholders shall include at a minimum: the residents\nand taxpayers of the area of the state served by the authority, the\npersons that use the services provided by the authority, and the\nemployees of the authority and any employee organization; the goals of\nthe authority in response to the needs of each group of stakeholders;\nand a list of measures by which performance of the authority and the\nachievement of its goals may be evaluated.\n  2. The authority shall thereafter reexamine its mission statement and\nmeasurements on an annual basis, and publish on its website self\nevaluations based on the stated measures.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>