<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1269-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1269-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1269_A">
        <num>1269-A</num>
        <heading>Metropolitan transportation authority capital program review board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1269-a. Metropolitan transportation authority capital program review\nboard. 1. The metropolitan transportation authority capital program\nreview board is hereby created to exercise the powers, duties and\nprerogatives as hereinafter provided in sections twelve hundred\nsixty-nine-b and twelve hundred sixty-nine-c of this title.\n  2. The voting membership of the board shall consist of four persons\nappointed by the governor of which one shall be upon the recommendation\nof the temporary president of the senate, one upon the recommendation of\nthe speaker of the assembly and one upon the recommendation of the mayor\nof the city of New York. The member appointed upon the recommendation of\nthe mayor of the city of New York shall participate and be entitled to\nvote only with respect to bond resolutions and the capital program plans\nand any amendments or modifications thereof for transit facilities\noperated by the New York city transit authority, its subsidiaries and\nthe Staten Island rapid transit operating authority.  Upon\nrecommendation of the nominating party, the governor may replace any\nmember in accordance with the provision contained herein for the\nappointment of members. The governor shall designate one of the members\nto serve as chairman. Any determination of the board shall be evidenced\nby a certification thereof executed by all the members entitled to vote\non the matter so certified. Each member of the board shall be entitled\nto designate a representative to attend meetings of the board in his\nplace and to vote or otherwise act on his behalf in his absence. Notice\nof such designation shall be furnished in writing to the board by the\ndesignating member. A representative shall serve at the pleasure of the\ndesignating member during the member's term of office. A representative\nshall not be authorized to delegate any of his duties or functions to\nany other person.\n  3. The governor shall also appoint two non-voting members to the\nmetropolitan transportation authority capital program review board of\nwhich one shall be upon the recommendation of the minority leader of the\nsenate and one upon the recommendation of the minority leader of the\nassembly. Each non-voting member shall be entitled to designate a\nrepresentative to attend meetings of the board in his place.\n  4. The members of the metropolitan transportation authority capital\nprogram review board, and their representatives shall be deemed\nemployees within the meaning of such term as provided for in section\nseventeen of the public officers law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>