<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-04-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1270-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1270_I">
        <num>1270-I</num>
        <heading>New York city transportation assistance fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1270_I__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the "subway action plan account"; (ii) the "outer\nborough transportation account"; and (iii) the "general transportation\naccount".  The authority shall make deposits in the subway action plan\naccount of the moneys received by it pursuant to the provisions of\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1270_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twelve hundred ninety-nine-H of the tax law\nin accordance with the provisions thereof, shall make deposits in the\nouter borough transportation account of the moneys received by it\npursuant to the provisions of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1270_I__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twelve hundred\nninety-nine-H of the tax law in accordance with the provisions thereof,\nand shall make deposits in the general transportation account of the\nmoneys received by it pursuant to the provisions of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1270_I__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection twelve hundred ninety-nine-H of the tax law in accordance with\nthe provisions thereof, and pursuant to the provisions of section eleven\nhundred eleven-C of vehicle and traffic law.\n  2. Moneys in the subway action plan account shall be used for the\nexclusive purpose of funding the operating and capital costs of the\nmetropolitan transportation authority's New York city subway action\nplan. Such funds may be used for infrastructure including construction,\nreconstruction, reconditioning and preservation of transportation\nsystems, facilities and equipment, acquisition of property, and for\noperating costs including personal services, non-personal services,\nfringe benefits, and contractual services. Funds may also be used to pay\nor to reimburse the authority for its payment of debt service and\nreserve requirements on that portion of authority bonds and notes issued\nby the authority for capital costs of the metropolitan transportation\nauthority's New York city subway action plan.\n  3. Moneys in the outer borough transportation account shall be used\nfor the exclusive purpose of funding the operating and capital costs of\nmetropolitan transportation authority facilities, equipment and services\nin the counties of Bronx, Kings, Queens and Richmond, and any projects\nimproving transportation connections from such counties to New York\nCounty. Such funds may be used for infrastructure including\nconstruction, reconstruction, reconditioning and preservation of\ntransportation systems, facilities and equipment, acquisition of\nproperty, and for operating costs including personal services,\nnon-personal services, fringe benefits, and contractual services. Funds\nmay also be used to fund a toll reduction program for any crossings\nunder the jurisdiction of the metropolitan transportation authority or\nits subsidiaries or affiliates. Funds may also be used to pay or to\nreimburse the authority for its payment of debt service and reserve\nrequirements on th...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>