<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1270-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1270-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1270_B">
        <num>1270-B</num>
        <heading>Metropolitan transportation authority Dutchess, Orange and Rockland fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1270_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\n"Dutchess account"; (ii) the "Orange account"; and (iii) the "Rockland\naccount".\n  2. The metropolitan transportation authority Dutchess, Orange and\nRockland fund shall consist of moneys transferred by the authority\npursuant to subdivision four of section twelve hundred seventy-a of this\ntitle.\n  3. Moneys in the Dutchess account, the Orange account, and the\nRockland account shall on a quarterly basis be</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1270_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>paid to the counties\nof Dutchess, Orange and Rockland, respectively, for the purposes of\nproviding mass transportation operating assistance, including debt\nservice on bonds or notes issued for such purposes, or for providing the\nfollowing types of capital projects within such county: capacity and\ninfrastructure improvements to state, county, town, city, village roads,\nhighways, parkways or bridges; or state, county, town, city, village\nmass transportation projects; or (ii) transferred to the suburban\ntransportation fund pursuant to a resolution, which is irrevocable\nduring the term of any outstanding bonds or notes issued, adopted by the\ncounty legislature of Dutchess county, the county legislature of Orange\ncounty or the county legislature of Rockland county directing the\nauthority to make all such future transfers of funds from its respective\naccount to the suburban transportation fund. The first quarterly payment\nor transfer shall occur during the quarter beginning January first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>