<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1276-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1276-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1276-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1276-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1276-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1276-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1276-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1276_F">
        <num>1276-F</num>
        <heading>Metropolitan transportation authority transit performance metrics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"additional platform time" means for the subways the average added\ntime that customers spend waiting on the platform for a train, compared\nwith their scheduled wait time.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"additional train time" means for the subways the average\nadditional time customers spend onboard the train, compared with their\nscheduled on-train time.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"customer journey time performance" means for the subways the\npercentage of customer trips with an estimated total travel time within\nfive minutes of the scheduled total travel time.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"elevator availability" means percentage of facilities that\nrequire the use of stairs and have an operational elevator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"escalator availability" means percentage of facilities that\nrequire the use of stairs and have an operational escalator.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"additional journey time" means for the subways comparison of\nmeasured or estimated actual journey time compared to schedule.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"journey time" means for the subways time on platform and the time\non train. Journey time is calculated as either actual journey times that\ncustomers experience, or as scheduled journey times. Journey time and\nits components may be based on a manual or an automatically generated\nsample.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"major incidents" mean</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_h__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for the subway incidents that delay\nfifty or more trains where a train is considered delayed if it is more\nthan five minutes late or skips planned stops, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_h__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for the commuter\nrailroads incidents that delay ten or more trains greater than five\nminutes and fifty-nine seconds.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"lost time accidents" means a job related incident that results in\nthe inability of an employee to perform full job duties for at least one\nworking day beyond the day of the incident. Rates are based on lost time\naccidents per one hundred employees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"employees' lost time days" means for the commuter railroads the\ntotal number of calendar days employees' treating medical professionals\nhave determined that they cannot work due to an occupation injury or\nillness.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"employee lost time rate" means for the commuter railroads the\nnumber of occupational injuries or illnesses per two hundred thousand\nemployee hours worked.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"terminal on-time performance" means</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_l__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for the subways the\npercentage of trains arriving at their destination terminals as\nscheduled with a train counted as on-time if it arrives at its\ndestination early, on time, or no more than five minutes late, and has\nnot skipped any planned stops, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_l__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for the commuter railroads the\npercentage of trains arriving at their final destination terminals as\nscheduled with a train counted as on-time if it arrives at its\ndestination early, on-time or no more than five minutes and fifty-nine\nseconds late. Provided that the percentage of trains not arriving at\ntheir final destinations shall include unscheduled cancellations.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"additional data" means</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_m__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for the subways the percentage of\ntrains arriving at their scheduled terminals between four and five\nminutes after their scheduled arrival time;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_m__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for the commuter\nrailroads the percentage of trains arriving at their scheduled terminals\nbetween four and five minutes and fifty-nine seconds after their\nscheduled arrival time; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_m__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for commuter rails the percentage of\ncancelled trains.\n  2. Reporting. The authority shall take all practicable measures to\ncollect, compile and publish meaningful and informative performance\nmetrics for all customer trips provided by the New York city transit\nauthority subways, Long Island rail road and Metro-North commuter\nrailroad on a monthly basis including all applicable performance metrics\nas defined in subdivision one of this section. If the authority cannot\npracticably collect and compile any such performance metric for a\ncustomer trip type, it may, subject to the approval by the chairman of\nthe metropolitan transportation authority, substitute an equivalent\nperformance metric based on international public transport benchmarking\nand best practices that comparably measures system performance and\nservice delivery.\n  3. International benchmarking.</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall publish an\nannual report presenting the authority's performance in comparison with\nother national and international peer agencies. This report shall\ninclude, but not be limited to, the following metrics:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>total operating cost per car per mile;\n  (ii) maintenance cost per car per mile;\n  (iii) passenger journeys per total staff and contractor hours; and\n  (iv) staff hours lost to accidents.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1276_F__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall also provide an annual implementation report\nto the governor, the temporary president of the senate, the speaker of\nthe assembly, the minority leader of the assembly and senate, and the\nchairs and ranking members of the transportation and corporations,\nauthorities and commissions committees on or before January thirty-first\nevery year, and publish such report on its website.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>