<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-L"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-L"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1279-L"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-L/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-L/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1279_L">
        <num>1279-L</num>
        <heading>Right to share employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1279-l. Right to share employees. 1. It is hereby found and declared\nto be necessary and proper to authorize the authority, its subsidiaries,\naffiliates, and subsidiaries of affiliates, powers to effectuate and\nensure such entities continued financial viability, which is at issue\ngiven sizable operating deficits and significant capital needs. Allowing\nwholesale internal management reforms will create savings, combat\nentrenched bureaucracies, create streamlined, uniform, and efficient\nservices, ensure public accountability and reestablish public trust. In\norder to facilitate these necessary goals it is both reasonable and a\nlegitimate public purpose to provide systematic authority for the\nsharing of employees within and between the respective entities.\n  2. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the\nauthority, its subsidiaries, affiliates, and subsidiaries of affiliates\nshall each have the right to share employees within and between such\nentities and to assign such employees to perform any operation or\nfunction subject only to a determination that they are substantially\nsimilar to any operation or function currently performed. Substantially\nsimilar operation or function shall be determined exclusively by the\nauthority.\n  3. Nothing set forth in this subdivision shall be construed to impede,\ninfringe or diminish the rights and benefits that accrue to employees\nand employers through collective bargaining agreements, or impact or\nchange an employee's membership in a bargaining unit.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>