<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1279-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1279_E">
        <num>1279-E</num>
        <heading>Assignment, transfer, sharing or consolidating powers, functions or activities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any provision of this\ntitle or any other provision of law, general, special or local, the\nauthority shall develop and complete a personnel and reorganization plan\nno later than June thirtieth, two thousand nineteen which shall, in\nwhole or in part, assign, transfer, share, or consolidate any one or\nmore of its powers, duties, functions or activities or any department,\ndivision or office established therewith, or any of those of its\nsubsidiaries, or affiliates or their subsidiaries, within or between\nitself, its subsidiaries or affiliates or their subsidiaries, including,\nbut not limited to the New York City Transit Authority, the Long Island\nRail Road, the Metro North Commuter Railroad Company, MTA Capital\nConstruction, MTA New York City Bus, Triborough bridge and tunnel\nauthority, and the MTA Staten Island Railway, in a manner consistent\nwith the provisions of this section. Such plan shall identify common\nfunctions and assign, transfer, share or consolidate, in whole or in\npart, such functions between the authority and its subsidiaries,\naffiliates and subsidiaries of affiliates and shall be accompanied by an\nindependent evaluation of existing personnel within or between itself,\nits subsidiaries, or affiliates or their subsidiaries in coordination\nwith the authority's senior management. This plan shall be approved by\nthe board of the authority by July thirtieth, two thousand nineteen.\nUpon such approval, the board shall also appoint a director of MTA\ntransformation whose responsibilities shall include implementing the\npersonnel and reorganization plan and reporting directly to the board\nregarding the director's activities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon receipt of the review pursuant to section twelve hundred\nseventy-nine-f of this title the authority shall revise the personnel\nand reorganization plan to consider and incorporate the findings of such\nreview within ninety days of receipt. Such revised personnel and\nreorganization plan shall be approved by the board of the authority.\n  2. Such assignment, transfer, sharing, or consolidation pursuant to\nthis section shall occur only if approved by resolution of the board of\nthe authority, serving on behalf of the authority and any affected\nsubsidiary or affiliate or their subsidiary, adopted by not less than a\nmajority vote of the whole number of members of the authority then in\noffice, with the chairman having one additional vote in the event of a\ntie vote.\n  3. Pursuant to this section, any such assigning, transferring,\nsharing, or consolidating of powers, duties, functions or activities\nshall not be authorized where it would impair any rights and remedies of\nany holders of notes, bonds or other obligations issued by the\nauthority, its subsidiaries, or affiliates or their subsidiaries.\nNothing set forth in this section shall be construed to impede, infringe\nor diminish the rights and benefits that accrue to employees and\nemployers through collective bargaining agreements, or impact or change\nan employee's membership in a bargaining unit.\n  4. No consolidation shall result in the complete dissolution or merger\nwithin or between the authority or its subsidiaries, affiliates or their\nsubsidiaries.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>