<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1279-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1279_B">
        <num>1279-B</num>
        <heading>Transition--election to withdraw from the metropolitan commuter transportation district</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>January first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven. If any such\ncounty plans to withdraw from the district on January first, nineteen\nhundred eighty-seven, it shall</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no later than seventy-five days after\nthe effective date of this section, furnish the commissioner of\ntransportation, and chairman of the authority and the other counties\nwhich have an option to withdraw, a resolution adopted by the county\nlegislature providing notice of intent to withdraw, (ii) on or before\nOctober first, nineteen hundred eighty-six, furnish to the commissioner\nof transportation, the chairman of the authority and other counties\nwhich have an option to withdraw, a resolution adopted by the county\nlegislature providing for a public transportation plan. For the purposes\nof this section, a "public transportation plan" shall mean a plan that\nmaintains adequate and continuous public transportation services from\nthe withdrawing county to the city of New York or any terminus\npreviously served, provides a reasonable level of rail passenger\nservice, provides a schedule for implementing such service, protects the\npublic investment in the rail transportation system and any other\ncriteria deemed necessary by the commissioner of transportation. Prior\nto withdrawal pursuant to this paragraph or paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, a county must receive approval of its public transportation\nplan pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, (iii) on or before\nDecember fifteenth, nineteen hundred eighty-six, furnish the\ncommissioner of transportation, a copy of an agreement with the\nauthority or an operator of rail passenger service for the provision of\nrail passenger service to and from such county and the city of New York\nor any terminus previously served.\n  If a county planning to withdraw on January first, nineteen hundred\neighty-seven is unable to withdraw because it could not meet the\nrequirements of this paragraph, it may elect to withdraw pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision hereafter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>January first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight or January first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine. If any such county plans to withdraw on\neither January first, nineteen hundred eighty-eight or January first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-nine, it shall</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>no later than ninety days\nafter the first of January of the year immediately preceding the year in\nwhich such county plans to withdraw from the district, furnish the\ncommissioner of transportation, the chairman of the authority and the\nother counties which have an option to withdraw, a resolution adopted by\nthe county legislature providing notice of intent to withdraw from the\ndistrict, (ii) no later than one hundred twenty days after the first of\nJanuary of the year immediately preceding the year in which such county\nplans to withdraw from the district furnish to the commissioner of\ntransportation, the chairman of the authority and the counties which\nhave an option to withdraw a resolution adopted by the county\nlegislature providing a public transportation plan as described in this\nsection, (iii) on or before October first of the year immediately\npreceding the year in which such county plans to withdraw from the\ndistrict, furnish to the commissioner a copy of an agreement with the\nauthority or an operator of rail passenger service for the provision of\nrail passenger service to and from such county and the city of New York\nor any terminus previously served.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No later than thirty days after receipt of the public\ntransportation plan the commissioner of transportation shall, in\nwriting, either approve such plan as conforming with the requirements\nheretofore described or disapprove such plan as failing to meet such\nrequirements and the reasons therefor. Disapproval of a plan shall not\nprohibit a county from resubmitting a public transportation plan and\nsuch resubmitted plan shall be approved or disapproved no later than\nfifteen days after receipt by the commissioner of transportation. The\npublic transportation plan shall be subject to any state or federal\npublic hearing requirements which the authority would be subject to if\nthe authority made the changes proposed by such plan.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any such county which plans to withdraw from the district must\nmeet the requirements of this section prior to the effective date of\nwithdrawal, and no withdrawal for the purposes of this section shall\ntake effect unless such county furnishes the resolutions and agreement\nprior to the effective date of withdrawal.\n  2. The authority and any subsidiary corporation of the authority shall\nenter into an agreement or agreements with a county that plans to\nwithdraw from the district to transfer and assign to such county all\nauthority and subsidiary railroad facilities and operations, rights and\nobligations, and contract rights and obligations, including operating\ncontract rights and obligations, which are owned, operated, maintained\nor used directly or by contract or which are otherwise involved in the\nprovision of railroad services to such counties. Such agreement shall\nprovide, in the event a facility, operation, right or obligation is\nnecessary and material to the provision of rail passenger service in the\ndistrict or is not assignable under applicable bond covenants or\ncontracts or the parties agree that it should not be assigned, that the\nauthority or subsidiary thereof shall continue to hold and be\nresponsible for such facility, operation, right or obligation and that\nsuch county shall reimburse to the authority that portion of the cost to\nthe authority or subsidiary of its retention of such facility,\noperation, right or obligation that is allocable to such county. If the\nparties agree that the authority or subsidiary thereof shall operate the\nrailroad facilities in a county after the effective date of such\ncounty's withdrawal, the agreement also shall provide for the terms and\nconditions of the operation of such service.\n  3. Within forty-five days of the effective date of this section, the\nauthority and any subsidiary corporation of the authority shall provide\nto the counties of Dutchess, Orange and Rockland a written statement,\nincludi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>