<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-10-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1279-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1279_I">
        <num>1279-I</num>
        <heading>Open data reporting</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"open data website" shall mean the website data.ny.gov or such\nother successor website maintained by, or on behalf of, the state, as\ndeemed appropriate by the New York state office of information\ntechnology services under Executive Order 95 of 2013, or any successor\nagency or order;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"data" shall mean final versions of statistical or factual\ninformation that</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>are in alphanumeric form reflected in a list,\ntable, graph, chart or other non-narrative form, that can be digitally\ntransmitted or processed; (ii) are regularly created or maintained by or\non behalf of the metropolitan transportation authority, its subsidiaries\nand affiliates and are controlled by such entities; and (iii) record a\nmeasurement, transaction or determination related to the mission of the\nmetropolitan transportation authority, its subsidiaries and affiliates.\nThe term "data" shall not include image files, such as designs,\ndrawings, photos or scanned copies of original documents; provided,\nhowever, that the term "data" shall include statistical or factual\ninformation about image files and geographic information system data;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"data set" shall mean a named collection of related records\nmaintained on a storage device, with the collection containing data\norganized or formatted in a specific or prescribed way, often in tabular\nform; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"publishable MTA data" shall mean data that is collected by the\nmetropolitan transportation authority, its subsidiaries and affiliates\nwhere the authority, subsidiary or affiliate is permitted, required or\nable to make the data available to the public, consistent with any and\nall applicable laws, rules, regulations, ordinances, resolutions,\npolicies or other restrictions, requirements or rights associated with\nthe publishable MTA data, including but not limited to contractual or\nother legal orders, restrictions or requirements. Data shall not be\npublishable MTA data if making such data available on the open data\nwebsite would violate statute or regulation, including, but not limited\nto, disclosures that would constitute an unwarranted invasion of\npersonal privacy, endanger the public health, safety or welfare, hinder\nthe operation of government, including criminal and civil\ninvestigations, or impose an undue financial, operational or\nadministrative burden on the authority or its subsidiaries or\naffiliates.\n  3. As required by Executive Order 95 of 2013, the metropolitan\ntransportation authority shall designate a data coordinator, who shall:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have authority equivalent to that of a deputy commissioner or the\nhead of a division or department;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>have knowledge of data and resources in use by the entity; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be responsible for the compliance of the authority, its\nsubsidiaries and affiliates with the order.\n  4. The authority and its subsidiaries and affiliates shall make their\npublishable MTA data available on its website and the open data website\nas follows:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall create a catalogue of publishable MTA data\nwithin one hundred eighty days of the effective date of this section;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The metropolitan transportation authority shall within one hundred\neighty days of the effective date of this section, submit to the\nlegislature and publish on its shared internet website a schedule for\nmaking its publishable MTA data publicly available. Such schedule shall\nprovide for updating the data catalogue as appropriate; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1279_I__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The metropolitan transportation authority shall create schedules\nfor publishing all publishable MTA data within three years of the\neffective date of this section.\n  5. The metropolitan transportation authority, its subsidiaries and\naffiliates shall not be prevented from publishing data in advance of the\ndates set in their schedules.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>