<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1279-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1279-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1279_A">
        <num>1279-A</num>
        <heading>Management advisory board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1279-a. Management advisory board. 1. There is hereby created in the\noffice of the metropolitan transportation authority inspector general a\nmanagement advisory board, consisting of thirteen members appointed by\nthe governor, of whom two shall be appointed upon nomination by the\ntemporary president of the senate, two upon nomination by the speaker of\nthe assembly, one upon nomination by the minority leader of the senate\nand one upon nomination by the minority leader of the assembly. All\nmembers shall serve for a term of three years, except that, of the two\nmembers first appointed upon nomination by the temporary president of\nthe senate, one shall serve for a term of two years and one shall serve\nfor a term of one year; of the two members first appointed upon\nnomination by the speaker of the assembly, one shall serve for a term of\ntwo years and one shall serve for a term of one year; and, of two of the\nmembers first appointed by the governor without nomination by any other\nperson, two shall each serve for a term of two years and two shall each\nserve for a term of one year. One of the members appointed to the\nmanagement advisory board directly by the governor shall be designated\nby the governor to serve as its chairman.\n  2. All members of the management advisory board shall be residents of\nthe metropolitan transportation district, and shall be persons with\nsubstantial experience in the management of private enterprise, in the\ndelivery of public services, or in labor or labor-management relations.\n  3. The management advisory board shall assist the metropolitan\ntransportation authority inspector general in identifying ways to\nimprove services, reduce costs and increase the efficiency of the\nauthority and its subsidiaries, the Triborough bridge and tunnel\nauthority or the New York city transit authority and its subsidiary.\n  4. No later than April first, nineteen hundred eighty-four, and\nannually thereafter, the management advisory board shall submit to the\ngovernor and the legislature a report on its activities during the\nprevious year.\n  5. The office of the metropolitan transportation authority inspector\ngeneral shall provide the management advisory board with such staff\nsupport as may be required for the performance of its duties.\n  6. Members of the management advisory board shall serve without\ncompensation, but shall be reimbursed for expenses reasonably incurred\nin the performance of their duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>