<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1285-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1285_H">
        <num>1285-H</num>
        <heading>Inactive hazardous waste disposal site remedial programs</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1285-h. Inactive hazardous waste disposal site remedial programs.\n1. The corporation and any owner of an inactive hazardous waste disposal\nsite, or any state agency or any person or municipality identified by\nthe commissioner of the department of environmental conservation\npursuant to section 27-1313 of the environmental conservation law as\nresponsible for developing and implementing an inactive hazardous waste\ndisposal site remedial program pursuant to section 27-1313 of the\nenvironmental conservation law or section thirteen hundred eighty-nine-b\nof the public health law may enter into a contract for the development\nand/or implementation of such a program upon such terms and conditions\nas the corporation shall determine to be reasonable. Such contract shall\ninclude payment to the corporation pursuant to the contract. The\ncorporation may subcontract for the development or implementation of\nsuch a program.\n  2. When requested by the owner of an inactive hazardous waste disposal\nsite, or by any state agency or by any person or municipality identified\nby the commissioner of the department of environmental conservation\npursuant to section 27-1313 of the environmental conservation law as\nresponsible for the disposal of hazardous waste at such site, the\ncorporation may advise such owner, state agency, person or municipality\non matters relating to the development and implementation of an inactive\nhazardous waste remedial program and pursuant to a contract with such an\nowner, state agency, person or municipality may render technical\nassistance and may undertake research, planning and testing with respect\nto any such program. The corporation may make a reasonable charge to any\nsuch owner, state agency, person or municipality for the performance of\nany of the functions authorized by this subdivision.\n  3. The corporation shall have the authority to contract with the\ndepartment of environmental conservation to perform necessary work in\nconnection with inactive hazardous waste disposal site remedial programs\npursuant to section 27-1313 of the environmental conservation law. Such\ncontract shall include payment to the corporation pursuant to the\ncontract. The corporation may subcontract for the development or\nimplementation of such a program.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>