<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1285-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1285_I">
        <num>1285-I</num>
        <heading>Commercial and industrial waste audits</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_I__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>establish an application process consistent with the rules and\nregulations of the program;\n  (ii) establish by rule and regulation a commercial and industrial\nsolid waste audit program application evaluation procedure consistent\nwith the requirements of this section; and\n  (iii) establish by rule and regulation, upon consultation with the\ndirector of the budget, a sliding fee schedule to offset the costs of\nthe audit. The fee schedule established pursuant to this section shall\nbe intended to provide revenues sufficient to meet solely the costs\nincurred by the corporation in performing such audits. The chairman is\nauthorized and directed to deposit all money received in payment of fees\nunder this section in an account within the miscellaneous special\nrevenue fund.\n  c. Waste audits conducted pursuant to this section may include but\nneed not be limited to identification of:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_I__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all waste generated within the facility;\n  (ii) the regulatory requirements associated with the recovery, reuse\nor disposal of such waste, and the implications of such requirements for\nvarious reduction and reuse options;\n  (iii) any methodologies, processes, equipment, or production changes\nthat could be utilized to reduce the amount of waste generated and\nconsumer waste resulting from the product, process or service\nmanufactured, distributed or sold;\n  (iv) on site recycling or waste treatment technologies that could be\nutilized to reduce the need for waste disposal capacity;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_I__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>potential markets for waste generated by the facility, including\nlocal materials recycling programs, and the ability of such markets to\nreadily absorb the wastes generated by such facility; and\n  (vi) economic practicality of alternative waste reduction strategies.\n  d. Any person for whom a waste audit is prepared shall within one\nhundred eighty days submit to the corporation findings with respect to\nthe report and the status of steps to implement any recommended\nstrategies identified in such audit.\n  e. Beginning January first, nineteen hundred eighty-nine, the chairman\nshall make an annual report concerning the activities undertaken\npursuant to this section which shall include, at a minimum</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_I__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nnumber of businesses which received assistance, (ii) the nature of\nassistance provided through the programs, (iii) needs and problems\nconfronted by such businesses in establishing and implementing programs,\nand (iv) the number of businesses which applied for assistance. The\nchairman shall submit to the director of the division of the budget, the\nchairman and the ranking minority member of the senate finance committee\nand the chairman and the ranking minority member of the assembly ways\nand means committee an evaluation of the program prepared by an entity\nindependent of the authority. Such evaluation shall be submitted by\nSeptember first, nineteen hundred ninety and by September first every\ntwo years thereafter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>