<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1285-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1285_K">
        <num>1285-K</num>
        <heading>Financing of the design, acquisition, construction, improvement and installation of Riverbank Park</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all costs\nof the corporation in financing the design, acquisition, construction,\nimprovement and installation of all or any portion of Riverbank Park,\nand any claims arising therefrom,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all fees and other charges of, and\nall expenses incurred by, the corporation in connection with the\nissuance and administration of any bonds or notes issued by the\ncorporation for such purpose, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_K__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>amounts sufficient to pay all\nprincipal, premium, if any, and interest on such bonds or notes. Such\npayment or reimbursement may be made annually or otherwise, may be in\nfixed amounts or based on any factors or other matters, or may be made\nin any other manner, as such contract or contracts shall provide.\n  2. Any contract, lease, easement, license or other instrument entered\ninto by the corporation pursuant to subdivision one of this section may\nbe assigned or pledged by the corporation as security for its bonds or\nnotes issued for the purpose of financing the design, acquisition,\nconstruction, improvement and installation of all or any portion of\nRiverbank Park.\n  3. The corporation, any state agency, the city of New York or any\nagency or instrumentality thereof, may enter into any leases, easements,\nlicenses, or other instruments, for the purpose of granting to the\ncorporation any interest in real property which the corporation shall\ndeem necessary for the purpose of financing the design, acquisition,\nconstruction, improvement and installation of all or any portion of\nRiverbank Park.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision one of this section,\nany contract, lease, easement, license or other instrument entered into\nby the corporation with any state agency, pursuant to subdivision one of\nthis section, shall</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_K__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>provide that the obligation of the state or such\nstate agency to pay the amounts therein provided shall not constitute a\ndebt of the state within the meaning of any constitutional or statutory\nprovision, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_K__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>be deemed executory only to the extent moneys are\navailable, and provide that the obligation of the state or such state\nagency to make payments thereunder is subject to annual appropriation by\nthe legislature.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>