<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1285-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1285_D">
        <num>1285-D</num>
        <heading>Studies regarding design, construction and operation of industrial waste treatment, storage and disposal facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1285-d. Studies regarding design, construction and operation of\nindustrial waste treatment, storage and disposal facilities. 1. The\npurposes of the corporation shall include research and development of\ntechnologies for treatment, storage and disposal of industrial hazardous\nwastes consistent with economic, social and environmental objectives. In\ncarrying out such purposes the corporation shall prepare studies\nregarding the best technology or systems possible for the design,\nconstruction and operation of industrial hazardous waste treatment,\nstorage and disposal facilities including methods to recover materials\nor energy and to detoxify or neutralize wastes. Studies shall also be\nmade of methods to guarantee long-term maintenance, ownership,\nmonitoring, and environmental soundness of long-term hazardous waste\nstorage and disposal sites. With respect to matters of operation and\nlong-term maintenance, consideration shall be given to the various\noptions for locating such storage and disposal sites and for public or\nprivate ownership and for public or private operation consistent with\nthe maximum protection of public health, safety and welfare and the\nnatural environment.\n  2. Not later than one year from the effective date of this section,\nthe corporation shall submit a report to the governor and the\nlegislature of its studies conducted pursuant to subdivision one of this\nsection.\n  3. In exercising its responsibilities, the corporation shall also\ncooperate and act in conjunction with industrial, commercial, medical,\nscientific, public interest and educational organizations within the\nstate, and with agencies of the federal government, of the state and its\npolitical subdivisions, of other states, and joint agencies thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>