<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1285-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1285-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1285_G">
        <num>1285-G</num>
        <heading>Industrial materials recycling program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_G__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>cause, or significantly contribute to an increase in mortality or\nan increase in serious irreversible, or incapacitating reversible\nillness; or\n  (ii) pose a substantial present or potential hazard to human health or\nthe environment when improperly treated, stored, transported, disposed\nor otherwise managed.\n  b. "Industrial solid waste" means any garbage, refuse, sludge from a\nwaste treatment plant, or air pollution control facility, and other\ndiscarded material, including solid, liquid, semisolid, mining and\nagricultural operations as a result of a commercial or industrial\nprocess but does not include solid or dissolved material in domestic\nsewage, or solid or dissolved materials in irrigation return flows or\nindustrial discharges which are point sources subject to permits under\narticle seventeen of the environmental conservation law, or source,\nspecial nuclear or by-product material as defined in the Atomic Energy\nAct of 1954, as amended except as may be provided by existing agreements\nbetween the state of New York and the government of the United States.\n  c. "Industrial material" means hazardous waste and industrial solid\nwaste.\n  d. "Recovery and recycling" means any method or technique utilized to\nseparate, process, modify, convert, treat, or otherwise prepare\nindustrial materials so that component materials or substances may be\nused as raw materials or energy sources.\n  e. "Person" means an individual, trust, firm, joint stock company,\ncorporation (including a government corporation), partnership,\nassociation, state, municipality, commission, political subdivision of a\nstate, or any interstate body.\n  f. "Generator" means a person whose industrial activities produce\nindustrial material.\n  3. Industrial materials recycling program. a. The corporation shall\nundertake and be responsible for a program to encourage industrial\nmaterials reduction, recovery and recycling as hereinafter provided. The\ncorporation shall give first prior...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_G__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>identification of all hazardous wastes generated at the facility;\n  (ii) identification of the regulatory requirements associated with the\nstorage, treatment, or disposal of all hazardous wastes generated at the\nfacility;\n  (iii) identification of any methodologies, processes, equipment, or\nproduction changes which could be utilized by the facility to reduce the\namount or toxicity of hazardous wastes generated at the facility;\n  (iv) identification of any on-site recycling or waste treatment\ntechnologies which could be utilized to reduce the amount or toxicity of\nhazardous wastes disposed of by the facility; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_G__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>identification of any potential markets for hazardous waste\ngenerated by the facility, including the use of waste exchange markets.\n  c. The corporation shall establish by rule and regulation, upon\nconsultation with the director of the budget, a sliding fee schedule to\noffset the costs of conducting on-site audits. The fee schedule\nestablished pursuant to this section shall be intended to provide\nrevenues sufficient to meet solely the costs incurred by the corporation\nin performing such audits, provided that the corporation may use\ntechnical assistance grants it receives from the federal government,\nprivate foundations, or other institutions to reduce or eliminate fees\ncharged generators for performing such audits, and further provided that\nmonies appropriated to the corporation to carry out the purposes of this\nsubdivision shall not be used to provide financial assistance to waste\ngenerators for the purchase of manufacturing plants or equipment,\nproperty, real or otherwise, engineering or legal services, or any other\ncost incident to the actual implementation of a waste reduction or\nmanagement project. The chairman of the corporation is authorized and\ndirected to deposit all monies received in payment of fees under this\nsubdivision in an account within the miscellaneous special revenue fund.\n  d. Any person receiving audit services pursuant to this subdivision\nshall, within ninety days of the completion of such audit, submit to the\ncorporation a description of the steps it will take, if any, to\nimplement any recommended waste reduction, recycling, or treatment\nstrategies identified in such audit.\n  e. In implementing the small quantity generator hazardous waste audit\nprogram, the corporation is authorized to:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1285_G__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>hire or contract with an appropriate number of hazardous waste\nmanagement specialists to conduct on-site waste audits;\n  (ii) employ such public information methods as are appropriate to\nidentify and inform eligible hazardous waste generators of the existence\nof the waste audit program;\n  (iii) establish a small quantity generator hazardous waste audit\nprogram application consistent with the policies and goals of this\nsection; and\n  (iv) establish by rule and regulation a small quantity generator\nhazardous waste audit program application evaluation procedure\nconsistent with the policies and goals of this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>