<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1296"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1296"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1296"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1296/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1296/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1296/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1296/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1296">
        <num>1296</num>
        <heading>Exemption from taxation; payments in lieu of taxes</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>determine the full value of such property as of the applicable\ntaxable status date for the assessment role for which in lieu payments\nare being computed;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>determine the full value of such property as of such taxable\nstatus date attributable to improvements constructed or reconstructed by\nthe corporation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>deduct item</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>from item</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>multiply the full value determined in item</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by the ratio of\nassessed value to full value of other property on the same assessment\nroll;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the result determined in item</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1296__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall be the approved assessed\nvaluation for such property. The determinations of the full value and\nthe ratio of assessed value to full value shall be determined by the\ncommissioner.\n  4. Application for an approved assessed valuation shall be made by the\nassessor of the assessing unit within which such property is located.\nApplication shall be made as soon as practicable after acquisition of\nsuch property by the corporation. The application shall be made on a\nform approved by the commissioner of taxation and finance and shall\ncontain such information as such commissioner shall require.\n  5. Upon approval of such application by the commissioner the\ncommissioner shall certify such approved assessed valuation to the\nassessing unit and to the corporation. The approved assessed valuation\nshall be entered by the assessor or other local official on the\nassessment roll with the notation that such property is exempt from\ntaxation, special ad valorem levies and special assessments but\nqualifies for payments in lieu of taxes, special ad valorem levies and\nspecial assessments pursuant to this section. The approved assessed\nvaluation shall be treated for all purposes as taxable assessed\nvaluation and taxable full valuation on the assessment roll for which it\nis made. Amounts shall be extended against such approved assessed\nvaluation in the same manner and at the same time as taxes, special ad\nvalorem levies or special assessments are extended against taxable\nproperty. The appropriate collecting officer shall transmit a statement\nof the amounts computed as payable as in lieu of taxes, special ad\nvalorem levies and special assessments to the corporation. The\nprovisions of any general or special law relating to the collection and\nenforcement of taxes shall not be applicable to property subject to the\nprovisions of this section.\n  6. The terms "taxation," "special ad valorem levies," "special\nassessments" and "assessing unit" shall have the same meani...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>