<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1299-GG"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1299_GG">
        <num>1299-GG</num>
        <heading>Acquisition and disposition of real property by department of transportation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1299-gg. Acquisition and disposition of real property by\ndepartment of transportation. If funds are made available by the\nauthority for the payment of the cost and expense of the acquisition\nthereof, the department of transportation of the state of New York, when\nrequested by the authority, may acquire such real property in the name\nof the state as may be determined from time to time by the authority as\nbeing necessary, convenient or desirable to effectuate the purposes of\nthis title, may remove the owner or occupant thereof where necessary and\nobtain possession and, when requested by the authority, may dispose of\nany real property so acquired, all according to the procedure provided\nin section thirty of the highway law. The authority shall have the right\nto possess and use for its corporate purposes all such real property so\nacquired. Claims for the value of the property appropriated and for\nlegal damages caused by any such appropriation shall be adjusted and\ndetermined by such department with the approval of the authority or by\nthe court of claims as provided in section thirty of the highway law.\nWhen a claim has been filed with the court of claims, the claimant shall\ncause a copy of such claim to be served upon the authority and the\nauthority shall have the right to be represented and heard before such\ncourt. All awards and judgments arising from such claims shall be paid\nout of moneys of the authority. No real property may be acquired\npursuant to the provisions of this section for purposes other than a\ntransportation facility unless the governing body of the city, village\nor town in which such real property is located shall first consent to\nsuch acquisition.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1299-gg's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>