<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-DD"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-DD"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1299-DD"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1299_DD">
        <num>1299-DD</num>
        <heading>Rochester-Genesee regional transportation authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_DD__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is hereby created the Rochester-Genesee regional\ntransportation authority. The authority shall be a body corporate and\npolitic constituting a public benefit corporation. It shall consist of:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_DD__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>at least one member from each county that elects to join the\nauthority except that the county of Monroe shall have seven members of\nwhom three shall be appointed from the city of Rochester and four at\nlarge from the county of Monroe, (ii) and a voting member who is a\ntransit dependent individual appointed pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_DD__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision, and (iii) one non-voting member as described in paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_DD__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. The members shall be appointed by the governor\nby and with the advice and consent of the senate. The governor shall\nmake initial appointments to the authority in such number and from lists\nsubmitted as follows: three members shall be appointed to the authority\nfrom a list of not less than six names, all of whom must be residents of\nthe city of Rochester, submitted to the governor by the council of the\ncity of Rochester; four persons from a list of not less than eight\npersons, all of whom must be residents of the county of Monroe submitted\nby the legislature of the county of Monroe. Other counties electing to\nparticipate shall each submit to the governor a list of not less than\ntwo persons for each one hundred thousand or major fraction of the total\npopulation, as determined by the last federal decennial or federal\ncounty-wide special census. From the counties outside the county of\nMonroe which shall elect to participate, the governor shall appoint one\nmember for each one hundred thousand or major fraction of the total\npopulation, as determined by the last federal decennial or federal\ncounty-wide special census, with a minimum of one member to represent\neach county outside the county of Monroe so electing to participate. All\nmembers of the authority shall be residents of the area from which they\nare nominated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_DD__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The non-voting member of the authority, who shall not be\nconsidered in determining a quorum, shall be recommended to the governor\nby the labor organization representing the plurality of the employees\nwithin the authority and shall be a resident of the Rochester-Genesee\nregional transportation district as described in section twelve hundred\nninety-nine-cc of this title. Such non-voting member shall be appointed\nfor a term of five years, provided, however, that if at any time during\nthe term of appointment such non-voting member ceases to be affiliated\nwith the labor organization representing the plurality of employees\nwithin the authority, then such labor organization may at any time\nduring such term recommend a new member to the governor who shall serve\nthe remainder of the term. If the local bargaining unit decertifies its\nexisting union affiliation and certifies a new union, the union which\nrepresents the plurality of the employees may recommend a new member to\nthe governor who shall serve the remainder of the term. The chairman of\nthe authority, at his or her discretion, may exclude such non-voting\nmember from attending any portion of a meeting of the authority or of\nany committee held for the purpose of discussing negotiations with labor\norganizations, pending litigation involving the labor organization, or\nthe investigation, evaluation, or discipline of an employee.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_DD__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The voting member who is a transit dependent individual as\ndescribed in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_DD__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall be appointed by the\ngovernor for a term of five years. Such member shall be a resident of a\ncounty within the district. If a vacancy occurs for such position, a\nreplacement shall be appointed within six months pursuant to this\nprocess. Any local or statewide transit advocacy organization may\nrecommend one or more transit dependent individuals to be considered\npursuant to this section.\n  2. The members of the authority shall continue in office until their\nsuccessors are appointed and shall have qualified. One member appointed\nfrom the city of Rochester and one member appointed from the county of\nMonroe shall be appointed for terms ending July thirty-first, nineteen\nhundred seventy-one; one member appointed from the city of Rochester and\ntwo members appointed from the county of Monroe shall be appointed for\nterms ending July thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-two; and one\nmember appointed from the city and one member appointed from the county\nof Monroe shall be appointed for terms ending July thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-three. The member (or members) who is (or are)\nappointed from the other counties shall be appointed for a term (or\nterms) of five years, but all terminating on the thirty-first day of\nJuly of the fifth year. Thereafter, upon expiration of the term of a\nmember of the authority a successor shall be appointed by the governor\nfor a term expiring five years after the expiration of the term of his\npredecessor. If a vacancy shall occur by reason of a death,\ndisqualification, resignation or removal of a member, the successor\nshall be appointed by the governor for the unexpired term. Persons\nsucceeding members from the city of Rochester and the county of Monroe\non the authority shall be appointed from the same area and by the same\nprocedure as the original appointments. In the event of a vacancy as\ndefined herein, the successor appointed by the governor for an unexpired\nterm shall be from the...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>