<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1299-GG*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-GG*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1299_GG*2">
        <num>1299-GG*2</num>
        <heading>General powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_GG*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding section one hundred thirteen of the retirement\nand social security law or any other general or special law, the\nauthority and any of its subsidiary corporations may continue or provide\nto its affected officers and employees any retirement, disability, death\nor other benefits provided or required for railroad personnel pursuant\nto federal or state law. Notwithstanding any provisions of the civil\nservice law, no officer or employee of a subsidiary corporation, of the\nauthority, other than a public benefit subsidiary corporation, shall be\na public officer or a public employee;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_GG*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority and any of its public benefit subsidiary\ncorporations may be a "participating employer" in the New York state\nemployees' retirement system with respect to one or more classes of\nofficers and employees of such authority or any such public benefit\nsubsidiary corporation, as may be provided by resolution of such\nauthority or any such public benefit subsidiary corporation, as the case\nmay be, or any subsequent amendment thereof, filed with the comptroller\nand accepted by him pursuant to section thirty-one of the retirement and\nsocial security law. In taking any action pursuant to this paragraph\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_GG*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>, the authority and any of its public benefit subsidiary corporations\nshall consider the coverages and benefits continued or provided pursuant\nto paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_GG*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision;\n  10. To make plans, surveys, and studies necessary, convenient or\ndesirable to the effectuation of the purposes and powers of the\nauthority and to prepare recommendations in regard thereto and shall\nundertake a study of the port potential of Sodus Bay and shall undertake\na feasibility study of the merging of the Rochester-Monroe County Port\nAuthority into the Rochester-Genesee Regional Transportation Authority.\n  11. To enter upon such lands, waters or premises as in the judgment of\nthe authority may be necessary, convenient or desirable for the purpose\nof making surveys, soundings, borings and examinations to accomplish any\npurpose authorized by this title, the authority being liable for actual\ndamage done;\n  12. The authority may conduct investigations and hearings in the\nfurtherance of its general purposes, and in aid thereof have access to\nany books, records or papers relevant thereto; and if any person whose\ntestimony shall be required for the proper performance of the duties of\nthe authority shall fail or refuse to aid or assist the authority in the\nconduct of any investigation or hearing, or to produce any relevant\nbooks, records or other papers, the authority is authorized to apply for\nprocess of subpoena, to issue out of any court of general original\njurisdiction whose process can reach such person, upon due cause shown;\n  13. To do all things necessary, convenient or desirable to carry out\nits purposes and for the exercise of the powers granted in this title.\n  14. To enter into collective bargaining agreements with labor\nrepresentatives duly elected by the employees of the authority.\n  15. To insure or provide for the insurance of the authority's property\nor operations as required by law and also against such other risks as\nthe authority may deem advisable.\n  B. The authority shall file in the office of the commissioner of\ntransportation of the state of New York annual reports, after the close\nof each of...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_GG*2__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cost breakdown of real property acquired;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_GG*2__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Cost breakdown in appropriate units of facilities acquired;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_GG*2__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Operating revenues;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_GG*2__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Operating expenses.\n  The authority shall also file copies of such reports with the city\ncouncil of the city of Rochester and with the county legislative bodies\nin all counties where such authority operates.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1299-gg's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>