<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1299-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1299_Q">
        <num>1299-Q</num>
        <heading>Station operation and maintenance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1299-q. Station operation and maintenance. The operation,\nmaintenance and use of passenger stations shall be public purposes of\nthe counties of Erie and Niagara. The total cost to the authority and\neach of its subsidiary corporations of operation, maintenance and use of\neach passenger station within the district serviced by one or more\nrailroad facilities of the authority or of such subsidiary corporation,\nincluding the buildings, appurtenances, platforms, lands and approaches\nincidental or adjacent thereto, shall be borne by the county within the\ndistrict in which such station is located. On or before June first of\neach year, the authority shall determine and certify to the counties of\nErie and Niagara the total cost to the authority and its subsidiary\ncorporations, for the twelve-month period ending the preceding March\nthirty-first, of operation, maintenance and use of each such passenger\nstation within each county, respectively. On or before the following\nSeptember first, of each year, each such county shall pay to the\nauthority such cost so certified to it on or before the preceding June\nfirst. If for any such twelve-month period the authority determines that\nthe total revenues of any railroad facility will be such as not to\nrequire payment for the full amount of the costs of operation,\nmaintenance and use of the passenger stations served by such facility,\nthe authority in its discretion may reduce by a uniform percentage of\nestablished costs the amounts required of each county so served,\nprovided however, that the amount required of any such county shall not\nbe reduced for any such twelve-month period below the total cost to the\nauthority and its subsidiary corporations so certified of maintenance\nand use of such passenger stations so served in such county. Each county\nshall have power to finance such costs to it by the issuance of budget\nnotes pursuant to section 29.00 of the local finance law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>