<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1299-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1299_S">
        <num>1299-S</num>
        <heading>Five-year capital and operating plans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_S__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before\nOctober first, nineteen hundred ninety, and annually thereafter on or\nbefore April first, the authority shall adopt a capital program plan for\nthe five-year period commencing April first. The plan shall contain the\ncapital program, separately itemized, by the following functions: metro\ntransit operations, airport operations, and port operations.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_S__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The plan shall set goals and objectives by function for capital\nspending, establish standards for service and operations, describe each\ncapital project proposed to be initiated in each of the years covered by\nthe plan and explain how each proposed project supports the achievement\nof the service and operational standards established in the plan. The\nplan shall list separately by function those projects contributing to\nthe maintenance of the system infrastructure and those intended to\nenhance the system. The plan shall also include an estimated cost for\neach project and set forth an estimate of the amount of capital funding\nrequired for each year of the plan and the expected sources of such\nfunding. It shall also include a project schedule for the initiation and\ncompletion of each project. Each plan subsequent to the first such plan\nshall describe the current status of each capital project included in\nthe previously adopted plan.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_S__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the annual update, a quarterly capital plan status\nreport shall be provided to the committee on capital planning and shall\ninclude, but not be limited to, a description of any material change in\nthe scope, cost, funding or time of initiation or completion of a\nproject as adopted in the plan. The first such report shall cover the\nthree month period commencing April first, nineteen hundred ninety-one\nand shall be submitted no later than thirty days after the end of the\nquarter. Thereafter, quarterly reports shall be submitted on the last\nday of October, January, April and July.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_S__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before October first, nineteen hundred ninety, and\nannually thereafter on or before April first, the authority shall adopt\nan operating plan for the five-year period commencing April first. The\nplan shall include the annual estimated operating cost for the following\nauthority functions: metro transit operations, airport operations, and\nport operations. The plans shall also include the proposed method of\nfinancing for the level of service defined for each year of the plan and\nshall fully allocate the general authority costs to the authority's\nfunctions. The plan shall provide a narrative describing the overall\nfinancial condition of the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_S__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the annual update, the authority shall prepare for\nthe committee on finance and audit quarterly reports on the financial\ncondition of each of its functions. The first such report shall cover\nthe three month period commencing April first, nineteen hundred\nninety-one and shall be submitted no later than thirty days after the\nend of the quarter. Thereafter, quarterly reports shall be submitted on\nthe last day of October, January, April and July. The reports shall\ninclude a budgetary comparison of the most recent quarter and\nyear-to-date actual revenues and expenditures with the same time period\nin the previous year and with the projections for that time period based\non the board approved budget. The reporting for the metro transit\noperations shall be separate for the bus and light rail divisions.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_S__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before October first, nineteen hundred ninety, and\nannually thereafter on or before April first, the authority shall set\noperational performance goals and objectives for the metro transit\noperations, consistent with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_S__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of this\nsection and shall establish performance indicators to measure standards\nof service and operations. The performance indicators shall include:\nrevenue passengers, total passengers, revenue vehicle miles, revenue\nvehicle hours, number of employees by department, vehicle mean distance\nbetween failure, on-time performance for total service provided, the\ncost per revenue passenger, the cost per revenue vehicle mile and the\nrevenue-to-cost ratio.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_S__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall prepare for the committee on operations and\npersonnel quarterly reports on the operating performance of the metro\ntransit operations. The first such report shall cover the three month\nperiod commencing April first, nineteen hundred ninety-one and shall be\nsubmitted no later than thirty days after the end of the quarter.\nThereafter, quarterly reports shall be submitted on the last day of\nOctober, January, April and July. The reporting for the metro transit\noperations shall be separate for the bus and light rail divisions. The\nreport shall compare the performance indicators of the most recent\nquarter and the year-to-date performance indicators with the same time\nperiod in the previous year and with the annual goals established\npursuant to this subdivision.\n  4. Any and all annual reports, including interim reports, shall be\nsubmitted to the director of the division of the budget, the\ncommissioner of transportation and the chief executive officer of Erie\ncounty and Niagara county, the county legislatures of Erie county and\nNiagara county, the temporary president of the senate, the speaker of\nthe assembly, the chairpersons of the senate finance committee and the\nassembly ways and means committee, and the chairpersons of the senate\nand assembly transportation committees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>