<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FFF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FFF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1299-FFF"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1299_FFF">
        <num>1299-FFF</num>
        <heading>Filing five year performance, capital and operating finance plans</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_FFF__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before October first, nineteen hundred\nninety-four, and annually thereafter on or before April first, the\nauthority shall adopt an operational performance plan for the five-year\nperiod commencing April first. The plan shall set operational\nperformance plan goals and objectives, including but not limited to\nridership and passenger revenue goals and objectives for the period, for\nfixed route bus operations, and shall establish performance indicators\nto measure standards of service and operations. The performance\nindicators shall include: revenue passengers, total passengers, revenue\nvehicle miles, revenue vehicle hours, number of employees by department,\nvehicle mean distance between failures, on-time performance for total\nservice provided, the cost per passenger, the cost per revenue vehicle\nmile and the operating-revenue-to-cost ratio.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_FFF__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Quarterly reports shall be prepared for authority members on\noperating performance of fixed route bus operations. The first such\nreport shall cover the three-month period commencing April first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-five and shall be submitted no later than thirty\ndays after the end of the quarter. Thereafter, quarterly reports shall\nbe submitted on the last day of October, January, April, and July of\neach year. The report shall compare the performance indicators for the\nmost recent quarter and the year-to-date performance indicators with the\nsame time period in the previous year with the annual goals established\npursuant to this subdivision.\n  2.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_FFF__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before October first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, and\nannually thereafter on or before April first, the authority shall adopt\na capital program plan for the five-year period commencing April first.\nThe plan shall contain the capital program, separately itemized, by the\nfollowing functions: regular fixed route bus service, demand responsive\nbus service, and any aviation facilities and any marine facilities for\nwhich it currently has or shall assume responsibility.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_FFF__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The plan shall set goals and objectives by function for capital\nspending, establish standards for service and operation, describe each\ncapital project to be initiated in each of the years covered by the plan\nand explain how each proposed project supports the goals and objectives\nand the service and operational standards established in the performance\nplan. The plan shall list separately by function those projects\ncontributing to the maintenance of the system infrastructure and those\nintended to enhance the system. The plan shall also include an estimated\ncost for each project and set forth an estimate of the amount of capital\nfunding required for each year of the plan and the expected sources of\nsuch funding. It shall also include a project schedule for the\ninitiation and completion of each project. Each plan subsequent to the\nfirst such plan shall describe the current status of each capital\nproject which has a total estimated cost of one hundred thousand dollars\nor more and which was included in the previously adopted plan.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_FFF__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the annual update, a quarterly capital plan status\nreport shall be provided to the authority members and shall include, but\nnot be limited to, a description of any material change in the scope,\ncost, funding or time of initiation or completion of a project which has\na total estimated cost of one hundred thousand dollars or more, as\nadopted in the plan. The first such report shall cover the three-month\nperiod commencing April first, nineteen hundred ninety-five and shall be\nsubmitted no later than thirty days after the end of the quarter.\nThereafter, quarterly reports shall be submitted on the last day of\nOctober, January, April, and July of each year.\n  3.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_FFF__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On or before October first, nineteen hundred ninety-four, and\nannually thereafter on or before April first, the authority shall adopt\nan operating finance plan for the five-year period commencing April\nfirst. The plan shall include the annual estimated operating cost for\nthe following authority functions: fixed bus operations, demand\nresponsive bus operations, and any aviation facilities and any marine\nfacilities for which it currently has, or shall assume responsibility.\nThe plan shall include the proposed method of financing for the level of\nservice defined for each year of the plan and shall fully allocate the\nauthority's general costs to each of the above separate functions. The\nplan shall provide a narrative describing the overall financial\ncondition of the operating budget of the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1299_FFF__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the annual update, quarterly operating budget\nreports shall be prepared for the authority members on the financial\ncondition of each of the authority's functions. The first such report\nshall cover the three-month period commencing April first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-five and shall be submitted no later than thirty days\nafter the end of the quarter. Thereafter, quarterly reports shall be\nsubmitted on the last day of October, January, April, and July of each\nyear. The reports shall include a budgetary comparison of the most\nrecent quarter and year-to-date actual revenue and expenditures with the\nsame time period in the previous year and with the projections for that\ntime period based on the board approved budget. The reporting for fixed\nroute bus operations shall be separate from the reporting for demand\nresponsive bus service.\n  4. Any and all reports, including interim reports, shall be submitted\nto the director of the division of the budget, the commissioner of\ntransportation and the chief executive officers of Genesee, Livingston,\nMonroe, and Wayne counties, the county legislatures of Genesee,\nLivingston, Monroe, and Wayne counties, the temporary president of the\nsenate, the speaker of the assembly, the chairpersons of the senate\nfinance committee and the assembly ways and means committee, and the\nchairpersons of the senate and assembly transportation committees.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>