<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1299-FF"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-FF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1299_FF">
        <num>1299-FF</num>
        <heading>Formulation, filing and adoption of master plan; amendments</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1299-ff. Formulation, filing and adoption of master plan;\namendments.  The authority shall formulate a master plan for\ntransportation within the district. In formulating such master plan, the\nauthority shall consult and cooperate with the commissioner of\ntransportation and planning authorities in the areas of its operations,\nand shall utilize state, local or regional transportation planning. The\nauthority shall request and use existing studies, plans, surveys, data\nand other materials completed by or under development by any state\nagency or municipality or political subdivision of the state. The\nauthority shall file copies of such plan with the commissioner of\ntransportation, the Genesee-Finger Lakes Regional Planning Board, the\ncity council of the city of Rochester, the legislature of the county of\nMonroe, and with the legislative body of any other county, within the\ndistrict, affected by such plan, as hereinafter stated, except where\napplications for state or federal aid have been filed for any particular\ntransportation undertaking prior to the enactment of this legislation.\nThe plan shall contain information regarding the transportation system\nthat the authority intends to provide including information regarding\nthe facilities connected therewith, the services the authority\ncontemplates providing and the estimated costs and the proposed method\nof financing. During sixty days after the filing of the master plan with\nthe commissioner of transportation, in the Office of the Genesee-Finger\nLakes Regional Planning Board and with the legislative bodies as\naforesaid, said plan shall be available for public inspection at the\noffice or offices of the authority and at such other places in the areas\naffected, within the district, as the authority may designate. Not\nearlier than thirty days after the filing of said master plan with the\ncommissioner of transportation, the Genesee-Finger Lakes Regional\nPlanning Board and such legislative bodies, a public hearing on said\nplan shall be held by the authority. Notice of such a hearing shall be\ngiven to the commissioner of transportation, the Genesee-Finger Lakes\nRegional Planning Board and the legislative bodies as aforesaid and by\npublication once a week for two weeks prior to the said hearing at the\ntime and place fixed by the authority in newspapers of general\ncirculation within the areas affected, to be selected by the authority.\nThe last publication date shall not be less than five days before said\nhearing. Within thirty days following said public hearing, the authority\nshall provide a transcript of such hearing to the commissioner of\ntransportation, the Genesee-Finger Lakes Regional Planning Board and the\nlegislative bodies as aforesaid, together with any amendments the\nauthority may propose to the master plan. The authority shall request\napproval of the master plan, including such amendments as the authority\nmay propose, from the aforementioned legislative bodies and the\ncommissioner of transportation. Any part of said plan which is\ndisapproved by a political subdivision because it alters existing\nservices or the financing thereof within said political subdivision\nshall not become operative. This disapproval of part or parts of the\nplan shall not make the entire plan inoperative. Any part of said plan\nwhich is disapproved by the commissioner of transportation because it\nconflicts with a state-wide comprehensive master plan for transportation\nor the Rochester Metropolitan transportation plan or, in the absence of\nsuch plans, would have an adverse effect upon sound transportation\ndevelopment policy and planning, shall not become operative. If the said\nlegislative bodies or said regional planning board fail to act within\nsaid sixty days or in the case of the commissioner of transportation\nwithin ninety days after approval is requested, said failure shall be\ndeemed approval, and the authority may adopt the master plan by a\nmajority vote of its membership and may include changes, if any,\nrecommended by said commissioner of transportation, planning board or\nsaid legislative bodies.\n  The master plan may be amended from time to time in the same manner\nusing the procedures outlined herein for the original adoption, except\nthat proposed changes made by the authority upon recommendations of the\ncommissioner of transportation, said legislative bodies or the\nGenesee-Finger Lakes Regional Planning Board in the first plan may be\nembodied or continued by a majority vote of the authority without\nadditional hearings thereon as required for the amendments proposed to\nbe made.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>