<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-JJ"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-JJ"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1299-JJ"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-JJ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-JJ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-JJ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1299-JJ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1299_JJ">
        <num>1299-JJ</num>
        <heading>Co-operation and assistance of other agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1299-jj. Co-operation and assistance of other agencies. In the\ninterest of economy and to promote coordination of authority projects\nwith state, local, county and regional plans and also to carry out the\nobjective of full participation of all agencies in the development of a\ntransportation system and facilities to meet the objectives of this act,\nthe authority shall request and use existing studies, master plans,\nsurveys, data and other materials completed by or under development by\nany state agency or any municipality or political subdivision of the\nstate. The authority shall consult with and cooperate with the\ncommissioner of transportation and with planning authorities in the\nareas of its operations and shall utilize local or state planning. When\na project is contemplated by the authority, the authority shall submit a\npreliminary prospectus thereof to the commissioner of transportation for\nreview and comment and shall consider the report of the commissioner in\nformulating detailed plans for such project. When a project is\ncontemplated by the authority within the jurisdiction of any county\nplanning board or the Genesee-Finger Lakes Regional Planning Board, the\nauthority shall prepare a preliminary prospectus thereof, describing the\npurpose, general location, and nature of the project contemplated, with\nsuch further data relative thereto that the authority shall consider\npertinent. Within sixty days of receipt of such prospectus such planning\nboard or boards shall prepare a report thereon, commenting on its\nconformity or lack of conformity with any related official plan of the\nstate or region or any official planning agency within the region. Such\nreport shall be considered by the authority in formulating detailed\nplans for such a project. At the request of the authority, each such\nagency, municipality or subdivision which is engaged in highway or other\ntransportation activities or in land use or development planning, or\nwhich is charged with the duty of providing or regulating any\ntransportation facility or any other public facility, is further\nauthorized to provide the authority with information regarding its plans\nand programs affecting the transportation district so that the authority\nmay have available to it current information with respect thereto. The\nofficers and personnel of such agencies, municipalities or subdivisions,\nand of any other government or agency whatever, may serve at the request\nof the authority upon such advisory committees as the authority shall\ndetermine to create and such officers and personnel may serve upon such\ncommittees without forfeiture of office or employment and with no loss\nor diminution in the compensation, status, rights and privileges which\nthey otherwise enjoy.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>