<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1303"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1303"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1303"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1303/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1303">
        <num>1303</num>
        <heading>Capital District transportation authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1303__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is\nhereby created the Capital District transportation authority. The\nauthority shall be a body corporate and politic constituting a public\nbenefit corporation. It shall consist of not less than eight nor more\nthan fifteen members, including a chairman and shall have one non-voting\nmember as described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1303__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. At least one\nvoting member shall be a transit dependent individual who shall be\nappointed by the governor. If a vacancy occurs for such transit\ndependent individual member position, a replacement shall be appointed\nwithin six months, subject to the same appointment process within this\nparagraph. The members shall be appointed by the governor by and with\nthe advice and consent of the senate. The governor shall make initial\nappointments to the authority in such number and from lists submitted as\nfollows: three members shall be appointed to the authority from a list\nof six names, all of whom shall be residents of the county of Albany,\nfour of which names shall be submitted to the governor by the majority\nparty of the legislature of the county of Albany and two of which names\nshall be submitted by the minority party of such legislature; two\nmembers shall be appointed to the authority from a list of four names,\nall of whom shall be residents of the county of Schenectady, three of\nwhich names shall be submitted to the governor by the majority party of\nthe legislature of the county of Schenectady and one of which names\nshall be submitted by the minority party of such legislature; two\nmembers shall be appointed to the authority from a list of four names,\nall of whom shall be residents of the county of Rensselaer, three of\nwhich names shall be submitted to the governor by the majority party of\nthe legislature of the county of Rensselaer and one of which names shall\nbe submitted by the minority party of such legislature; two members\nshall be appointed to the authority from a list of four names, all of\nwhom shall be residents of the county of Saratoga, three of which names\nshall be submitted to the governor by the majority party of the\nlegislature of the county of Saratoga and one of which names shall be\nsubmitted by the minority party of such legislature.  Other counties\nelecting to participate shall each submit to the governor...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1303__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The non-voting member of the authority, who shall not be\nconsidered in determining a quorum, shall be recommended to the governor\nby the labor organization representing the plurality of the employees\nwithin the authority and shall be a resident of the Capital District\ntransportation district as described in section thirteen hundred two of\nthis title. The non-voting member shall be appointed for a term of five\nyears, provided, however, that if at any time during the term of\nappointment the non-voting member ceases to be affiliated with the labor\norganization representing the plurality of employees within the\nauthority, then such labor organization may at any time during such term\nrecommend a new member to the governor who shall serve the remainder of\nthe term. If the local bargaining unit decertifies its existing union\naffiliation and certifies a new union, the union which represents the\nplurality of the employees may recommend a new member to the governor\nwho shall serve the remainder of the term. The chairman of the\nauthority, at his or her discretion, may exclude such non-voting member\nfrom attending any portion of a meeting of the authority or of any\ncommittee held for the purpose of discussing negotiations with labor\norganizations, pending litigation involving the labor organization, or\nthe investigation, evaluation, or discipline of an employee.\n  2. The members of the authority shall continue in office until their\nsuccessors are appointed and shall have qualified. One of the members\nappointed from the county of Albany shall be appointed for a term ending\nJuly thirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-two; one of the members\nappointed from the counties of Albany, Schenectady, Rensselaer and\nSaratoga, respectively, shall be appointed for terms ending July\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred seventy-three, respectively; one of the\nmembers appointed from the counties of Albany, Schenectady, Rensselaer\nand Saratoga, respectively, shall be appoin...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>