<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1328"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1328"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1328"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1328/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1328/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1328">
        <num>1328</num>
        <heading>Central New York regional transportation authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nThere is hereby created the central New York regional transportation\nauthority. The authority shall be a body corporate and politic\nconstituting a public benefit corporation. It shall consist of not more\nthan twelve members, including a chairman and shall have one non-voting\nmember as described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision. At least one\nvoting member shall be a transit dependent individual who shall be\nappointed by the governor. If a vacancy occurs for such transit\ndependent individual member position, a replacement shall be appointed\nwithin six months, subject to the same appointment process within this\nparagraph. The members shall be appointed by the governor by and with\nthe advice and consent of the senate. The governor shall make initial\nappointments to the authority in such number and from lists submitted as\nfollows: three members shall be appointed to the authority from a list\nof not less than six names, submitted to the governor by the common\ncouncil of the city of Syracuse, five members from a list of not less\nthan ten names, submitted by the legislature of the county of Onondaga\nand two members shall be appointed from a list of not less than four\nnames submitted by the legislature of the county of Oneida. Other\ncounties electing to participate shall each submit to the governor a\nlist of not less than two persons for each one hundred thousand or major\nfraction of the total population, as determined by the nineteen hundred\nseventy or any subsequent federal decennial or federal county-wide\nspecial census, of the counties outside the county of Onondaga which\nshall elect to participate, from which number the governor shall appoint\none member for each one hundred thousand or major fraction of the total\npopulation, as determined by such federal decennial or federal\ncounty-wide special census, with a maximum of three members to represent\nsuch counties outside the county of Onondaga so electing to participate.\nIn addition to the members specified above, the governor shall appoint a\ntransit dependent individual as a voting member who resides within a\ncounty within the district. Any local or statewide transit advocacy\norganization may recommend one or more transit dependent individuals to\nbe considered for appointment pursuant to this sect...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1328__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The non-voting member of the authority, who shall not be\nconsidered in determining a quorum, shall be recommended to the governor\nby the labor organization representing the plurality of the employees\nwithin the authority. The non-voting member shall be appointed for a\nterm of seven years, provided, however, that if at any time during the\nterm of appointment the non-voting member ceases to be affiliated with\nthe labor organization representing the plurality of employees within\nthe authority, then such labor organization may at any time during such\nterm recommend a new member to the governor who shall serve the\nremainder of the term. If the local bargaining unit decertifies its\nexisting union affiliation and certifies a new union, the union which\nrepresents the plurality of the employees may recommend a new member to\nthe governor who shall serve the remainder of the term. The chairman of\nthe authority, at his or her discretion, may exclude such non-voting\nmember from attending any portion of a meeting of the authority or of\nany committee held for the purpose of discussing negotiations with labor\norganizations, pending litigation involving the labor organization, or\nthe investigation, evaluation, or discipline of an employee.\n  2. The members of the authority shall continue in office until their\nsuccessors are appointed and shall have qualified. One member\nrecommended by the common council of the city of Syracuse and one member\nrecommended by the legislature of the county of Onondaga shall be\nappointed for terms ending July thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nseventy-five; one member recommended by the common council of the city\nof Syracuse and two members recommended by the legislature of the county\nof Onondaga shall be appointed for terms ending July thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-six; and one member recommended by the common\ncouncil of the city of Syracuse and two members recommended by the\nlegislature of the county of Onondaga shall b...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>