<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1330"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1330"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1330"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1330/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1330/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1330">
        <num>1330</num>
        <heading>Formulation, filing and adoption of action plan; amendments</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1330. Formulation, filing and adoption of action plan; amendments.\nThe authority shall formulate an action plan for transportation within\nthe district. In formulating such plan, the authority shall consult and\ncooperate with the commissioner and the planning authorities in the area\nof its operations, and shall utilize state, local or regional\ntransportation planning. The authority shall request and use existing\nstudies, plans, surveys, data and other materials completed by or under\ndevelopment by any state agency or municipality. The authority shall\nfile copies of such plan with the commissioner, the central New York\nregional planning and development board, the common council of the city\nof Syracuse, the county legislature of the county of Onondaga, and with\nthe legislative body of any other county, within the district, affected\nby such plan, as hereinafter stated. The plan shall contain information\nregarding the transportation system that the authority intends to\nprovide including information regarding the facilities connected\ntherewith, the services the authority contemplates providing and the\nestimated costs and the proposed method of financing. During sixty days\nafter the filing of the action plan with the commissioner, the central\nNew York regional planning and development board and with the\nlegislative body or bodies as aforesaid, said plan shall be available\nfor public inspection at the office or offices of the authority and at\nsuch other places in the areas affected, within the district, as the\nauthority may designate. Not earlier than thirty days after the filing\nof said action plan with the commissioner, the central New York regional\nplanning and development board and such legislative body or bodies, a\npublic hearing on said plan shall be held by the authority.  Notice of\nsuch a hearing shall be given to the commissioner, the central New York\nregional planning and development board and the legislative body or\nbodies as aforesaid and by publication once a week for two weeks prior\nto the said hearing at the time and place fixed by the authority in\nnewspapers of general circulation within the areas affected, to be\nselected by the authority. The last publication date shall not be less\nthan five days before said hearing. Within thirty days following said\npublic hearing, the authority shall provide a transcript of such hearing\nto the commissioner, the central New York regional planning and\ndevelopment board and the legislative body or bodies as aforesaid,\ntogether with any amendments the authority may propose to the action\nplan. The authority shall request approval of the action plan, including\nsuch amendments as the authority may propose, from the commissioner and\nthe aforementioned legislative body or bodies. Any part of said plan\nwhich is disapproved by a political subdivision because it alters\nexisting services or the financing thereof within said political\nsubdivision shall not become operative.  The commissioner may disapprove\nany part of said plan if he finds that it conflicts with a state-wide\ncomprehensive master plan for transportation or the Syracuse\nmetropolitan transportation study and the Oswego-Fulton area\ntransportation study or, in the absence of such plans, would have an\nadverse effect upon sound transportation development policy and\nplanning. Any part of such plan so disapproved by the commissioner shall\nnot become operative. Disapproval of part or parts of the plan shall not\nmake the entire plan inoperative. If the said legislative body or bodies\nfail to act within sixty days or in the case of the commissioner within\nninety days after approval is requested, said failure shall be deemed\napproval, and the authority may adopt the action plan by a majority vote\nof its membership and may include changes, if any, recommended by the\ncommissioner, said planning board or legislative body or bodies.\n  The action plan may be amended from time to time in the same manner\nusing the procedures outlined herein for the original adoption, except\nthat a proposed amendment which is recommended by the legislative body\nor bodies affected thereby and approval by the commissioner may be\nembodied or continued by a majority vote of the authority without\nadditional hearings thereon as required for the amendments proposed to\nbe made.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>