<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1334"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1334"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1334"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1334/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1334/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1334/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1334/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1334">
        <num>1334</num>
        <heading>Cooperation and assistance of other agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1334. Cooperation and assistance of other agencies. In the interest\nof economy and to promote coordination of authority projects with state,\nlocal, county and regional plans and also to carry out the objective of\nfull participation of all agencies in the development of a\ntransportation system and facilities to meet the objectives of this act,\nthe authority shall request and use existing studies, master plans,\nsurveys, data and other materials completed by or under development by\nany state agency or any municipality or political subdivision of the\nstate. The authority shall consult with and cooperate with the\ncommissioner and with planning authorities in the areas of its\noperations and shall utilize local or state planning. When a project is\ncontemplated by the authority, the authority shall submit a preliminary\nprospectus thereof to the commissioner for review and comment and shall\nconsider the report of the commissioner in formulating detailed plans\nfor such project. When a project is contemplated by the authority within\nthe jurisdiction of any county planning board or the central New York\nregional planning and development board, the authority shall prepare and\nsubmit to such planning board or boards a preliminary prospectus\nthereof, describing the purpose, general location, and nature of the\nproject contemplated, with such further data relative thereto that the\nauthority shall consider pertinent. Within sixty days of receipt of such\nprospectus such planning board or boards shall prepare a report thereon,\ncommenting on its conformity or lack of conformity with any related\nofficial plan of the state or region or any official planning agency\nwithin the region. Such report shall be considered by the authority in\nformulating detailed plans for such a project. At the request of the\nauthority, each such agency, municipality or subdivision which is\nengaged in highway or other transportation activities or in land use or\ndevelopment planning, or which is charged with the duty of providing or\nregulating any transportation facility or any other public facility, is\nfurther authorized to provide the authority with information regarding\nits plans and programs affecting the transportation district so that the\nauthority may have available to it current information with respect\nthereto. The officers and personnel of such agencies, municipalities or\nsubdivisions, and of any other government or agency whatever, may serve\nat the request of the authority upon such advisory committees as the\nauthority shall determine to create and such officers and personnel may\nserve upon such committees without forfeiture of office or employment\nand with no loss or diminution in the compensation, status, rights and\nprivileges which they otherwise enjoy.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>