<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1353"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1353"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1353"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1353/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1353/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1353/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1353/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1353">
        <num>1353</num>
        <heading>Port of Oswego authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1353. Port of Oswego authority. The board heretofore created by this\nsection and known as the Oswego port authority is hereby continued and\nshall hereafter be known and designated as the port of Oswego authority.\nSuch board shall be a body corporate and politic, constituting a public\nbenefit corporation. The board shall consist of nine members, seven of\nwhom shall be residents of the city of Oswego and one of whom shall be a\nresident of the town of Scriba, with at least one thereof being a member\nof or recommended by the county planning board of the county of Oswego\ncommencing with the expiration of the term occurring first after July\nfirst nineteen hundred seventy-five. The terms of office of all members\nof the authority heretofore appointed and in office on March\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty, shall expire and terminate on such\ndate, provided, however, that they shall continue in office as such\nuntil the members first to be appointed by the governor as hereinafter\nin this section provided shall have qualified. The members of said\nauthority shall be appointed by the governor, by and with the advice and\nconsent of the senate. Of the members first appointed by the governor\ntwo members shall be appointed for a term ending September first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-one, two for terms ending September first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-two, two for terms ending September first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-three, and one for a term ending September first,\nnineteen hundred sixty-four. Any member appointed by the governor to\nfill any newly created membership on the board shall be appointed for a\nterm ending on the first day of September nineteen hundred seventy-six.\nThereafter, upon the expiration of the term of a member, a successor\nshall be appointed by the governor for a term expiring four years after\nthe expiration of the term of his predecessor. If a vacancy shall occur\nby reason of a death, disqualification, resignation or removal of a\nmember, the successor shall be appointed by the governor for the\nunexpired term. The members of the authority shall, before entering upon\nthe duties of their office, take the constitutional oath of office and\nfile the same in the office of the secretary of state. The authority\nshall organize by the selection from its members of a chairman, vice\nchairman, and a secretary. It shall adopt such rules as it may deem\nnecessary and proper for the government of its own proceedings and the\nregulation and use of port facilities and industrial projects in the\ndistrict, and shall keep a record of its proceedings. Rules pertaining\nto the regulation and use of port facilities and industrial projects\nshall be fair, reasonable and impartial and shall be subject to any law,\nrule or regulation administered by the interstate commerce commission or\nthe public service commission or the water resources commission, or any\nother department or commission of the United States of America or of the\nstate of New York, which has the jurisdiction in such matters and shall\nnot operate to deprive any person or corporation, private or public, of\nany property without due process of law. A majority of the members of\nthe authority shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business\nand the concurrence of a majority of all members shall be necessary to\nthe validity of any order of the authority. A member may be removed by\nthe governor for cause after giving such member a copy of the charges\nand an opportunity to be heard thereon. The members of the authority\nshall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement\nof their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of\ntheir official duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>