<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1355"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1355"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1355"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1355/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1355/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1355/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1355/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1355">
        <num>1355</num>
        <heading>Orders, service thereof and penalties</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1355. Orders, service thereof and penalties. The authority may make,\nand cause to be served upon any corporation or individual, within the\nport district, excepting the city of Oswego and the town of Scriba, any\nreasonable order which it may determine to be necessary for the proper\ndevelopment, maintenance and use of the port, relating to the\nconstruction, equipment, repair, maintenance, use and rental of any\ndock, wharf, slip, terminal, warehouse or industrial project owned or\nleased by any such corporation or individual within the district. There\nshall be served with a copy of the order a notice specifying a day, not\nless than ten days after such service, when such corporation or\nindividual may appear before the authority, present written objections\nto the making of the order and be heard on such objections. If no such\nobjections are filed within the time stated, or if the order be\nsustained as the result of such hearing, either in its original or\nmodified form, such order shall be final, subject only to review by a\ncourt of competent jurisdiction. When an order of the authority shall\nbecome final, including the termination of any court proceeding\nsustaining the order, or of the time for beginning such a proceeding if\nnone be brought, if the corporation or individual shall fail to obey it,\nor if any corporation or individual shall violate a lawful rule of the\nauthority, the authority may commence and maintain an action or\nproceeding in an appropriate court having jurisdiction, for the purpose\nof having such disobedience to an order or violation of a rule prevented\nor obedience enforced, either by mandamus or injunction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>