<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1357"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1357"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1357"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1357/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1357/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1357/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1357/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1357">
        <num>1357</num>
        <heading>Real estate and title thereto</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1357. Real estate and title thereto. 1. The authority may lease or\nacquire title to real and personal property including water front\nproperty, ferries, bridges, wharf property, land under water, public\nlandings, wharves and docks in the name of "Oswego port authority" by\npurchase, grant or gift from the city of Oswego, town of Scriba, state\nof New York, United States of America, or from any corporation or\nindividual for the development of port facilities and industrial\nprojects in the district, and shall have the power to sell, subject to\napproval by order of the supreme court, lease or otherwise dispose of\nsaid real property and shall retain and have the power to use the\nproceeds of sale, rentals or other moneys derived from the disposition\nthereof for its purposes. Any instrument affecting real property shall\nbe signed by the chairman of the authority, attested by its secretary\nand have the seal of the authority affixed thereto.\n  1-a. Authority is hereby conferred upon the city of Oswego and the\ntown of Scriba to give, lease, sell, grant and convey real and personal\nproperty including water front property, ferries, bridges, wharf\nproperty, land under water, public landings, wharves and docks to the\nauthority, with or without consideration as such city or town shall\ndetermine.\n  2. The authority shall have power to condemn real property located\nwithin its territorial limits and owned by any person or corporation,\nexcepting a person or corporation subject to the jurisdiction,\nsupervision and regulation of the Public Service Commission, which the\nauthority deems necessary for the development of port facilities and\nindustrial projects in the district. The authority shall exercise the\npower of condemnation hereby granted in the manner provided in the\ncondemnation law.\n  3. The authority and the city of Oswego may enter into contracts for\nthe acquisition by the city or the authority of real property for the\nbenefit of and in the name of the city of Oswego for the purpose of\nwidening existing streets, avenues, parkways, roads or highways or for\nnew streets, avenues, parkways, roads or highways to port facilities\nwithin the port district, or partly for such purpose and partly for\nother city purposes. Such contracts may provide for the work of\nimprovement by the city. The city may close such streets, avenues,\nparkways, roads or highways as may be necessary or convenient.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>