<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1369"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1369"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1369"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1369/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1369/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1369/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1369/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1369">
        <num>1369</num>
        <heading>Bond legal investments</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1369. Bond legal investments. The bonds of the authority are hereby\nmade securities in which all public officers and bodies of the state of\nNew York and all municipalities and municipal subdivisions thereof, all\ninsurance companies and associations and other persons carrying on an\ninsurance business, all banks, bankers, trust companies, savings banks\nand savings associations, including savings and loan associations,\nbuilding and loan associations, investment companies and other persons,\nexcept as hereinafter provided, who are now, or may hereafter be,\nauthorized to invest in bonds or other obligations of the state, may\nproperly and legally invest funds, including capital, in their control\nor belonging to them, provided that, notwithstanding the provisions of\nany other general or special law to the contrary, the bonds shall not be\neligible for the investment of funds, including capital, of trusts,\nestates or guardianships under the control of individual administrators,\nguardians, executors, trustees and other individual fiduciaries. The\nbonds are also hereby made securities which may be deposited with and\nmay be received by all public officers and bodies of the state of New\nYork and all municipalities and municipal subdivisions thereof for any\npurpose for which the deposit of bonds or other obligations of the state\nis now, or may hereafter be, authorized.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>