<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1377"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1377"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1377"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1377/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1377/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1377/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1377/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1377">
        <num>1377</num>
        <heading>Ogdensburg and Waddington port districts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1377. Ogdensburg and Waddington port districts. There are hereby\ncreated and established two districts: the Ogdensburg port district and\nthe Waddington port district. The Ogdensburg port district shall embrace\nthe city of Ogdensburg and the town of Lisbon and the town of\nOswegatchie; a strip of land five hundred feet in width in the towns of\nMadrid and Potsdam, in the county of St. Lawrence, being two hundred\nfifty feet on each side of the center line of that portion of the\nRutland railway corporation right-of-way line extending from the city of\nOgdensburg to the village of Norwood, town of Potsdam, which portion\ncommences at the bounds of the said two-mile area and terminates at\nRutland railway corporation chaining station 1325+48 and a further strip\nof land five hundred feet in width in the towns of Canton and DeKalb in\nthe county of St. Lawrence, being two hundred fifty feet on each side of\nthe center line of that portion of the Penn Central transportation\ncompany right-of-way extending from the city of Ogdensburg to the town\nof DeKalb which portion commences at the bounds of the said two mile\narea and terminates at Penn Central transportation company chaining\nstation 0+0 (mile post 0.0) and all lands and water under and in the St.\nLawrence river lying or situated within the boundaries of the city of\nOgdensburg subject to the right, title, interest and control of the\nstate under the constitution or any law of the state of New York and\nsubject to the right, title, interest and control of the United States\nunder any law of the United States of America. The Waddington port\ndistrict should embrace the village of Waddington, and all lands and\nwater under and in the St. Lawrence river and Little river bounded on\nthe east by the northerly extension of the village of Waddington\neasterly bounds, on the west by the northerly extension of the village\nof Waddington westerly bounds and on the north by the international\nboundary line between Canada and the United States excluding therefrom\nOgden island and all lands and water under and in the St. Lawrence river\nlying to the north of Ogden island; and a strip of land five hundred\nfeet in width in the towns of Waddington, Madrid, Louisville and Norfolk\nbeing two hundred and fifty feet on each side of the center line of the\nNorwood and St. Lawrence railroad company extending from the village of\nWaddington, to and including the village of Norwood and an industrial\nsite of approximately 40 acres adjacent to Norwood and St. Lawrence\nrailroad company mile post number two, subject to the right, title,\ninterest and control of the state under the constitution or any law of\nthe state of New York and subject to the right, title, interest and\ncontrol of the United States under any law of the United States of\nAmerica.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>