<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1378"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1378"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1378"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1378/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1378/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1378/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1378/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1378">
        <num>1378</num>
        <heading>Ogdensburg port authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1378. Ogdensburg port authority. A board to be known as the\nOgdensburg port authority is hereby created. Such board shall be a body\ncorporate and politic, constituting a public benefit corporation. The\nboard shall consist of five members all of whom shall be residents of\nthe city of Ogdensburg. The members of said authority shall be appointed\nby the mayor. One member shall be designated by the mayor to serve until\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-eight; one to serve until\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred fifty-nine; one to serve until\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty; one to serve until\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-one; and one to serve\nuntil December thirty-first, nineteen hundred sixty-two. Upon the\nexpiration of the term of a member, a successor shall be appointed by\nthe mayor for a term expiring five years after the expiration of the\nterm of his predecessor. If a vacancy shall occur by reason of a death,\ndisqualification, resignation or removal of a member, the successor\nshall be appointed by the mayor for the unexpired term. The members of\nthe authority shall, before entering upon the duties of their office,\ntake the constitutional oath of office and file the same in the office\nof the clerk of the county of St. Lawrence. The authority shall organize\nby the selection from its members of a chairman, vice chairman, and a\nsecretary. It shall adopt such rules as it may deem necessary and proper\nfor the government of its own proceedings and the regulation and use of\nport facilities in the district, and shall keep a record of its\nproceedings. Rules pertaining to the regulation and use of port\nfacilities shall be fair, reasonable and impartial and shall be subject\nto any law, rule or regulation administered by the interstate commerce\ncommission or the public service commission or the water power and\ncontrol commission, or any other department or commission of the United\nStates of America or of the state of New York, which has the\njurisdiction in such matters and shall not operate to deprive any person\nor corporation, private or public, of any property without due process\nof law. A majority of the members of the authority shall constitute a\nquorum for the transaction of business and the concurrence of a majority\nof all members shall be necessary to the validity of any order of the\nauthority. A member may be removed by the appointing power for cause\nafter giving such member a copy of the charges and an opportunity to be\nheard in his own defense in person or by counsel upon not less than ten\ndays' notice. The decision of the appointing power shall be subject to\nreview pursuant to article seventy-eight of the civil practice act. The\nmembers of the authority shall serve without compensation but shall be\nentitled to reimbursement of their actual and necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of their official duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>