<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1382"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1382"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1382"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1382/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1382/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1382/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1382/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1382">
        <num>1382</num>
        <heading>Real estate and title thereto</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1382. Real estate and title thereto. 1. The authority may lease or\nacquire title to real and personal property including water front\nproperty, ferries, bridges, wharf property, land under water, public\nlandings, wharves and docks in the name of "Ogdensburg port authority"\nby purchase, grant or gift from the city of Ogdensburg, state of New\nYork, United States of America, or from any corporation or individual\nfor the development of port facilities in the district, and shall have\nthe power to sell, subject to approval by order of the supreme court,\nlease or otherwise dispose of said real property and shall retain and\nhave the power to use the proceeds of sale, rentals or other moneys\nderived from the disposition thereof for its purposes. Any instrument\naffecting real property shall be signed by the chairman of the\nauthority, attested by its secretary and have the seal of the authority\naffixed thereto.\n  2. Authority is hereby conferred upon the city to give, lease, sell,\ngrant and convey real and personal property including water front\nproperty, ferries, bridges, wharf property, land under water, public\nlandings, wharves and docks to the authority, with or without\nconsideration as such city shall determine.\n  3. The authority shall have power to condemn real property located\nwithin its territorial limits and owned by any person or corporation,\nexcepting a person or corporation subject to the jurisdiction,\nsupervision and regulation of the public service commission, which the\nauthority deems necessary for the development of port facilities in the\ndistrict. The authority shall exercise the power of condemnation hereby\ngranted in the manner provided in the condemnation law.\n  4. The authority and the city may enter into contracts for the\nacquisition by the city or the authority of real property for the\nbenefit of and in the name of the city for the purpose of widening\nexisting streets, avenues, parkways, roads or highways or for new\nstreets, avenues, parkways, roads or highways to port facilities within\nthe port district, or partly for such purpose and partly for other city\npurposes. Such contracts may provide for the work of improvement by the\ncity. The city may close such streets, avenues, parkways, roads or\nhighways as may be necessary or convenient.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>