<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1383"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1383"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1383"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1383/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1383/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1383/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1383/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1383">
        <num>1383</num>
        <heading>Grants from commissioner of general services</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1383__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any and all\nexecutory contracts, agreements and permits for the use of said port\nfacilities by third persons as tenants, licensees, or otherwise, or for\nthe docking, mooring or anchorage thereat of vessels owned by third\npersons, or for the loading, unloading, handling, storage, processing or\nmanipulation of grain, freight, or other property of third persons, or\nfor the rendering of any other services to third persons at said pier\nproperties as wharfinger or warehouseman or otherwise;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1383__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any and all\nexecutory contracts and agreements for the furnishing by third persons\nof electricity, gas, steam, water or telephone service at said port\nfacilities.\n  6. The authority shall not grant or convey title to said port\nfacilities to any person or legal entity other than the people of the\nstate of New York.\n  7. If the authority shall violate any of the conditions herein set\nforth or such other conditions as the board of commissioners of the land\noffice heretofore included in any lease or grant of said port facilities\nor any other conditions as the office of general services may include in\nany lease or grant of said port facilities and such violation of any of\nsaid conditions shall not have been remedied by the authority within\nninety days after the giving of notice of the existence of such\nviolation by the commissioner of transportation of the state of New\nYork, then at the option of the state such port facilities shall revert\nto the people of the state of New York.\n  8. If the port facilities revert to the people of the state of New\nYork they shall be and shall be deemed to be unappropriated state lands.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>