<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1385"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1385"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1385"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1385/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1385/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1385/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1385/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1385">
        <num>1385</num>
        <heading>Contracts; manner of letting</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1385. Contracts; manner of letting. Where the expense of the\nconstruction of a project, of a part thereof, or an addition, betterment\nor extension to the port facilities, or the purchase of materials,\nsupplies and equipment involves an expense exceeding two thousand\ndollars, the authority shall advertise for bids and shall award the\ncontract to the lowest responsible bidder fully complying with the plans\nand specifications. Such advertisement shall be published once, not less\nthan one week prior to the date fixed for the opening of bids, in one\nnewspaper having a general circulation in the city of Ogdensburg. The\nauthority may make rules and regulations for the submission of bids and\naward of contract thereon and may provide in such rules and regulations\nthat no performance, bond or undertaking need be furnished by the\ncontractor for the purchase of materials, supplies and equipment in an\namount not exceeding two thousand dollars.  No contract shall be entered\ninto for the construction of a project, or part thereof, or for an\naddition, betterment or extension to the facilities or for the purchase\nof materials, supplies and equipment in an amount exceeding two thousand\ndollars unless the contractor shall give an undertaking with a\nsufficient surety or sureties approved by the authority and in the\namount fixed by the authority for the faithful performance of the\ncontract. As to a contract entered into for the construction, the\nundertaking shall provide, among other things, that the person or\ncorporation entering into such a contract will pay for all materials\nfurnished and services rendered in the performance of the contract and\nthat a person or corporation furnishing such materials or rendering such\nservices may maintain an action to recover for the same against the\nobligor in the undertaking as though such person or corporation were\nnamed therein, provided the action is brought within one year after the\ntime the cause of action accrued. In case of public emergency involving\naccident or other damage by which the port facilities, or any part\nthereof, shall become disabled, the authority may cause all necessary\nrepairs thereto to be made without advertisement, bidding and the\nletting of a formal contract therefor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>