<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1387"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1387"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1387"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1387/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1387/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1387/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1387/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1387">
        <num>1387</num>
        <heading>Special port development and improvement powers</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1387__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the\ndevelopment, improvement, promotion, preservation and utilization of the\nport district and projects, including the Ogdensburg municipal airport\nand the industrial park development on lands wholly or in part acquired\npursuant to the provisions of subdivision one of section thirteen\nhundred eighty-three of this chapter; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1387__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the payment and\ncollection of fees, charges, rentals and other receipts from its\nproperties and facilities within the port district, including the\nOgdensburg municipal airport and the industrial park development, which\nfees, charges, rentals and other receipts are hereinafter referred to as\n"port revenue." Until such time as the state of New York is fully\nreimbursed by the authority for the total amount of money advanced by\nthe state to the authority no rule, regulation, schedule or rate in\nrelation to or governing port revenue shall become effective or\ncontrolling unless approved by the director of the budget of the state\nof New York.\n  2. Until such time as the state of New York is fully reimbursed for\nthe total amount of money advanced by the state to the authority all\nport revenue received by the authority shall be paid to the state\ncomptroller as agent of the authority and deposited in a separate bank\naccount or accounts to be known as the "Ogdensburg port fund." The\nmoneys in such fund shall be available subject to the approval of the\ndirector of the budget of the state of New York for the payment of any\nand all costs and expenditures incurred in relation to the acquisition\nof property, construction, equipment, maintenance, repair, operation and\nimprovement of the industrial park development, port and airport. The\nmoneys of the Ogdensburg port fund when made available shall be paid\nfrom such fund on the audit and warrant of the state comptroller on\nvouchers approved solely by the chairman of the authority or his duly\ndesignated officer.\n  3. All moneys in the Ogdensburg port fund in excess of the sum of two\nhundred thousand dollars shall on the first day of each month be paid by\nthe authority to the state comptroller provided, however, that effective\nJune thirty, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, the director of the budget\nand the authority shall establish within the provisions of a written\nagreement between the authority and th...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>