<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1427"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1427"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1427"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1427/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1427/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1427/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1427/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1427">
        <num>1427</num>
        <heading>White Plains parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1427. White Plains parking authority. 1. A board to be known as\n"White Plains parking authority" is hereby created. Such board shall be\na body corporate and politic, constituting a public benefit corporation.\nIt shall consist of a chairman and six other members, who shall be\nappointed by the mayor of the city. On or before the first day of July,\nnineteen hundred eighty, the mayor shall appoint four members, two for\nterms of office expiring on the thirtieth day of June, nineteen hundred\neighty-two, and two for terms of office expiring on the thirtieth day of\nJune, nineteen hundred eighty-three.  The two members appointed for\nterms of office expiring on the thirtieth day of June, nineteen hundred\neighty-two, shall be deemed to have been appointed to fill two existing\nvacancies in such board occurring by the expiration of the terms of\noffice of two members heretofore appointed for terms expiring on the\nthirtieth day of June, nineteen hundred seventy-nine. Each of three\nmembers whose term of office expires on the thirtieth day of June,\nnineteen hundred eighty-one, shall continue to serve until such date or\nuntil the appointment and qualification of his successor. The terms of\noffice of all successor members shall be three years, so that the term\nof office of one-third of such members, as nearly as possible, shall\nexpire on the thirtieth day of June in each year. Each member shall\ncontinue to serve until the appointment and qualification of his\nsuccessor. Vacancies in such board occurring otherwise than by the\nexpiration of term shall be filled for the unexpired term. The members\nof the board shall choose from their number a vice-chairman. The mayor\nmay remove any member of the board for inefficiency, neglect of duty or\nmisconduct in office, giving him a copy of the charges against him and\nan opportunity of being heard in person, or by counsel, in his defense\nupon not less than ten days' notice. The members of the board shall be\nentitled to no compensation for their services but shall be entitled to\nreimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties. The powers of the authority shall\nbe vested in and exercised by a majority of the members of the board\nthen in office.  Such board may delegate to one or more of its members\nor to its officers, agents and employees such powers and duties as it\nmay deem proper.\n  2. It is hereby determined and declared that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers, purposes, and duties are in all respects for\nthe benefit of the people of the city of White Plains and the state of\nNew York, for the improvement of their health, welfare and prosperity\nand that said purposes are public purposes and that the authority is and\nwill be performing an essential governmental function in the exercise of\nthe powers conferred upon it by this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>