<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1475-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1475-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1475-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1475-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1475-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1475-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1475-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1475_D">
        <num>1475-D</num>
        <heading>Purpose and powers of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1475-d. Purpose and powers of the authority. The purpose of the\nauthority shall be to construct, operate and maintain one or more\nprojects in the city. To carry out such purpose, the authority shall\nhave power:\n  1. To sue and be sued;\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;\n  3. To acquire, hold and dispose of personal property for its corporate\npurposes, including the power to purchase prospective or tentative\nawards in connection with the condemnation of real property;\n  4. To acquire in the name of the city by purchase or condemnation, and\nuse necessary real property. All real property acquired by the authority\nby condemnation shall be acquired in the manner provided in the eminent\ndomain procedure law or in the manner provided by law for the\ncondemnation of land by the city;\n  5. To make by-laws for the management and regulation of its affairs,\nand, subject to agreements with bondholders, for the regulation of the\nproject;\n  6. With the consent of the city to use agents, employees and\nfacilities of the city, paying to the city its agreed proportion of the\ncompensation or costs;\n  7. To appoint officers, agents and employees, to prescribe their\nqualifications and to fix their compensation; subject, however, to the\nprovisions of section fourteen hundred seventy-five-c of this title;\n  8. To appoint an attorney, who may be the corporation counsel, and to\nfix his or her compensation;\n  9. To make contracts and leases, and to execute all instruments\nnecessary or convenient;\n  10. To construct such buildings, structures and facilities as may be\nnecessary;\n  11. To reconstruct, improve, maintain and operate the projects;\n  12. To accept grants, loans or contributions from the United States,\nthe state of New York, or any agency or instrumentality of either of\nthem, or the city, or an individual, by bequest or otherwise, and to\nexpend the proceeds for any purposes of the authority;\n  13. To fix and collect rentals, fees and other charges for the use of\nthe projects or any of them subject to and in accordance with such\nagreements with bondholders as may be made as provided in this title;\n  14. To construct, operate or maintain in the projects all facilities\nnecessary or convenient in connection therewith; and to contract for the\nconstruction, operation or maintenance of any parts thereof or for\nservices to be performed; to rent parts thereof, and grant concessions,\nall on such terms and conditions as it may determine; provided, however,\nthat neither the authority, the city, nor any other person, firm or\ncorporation shall, within or on any property comprising a part of any\nproject authorized by this title, sell, dispense or otherwise handle any\nproduct used in or for the servicing of any motor vehicle using any\nproject or facility authorized by this title; and\n  15. To do all things necessary, convenient or desirable, including\nancillary and incidental activities, to carry out its purposes and for\nthe exercise of the powers granted in this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>