<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1500-S"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1500-S"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1500-S"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1500-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1500-S/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1500-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1500-S/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1500_S">
        <num>1500-S</num>
        <heading>Code of ethics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall accept other employment, which will\nimpair such authority employee's independence of judgment in the\nexercise of such employee's official duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall accept employment or engage in any\nbusiness or professional activity which will require the employee to\ndisclose confidential information which such employee has gained by\nreason of their official position or authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall disclose confidential information\nacquired by the employee in the course of such employee's official\nduties nor use such information to further any personal interests.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall use or attempt to use such employee's\nofficial position to secure unwarranted privileges or exemptions for\npersonal gain or the personal gain of others.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall engage in any transaction as\nrepresentative or agent of the authority with any business entity in\nwhich such employee has a direct or indirect financial interest that\nmight reasonably tend to conflict with the proper discharge of such\nemployee's official duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall not by such employee's conduct give\nreasonable basis for the impression that any person can improperly\ninfluence such employee or unduly enjoy such employee's favor in the\nperformance of their official duties, or that such employee is affected\nby the kinship, rank, position or influence of any party or person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall abstain from making personal\ninvestments in enterprises which such authority employee has reason to\nbelieve may be directly involved in decisions to be made by the employee\nor which will otherwise create substantial conflict between such\nemployee's duty in the public interest and their private interest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall endeavor to pursue a course of conduct\nwhich will not raise suspicion among the public that such employee is\nlikely to be engaged in acts that are in violation of public trust.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee who is employed on a full-time basis by any\nfirm, company, or association, is a member of such firm, company or,\nassociation, or owns or controls, directly or indirectly, a substantial\nportion of stock of such firm, company, or association which sells goods\nor services shall sell such goods or services to any person, firm,\ncorporation or association which is licensed or whose rates are fixed by\nthe authority in which such employee serves or is employed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1500_S__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any authority employee shall have any financial interest,\ndirect or indirect, having a value of ten thousand dollars or more in\nany activity which is subject to the jurisdiction of a regulatory\nagency, such authority employee shall file with the secretary of state a\nwritten statement that such employee has such a financial interest in\nsuch activity. Such statement shall be open to public inspection.\n  4. In addition to any applicable provision of law, any authority\nemployee who shall knowingly and intentionally violate any of the\nprovisions of this section may be fined, suspended, or removed from\noffice or employment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>