<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-152"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-152"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="152"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-152/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-152/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-152/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-152/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_152">
        <num>152</num>
        <heading>Jones Beach State Parkway Authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 152. Jones Beach State Parkway Authority. A board, to be known as\n"Jones Beach State Parkway Authority," is hereby created. Such board\nshall be a body corporate and politic constituting a public benefit\ncorporation. It shall consist of the commissioners of the Long Island\nstate park commission and their successors. In case such commission\nshall cease to exist the board shall consist of three members who shall\nbe appointed by the governor, by and with the consent of the senate; the\nterm of office of the members so appointed shall be two, four and six\nyears, respectively, and thereafter the terms of office of the said\nmembers so appointed shall be six years. The president of the board\nshall be the president of the Long Island state park commission or if\nsuch commission shall cease to exist shall be appointed by the governor.\nThe members of the board shall be entitled to no compensation for their\nservices, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for all expenses\nincurred or to be incurred in connection with the Jones Beach parkway.\nThe power of such corporation shall be vested in and exercised by a\nmajority of the members of the board then in office. The board may\ndelegate to one or more of its members, or to its agents and employees,\nsuch powers and duties as it may deem proper. The board and its\ncorporate existence shall continue only for a period of five years and\nthereafter until all its liabilities have been met and its bonds have\nbeen paid in full or such liabilities or bonds have otherwise been\ndischarged. Upon its ceasing to exist all its rights and properties\nshall pass to the state and become subject to the jurisdiction of the\ncommission.\n  * NB (Authority abolished June 30, 1978)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>