<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="153-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_153_B">
        <num>153-B</num>
        <heading>Further additional powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Southern state parkway, together\nwith incidental parkway facilities now existing or hereafter\nconstructed, on and along said parkway, from and including a connection\nwith the Belt parkway to Wantagh avenue and to acquire real property and\nrights therein for future widening of Southern state parkway between\nWantagh avenue and the easterly boundary of Nassau county,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nMeadowbrook state parkway from Merrick road to the Southern state\nparkway, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Wantagh state parkway from Merrick road to the Southern\nstate parkway;\n  3. To construct, reconstruct, improve and thereafter maintain and\noperate facilities such as gasoline, comfort, repair and storage\nstations and other similar facilities along the route of the extension\nof Meadowbrook state parkway referred to in paragraph one of this\nsection and the parts of the parkways referred to in paragraph two of\nthis section, to contract for such construction, and to lease the right\nto construct and use such facilities on such terms and for such\nconsideration as it shall determine, provided, however, that no lease be\nmade for a period of more than ten years from the date when it is made;\n  4. To construct and maintain over, under, along or across the\nextension of Meadowbrook state parkway referred to in paragraph one of\nthis section and the parts of the parkways referred to in paragraph two\nof this section, telephone, telegraph or electric wires and cables, gas\nmains, water mains, and other mechanical equipment not inconsistent with\npark or parkway purposes; to contract for such construction and to lease\nthe right to construct and/or use the same on such terms and for such\nconsideration as it shall determine, provided, however, that no lease\nshall be made for a period of more than ten years from the date when it\nis made. The authority shall also have power to grant, with respect to\nany real property under its jurisdiction, on such terms and conditions\nand under such regulations and restrictions as the authority shall deem\njust and proper, licenses or easements to any governmental agency of the\nstate of New York or to any municipal corporation, public district or\ngovernmental agency thereof, or to the United States of America or any\ngovernmental agency thereof for any public purposes and in addition\nthereto may grant licenses or easements to individuals, partnerships and\ncorporations for drainage facilities, sewers, water and gas mains,\nelectr...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>purposes authorized by section one\nhundred fifty-three-b;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>reconstructing, widening and otherwise\nimproving Meadowbrook parkway from Merrick road to Jones Beach state\npark, Wantagh parkway from Merrick road to Jones Beach state park and\nLoop parkway;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>constructing additional parking facilities on Jones\nBeach at a total cost of not exceeding one million two hundred fifty\nthousand dollars; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the payment of all costs and expenses\nincidental to the issuance of such bonds, including interest during\nconstruction. Such bonds shall mature not later than forty years from\nJanuary first, nineteen hundred fifty-four, and the authority shall not\nhave power to refund the issuance of such bonds. The authority shall\nhave power to employ financial advisors in connection with the issuance\nof such bonds. No revenues or moneys of the authority, other than the\ntolls and other revenues from the Southern state parkway and the\nproceeds from the sale of the bonds, shall be pledged for or shall be\napplicable to the payment of such bonds. All the provisions of this\ntitle relating to bonds which are not inconsistent with the provisions\nof this section, shall apply to the bonds authorized by this section\nexcept section one hundred fifty-eight and subdivisions two and three of\nsection one hundred fifty-eight-a. The authority also shall have power\nfrom time to time in anticipation of the issuance of bonds pursuant to\nthis section to borrow money on bank loans and to evidence such loans by\nnotes or otherwise. Such loans and notes shall be subject to the same\nprovisions of this title as relates to bonds issued pursuant to this\nsection;\n  8. Bonds issued pursuant to this section shall be sold at public sale,\nupon sealed bids publicly opened and read, to the bidder who shall offer\nthe lowest interest cost to the authority, or if the authority shall so\ndetermine, at the highest price. The notice of sale shall be published\nat least once, not less than seven nor more than thirty days before the\ndate of sale, in a financial newspaper published and circulated in the\ncity of New York. Such notice shall contain a statement of the time and\nplace where all bids received in pursuance of such notice will be\npublicly opened and read. Such bonds shall be sold for a price not less\nthan ninety-eight per centum of the par value thereof, plus accrued\ninterest. The provision...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>