<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="153-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-153-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_153_A">
        <num>153-A</num>
        <heading>Additional powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Captree parkway;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_153_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such improvements along\nCaptree parkway and Captree bridge and on Jones Beach island as it shall\ndeem desirable for park and parkway purposes, including but not limited\nto automobile parking places, bathhouses, swimming pools, restaurants,\nboat basins, docks and slips and other recreational facilities.\n  3. To maintain, reconstruct and operate Captree bridge and, but only\nif and as permitted in any agreement with bondholders, to maintain,\nreconstruct and operate Captree parkway and such park and parkway\nimprovements as it shall construct along Captree parkway and on Jones\nBeach island.\n  4. Subject to and in accordance with any agreements with bondholders,\nto charge tolls for the use of Captree bridge and to charge rentals and\nmake other charges for the use of any parkway or improvement operated by\nit.\n  5. To construct and maintain over, under, along or across Captree\nbridge and, if constructed by the parkway authority, over, under, along\nor across Captree parkway, telephone, telegraph or electric wires and\ncables, gas mains, water mains, and other mechanical equipment not\ninconsistent with park or parkway purposes; to contract for such\nconstruction and to lease the right to construct and/or use the same on\nsuch terms and for such consideration as it shall determine, provided,\nhowever, that no lease shall be made for a period of more than ten years\nfrom the date when it is made.\n  6. To construct and maintain facilities for the public on and along\nCaptree bridge and if constructed by it, on and along Captree parkway\n(not inconsistent with the use of Captree bridge as a bridge and Captree\nparkway as a parkway), to contract for such construction, and to lease\nthe right to construct and/or use such facilities on such terms and for\nsuch consideration as it shall determine, provided, however, that no\nlease shall be made for a period of more than ten years from the date\nwhen it is made.\n  7. To do all things necessary or convenient to enfor...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>