<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1552"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1552">
        <num>1552</num>
        <heading>Moneys of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1552. Moneys of the authority. All moneys of the authority shall\nbe paid to the treasurer of the village as agent of the authority, who\nshall not commingle such moneys with any other moneys. Such moneys shall\nbe deposited in a separate bank account or accounts. The moneys in such\naccounts shall be paid out by the treasurer on requisition of the\nchairman of the authority or of such person or persons as the authority\nmay authorize to make such requisitions after audit by the treasurer.\nAll deposits of such moneys shall, if required by the treasurer or the\nauthority, be secured by obligations of the United States or of the\nstate of New York of a market value equal at all times to the amount of\nthe deposit, and all banks and trust companies are authorized to give\nsuch security for such deposits. The treasurer and his legally\nauthorized representatives are authorized and empowered from time to\ntime to examine the accounts and books of the authority, including its\nreceipts, disbursements, contracts, leases, sinking funds, investments\nand any other records and papers relating to its financial standing. The\nauthority shall have power, notwithstanding the provisions of this\nsection, to contract with the holders of any of its bonds as to the\ncustody, collection, securing, investment and payment of any moneys of\nthe authority or any moneys held in trust or otherwise for the payment\nof bonds or in any way to secure bonds, and to carry out any such\ncontract notwithstanding that such contract may be inconsistent with the\nprevious provisions of this section. Moneys held in trust or otherwise\nfor the payment of bonds or in any way to secure bonds and deposits of\nsuch moneys may be acquired in the same manner as moneys of the\nauthority, and all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such\nsecurity for such deposits. The accounts of the authority shall be\nsubject to the supervision of the state comptroller and he or his\nlegally authorized representatives are hereby authorized and empowered\nfrom time to time to examine the accounts and books of the authority,\nincluding its receipts, disbursements, contracts, sinking funds,\ninvestments and any other matter relating to its financial standing and\nfiscal affairs. The authority shall render a complete annual account of\nits proceedings to the board of trustees at its first meeting in January\nof each and every year.\n  * NB Dissolved December 1977\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1552's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>