<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1552*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1552*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1552*2">
        <num>1552*2</num>
        <heading>Endicott parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1552. Endicott parking authority. A board to be known as "Endicott\nparking authority" is hereby created. Such board shall be a body\ncorporate, constituting a public benefit corporation, and its existence\nshall commence upon the appointment of the members as herein provided.\nIt shall consist of a chairman and four other members, who shall be\nappointed by the board of trustees of the village. Of the members first\nappointed, one shall be appointed for a period of one year, one for a\nperiod of two years, one for a period of three years, one for a period\nof four years, and one for a period of five years. At the expiration of\nsuch terms, the terms of office of their successors shall be five years.\nEach member shall continue to serve until the appointment and\nqualification of his successor. Vacancies in such board occurring\notherwise than by the expiration of term shall be filled by the village\nboard of trustees for the unexpired term. The members of the board shall\nchoose from their number a vice-chairman. The village board of trustees\nmay remove any member of the board for inefficiency, neglect of duty or\nmisconduct in office, giving him a copy of the charges against him and\nan opportunity of being heard in person, or by counsel, in his defense\nupon not less than ten days notice. The members of the board shall be\nentitled to no compensation for their services but shall be entitled to\nreimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties. The powers of the authority shall\nbe vested in and exercised by a majority of the members of the board\nthen in office. Such board may delegate to one or more of its members or\nto its officers, agents and employees such powers and duties as it may\ndeem proper. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue only\nfor a period of five years, and thereafter until all its liabilities\nhave been met and its bonds have been paid in full or such liabilities\nor bonds have otherwise been discharged. Upon its ceasing to exist, all\nits rights and properties shall pass to the village.\n  * NB Dissolved December 31, 1977\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1552's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>