<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1596-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1596_D">
        <num>1596-D</num>
        <heading>Purpose and powers of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1596-d. Purpose and powers of the authority. The purpose of the\nauthority shall be to construct, operate and maintain one or more\nprojects in the city. To carry out said purpose, the authority shall\nhave power:\n  1. To sue and be sued;\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;\n  3. To acquire, hold and dispose of personal property for its corporate\npurposes, including the power to purchase prospective or tentative\nawards in connection with the condemnation of real property;\n  4. To acquire in the name of the city by purchase or condemnation, and\nuse real property necessary or convenient. All real property acquired by\ncondemnation by the authority shall be acquired in the manner provided\nin the condemnation law or in the manner provided by law for the\ncondemnation of land by the city;\n  5. To make by-laws for the management and regulation of its affairs,\nand, subject to agreements with bondholders, for the regulation of the\nproject;\n  6. With the consent of the city to use agents, employees, and\nfacilities of the city, including the corporation counsel, paying to the\ncity its agreed proportion of the compensation or costs;\n  7. To appoint officers, agents and employees, to prescribe their\nqualifications and to fix their compensation; subject, however, to the\nprovisions of the civil service law, as hereinafter provided;\n  7-a. To designate officers and employees, appointed or used by the\nauthority, as hereinabove specified, who shall be empowered to issue\nappearance tickets as provided for in article one hundred fifty of the\ncriminal procedure law. Persons so designated are hereby authorized to\nissue and serve such tickets for traffic infractions relating to parking\nwithin project areas as defined herein, in accordance with law and when\nauthorized by local law of the city to issue and serve such tickets for\ntraffic infractions committed anywhere in the city at parking spaces\ncontrolled by parking meters.\n  8. To make contracts and leases, and to execute all instruments\nnecessary or convenient;\n  9. To construct such buildings, structures and facilities as may be\nnecessary or convenient;\n  10. To reconstruct, improve, maintain and operate the projects;\n  11. To accept grants, loans or contributions from the United States,\nthe state of New York, or any agency or instrumentality of either of\nthem, or the city, and to expend the proceeds for any purposes of the\nauthority;\n  12. To fix and collect rentals, fees and other charges for the use of\nthe projects or any of them subject to and in accordance with such\nagreements with bondholders as may be made as hereinafter provided;\n  13. To construct, operate or maintain in the projects all facilities\nnecessary or convenient in connection therewith; and to contract for the\nconstruction, operation or maintenance of any parts thereof or for\nservices to be performed; to rent parts thereof, and grant concessions,\nall on such terms and conditions as it may determine; provided, however,\nthat neither the authority, the city of Yonkers, or any agency of the\nauthority or city, or any other person, firm or corporation shall,\nwithin or on any property comprising a part of any project authorized by\nthis title, sell, dispense or otherwise handle any product used in or\nfor the servicing of any motor vehicle using any project or facility\nauthorized by this title, and provided further that the location of\nsites of the projects shall be subject to the prior advice of the\nplanning board of the city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>