<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1596-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1596-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1596_C">
        <num>1596-C</num>
        <heading>City of Yonkers parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1596-c. City of Yonkers parking authority. A board to be known as\n"City of Yonkers parking authority" is hereby created. Such board shall\nbe a body corporate and politic, constituting a public benefit\ncorporation, and its existence shall commence upon the appointment of\nthe members as herein provided. It shall consist of a chairman,\nappointed by the mayor of the city of Yonkers, and four other members,\nwho shall also be appointed by the mayor. The appointment of the\nchairman shall be for a term of five years and of each of the other\nmembers for terms of one, two, three and four years from the first day\nof April, nineteen hundred sixty-four. At the expiration of such terms,\nthe terms of office of their successors shall be five years so that the\nterm of office of one-fifth of such members shall expire on the\nthirty-first day of March in each year. Each member shall continue to\nserve until the appointment and qualification of his successor.\nVacancies in such board occurring otherwise than by the expiration of\nsuch term, shall be filled for the unexpired term. The members of the\nboard shall choose from their number a vice-chairman. The mayor may\nremove any member of the board for inefficiency, neglect of duty or\nmisconduct in office, giving him a copy of the charges against him and\nan opportunity of being heard in person, or by counsel, in his defense\nupon not less than ten days' notice. The members of the board shall be\nentitled to no compensation for their services but shall be entitled to\nreimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties. The powers of the authority shall\nbe vested in and exercised by a majority of the members of the board\nthen in office. Such board may delegate to one or more of its members or\nto its officers, agents and employees such powers and duties as it may\ndeem proper. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue only\nto the thirty-first day of December, nineteen hundred ninety-nine, and\nthereafter until all its liabilities have been met and its bonds have\nbeen paid in full or such liabilities or bonds have otherwise been\ndischarged. Upon its ceasing to exist, all its rights and properties\nshall pass to the city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>