<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-J*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-J*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-J*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-J*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-J*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-J*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-J*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_J*2">
        <num>1599-J*2</num>
        <heading>Notes of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-j. Notes of the authority. The authority shall have power\nfrom time to time to issue notes and from time to time to issue renewal\nnotes (herein referred to as notes) maturing not later than five years\nfrom their respective original dates in an amount not exceeding at any\ntime one hundred thousand dollars, over and above the amount of bonds\nauthorized by subdivision one of section fifteen hundred ninety-nine-i\nof this title, for any purpose or purposes for which bonds may be\nissued, whenever the authority shall determine that payment thereof can\nbe made in full from any moneys or revenues which the authority expects\nto receive from any source. Such notes may, among other things, be\nissued to provide funds to pay preliminary costs of surveys, plans or\nother matters relating to any proposed project. The authority may pledge\nsuch moneys or revenues (subject to any other pledge thereof) for the\npayment of the notes and may in addition secure the notes in the same\nmanner and with the same effect as herein provided for bonds. The notes\nshall be issued in the same manner as bonds. The authority shall have\npower to make contracts for the future sale from time to time of the\nnotes, by which the purchasers shall be committed to purchase the notes\nfrom time to time on terms and conditions stated in such contracts, and\nthe authority shall have power to pay such consideration as it shall\ndeem proper for such commitments. In case of default on its notes or\nviolation of any of the obligations of the authority to the noteholders,\nthe noteholders shall have all the remedies provided herein for\nbondholders.\n  * NB Authority terminated 07/01/1974\n  * NB There are 4 ยง 1599-j's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>