<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-D*4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-D*4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-D*4"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-D*4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-D*4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-D*4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-D*4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_D*4">
        <num>1599-D*4</num>
        <heading>Purpose and powers of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-d. Purpose and powers of the authority. The purpose of the\nauthority shall be to provide, construct, operate and maintain, or any\ncombination thereof, one or more projects in the city. To carry out said\npurpose, the authority shall have the power:\n  1. To sue and be sued;\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;\n  3. To acquire, hold and dispose of personal property for its corporate\npurposes, including the power to purchase prospective or tentative\nawards in connection with the acquisition of real property by the\nexercise of the power of eminant domain;\n  4. To acquire in the name of the authority by purchase, eminant domain\nor gift, and use necessary real property. All real property acquired by\nthe authority by eminant domain shall be acquired in the manner provided\nin the eminent domain procedure law or in the manner provided by law for\nthe acquisition of land through eminant domain by the city;\n  5. To determine its fiscal year, and to make by-laws for the\nmanagement and regulation of its affairs, and, subject to agreements\nwith bondholders, for the regulation of the project;\n  6. With the consent of the city to use agents, employees and\nfacilities of the city, paying to the city its agreed proportion of the\ncompensation or costs;\n  7. To appoint officers, agents employees and such clerical,\nengineering and other professional assistants and consultants as it may\ndeem necessary for the purposes of this title to prescribe their\nqualifications and to fix their compensation; subject, however, to the\nprovisions of the civil service law, as hereinafter provided;\n  8. To appoint an attorney, and to fix his compensation;\n  9. To borrow money, make contracts and leases, and to execute all\ninstruments necessary or convenient;\n  10. To acquire, construct, reconstruct, improve, equip and furnish any\nproject as may be necessary and convenient;\n  11. To maintain and operate the projects;\n  12. To apply for and to accept gifts or grants or contributions or\nloans of funds or property or financial or other aid in any form from\nthe United States, the state of New York, or any agency or\ninstrumentality thereof, or the city, or an individual, by bequest or\notherwise, or from any other source, and to expend the proceeds for any\npurposes specified in this title, and to comply, subject to the\nprovisions of this title, with the terms and conditions thereof;\n  13. To fix and collect rentals, fees and other charges for the use of\nthe projects or any of them and to pledge the same, all subject to and\nin accordance with such agreements with bondholders as may be made as\nhereinafter provided;\n  14. To construct, operate or maintain in the projects all facilities\nnecessary or convenient in connection therewith; and to contract for the\nconstruction, operation or maintenance of any parts thereof or for\nservices to be performed; to rent parts thereof, and grant concessions,\nall on such terms and conditions as it may determine;\n  15. To do whatever may be necessary to give effect to the purposes of\nthis title, and in general to have and exercise all other powers\nnecessary or incidental to the purposes of this title.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 08/05/2002\n  * NB There are 4 ยง 1599-d's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>