<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-EEE*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-EEE*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-EEE*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-EEE*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-EEE*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-EEE*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-EEE*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_EEE*2">
        <num>1599-EEE*2</num>
        <heading>Civil service status of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-eee. Civil service status of officers and employees. Officers\nand employees of any board, commission or department of the city may be\ntransferred to the authority in accordance with the provisions of the\ncivil service law and shall be eligible for such transfer and\nappointment without examination to offices and positions under the\nauthority. Officers and employees of the city who are members or\nbeneficiaries of any existing pension or retirement system shall\ncontinue to have the rights, privileges, obligations and status with\nrespect to such system or systems as are now prescribed by law, and all\nsuch employees who have been appointed to positions in the service of\nthe city under the rules of the municipal civil service commission of\nthe city shall have the same status with respect thereto after transfer\nto the authority as they had under their original appointments. The\nappointment and promotion of all employees of the authority shall be\nmade in accordance with the provisions of the civil service law and the\nrules of the city civil service commission.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 04/01/1977\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1599-eee's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>