<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-FFF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-FFF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-FFF"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-FFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-FFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-FFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-FFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_FFF">
        <num>1599-FFF</num>
        <heading>Conveyance of property by the village to the authority; acquisition of property by the village or by the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1599_FFF__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The\nvillage may, by resolution or resolutions of the board of trustees or by\ninstruments authorized by such resolutions, convey, with or without\nconsideration, to the authority real and personal property owned by the\nvillage for use by the authority as a project or projects or a part\nthereof. In case of real property so conveyed, the title thereto shall\nremain in the village but the authority shall have the use and occupancy\nthereof for so long as its corporate existence shall continue. In the\ncase of personal property so conveyed, the title shall pass to the\nauthority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1599_FFF__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The village may acquire in the name of the village by purchase or\ncondemnation real property in the village for any of the projects or for\nthe widening of existing roads, streets, avenues or highways, or for new\nroads, streets, avenues or highways, within a radius of one mile to any\nof the projects, or partly for such purposes and partly for other\nvillage purposes, by purchase or condemnation in the manner provided by\nlaw for the acquisition of real property by the village. For like\npurposes, the village may close such streets, roads, avenues, or\nhighways as may be necessary or convenient, except as to state highways\nand arterial ways which may not be closed without the consent of the\nstate commissioner of transportation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1599_FFF__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Contracts may be entered into between the village and the\nauthority providing for the property to be conveyed by the village to\nthe authority, the additional property to be acquired by the village and\nso conveyed, the streets, roads, avenues, and highways to be closed by\nthe village and the amounts, terms and conditions of payment to be made\nby the authority. Such contracts may also contain covenants by the\nvillage as to the road, street, avenue and highway improvements to be\nmade by the village. Any such contracts between the village and the\nauthority may be pledged by the authority to secure its bonds and may\nnot be modified thereafter except as provided by the terms of the\npledge. The board of trustees may authorize such contracts between the\nvillage and the authority and no other authorization on the part of the\nvillage for such contracts shall be necessary. Any such contracts may be\nso authorized and entered into by the village and in such manner as the\nboard of trustees may determine, and the payments required to be made by\nthe village may be made and financed notwithstanding that no provision\ntherefor shall have first been made in the capital budget of the\nvillage. All contractual or other obligations of the village incurred in\ncarrying out the provisions of this title shall be included in and\nprovided for by each capital budget of the village thereafter made, if\nand to the extent that they may appropriately be included therein.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1599_FFF__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to the provisions of subsection</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1599_FFF__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fifteen\nhundred ninety-nine-ccc hereof, the authority may itself acquire real\nproperty for a project in the name of the village at the cost and\nexpense of the authority by purchase or condemnation pursuant to the\ncondemnation law or pursuant to the laws relating to the condemnation of\nland by the village. The authority shall have the use and occupancy of\nsuch real property so long as its corporate existence shall continue.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1599_FFF__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In case the authority shall have the use and occupancy of any real\nproperty which it shall determine is no longer required for a project\nthen, if such real property was acquired at the cost and expense of the\nvillage, the authority shall have power to surrender its use and\noccupancy thereof to the village, or, if such real property was acquired\nat the cost and expense of the authority, then the authority shall have\npower to sell, lease or otherwise dispose of said real property at\npublic or private sale, and shall retain and have the power to use the\nproceeds of sale, rentals, or other moneys derived from the disposition\nthereof for its purposes.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 06/01/1976\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1599-fff's\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>