<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-B*3"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-B*3"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-B*3"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-B*3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-B*3/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-B*3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-B*3/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_B*3">
        <num>1599-B*3</num>
        <heading>Niagara Falls parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-b. Niagara Falls parking authority. A board to be known as\n"Niagara Falls Parking Authority" is hereby created. Such board shall be\na body corporate, constituting a public benefit corporation, and its\nexistence shall commence upon the appointment of the members by the City\nCouncil. The board shall consist of the Mayor of the City of Niagara\nFalls who shall serve as Chairman; the City Manager; the Comptroller;\nChief Planning Officer and Traffic Engineer. Each member of the board\nshall continue to serve so long as he shall serve in his city position.\nThe members of the board shall choose from their number a vice-chairman.\nThe members of the board shall be entitled to no compensation for their\nservices but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties.\nThe powers of the authority shall be vested in and exercised by a\nmajority of the members of the board. Such board may delegate to one or\nmore of its members or to its officers, agents and employees such powers\nand duties as it may deem proper. Such board and its corporate existence\nshall continue only for a period of five years, and thereafter until all\nits liabilities have been met, and its bonds have been paid in full or\nsuch liabilities or bonds have otherwise been discharged. Upon its\nceasing to exist, all its rights and properties shall pass to the city.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 07/01/1974\n  * NB There are 4 ยง 1599-b's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>