<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_M">
        <num>1599-M</num>
        <heading>Bonds legal investments for public officers and fiduciaries</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-m. Bonds legal investments for public officers and\nfiduciaries.  The bonds are hereby made securities in which all public\nofficers, and bodies of this state and all municipalities and municipal\nsubdivisions, all insurance companies and associations and other persons\ncarrying on an insurance business, all banks, bankers, trust companies,\nsavings banks and savings associations, including savings and loan\nassociations, building and loan associations, investment companies and\nother persons carrying on a banking business, all administrators,\nguardians, executors, trustees and other fiduciaries and all other\npersons whatsoever who are now or may hereafter be authorized to invest\nin bonds or other obligations of the state, may properly and legally\ninvest funds including capital in their control or belonging to them.\nThe bonds are also hereby made securities which may be deposited with\nand shall be received by all public officers and bodies of this state\nand all municipalities and municipal subdivisions for any purpose for\nwhich the deposit of bonds or other obligations of this state is now or\nmay hereafter be authorized.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 12/31/99\n  * NB There are 4 ยง 1599-m's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>