<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C*4"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C*4"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-C*4"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C*4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C*4/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C*4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C*4/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_C*4">
        <num>1599-C*4</num>
        <heading>Schenectady parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-c. Schenectady parking authority. 1. A board to be known as\n"Schenectady Parking Authority" is hereby created. Such board shall be a\nbody corporate and politic, constituting a public benefit corporation,\nand its existence shall commence upon the appointment of the members as\nherein provided. It shall consist of a chairman and four other members,\nwho shall be appointed by the mayor, with the advice and consent of the\ncity council. Of the members first appointed, one shall be appointed for\na period of one year, one for a period of two years, one for a period of\nthree years, one for a period of four years, and one for a period of\nfive years. At the expiration of such terms, the terms of office of\ntheir successors shall be five years. Each member shall continue to\nserve until the appointment and qualification of his successor. A member\nmay be removed at will by the mayor with the approval of the city\ncouncil, giving him a copy of the charges against him and an opportunity\nof being heard in person, or by counsel, in his defense upon not less\nthan ten day's notice. Vacancies in such board occurring otherwise than\nby the expiration of term shall be filled for the unexpired term by the\nmayor, with the advice and consent of the city council. The members of\nthe board shall choose from their number a vice-chairman and such other\nofficers deemed desirable by the board. The members of the board shall\nbe entitled to no compensation for their services but shall be entitled\nto reimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties. The powers of the authority shall\nbe vested in and exercised by a majority of the members of the board\nthen in office. Such board may delegate to one or more of its members or\nto its officers, agents and employees such powers and duties as it may\ndeem proper. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue only\nfor a period of fifteen years, and thereafter until all its liabilities\nand duties have been met, and its bonds have been paid in full or such\nliabilities and duties or bonds have otherwise been discharged. Upon its\nceasing to exist, all its rights and properties shall pass to the city.\n  2. No public officer or employee shall be ineligible for appointment\nas a member or officer of the authority and any public officer or\nemployee may accept such appointment and serve as a member or officer\nwithout forfeiture of any other public office or position of public\nemployment by reason thereof. Any one or more members or officers of the\nauthority may be an officer or employee of the city. In the event that\nan officer or employee of the city shall be appointed as a member or\nofficer of the authority, acceptance or retention of such appointment\nshall not be deemed a forfeiture of his city office or employment, or\nincompatible therewith or affect his tenure or compensation in any way.\n  3. It is hereby determined and declared that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers, purposes and duties are in all respects for\nthe benefit of the people of the city of Schenectady and the state of\nNew York, and that said purposes are public purposes and that the\nauthority is and will be performing an essential governmental function\nin the exercise of the powers conferred upon it by this title.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 08/05/2002\n  * NB There are 4 ยง 1599-c's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>