<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-CCC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-CCC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-CCC"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-CCC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-CCC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-CCC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-CCC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_CCC">
        <num>1599-CCC</num>
        <heading>Mount Kisco parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-ccc. Mount Kisco parking authority. A board to be known as\n"Mount Kisco parking authority" is hereby created. Such board shall be a\nbody corporate, constituting a public benefit corporation, and its\nexistence shall commence upon the appointment of the members as herein\nprovided. It shall consist of a chairman and four other members, who\nshall be appointed by the mayor with the approval of the board of\ntrustees of the village. Of the members first appointed, one shall be\nappointed for a period of one year, one for a period of two years, one\nfor a period of three years, one for a period of four years, and one for\na period of five years. At the expiration of such terms, the terms of\noffice of their successors shall be five years. Each member shall\ncontinue to serve until the appointment and qualification of his\nsuccessor. Vacancies in such board occurring otherwise than by the\nexpiration of term shall be filled for the unexpired term. The members\nof the board shall choose from their number a vice-chairman. The board\nof trustees may remove any member of the board for inefficiency, neglect\nof duty or misconduct in office, giving him a copy of the charges\nagainst him and an opportunity of being heard in person, or by counsel,\nin his defense upon not less than ten days' notice. The members of the\nboard shall be entitled to no compensation for their services but shall\nbe entitled to reimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of their official duties. The powers of the\nauthority shall be vested in and exercised by a majority of the members\nof the board then in office. Such board may delegate to one or more of\nits members or to its officers, agents and employees such powers and\nduties as it may deem proper. Such board and its corporate existence\nshall continue only for a period of five years, and thereafter until all\nits liabilities have been met and its bonds have been paid in full or\nsuch liabilities or bonds have otherwise been discharged. Upon its\nceasing to exist, all its rights and properties shall pass to the\nvillage.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 06/01/1976\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1599-ccc's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>