<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_F">
        <num>1599-F</num>
        <heading>Conveyance of property by the city to the authority; acquisition of property by the city or by the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-f. Conveyance of property by the city to the authority;\nacquisition of property by the city or by the authority. 1. The city\nmay, by ordinance or ordinances or resolutions of the common council or\nby instruments authorized by such ordinances, convey, with or without\nconsideration, to the authority real and personal property owned by the\ncity for use by the authority as a project or projects or a part\nthereof. In the case of real property so conveyed, the title thereto\nshall remain in the city but the authority shall have the use and\noccupancy thereof for so long as its corporate existence shall continue.\nIn the case of personal property so conveyed, the title shall pass to\nthe authority.\n  2. The city may acquire by purchase or condemnation real property in\nthe name of the city for any of the projects or for the widening of\nexisting roads, streets, parkways, avenues or highways or for new roads,\nstreets, parkways, avenues or highways to any of the projects, or partly\nfor such purposes and partly for other city purposes, by purchase or\ncondemnation in the manner provided by law for the acquisition of real\nproperty by the city. The city may close such streets, roads, parkways,\navenues, or highways as may be necessary or convenient.\n  3. Contracts may be entered into between the city and the authority\nproviding for the property to be conveyed by the city to the authority,\nthe additional property to be acquired by the city and so conveyed, the\nstreets, roads, parkways, avenues, and highways to be closed by the city\nand the amounts, terms and conditions of payment to be made by the\nauthority. Such contracts may also contain covenants by the city as to\nthe road, street, parkway, avenue and highway improvements to be made by\nthe city. Any such contracts between the city and the authority may be\npledged by the authority to secure its bonds and may not be modified\nthereafter except as provided by the terms of the pledge. The common\ncouncil may authorize such contracts between the city and the authority\nand no other authorization on the part of the city for such contracts\nshall be necessary. Any such contracts may be so authorized and entered\ninto by the city and in such manner as the common council may determine,\nand the payments required to be made by the city may be made and\nfinanced notwithstanding that no provision therefor shall have first\nbeen made in the capital budget of the city. All contractual or other\nobligations of the city incurred in carrying out the provisions of this\ntitle shall be included in and provided for by each capital budget of\nthe city thereafter made, if and to the extent that they may\nappropriately be included therein.\n  4. The authority may itself acquire real property for a project in the\nname of the city at the cost and expense of the authority by purchase or\ncondemnation pursuant to the condemnation law or pursuant to the laws\nrelating to the condemnation of land by the city. The authority shall\nhave the use and occupancy of such real property so long as its\ncorporate existence shall continue.\n  5. In case the authority shall have the use and occupancy of any real\nproperty which it shall determine is no longer required for a project\nthen, if such real property was acquired at the cost and expense of the\ncity, the authority shall have power to surrender its use and occupancy\nthereof to the city, or, if such real property was acquired at the cost\nand expense of the authority, then the authority shall have power to\nsell, lease or otherwise dispose of said real property and shall retain\nand have the power to use the proceeds of sale, rentals or other moneys\nderived from the disposition thereof for its purposes.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 12/31/99\n  * NB There are 4 ยง 1599-f's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>