<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1599-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1599-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1599_C">
        <num>1599-C</num>
        <heading>City of Binghamton parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1599-c. City of Binghamton parking authority. A board to be known\nas "City of Binghamton parking authority" is hereby created. Such board\nshall be a body corporate and politic, constituting a public benefit\ncorporation, and its existence shall commence upon the appointment of\nthe members as herein provided. It shall consist of a chairman,\nappointed by the mayor of the city of Binghamton, and four other\nmembers, who shall also be appointed by the mayor. The appointment of\nthe chairman shall be for a term of five years and of each of the other\nmembers for terms of one, two, three and four years from the first day\nof July, nineteen hundred sixty-nine. At the expiration of such terms,\nthe terms of office of their successors shall be five years so that the\nterm of office of one-fifth of such members shall expire on the\nthirtieth day of June in each year. Each member shall continue to serve\nuntil the appointment and qualification of his successor. Vacancies in\nsuch board occurring otherwise than by the expiration of such term,\nshall be filled for the unexpired term. The members of the board shall\nchoose from their number a vice-chairman. The mayor may remove any\nmember of the board for inefficiency, neglect of duty or misconduct in\noffice, giving him a copy of the charges against him and an opportunity\nof being heard in person, or by counsel, in his defense upon not less\nthan ten days' notice. The members of the board shall be entitled to no\ncompensation for their services but shall be entitled to reimbursement\nfor their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of\ntheir official duties. The powers of the authority shall be vested in\nand exercised by a majority of the members of the board then in office.\nSuch board may delegate to one or more of its members or to its\nofficers, agents and employees such powers and duties as it may deem\nproper. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue only to\nthe thirty-first day of December, nineteen hundred ninety-nine, and\nthereafter until all its liabilities have been met and its bonds have\nbeen paid in full or such liabilities or bonds have otherwise been\ndischarged. Upon its ceasing to exist, all its rights and properties\nshall pass to the city.\n  * NB Authority ceased to exist 12/31/99\n  * NB There are 4 ยง 1599-c's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>