<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-160"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-160"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="160"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-160/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-160/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_160">
        <num>160</num>
        <heading>Bonds legal investments for public officers and fiduciaries</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 160. Bonds legal investments for public officers and fiduciaries.\nThe bonds are hereby made securities in which all public officers and\nbodies of this state and all municipalities and municipal subdivisions,\nall insurance companies and associations and other persons carrying on\nan insurance business, all banks, bankers, trust companies, savings\nbanks and savings institutions, including savings and loan associations,\nbuilding and loan associations, investment companies and other persons\ncarrying on a banking business, administrators, guardians, executors,\ntrustees and other fiduciaries and all other persons whatsoever who are\nnow or may hereafter be authorized to invest in bonds or other\nobligations of the state may properly and legally invest funds,\nincluding capital in their control or belonging to them. The bonds are\nalso hereby made securities which may be deposited with and shall be\nreceived by all public officers and bodies of this state and all\nmunicipalities and municipal subdivisions for any purpose for which the\ndeposit of bonds or other obligations of this state is now or may\nhereafter be authorized.\n  * NB (Authority abolished June 30, 1978)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>