<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-01-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1600-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1600_C">
        <num>1600-C</num>
        <heading>Tarrytown parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1600-c. Tarrytown parking authority. A board to be known as\n"Tarrytown parking authority" is hereby created. Such board shall be a\nbody corporate and politic, constituting a public benefit corporation,\nand its existence shall commence upon the appointment of the members as\nherein provided. It shall consist of a chairman and four other members,\nall of whom shall be appointed by the mayor with the approval of the\nboard of trustees of the village. The appointment of the chairman shall\nbe for a term of five years. Of the other members first appointed, one\nshall be appointed for a period of one year, one for a period of two\nyears, one for a period of three years, one for a period of four years.\nAt the expiration of such terms, the terms of office of their successors\nshall be five years. Each member shall continue to serve until the\nappointment and qualification of his successor. Vacancies in such board\noccurring otherwise than by the expiration of such term, shall be filled\nfor the unexpired term. The members of the board shall choose from their\nnumber a vice-chairman and such other officers deemed desirable by the\nboard. The board of trustees may remove any member of the board for\ninefficiency, neglect of duty or misconduct in office, giving him a copy\nof the charges against him and an opportunity of being heard in person,\nor by counsel, in his defense upon not less than ten days' notice. The\nmembers of the board shall be entitled to no compensation for their\nservices but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties.\nThe powers of the authority shall be vested in and exercised by a\nmajority of the members of the board then in office. Such board may\ndelegate to one or more of its members or to its officers, agents and\nemployees such powers and duties as it may deem proper. Such board and\nits corporate existence shall continue only to the thirty-first day of\nDecember, nineteen hundred ninety-nine, and thereafter until all its\nliabilities and duties have been met and its bonds and notes have been\npaid in full or such liabilities, bonds and notes have otherwise been\ndischarged. Upon its ceasing to exist, all its rights and properties\nshall pass to the village.\n  * NB Ceased to exist December 31, 1999\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>