<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-01-09" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1600-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1600-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1600_J">
        <num>1600-J</num>
        <heading>Notes of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1600-j. Notes of the authority. The authority shall have power\nfrom time to time to issue notes and from time to time to issue renewal\nnotes (herein referred to as notes) for any purpose or purposes for\nwhich bonds may be issued, whenever the authority shall determine that\npayment thereof can be made in full from any moneys or revenues which\nthe authority expects to receive from any source. The authority may\npledge such moneys or revenues or source thereof (subject to any other\npledge thereof) for the payment of the notes and may in addition secure\nthe notes in the same manner and with the same effect as herein provided\nfor bonds. The notes shall be sold and issued in the same manner as\nbonds.  The authority shall have power to make contracts for the future\nsale from time to time of the notes, by which the purchaser shall be\ncommitted to purchase the notes from time to time on terms and\nconditions stated in such contracts, and the authority shall have power\nto pay such consideration as it shall deem proper for such commitments.\nIn case of default on its notes, or violation of any of the obligations\nof the authority to the noteholders, the noteholders shall have all the\nremedies provided herein for bondholders. Such notes shall be as fully\nnegotiable as the bonds of the authority.\n  * NB Ceased to exist December 31, 1999\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>