<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1621-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1621-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-11-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1621-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1621-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1621-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1621-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1621-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1621_C">
        <num>1621-C</num>
        <heading>Middletown parking authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1621_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The board shall consist of a chairperson and four other\nmembers, all of whom shall be appointed by the mayor with the approval\nof the common council of the city. The appointment of the chairperson\nshall be for a term of four years. Of the other members first appointed,\none shall be appointed for a period of one year, one for a period of two\nyears, one for a period of three years, and one for a period of four\nyears. At the expiration of such terms, the terms of office of the\nsuccessors of the board members shall be four years. Each member shall\ncontinue to serve until the appointment and qualification of his or her\nsuccessor. A board member may be appointed for additional terms.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1621_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Vacancies on the board occurring otherwise than by the expiration\nof term, shall be filled for the unexpired term by the mayor with the\napproval of the common council.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1621_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The members of the board shall choose from their number a\nvice-chairperson and such other officers deemed desirable by the board.\n  3. The common council may remove any member of the board for\ninefficiency, neglect of duty or misconduct in office, giving the board\nmember a copy of the charges against the board member and an opportunity\nof being heard in person, or by counsel, in his or her defense, upon not\nless than ten days' notice.\n  4. The members of the board shall be entitled to no compensation for\ntheir services but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their actual\nand necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official\nduties.\n  5. The powers of the authority shall be vested in and exercised by a\nmajority of the members of the board then in office.\n  6. The board may delegate to one or more of its members or to its\nofficers, agents and employees such powers and duties as it may deem\nproper.\n  * NB Repealed per ยง 1621-r (see chapter 597 of 2023 ยง 2 for specifics)\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>