<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1622-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1622_D">
        <num>1622-D</num>
        <heading>Purpose and powers of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1622-d. Purpose and powers of the authority. The purpose of the\nauthority shall be to provide, operate or maintain or any combination\nthereof one or more projects in the village. To carry out said purpose,\nthe authority shall have power:\n  1. To sue and be sued;\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;\n  3. To acquire, hold and dispose of personal property for its corporate\npurposes, including the power to purchase prospective or tentative\nawards in connection with the condemnation of real property;\n  4. To acquire real property subject to the approval of at least four\nmembers of the board of trustees in the name of the village by purchase\nor condemnation or gift, and use necessary real property. All real\nproperty acquired by the authority by condemnation shall be acquired in\nthe manner provided in the eminent domain procedure law or in the manner\nprovided by law for the condemnation of land by the village, and further\nprovided, that the authority shall give the board of trustees of the\nvillage written notice of its intent to acquire any land by\ncondemnation, whereupon said board of trustees, within a period of\nforty-five days after the giving of such notice, by resolution voted\nupon affirmatively by at least four members of such board of trustees,\nmay determine that such land shall not be so acquired, in which event\nthe authority shall be without further power to so acquire the same by\ncondemnation;\n  5. To make by-laws for the management and regulation of its affairs,\nand, subject to agreements with bondholders, for the regulation of the\nproject;\n  6. With the consent of the village to use agents, employees, and\nfacilities of the village, including the village attorney, paying to the\nvillage its agreed proportion of the compensation or costs;\n  7. To appoint an attorney, and to fix his compensation;\n  8. To appoint officers, agents, employees, and consultants, to\nprescribe their qualifications and to fix their compensation; subject,\nhowever, to the provisions of the civil service law, as hereinafter\nprovided;\n  9. To make contracts, leases, as lessor or lessee, and any operating\nagreement, and to execute all instruments necessary or convenient;\n  10. To designate officers and employees, appointed or used by the\nauthority, as hereinabove specified, who shall be empowered to issue\nappearance tickets as provided for in article one hundred fifty of the\ncriminal procedure law. Persons so designated are hereby authorized to\nissue and serve such tickets for traffic infractions relating to parking\nwithin "project" areas as defined herein, in accordance with law and\nwhen authorized by local law of the village to issue and serve such\ntickets for traffic infractions committed anywhere in such village\nincluding at parking spaces controlled by parking meters.\n  11. To acquire, construct, reconstruct, improve, equip and furnish any\nproject as may be necessary or convenient;\n  12. To maintain and operate any project;\n  13. To accept grants, loans or contributions from the United States,\nthe state of New York, or any agency or instrumentality of either of\nthem, or the village, or any person, by bequest or otherwise, and to\nexpend the proceeds for any purposes of the authority;\n  14. To fix and collect rentals, fees and other charges for the use of\nany project and to pledge the same, all subject to and in accordance\nwith such agreements with bondholders as may be made as hereinafter\nprovided;\n  15. To construct, operate or maintain in the projects all facilities\nand equipment necessary or convenient in connection therewith; and to\ncontract for the providing, operation or maintenance of any parts\nthereof or for services to be performed; to rent parts thereof, and\ngrant concessions, all on such terms and conditions as it may determine;\nprovided, however, that neither the authority, the village, or any\nagency of the authority or village, or any other person, firm or\ncorporation shall, within or on any property comprising a part of any\nproject authorized by this title, sell, dispense or otherwise handle any\nproduct used in or for the servicing of any motor vehicle using any\nproject or facilities authorized by this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>