<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1622-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1622-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1622_C">
        <num>1622-C</num>
        <heading>Village of Nyack parking authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1622-c. Village of Nyack parking authority. A board to be known as\n"Village of Nyack parking authority" is hereby created. Such board shall\nbe a body corporate and politic, constituting a public benefit\ncorporation, and its existence shall commence upon the appointment of\nthe members as herein provided. It shall consist of a chairman and four\nother members, all of whom shall be appointed by the mayor with the\napproval of the board of trustees of the village. The appointment of the\nchairman shall be for a term of five years. Of the other members first\nappointed, one shall be appointed for a period of one year, one for a\nperiod of two years, one for a period of three years, one for a period\nof four years. At the expiration of such terms, the terms of office of\ntheir successors shall be five years. Each member shall continue to\nserve until the appointment and qualification of his successor.\nVacancies in such board occurring otherwise than by the expiration of\nsuch term, shall be filled for the unexpired term. The members of the\nboard shall choose from their number a vice-chairman and such other\nofficers deemed desirable by the board. The board of trustees may remove\nany member of the board for inefficiency, neglect of duty or misconduct\nin office, giving him a copy of the charges against him and an\nopportunity of being heard in person, or by counsel, in his defense upon\nnot less than ten days' notice. The members of the board shall be\nentitled to no compensation for their services but shall be entitled to\nreimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties. The powers of the authority shall\nbe vested in and exercised by a majority of the members of the board\nthen in office. Such board may delegate to one or more of its members or\nto its officers, agents and employees such powers and duties as it may\ndeem proper. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue only\nto the thirty-first day of December, twenty hundred fifteen, and\nthereafter until all its liabilities and duties have been met and its\nbonds and notes have been paid in full or such liabilities, bonds and\nnotes have otherwise been discharged. Upon its ceasing to exist, all its\nrights and properties shall pass to the village.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>