<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1676"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1676"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-08-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1676"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1676/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1676/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1676/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1676/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1676">
        <num>1676</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a housing\nunit, including an emergency temporary dormitory constructed pursuant to\nsection sixteen hundred seventy-nine of this title, or any other\nemergency temporary housing operated by the authority, including all\nnecessary and usual attendant and related facilities and equipment,\nacquired, designed, constructed, reconstructed, rehabilitated and\nimproved, or otherwise provided under the jurisdiction of the dormitory\nauthority for the use of students at a state-operated institution or\nstatutory or contract college under the jurisdiction of the State\nUniversity of New York, as defined in section three hundred fifty of the\neducation law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall also include a housing unit for the use of students,\nmarried students, faculty, staff and the families of such married\nstudents, faculty and staff, an academic building, administration\nbuilding, library, laboratory, classroom, health facility or other\nbuilding or structure essential, necessary or useful in the academic,\ncultural, health or research program, including all necessary and usual\nattendant and related facilities and equipment at any institution for\nhigher education located in this state and authorized to confer degrees\nby law or by the board of regents, other than a state-operated\ninstitution or statutory or contract college under the jurisdiction of\nthe State University of New York, as defined in section three hundred\nfifty of the education law, or at any non-profit institution or hospital\nat which the training of nurses is provided by a program approved by the\ndepartment of education of the state of New York, or for New York\nAcademy of Sciences, or for any of the following:\n  Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, Incorporated.\n  Center for the Arts at Ithaca, Incorporated.\n  Affiliated Colleges and Universities, Inc.\n  Brookdale Hospital Center.\n  Albany Medical Center Hospital.\n  St. Vincent's Hospital and Medical Center of New York.\n  Mount Vernon Hospital.\n  New York Medical College of New York, Incorporated.\n  Cortland Memorial Hospital.\n  Highland Hospital of Rochester, Incorporated.\n  Onondaga County Historical Museum.\n  Columbia Memorial Hospital.\n  St. Peter's Hospital of the city of Albany.\n  The department of health of the state of New York.\n  Beekman-Downtown Hospital.\n  Geneva General Hospital.\n  Optometric Center of New York.\n  Brookhaven Memorial Association, Incorporated, doing business as the\nBrookhaven Memorial Hospital.\n  Calvary Hospital, Inc.\n  Montefiore Hospital and Medical Center.\n  The Saratoga Hospital.\n  Booth Memorial Medical Center, Queens, New York.\n  Manhattan Eye, Ear and Th...</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>an intermediate care facility for the\ndevelopmentally disabled at Avenue S and Lake Street, Brooklyn;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a\npre-school program service facility at Mason and Seaview Avenues, Staten\nIsland;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a children and adult program service facility at Stillwell\nAvenue, Bronx;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a children and adult program service facility at\nLawrence Avenue, Brooklyn;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a pre-school program service building at\nLawrence Avenue, Brooklyn;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>an adult program service building at Port\nRichmond Avenue, Staten Island;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>children's program services building\nat Lawrence Avenue, Brooklyn; and for the leasehold improvements to\nManhattan and adult programs services sites.\n  Special act school districts listed in chapter five hundred sixty-six\nof the laws of nineteen hundred sixty-seven, as amended.\n  State-supported schools for the instruction of deaf and blind students\nand children with other handicapping conditions pursuant to article\neighty-five of the education law and chapter one thousand sixty of the\nlaws of nineteen hundred seventy-four.\n  Westchester School for Special Children, Westchester county, for the\nacquisition, financing, refinancing, construction, reconstruction,\nimprovement, renovation, development, expansion, furnishing, equipping\nor otherwise providing for a new school building, provided that the\nlocation within Westchester County is designated and bonds are issued on\nor before July first, two thousand eight.\n  Guided Growth, Inc. of Hawthorne, Westchester county, for the...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a twelve bed intermediate care\nfacility for the developmentally disabled and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>for expansion of the\nday program service facility at Rye Brook, New York.\n  Hospice, Buffalo, for the financing, construction and development of\nnew and renovated facilities for the care and treatment of terminally\nill individuals.\n  The National Sports Academy at Lake Placid, for the financing,\nrefinancing, reimbursement and development of a dormitory for students\nresiding at the academy and an academic facility.\n  Ferncliff Manor as a not-for-profit residential school serving\nchildren who are severely mentally disabled and medically involved, who\nwill also on a not-for-profit basis operate an intermediate care\nfacility, for the financing, construction, reconstruction, improvement,\nrenovation and development of five twelve bed dormitories in Westchester\nCounty for such children.\n  The Leake and Watts Children's Home (Incorporated), Yonkers, New York\nfor the financing, construction, reconstruction, improvement, renovation\nor otherwise for</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a new school building for the junior high and high\nschool vocational programs including a field house;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>a new children's\ncottage and renovation and reconstruction of eight existing children's\ncottages to provide more efficient heating and cooling systems, more\nsecure supervision and to increase the number of beds;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>renovation\nand reconstruction of the main building to provide new electrical and\nplumbing systems and internal rehabilitation; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1676__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>renovation and\nreconstruction of the old school building for multiple use.\n  Oxford University and the Oxford University Press, Incorporated; or\neither of them for the financing, acquisition, construction,\nreconstruction, renovation and rehabilitation of facilities to be\nlocated in the borough of Manhattan, in the city of New York.\n  Berkshire Farm Center and Services for Youth, Canaan, New York for the\nfinancing, construction, reconstruction, improvement, renovation,\nequipping or otherwise providing for a dining facility on the existing\ncampus of Berkshire Farm Center and Services for Youth in Canaan, New\nYork.\n  A public library.\n  South Street Seaport Museum, Inc.\n  United Cerebral Palsy Association of the Capital District, Inc., for\nthe financing, construction, reimbursement, and development of\nresidences and program facilities on lands owned by the Center, at\nlocations within Albany county.\n  Phoenix House Foundation, Inc., New York, New York, for the\nacquisition...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall also include, a laboratory, which may include academic\nfacilities, together with all necessary and usual attendant and related\nfacilities and equipment, erected for rental to the state of New York or\nthe government of the United States of America for research, laboratory\nor other related operations at any institution for higher education\nlocated in this state, and authorized to confer degrees by law or by the\nboard of regents, other than a state-operated institution or statutory\nor contract college under the jurisdiction of the State University of\nNew York, as defined in section three hundred fifty of the education\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall also include, a board of cooperative educational services\nschool facility, any building, library, laboratory, classroom or other\nbuilding or structure essential, necessary or useful for instruction in\na program of any board of cooperative educational services and located\nin the state of New York.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall also include, facilities, which may include a combined\noccupancy or multi-use building or portion thereof, for the Gananda\neducational facilities corporation, a not-for-profit corporation, and\nused in whole or in part by the Gananda school district pursuant to a\nlease or other agreement entered into under the provisions of chapter\nnine hundred twenty-eight of the laws of nineteen hundred seventy-two,\nas amended.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall also include, a facility for the aged.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall also include a child care facilities development project.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>It shall also include equipment, intellectual property or other\nintangible property, including information technology and software,\neligible for tax-exempt financing under the United States internal\nrevenue code.\n  3. The term "bond" shall mean bonds or notes issued by the authority\npursuant to this title;\n  5. The term "board" shall mean the members of the authority.\n  6. The term "facility for the aged" shall mean any real property,\nbuilding, unit within a building, or any structure on or improvement to\nreal property of any kind or description essential, necessary or useful\nin a program to provide facilities for the aged, including all usual\nattendant and related facilities, fixtures, equipment and connections\nfor utility services or any combinations thereof, acquired, designed,\nconstructed, reconstructed, rehabilitated and improved, or otherwise\nprovided by the dormitory authority for persons sixty years of age or\nolder, and any other person who is the spouse of and resides with a\nperson sixty years of age or older.\n  7. The term "locally sponsored community college" shall mean a college\nestablished and administered pursuant to article one hundred twenty-six\nof the education law;\n  8. The term "city university" shall mean the city university of New\nYork, comprised of the senior colleges and community colleges governed\nand administered by the board of higher education in the city of New\nYork pursuant to article one hundred twenty-five of the education law;\n  9. The term "facility", when used with respect to a locally sponsored\ncommunity college, shall mean a dormitory as defined in subdivision two\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this section.\n  10. The term "federally guaranteed security" means any security,\ninvestment or evidence of indebtedness which is issued pursuant to the\nnational housing act or any successor provision of law, each as amended\nfrom time to time, and which is either, directly or indirectly, insured\nor guaranteed, in whole as to the repayment of principal and interest by\nthe United States of America or any instrumentality thereof.\n  11. The term "federally insured mortgage note" means any loan secured\nby a mortgage for any hospital or health care institution facility which\nis either, directly or indirectly, insured or guaranteed, in whole or in\npart, as to the repayment of principal and interest by the United States\nof America or an instrumentality thereof, or any commitment by the\nUnited States of America or an instrumentality thereof to so insure or\nguarantee such a loan secured by a mortgage.\n  12. The term "direct loan" shall mean a loan by the authority to a\nstudent or the parents of a student or both for the purpose of financing\nthe cost of attendance by the student at a public institution for higher\neducation located in this state, recognized and approved by the regents\nof the university of the state of New York, which provides a course of\nstudy leading to the granting of a post-secondary degree, which is\nserviced and administered by a financial institution, the New York state\nhigher education services corporation or other qualified loan\norigination and servicing organization pursuant to the supplemental\nhigher education loan financing program authorized by section sixteen\nhundred seventy-nine of this title.\n  13. The term "education loan" shall mean a loan by the authority to an\nindependent institution for higher education located in this state,\nrecognized and approved by the regents of the university of the state of\nNew York, which provides a course of study leading to the granting of a\npost-secondary degree pursuant to the supple...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1676__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two\nof section thirty-nine of the judiciary law.\n  27. The term "combined occupancy structure" shall mean any building or\nother improvement on real property or an interest therein, containing\nboth court facilities and facilities intended to be used for purposes\nnot directly or indirectly related to the court facilities and occupied\nby one or more public officials, public bodies or not-for-profit\ncorporations, together with any other necessary or desirable facilities\nincidental to such purposes. Not more than forty-nine percent of a\ncombined occupancy structure shall be used for purposes unrelated to the\nfunction of the court facilities therein.\n  28. The term "state university educational facility" shall mean an\nacademic building, administrative building, housing unit for the use of\nfaculty and staff and the families of such faculty and staff who are\nliving with such faculty or staff, library, laboratory, classroom,\nlecture hall, health facility, or other building or structure essential,\nnecessary or useful in the academic, cultural, health or research\nprogram, including all necessary and attendant and related facilities\nand equipment, at any state-operated institution or statutory or\ncontract college under the jurisdiction of the state university of New\nYork, as defined in section three hundred fifty of the education law.\n  29. The term "state university athletic facility" shall mean an\nathletic facility which includes an outdoor stadium for athletic\ncompetitions at the state university of New York at Buffalo. Such\nfacility shall not be considered for any purpose to be a state\nuniversity educational facility within the meaning of this chapter; nor\nshall any bonds issued in connection with a state university athletic\nfacility be considered for any purpose to have been issued in connection\nwith a state university educational facility.\n  30. The term "private not-for-profit schools" shall mean those private\nnot-for-profit s...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>