<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1677"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1677"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1677"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1677/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1677/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1677/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1677/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1677">
        <num>1677</num>
        <heading>Dormitory Authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1677. Dormitory Authority. A board, to be known as the "Dormitory\nAuthority," is hereby created. Such board shall be a body corporate and\npolitic constituting a public benefit corporation. Such board shall\nconsist of the commissioner of education, the commissioner of health,\nthe comptroller or one member appointed by him or her who shall serve\nuntil his or her successor is appointed, the director of the budget, one\nmember appointed by the temporary president of the senate, one member\nappointed by the speaker of the assembly, and five members to be\nappointed by the governor, by and with the advice and consent of the\nsenate, for a term of three years. The governor shall also fill any\nvacancy which may occur by reason of the death, disqualification,\nresignation or removal of any member theretofore appointed. The\ncommissioner of education, the commissioner of health and the director\nof the budget each may appoint a person or persons to represent such\ncommissioner or director, respectively, at all meetings of such board\nfrom which such commissioner or director, as the case may be, may be\nabsent. Any such representative so designated shall have the power to\nattend and to vote at any meeting of such board from which the officer\nso designating him as a representative is absent with the same force and\neffect as if the officer designating him were present and voting. The\npowers of the board shall be vested in and exercised by a majority of\nthe whole number of the members thereof. The members of the board shall\nserve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement of\ntheir actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their\nofficial duties. The governor shall appoint a chair from among the\nmembers appointed by him or her who shall serve as such until his or her\nsuccessor is appointed. At the first meeting of the board and at the\nfirst meeting thereof in each fiscal year thereafter the members of the\nboard shall choose from their number a vice-chair and a secretary. The\nauthority may also use the facilities, employees, records and equipment\nof the state department of education with the consent of the regents.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>