<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1679-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1679-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1679-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1679-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1679-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1679-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1679-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1679_C">
        <num>1679-C</num>
        <heading>The New York higher education loan program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Corporation" shall mean the New York state higher education\nservices corporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Education loan" shall mean a loan made under the New York higher\neducation loan program established pursuant to part v of article\nfourteen of the education law.\n  2. In addition to the powers of the authority pursuant to the other\nsections of this title, the authority shall have power:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To enter into one or more agreements with the corporation, which\nagreement may provide for the securing of education loans in accordance\nwith part V of article fourteen of the education law, and to perform or\ncontract for the performance of its obligations under any such\nagreement;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To make and contract to make and to acquire and contract to\nacquire education loans and to enter into advance commitments for the\npurchase of said education loans;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to any agreement with bondholders or noteholders, to\ninvest moneys of the authority not required for immediate use, including\nproceeds from the sale of any bonds or notes, in education loans;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To service and execute contracts for the servicing of education\nloans acquired by the authority pursuant to this title, and to pay the\nreasonable value of services rendered to the authority pursuant to those\ncontracts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To prescribe standards and criteria for education loans purchases,\ninsofar as such standards and criteria are not inconsistent with the\napplicable agreement with the corporation;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to any agreement with bondholders or noteholders, to sell\nany education loans made or acquired by the authority at public or\nprivate sale and at such price or prices and on such terms as the\nauthority shall determine; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1679_C__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To establish, revise from time to time, charge and collect such\npremiums or fees in connection with education loans and its\nparticipation in the New York higher education loan program as the\nauthority shall determine.\n  3. The authority shall have the power and is hereby authorized from\ntime to time to issue bonds and notes, including without limitation for\nthe purposes of financing and refinancing education loans and of\nrefunding any bonds or notes issued for such purpose pursuant to part V\nof article fourteen of the education law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>