<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1680-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1680_C">
        <num>1680-C</num>
        <heading>Creation of the court facilities capital review board</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1680_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision thirteen of section sixteen hundred\nseventy-eight of this chapter.\n  The court facilities capital review board shall act on each capital\nplan within sixty days of the submission of such plan to the board. As\npart of its consideration of each capital plan, the board shall review\nand approve overall plans and cost estimates for the design,\nacquisition, construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, improvement,\nfurnishing or equipping of facilities of the courts and court-related\nagencies of the unified court system. Before approving any such plans or\ncost estimates, the court facilities capital review board must be\nsatisfied that the facilities to which they relate are suitable and\nsufficient for the transaction of the business of the unified court\nsystem. Approval of each political subdivision's capital plan shall be\nby unanimous vote of the voting membership of the board. In the event\nthat the chief administrator of the courts and the chief executive\nofficer of the political subdivision submitting a capital plan agree on\nthe plan, the capital plan may be disapproved only by an affirmative\nvote of at least two voting members of the board. If the board does not\nact on a capital plan within sixty days of the submission of such plan\nto the board, the capital plan shall be approved or disapproved by the\nchief administrator of the courts.\n  The court facilities capital review board shall consider, in approving\nor disapproving a capital plan for each political subdivision, the legal\nobligation of the political subdivision under section thirty-nine of the\njudiciary law to provide goods, services and facilities suitable and\nsufficient for the transaction of the business of the unified court\nsystem, and such political subdivision's fiscal capacity, including but\nnot limited to total taxes raised, total income generated, existing\nmunicipal debt and overall capital needs.\n  4. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to li...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>