<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-J*2"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-J*2"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-05-01" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1680-J*2"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-J*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-J*2/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-J*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1680-J*2/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1680_J*2">
        <num>1680-J*2</num>
        <heading>Authorization for the issuance of bonds for the health care efficiency and affordability law for New Yorkers (HEAL NY) capital grant program</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 1680-j. Authorization for the issuance of bonds for the health\ncare efficiency and affordability law for New Yorkers (HEAL NY) capital\ngrant program. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the\ncontrary, the dormitory authority of the state of New York is hereby\nauthorized to issue bonds or notes in one or more series in an aggregate\nprincipal amount not to exceed seven hundred fifty million dollars\nexcluding bonds issued to fund one or more debt service reserve funds,\nto pay costs of issuance of such bonds, and bonds or notes issued to\nrefund or otherwise repay such bonds or notes previously issued, for the\npurposes of financing project costs authorized under section\ntwenty-eight hundred eighteen of the public health law. Of such seven\nhundred fifty million dollars, ten million dollars shall be made\navailable to the community health centers capital program established\npursuant to section twenty-eight hundred seventeen of the public health\nlaw.\n  1. Such bonds and notes of the dormitory authority shall not be a debt\nof the state and the state shall not be liable thereon, nor shall they\nbe payable out of any funds other than those appropriated by the state\nto the authority for debt service and related expenses pursuant to any\nservice contract executed pursuant to subdivision two of this section,\nand such bonds and notes shall contain on the face thereof a statement\nto such effect. Except for purposes of complying with the internal\nrevenue code, any interest income earned on bond proceeds shall only be\nused to pay debt service on such bonds. All of the provisions of the\ndormitory authority act relating to bonds and notes which are not\ninconsistent with the provisions of this section shall apply to\nobligations authorized by this section, including but not limited to the\npower to establish adequate reserves therefore and to issue renewal\nnotes or refunding bonds thereof. The issuance of any bonds or notes\nhereunder shall further be subject to the approval of the director of\nthe division of the budget, and any projects funded through the issuance\nof bonds or notes hereunder shall be approved by the New York state\npublic authorities control board, as required under section fifty-one of\nthis chapter.\n  2. Notwithstanding any other law, rule or regulation to the contrary,\nin order to assist the dormitory authority in undertaking the\nadministration and financing of projects authorized under this section,\nthe director of the budget is hereby authorized to enter into one or\nmore service contracts with the dormitory authority, none of which shall\nexceed more than thirty years in duration, upon such terms and\nconditions as the director of the budget and the dormitory authority\nagree, so as to annually provide to the dormitory authority, in the\naggregate, a sum not to exceed the annual debt service payments and\nrelated expenses required for the bonds and notes issued pursuant to\nthis section. Any service contract entered into pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall provide that the obligation of the state to pay the\namount therein provided shall not constitute a debt of the state within\nthe meaning of any constitutional or statutory provision and shall be\ndeemed executory only to the extent of monies available and that no\nliability shall be incurred by the state beyond the monies available for\nsuch purposes, subject to annual appropriation by the legislature. Any\nsuch contract or any payments made or to be made thereunder may be\nassigned or pledged by the dormitory authority as security for its bonds\nand notes, as authorized by this section.\n  3. Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, and in accordance with\nsection four of the state finance law, the comptroller is hereby\nauthorized and directed to transfer from the health care reform act\n(HCRA) resources fund (061) to the general fund, upon the request of the\ndirector of the budget, up to $6,500,000 on or before March 31, 2006,\nand the comptroller is further hereby authorized and directed to\ntransfer from the healthcare reform act (HCRA); Resources fund (061) to\nthe Capital Projects Fund, upon the request of the director of budget,\nup to $139,000,000 for the period April 1, 2006 through March 31, 2007,\nup to $171,100,000 for the period April 1, 2007 through March 31, 2008,\nup to $208,100,000 for the period April 1, 2008 through March 31, 2009,\nup to $151,600,000 for the period April 1, 2009 through March 31, 2010,\nup to $215,743,000 for the period April 1, 2010 through March 31, 2011,\nup to $433,366,000 for the period April 1, 2011 through March 31, 2012,\nup to $150,806,000 for the period April 1, 2012 through March 31, 2013,\nup to $78,071,000 for the period April 1, 2013 through March 31, 2014,\nand up to $86,005,000 for the period April 1, 2014 through March 31,\n2015, and up to $86,005,000 for the period April 1, 2015 through\nDecember 31, 2017.\n  * NB There are 2 ยง 1680-j's\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>