<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1689"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1689">
        <num>1689</num>
        <heading>Board of cooperative educational services school facilities</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a proposition has been approved by the voters of a\nboard of cooperative educational services for the construction or\nproviding by the authority of a board of cooperative educational\nservices school facility or facilities and any and all necessary\napprovals of the commissioner of education have been obtained, all as\nprovided by subdivision eight of this section; (ii) an agreement and a\nlease have been executed by and between such board of cooperative\neducational services and the dormitory authority relating to the\nconstruction or otherwise providing of such board of cooperative\neducational services school facility or facilities, the leasing thereof\nby the dormitory authority to such board of cooperative educational\nservices and the financing thereof by the dormitory authority by the\nissuance of its obligations; and (iii) the dormitory authority has\nadopted its resolution authorizing obligations of the dormitory\nauthority for such purpose, the dormitory authority may determine to\nprovide that the validity of such agreement, lease, resolution of the\nauthority authorizing the issuance of obligations and the obligations\nauthorized and issued pursuant thereto may be contested only if:\n  1. Such agreement, lease, resolution and the obligations to be issued\npursuant to such resolution are authorized for a board of cooperative\neducational services school facility or facilities for which the board\nof cooperative educational services and the dormitory authority are not\nauthorized to execute an agreement and a lease or for which the\ndormitory authority is not authorized to issue obligations, or\n  2. The provisions of law which should be complied with at the date of\nthe publication of the notice hereinafter provided for, are not\nsubstantially complied with, and an action, suit or proceeding\ncontesting such validity is commenced within twenty days after the date\nof such publication, or\n  3. Such obligations are authorized in violation of the provision...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the dormitory authority shall determine to utilize the\nprovisions of this subdivision, the dormitory authority shall publish or\nshall cause a notice to be published in the manner hereinafter provided,\nwhich notice shall be in substantially the following form:\n  The (here insert the name of the board of cooperative educational\nservices) and the dormitory authority of the state of New York have\nentered into an agreement dated as of the ----- day of -----, 19---, and\na lease dated as of the ----- day of -----, 19---, and the dormitory\nauthority has adopted a resolution on the ----- day of -----, 19---, and\nthe validity of such agreement, lease, resolution and the obligations\nissued pursuant thereto may be hereafter contested only if such\nagreement, lease, resolution and the obligations issued pursuant thereto\nwere authorized for a board of cooperative educational services school\nfacility or facilities for which such board of cooperative educational\nservices and the dormitory authority are not authorized to enter into an\nagreement, lease and for which the dormitory authority is not authorized\nto issue such obligations or if the provisions of law which should have\nbeen complied with as of the date of publication of this notice were not\nsubstantially complied with, and an action, suit or proceeding\ncontesting such validity is commenced within twenty days after the date\nof publication of this notice, or such obligations were authorized in\nviolation of the provisions of the constitution.\n  By such agreement and lease such board of cooperative educational\nservices and the dormitory authority have agreed that the dormitory\nauthority shall provide the board of cooperative educational services\nschool facility or facilities described therein, that the dormitory\nauthority shall lease the same to such board of cooperative educational\nservices, which board of cooperative educational services shall pay\nannual rentals as agreed upon in such lease suffic...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe estimated cost of construction and equipment of such board of\ncooperative educational services school facility or facilities after\nfirst deducting federal grants-in-aid to be received; (ii) the amount\nrequired by the authority, if any, to be paid to reserve funds created\nby the resolution of the authority authorizing the bonds; and (iii) the\namounts required to make payments for legal, financing, administrative\nand other costs and expenses of the authority in connection with such\nboard of cooperative educational services school facilities and the\nfinancing thereof.\n  Executed counterparts of such agreement and lease and a certified copy\nof the resolution of the dormitory authority authorizing such\nobligations are on file in the office of the clerk of such board of\ncooperative educational services at (here insert the address of the\noffice of such clerk) and at the office of the dormitory authority (here\ninsert the address of such office) and such documents may be inspected\nat either of said offices during regular business hours.\n                   DORMITORY AUTHORITY OF THE STATE OF\n                NEW YORK and (here insert the name of the\n                board of cooperative educational services)\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The notice described in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision shall\nbe published once in each of two newspapers, if there shall be two, or\nin one newspaper, if there shall be but one, having general circulation\nwithin the board of cooperative educational services, but if no\nnewspaper shall then have general circulation therein, such notice shall\nbe posted in at least twenty of the most public places in said board of\ncooperative educational services.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>After the publication of such notice, the validity of the\nobligations authorized thereby may be contested only if:\n  1. Such agreement, lease, resolution of the dormitory authority\nauthorizing the obligations, and the obligations of the dormitory\nauthority were authorized for a board of cooperative educational\nservices school facility or facilities for which such board of\ncooperative educational services and the dormitory authority were not\nauthorized to execute an agreement and a lease or for which the\ndormitory authority is not authorized to issue obligations, or\n  2. The provisions of law which should be complied with at the date of\npublication of the notice hereinabove provided for, are not\nsubstantially complied with, and an action, suit or proceeding\ncontesting such validity is commenced within twenty days after the date\nof such publication, or\n  3. Such obligations are authorized in violation of the provisions of\nthe constitution.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If an action, suit or proceeding contesting the validity of such\nagreement, lease, resolution authorizing the obligations or the\nobligations authorized thereby is commenced within twenty days from the\ndate of publication of such notice, the court in which such action, suit\nor proceeding is commenced shall determine whether or not such\nagreement, lease, resolution and obligations were authorized for a board\nof cooperative educational services school facility or facilities for\nwhich the board of cooperative educational services and the dormitory\nauthority were authorized to enter into an agreement and a lease and for\nwhich the authority was authorized to issue obligations or the\nprovisions of law which should have been complied with were\nsubstantially complied with. The court may determine that the provisions\nof law which should have been complied with were substantially complied\nwith if:\n  1. The aggregate amount of obligations authorized does not exceed an\namount equal to the sum of;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the estimated cost of construction and\nequipment of such a board of cooperative educational services school\nfacility or facilities after first deducting federal grants-in-aid to be\nreceived; (ii) the amount, if any, required by the authority by the\nresolution to be paid to reserve funds created by the resolution of the\nauthority authorizing the obligations; and (iii) the amounts estimated\nby the authority to be required to make payments for legal, financing,\nadministrative and other costs and expenses of the authority in\nconnection with the providing of the facilities and the financing\nthereof.\n  2. Such agreement and lease were executed after a proposition\nauthorizing the same had been submitted to and approved by a majority of\nthe duly qualified voters of such board of cooperative educational\nservices.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such determination of the court as described in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nhereof may be arrived at notwithstanding any irregularity or failure to\nobserve a technicality in:\n  1. The form of such proposition approved by the duly qualified voters\nof such board of cooperative educational services.\n  2. The notice of the meeting at which such proposition was submitted.\n  3. The time or manner of the publication of such notice.\n  4. The conduct of the meeting at which such proposition was adopted.\n  5. Like matters in such proceedings.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the dormitory authority shall have utilized the provisions of\nthis subdivision, the obligations of the authority issued pursuant to\nthe resolution authorizing the same shall contain a recital\nsubstantially to the effect that the procedure for the validation of\nsuch bonds set forth in this section have been complied with and such\nrecital shall bind the board of cooperative educational services and the\ndormitory authority, and twenty days after such notice shall have been\npublished and after such obligations have been purchased in good faith\nand for fair value by any person, the validity of such agreement, lease,\nresolution and of the obligations issued pursuant to such resolution\nshall not be questioned by such board of cooperative educational\nservices or by any taxpayer thereof in any court.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the dormitory authority and such board of cooperative\neducational services shall deem it necessary to increase the amount of\nobligations of the authority to be issued in connection with the\nconstruction or providing of a board of cooperative educational services\nschool facility or facilities and shall have authorized the issuance of\nsuch additional obligations by the execution of a supplemental agreement\nand a supplemental lease between the dormitory authority and such board\nof cooperative educational services and the authority has adopted a\nsupplemental resolution authorizing such additional obligations, the\nprovisions of this subdivision also shall be applicable to such\nsupplemental agreement, supplemental lease, supplemental resolution and\nadditional obligations authorized and issued pursuant thereto.\n  13. No authorization given by the voters of a board of cooperative\neducational services prior to April first, nineteen hundred seventy-six\nof a lease or other agreement with the authority in connection with the\nprovision of a board of cooperative educational services school facility\nshall be held invalid by reason of any irregularity or failure to\nobserve a technicality in:\n  a. The form of such proposition approved by the duly qualified voters\nof such board of cooperative educational services,\n  b. The notice of the meeting at which such proposition was submitted,\n  c. The time or manner of the publication of such notice,\n  d. The conduct of the meeting at which such proposition was adopted,\n  e. Like matters in such proceedings, in any action or proceeding\ncommenced more than two years after the date of approval by such voters\nof the proposition authorizing such lease or other agreement. The\nforegoing limitation shall not be construed as extending any limitation\nperiod otherwise provided by law or authorizing any action or\nproceeding.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>