<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1689-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1689-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1689_G">
        <num>1689-G</num>
        <heading>Local government infrastructure; authority financing of eligible wireless 911 capital equipment</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1689_G__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision 6 of section one hundred nine-b of the general municipal\nlaw.\n  4. Whenever the authority enters into a financing agreement with an\neligible political subdivision, each eligible political subdivision is\nhereby authorized, in connection with the financing agreement, to assign\nand pledge to the authority, a sufficient portion of any and all public\nfunds to be apportioned or otherwise to be made payable to the eligible\npolitical subdivision by the state of New York, for payments required\nunder the financing agreement between the eligible political subdivision\nand the authority.\n  5. All local and state officers are hereby authorized and required to\npay all funds so assigned and pledged pursuant to subdivisions three and\nfour of this section to the authority or, upon the direction of the\nauthority, to any trustee of any authority bond, note or other\nobligation issued pursuant to a certificate filed by the authority\npursuant to the provisions of this section.\n  6. The authority shall submit annually to the governor, and the chairs\nof the assembly ways and means and senate finance committees a report\nwhich shall include but not be limited to, detailed information on the\nfinancing activity pursuant to this section, and a detailed summary of\nthe financing agreements entered into with any political subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>