<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-Q"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-Q"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1699-Q"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-Q/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-Q/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1699_Q">
        <num>1699-Q</num>
        <heading>Designation of contract negotiator for small business set-asides</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1699-q. Designation of contract negotiator for small business\nset-asides. The chairman shall designate an experienced contract\nnegotiator to serve as its small business procurement specialist whose\nduties shall include:\n  a. Compiling and maintaining a comprehensive bidders' list of small\nbusinesses. In this duty, he shall cooperate with the federal Small\nBusiness Administration in locating potential sources for various\nproducts and services.\n  b. Assisting small businesses in complying with the procedures for\nbidding on authority contracts at such educational institutions.\n  c. Examining requests from the board of trustees for the Medgar Evers\ncollege for the purchase of property or services or for construction,\nreconstruction, rehabilitation or improvement of college facilities to\nhelp determine which invitations to bid are to be designated small\nbusiness set-asides.\n  d. Making recommendations to the chairman for the simplification of\nprocurement specifications and terms in order to increase the\nopportunities for small business participation.\n  e. Assisting in investigations by the chairman to determine the\nresponsibility of bidders on small business set-asides.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>