<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1699-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1699-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1699_H">
        <num>1699-H</num>
        <heading>Reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1699-h. Reports. The board of directors of the dormitory authority\nshall report on progress in implementing the succession of the medical\ncare facilities finance agency and the facilities development\ncorporation into the dormitory authority by March first, nineteen\nhundred ninety-six and shall issue a final report on September first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-six. Such reports shall be provided to the chair\nand ranking minority member of the senate finance committee and the\nchair and ranking minority member of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee. Such report shall include, but not be limited to, the\nfollowing information:\n  1. Operational, financial, procedural and organizational improvements\nobtained or planned as a result of the succession;\n  2. The source and amount of each reserve fund or account, pledged and\nunpledged, held by the agency or authority on March thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-five and on March thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nninety-six with an explanation of the differences in amounts within each\nfund or account including identification of the amounts transferred to\nthe state's general fund;\n  3. The impact, if any, on any programs and/or projects affected by\nsuch succession;\n  4. A list of positions affected by the succession, including but not\nlimited to, positions of the housing finance agency estimated to have\nspent more than fifty percent of their time performing duties for the\nmedical care facilities finance agency. Such list shall identify those\npositions transferred to the dormitory authority under provisions of\nthis chapter and shall include each dormitory authority position's or\ntransferred position's bargaining unit, if any, civil service status, if\nany, and job title; and\n  5. Legislative proposals to achieve further operational, financial,\nprocedural and organizational improvements.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>