<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1727"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1727"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1727"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1727/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1727/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1727/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1727/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1727">
        <num>1727</num>
        <heading>New York city school construction authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1727. New York city school construction authority. 1. There is\nhereby established a public benefit corporation to be known as the "New\nYork city school construction authority".\n  2. The authority shall be governed by and its powers shall be\nexercised by a board of trustees consisting of three members. The\nmembers shall be the chancellor, or acting chancellor if the position of\nchancellor is vacant, and two other members, to be appointed by the\nmayor. The chancellor or acting chancellor shall serve as the\nchairperson of the board of trustees. No member of the city board or of\na community school board shall be one of the appointed members of the\nboard, nor shall an officer or employee of the city or state be one of\nthe appointed members of the board. The appointed members shall serve at\nthe pleasure of the mayor.\n  3. Each appointed member shall continue in office until a successor\nhas been appointed and qualifies. In the event a vacancy occurs in the\noffice of an appointed member, the vacancy shall be filled in the same\nmanner as was the original appointment of the trustee whose office\nbecame vacant.\n  4. Appointed members may engage in private employment, or in a\nprofession or business; provided, however, that notwithstanding any\notherwise applicable provision of general law, the members shall be\nsubject to the limitations contained in sections twenty-six hundred\nthree, twenty-six hundred four, twenty-six hundred five, and twenty-six\nhundred six of the New York city charter. The authority shall, for the\npurposes of such sections be an "agency" and such trustees shall be\n"public servants" for the purposes of such sections. In addition, such\ntrustees shall be subject to the provisions of section eleven hundred\nsixteen of such charter and shall for the purposes of such section be\n"officers of the city". Notwithstanding any otherwise applicable\nprovision of general law, employees of the authority shall be subject to\nsuch provisions of such charter and shall be deemed to be officers and\nemployees of the city of New York for purposes of the financial\ndisclosure requirements of section 12-110 of the administrative code of\nsuch city.\n  5. The board shall provide for the holding of regular meetings and\nsuch special meetings at the call of the chairman, as may be necessary.\nA majority of the whole number of trustees shall constitute a quorum for\nthe transaction of business. The powers of the board shall be vested in\nand exercised by a majority of the whole number of the members thereof.\n  6. Trustees shall receive no compensation for their services, but\nshall be reimbursed for the actual and necessary expenses incurred by\nthem in the performance of their official duties as trustees of the\nauthority.\n  7. The board shall appoint as president of the authority an individual\nwho has extensive executive-level construction experience. The\npresident, who shall not be a member of the board, shall be the chief\nexecutive officer of the authority and shall be responsible for the\ndischarge of the executive and administrative functions and powers of\nthe authority. The president shall serve at the pleasure of the board.\n  8. The authority shall continue in its corporate existence until\nterminated by law. Upon termination of the existence of the authority,\nall of the property interests of the authority shall pass to and vest in\nthe city and the city shall assume any outstanding contractual duties or\nobligations of the authority, except as otherwise may be specified by\nlaw.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>