<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1729"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1729"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1729"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1729/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1729/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1729/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1729/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1729">
        <num>1729</num>
        <heading>Transfer of property</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1729. Transfer of property. 1. The city board and the city, acting\nby the mayor alone or by resolution of the council, may convey or\ntransfer to the authority, with or without consideration and without any\nfurther authorization, any real, personal or mixed property (including\ninalienable property of the city, except for land mapped as parks), or\nany interest therein, in order to assist the authority in implementing a\nfive-year educational facilities capital plan.\n  2. In the event the authority wishes to obtain city property for use\nas an educational facility pursuant to an approved five-year educational\nfacilities capital plan, the authority shall request such property in\nwriting and shall submit such request directly to the mayor. The mayor\nshall have thirty days to respond to such request. If the request is\ndenied, the mayor shall set forth in writing the reasons for such\ndenial, including whether the city intends to use such property for\nother public uses. Such response shall be made available to the public\nupon request. If the mayor fails to respond to such request, the\nauthority may, at the expiration of the thirty-day period, condemn such\nproperty pursuant to its powers under subdivision six of section\nseventeen hundred twenty-eight of this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>