<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1734"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1734"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1734"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1734/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1734/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1734/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1734/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1734">
        <num>1734</num>
        <heading>Contracts of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1734__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>if bids for contracts for supplies, materials or equipment are of a\ntype regularly purchased by the authority and are to be solicited from a\nlist of potential suppliers, if such list is or has been developed\nconsistent with the provisions of subdivision six of this section or\n(ii) if bids are to be solicited from a list of pre-qualified bidders\npursuant to the provisions of paragraph d of subdivision three of this\nsection. Any such advertisement shall contain a statement of the time\nand place where all bids received pursuant to such notice will be\npublicly opened and read. At least fourteen days shall elapse between\nthe first publication of such advertisement or the solicitation of bids,\nas the case may be, and the date of opening and reading of bids.\n  b. The authority may designate any officer or employee to open the\nbids at the time and place bids are to be opened and may designate an\nofficer to award the contract to the lowest responsible bidder. Such\ndesignee shall make a record of all bids in such form and detail as the\nauthority shall prescribe. All bids received shall be publicly opened\nand read at the time and place specified in the advertisement or at the\ntime of solicitation, or to which the opening and reading have been\nadjourned by the authority. All bidders shall be notified of the time\nand place of any such adjournment.\n  5. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the authority may by resolution\napproved by a vote of its members declare</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1734__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>that competitive bidding\nfor non-construction contracts is impractical or inappropriate because\nof the existence of any of the circumstances hereinafter set forth or\n(ii) that competitive bidding for construction contracts is impractical\nor inappropriate because of the existence of the circumstances set forth\nin paragraph a of this subdivision. Thereafter the authority may proceed\nto award contracts without complying with the requirements of\nsubdivision two or three of this section. In each case where the\nauthority declares competitive bidding impractical or inappropriate, it\nshall state the reason therefor in writing and summarize any\nnegotiations that have been conducted and shall be made available upon\nrequest. Except for contracts awarded pursuant to paragraphs a, b and c\nof this subdivision, the authority shall not award any contract pursuant\nto this subdivision earlier than thirty days from the date on which the\nauthority declares that competitive bidding is impractical or\ninappropriate. Competitive bidding may only be declared impractical or\ninappropriate where:\n  a. the existence of an emergency involving danger to life, safety or\nproperty requires immediate action and cannot await competitive bidding\nor the item to be purchased is essential to efficient operation or the\nadequate provision of service by the city board or the authority and as\na consequence of unforeseen circumstance such purchase cannot await\ncompetitive bidding;\n  b. the authority receives no responsive bids or only a single\nresponsive bid in response to an invitation for competitive bids;\n  c. the item is available through an existing contract between a vendor\nand</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1734__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>another public authority provided that such other authority\nutilized a process of competitive bidding or a process of competitive\nrequests for proposals to award such contracts, or (ii) the city board,\nor (iii) the state of New York, or (iv) the city of New York, provided\nthat in any case when under this paragraph the authority determines that\nobtaining such item thereby would be in the public interest and sets\nforth the reason for such determination. The authority shall accept sole\nresponsibility for any payment due the vendor as a result of the\nauthority's order; or\n  d. the authority determines that it is in the public interest to award\ncontracts pursuant to a process for competitive requests for proposals\nas hereinafter set forth. For purposes of this section, a process for\ncompetitive requests for proposals shall mean a method of soliciting\nproposals and awarding a contract on the basis of a formal evaluation of\nthe characteristics, such as quality, cost, delivery schedule and\nfinancing of such proposals against stated selection criteria. Public\nnotice of the requests for proposals shall be given in the same manner\nas provided in subdivision three of this section and shall include the\nselection criteria. In the event the authority makes a material change\nin the selection criteria from those previously stated in the notice, it\nwill inform all proposers of such change and permit proposers to modify\ntheir proposals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1734__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority may award a contract pursuant to this paragraph only\nafter a resolution approved by a vote of its members at a public meeting\nof the authority with such resolution (A) disclosing the other proposers\nand the substance of their proposals, (B) summarizing the negotiation\nprocess including the opportunities, if any, available to proposers to\npresent and modify their proposals, and (C) setting forth the criteria\nupon which the selection was made.\n  (ii) Nothing in this paragraph shall require or preclude (A)\nnegotiations with any proposers following the receipt of responses to\nthe request for proposals or (B) the rejection of any or all proposals\nat any time. Upon the rejection of all proposals, the authority may\nsolicit new proposals or bids in any manner prescribed in this section.\n  6. Upon the adoption of a resolution by the authority stating, for\nreasons of efficiency, economy, compatibility or maintenance\nreliability, that there is a need for standardization, the authority may\nestablish procedures whereby particular supplies, materials or equipment\nare identified on a qualified products list. Such procedures shall\nprovide for products or vendors to be added to or deleted from such list\nand shall include provisions for public advertisement of the manner in\nwhich such lists are compiled. The authority shall review such list no\nless than twice a year for the purpose of making such modifications.\nContracts for particular supplies, materials or equipment identified on\na qualified products list may be awarded by the authority to the lowest\nresponsible bidder after obtaining sealed bids in accordance with this\nsection or without competitive sealed bids in instances when the item is\navailable from only a single source, except that the authority may\ndispense with advertising provided that it mails copies of the\ninvitation to bid to all vendors of the particular item on the qualified\nproducts list.\n  7. The authority shall compile a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>