<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1737"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1737"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1737"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1737/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1737/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1737/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1737/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1737">
        <num>1737</num>
        <heading>Civil service</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1737__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the authority may elect\nto delegate the administration of any or all of the provisions of the\ncivil service law, except article fourteen of such law, to the\ndepartment of personnel of the city of New York with respect to titles\nestablished at the authority and which the city has also established and\npromulgates; (ii) the civil service commission of the city of New York\nshall exercise on behalf of the authority the powers and duties of\nreview assigned under sections fifty, seventy-two, and seventy-six of\nthe civil service law; and (iii) the New York city office of\nadministrative trials and hearings will be designated the hearing office\nand shall conduct on behalf of the authority such hearings as are\nrequired by sections seventy-one, seventy-two, seventy-three,\nseventy-five and eighty-one of the civil service law.\n  b. In the event the authority elects to delegate administration of any\nor all of the provisions of the civil service law pursuant to paragraph\na of this subdivision, the city department of personnel shall enter into\na contract with such authority for the rendition of such services.  The\nauthority shall compensate the city of New York for such services only\nwith respect to such services rendered for or on behalf of the\nauthority. If the city of New York and the authority cannot agree on the\namount of such compensation, the city comptroller shall determine the\nfair and reasonable value of such services and the authority shall pay\nsuch sum to the city of New York.\n  2. a. Any person on an eligible list for a position with the city\nboard in effect on the effective date of this title shall continue to\nhold such position on such list and shall be entitled to the same civil\nservice rights.\n  b. The authority shall continue to use any new or existing civil\nservice lists promulgated by the city department of personnel until such\ntime as successor titles are established.\n  3. With respect to persons employed by the city board on the ef...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>