<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1739"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1739"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1739"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1739/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1739/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1739/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1739/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1739">
        <num>1739</num>
        <heading>Collective negotiation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1739. Collective negotiation. 1. For the purpose of article fourteen\nof the civil service law, the authority shall be deemed to be the public\nemployer and as such shall negotiate with and enter into written\nagreements with employee organizations representing the staff of the\nauthority that have been certified or recognized under such article. In\ncarrying on such negotiations, the authority shall consult with and seek\nassistance from the office of labor relations and collective bargaining\nof the city board and the New York city office of municipal labor\nrelations. The state public employment relations board shall have\nexclusive jurisdiction for the purpose of administering the provisions\nof such article and the provisions of section two hundred twelve of such\narticle shall not be applicable to any such negotiations.\n  2. Employees transferred from the city board to the authority shall be\nincluded in an appropriate employer-employee negotiating unit pursuant\nto article fourteen of the civil service law except for those employees\nwho are designated managerial or confidential. With respect to such\nemployees, the existing public employee organization recognized or\ncertified to represent the employees of the existing negotiating unit\nshall be recognized as the representative for the negotiating unit of\nthe authority.\n  3. Future alterations of the negotiating unit shall be made pursuant\nto article fourteen of the civil service law.\n  4. a. The authority shall consult with the appropriate public employee\norganization on the establishment of, and bargain all terms and\nconditions of, any new titles it establishes which have a community of\ninterest with titles already represented by the public employee\norganization which presently has representation rights for those titles\nat the city board or at the city of New York.\n  b. Any such titles for which terms and conditions are bargained\npursuant to paragraph a of this subdivision shall be deemed to be\nsuccessor titles within the meaning of applicable law and, so long as\nthe responsibilities of employees in these titles are reasonably related\nto the responsibilities of employees currently represented by a public\nemployee organization, shall be accreted to the appropriate bargaining\ncertificates for which such public employee organization shall be\nvoluntarily recognized as the bargaining agent under procedures\nacceptable to the state public employment relations board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>