<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1742"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1742"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1742"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1742/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1742/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1742/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1742/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1742">
        <num>1742</num>
        <heading>Exemption of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1742. Exemption of the authority. 1. Notwithstanding any other\nprovision of law, any real or personal property, while owned or subject\nto any rights of the authority, shall be exempt from all taxes, special\nassessments and special ad valorem levies and from the payment of any\nand all charges, rents or other payments to the city, other than charges\nfor services provided by the city's water and sewer systems. In\naddition, any in rem actions or proceedings brought against such\nproperty by the city or any other actions or proceedings concerning any\nof the above brought against the authority by the city, and any such\nactions or proceedings shall be void and shall be subject to dismissal\nupon application of the authority at the sole expense of the city of New\nYork. In no instance shall title to any such property pass to the city\nof New York except by deed or other appropriate document of sale,\nrelease or conveyance executed by the authority.\n  2. Debts of the authority shall not be considered debts of the state\nor debts of the city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>