<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1743"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1743"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1743"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1743/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1743/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1743/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1743/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1743">
        <num>1743</num>
        <heading>Equal employment opportunity program and minority and women-owned business enterprise program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1743__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision six of paragraph a of\nsection 6-108.1 of the administrative code of the city of New York may\nbe raised by the authority upon a determination that a higher limitation\nis necessary to meet the goals of the locally based enterprise program.\n  b. The authority shall establish and implement reasonable procedures\nto secure the meaningful participation of minority and women owned\nbusiness enterprises in its procurement process. In addition to\nprocedures it has already adopted for such purpose, the authority may\nuse the same measures, to enhance minority and women owned business\nenterprise participation, as are available to the city of New York\npursuant to article five-A of the general municipal law, section\nthirteen hundred four of the New York city charter, paragraphs one and\ntwo of subdivision i of section three hundred eleven of the New York\ncity charter, and section 6-129 of the administrative code of the city\nof New York.\n  3. The provisions of executive order fifty of the mayor of the city of\nNew York, dated April twenty-fifth, nineteen hundred eighty, as amended,\nshall apply to contracts of the authority unless and until such\nprovisions are revoked, and the requirements of chapter thirteen-B of\nthe charter of such city shall apply to contracts of the authority;\nprovided, however, that with respect to such order, or any other program\nconcerning equal employment opportunity or affirmative action to which\ncontracts entered into by the authority are subject, such program shall\nbe administered by an officer of the authority designated by the\nauthority, and no other agency shall have jurisdiction over the\ncompliance by the authority with the requirements of any such program.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>