<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1746"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1746"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1746"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1746/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1746/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1746/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1746/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1746">
        <num>1746</num>
        <heading>Audit, annual and quarterly reports</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1746. Audit, annual and quarterly reports. 1. Beginning in nineteen\nhundred ninety and every year thereafter, the authority shall, within\none hundred twenty days of the end of the city's fiscal year, submit to\nthe governor, the temporary president of the senate, the speaker of the\nassembly, the minority leader of the senate, the minority leader of the\nassembly, the chairs of the senate and assembly education committees and\nthe chairs of the senate and assembly committees on corporations,\nauthorities and commissions, the chairman of the senate committee on\ninvestigations, taxation, and government operations, the chairman of the\nassembly committee on oversight, analysis, and investigations, the mayor\nand the city board a report on its operations during such fiscal year.\nAn annual audit of the authority shall be conducted by an independent\ncertified public accountant, and the authority's independently audited\nfinancial statements shall be included in this report.\n  2. Beginning in nineteen hundred ninety, and every year thereafter,\nthe authority shall, on the last day of April, July, October, and\nJanuary, submit to all persons set forth in subdivision one of this\nsection a report detailing the extent of completion of all projects for\nconstruction, reconstruction, improvement, rehabilitation, maintenance,\nrepair, furnishing, equipping of or otherwise providing for educational\nfacilities for the city board, including, by project, identified\nshortfalls in schedule performance and providing explanation for such\nshortfalls. Such reports shall detail the extent of completion as\nexisted on the last day of the month preceding each report,\nrespectively.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>