<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1823"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1823"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1823"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1823/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1823/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1823/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1823/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1823">
        <num>1823</num>
        <heading>Further restrictions on loans and loan guarantees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Loans by the authority pursuant to paragraphs\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of section eighteen hundred three of this\nchapter may exceed forty percent but shall not exceed sixty percent of\nthe cost of the project for:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>projects which are or will be located in empire zones designated\npursuant to article eighteen-b of the general municipal law or in areas\nthat meet, in accordance with the most recent census data available, the\nfollowing criteria:\n  (A) the area must have a poverty rate of at least twenty percent for\nthe year to which the data relate; and\n  (B) the area must have an unemployment rate of at least one hundred\ntwenty-five percent of the statewide unemployment rate for the year to\nwhich the data relate;\n  (ii) projects involving companies in need of special assistance as\ndetermined by the findings of the members of the authority that such\ncompanies are unable to obtain a sufficient amount of financing at\nprevailing market rates of interest for businesses of similar size in\nthe same industry in New York state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In determining eligibility for loans involving companies in need\nof special assistance pursuant to subparagraph (ii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, the members of the authority shall consider:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the applicant's potential for creating jobs in New York state;\n  (ii) the benefits derived from the project in the community in which\nthe project is or will be located;\n  (iii) the interaction of a project with economic development programs\nadministered by the department of economic development, the New York\nstate urban development corporation and the New York state science and\ntechnology foundation;\n  (iv) the meaningful participation of minority and women-owned business\nenterprises and minority group members and women in a project;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_v">
          <num>(v)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the degree to which the project will support apprenticeship\ntraining;\n  (vi) compliance with the provisions of section eighteen hundred\ntwenty-six of this chapter with regard to the project occupant; and\n  (vii) in consultation with the department of economic development, the\neligibility of the applicant for assistance under the industrial\neffectiveness program pursuant to article seven of the economic\ndevelopment law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the rules and regulations promulgated with regard\nto loans made by the authority under other provisions of this title, the\nmembers of the authority shall also promulgate rules and regulations\npertaining to the loans made under subparagraphs</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision by December first, nineteen hundred\nninety-two.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>On an annual basis, the authority shall compile and publish:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in consultation with the department of economic development, a\nlisting of economically distressed areas as defined in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\n  (ii) the criteria for determining the eligibility of a project that is\nin need of special assistance under subparagraph (ii) of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>All otherwise applicable requirements and restrictions of this\ntitle shall apply to projects that are described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1823__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nthis subdivision, provided, however, that in the case of projects which\ninvolve the relocation of economic activity from another municipality\nwithin New York state, the authority shall also find that the project\noccupant has made reasonable efforts to carry out the project within the\nmunicipality from which the project occupant intends to move an\nindustrial, or manufacturing plant, or research and development\nfacility, or other eligible business facility.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>