<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1828"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1828"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1828"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1828/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1828/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1828/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1828/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1828">
        <num>1828</num>
        <heading>Expenses and reserve funds</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1828__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all expenses of the authority\nclearly attributable to its operations under subtitle II of this title,\n(ii) all expenses of the authority clearly attributable to its\noperations under subtitle III of this title, and (iii) expenses of the\nauthority not clearly attributable to a category set forth in clauses\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1828__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and (ii) of this subdivision.\n  2. To assure the continued operation and solvency of the authority for\nthe fulfillment of its corporate purposes with pollution control funds,\nprovision is made in subdivision two of section eighteen hundred twenty\nof this title for the accumulation in the pollution control capital\nreserve fund of an amount equal to the maximum amount of principal and\ninterest maturing and becoming due in any succeeding calendar year on\nall pollution control bonds of the authority then outstanding. In order\nfurther to secure such maintenance of the pollution control capital\nreserve fund, there shall be annually apportioned and paid to the\nauthority for deposit in the pollution control capital reserve fund such\nsum, if any, as shall be certified by the chairman of the authority to\nthe governor and director of the budget as necessary to restore the\npollution control capital reserve fund to an amount equal to the maximum\namount of principal and interest maturing and becoming due in any\nsucceeding calendar year on the pollution control bonds of the authority\nthen outstanding. The chairman of the authority shall annually, on or\nbefore December first, make and deliver to the governor and director of\nthe budget his certificate stating the amount, if any, required to\nrestore the pollution control capital reserve fund to the amount\naforesaid and the amount so stated in said certificate, if any, shall be\napportioned and paid to the authority during the then current state\nfiscal year. No amount or amounts shall be apportioned and paid to the\nauthority pursuant to this subdivision two until the authority has\nentered into a written agreement with the director of the budget\nproviding for the repayment thereof to the state. Any such agreement\nshall provide, in lieu of any other provisions required by law regarding\nsuch repayment, that the authority will repay the state in full from\npollution control funds the amount or amounts so apportio...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1828__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term\n"expenses" for the fiscal year means ordinary expenditures for operation\nand administration of the authority, including interest paid by the\nauthority on its bonds and notes, and, in addition, such amounts as the\nauthority may determine to be reasonable and necessary as a reserve\nagainst defaults on its loans and as a reserve against defaults in the\npayment or terms of loans guaranteed by the authority, but shall not\ninclude amounts required to be paid to the state under or pursuant to\nany written agreement entered into pursuant to subdivision two of this\nsection; and (ii) the term "available revenues" for the fiscal year\nmeans all amounts received on account of loans (exclusive of principal\nrepayments), and loan guarantees and applications therefor, and income\nor interest earned or added to funds of the authority due to investment\nthereof, and not required under the terms or provisions of any covenant\nor agreement with holders of any bonds or notes of the authority to be\napplied to any purposes other than payment of expenses of the authority.\n  5. The members of the authority shall formulate a plan and policy to\nprovide an expedited financial assistance process for fixed asset\nfinancing and other financing assistance programs provided by the\nauthority for new businesses and expansions of existing businesses\nwithin areas designated as empire zones pursuant to article eighteen-B\nof the general municipal law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>