<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1829-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1829-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1829-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1829-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1829-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1829-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1829-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1829_A">
        <num>1829-A</num>
        <heading>Submission of certain program information</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For those requests which are currently being evaluated but which\nhave not yet been approved such description shall include, but not be\nlimited to, the name and location of the applicant, the amount of\nassistance requested, the date of receipt of such request, and the\nstatus of such request.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In providing such report, where necessary to promote the\ndevelopment of proposed projects, the authority may delete references to\nthe specific names of the participants, instead making references to\nthem in some other form so as to make it possible to identify the\nprogress of specific proposals.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such report shall provide a breakdown, for each of the regions\nestablished pursuant to section two hundred thirty of the economic\ndevelopment law, of proposals for assistance through each program. In\naddition, such report shall summarize, by program, the data reported\npursuant to this paragraph.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>For those requests which have been evaluated and for which no\nfurther action has been recommended, the corporation shall present\nsummary data indicating why no further action was taken.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Such report shall include a description of the efforts and\nactivities of the authority to meet the financing needs of economically\ndistressed areas as described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision seven of\nsection eighteen hundred twenty-three of this chapter, and a description\nof the authority's efforts and activities with regard to companies in\nneed of special assistance as described in such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>.\n  2. Evaluations.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to any other requirements imposed by\nthis chapter or otherwise regarding evaluations of programs administered\nby the authority, each evaluation shall include an analysis of the job\ncreation effect of such program, the number of small businesses that\nreceived assistance, the number of minority and women-owned firms that\nreceived assistance, the number of projects undertaken in economically\ndistressed areas as described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision seven of\nsection eighteen hundred twenty-three of this chapter, the number of\nprojects involving companies in need of special assistance as described\nin such paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and, if applicable, the repayment experience of\nborrowers of funds from the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1829_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall submit to the governor, the speaker of the\nassembly, and the temporary president of the senate an evaluation of\nsuch programs prepared by an entity independent of the authority. Such\nevaluations shall be submitted by September first, nineteen hundred\nninety-four and by September first every four years thereafter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>