<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1835-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1835-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1835-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1835-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1835-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1835-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1835-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1835_C">
        <num>1835-C</num>
        <heading>Loans to lenders</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1835_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>obligations of or guaranteed by\nthe United States of America,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1835_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>obligations of the state or\nobligations the principal and interest of which are guaranteed by the\nstate, excluding any obligations of the authority,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1835_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>obligations of\nany corporation wholly owned by the United States of America,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1835_C__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nobligations of any corporation sponsored by the United States of America\nwhich are or may become eligible as collateral for advances to member\nbanks as determined by the board of governors of the federal reserve\nsystem, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1835_C__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>certificates of deposit or time deposits secured in such\nmanner, if any, as the authority shall determine.\n  7. The authority may require that any collateral security for loans to\nlenders be deposited with a bank, trust company or other financial\ninstitution (other than the lender pledging such collateral security)\nwhich shall be located in the state and designated by the authority as\ncustodian therefor or may require each lender to enter into an agreement\nwith the authority containing such provisions as the authority shall\nrequire to</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1835_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>adequately identify and maintain such collateral\nsecurity,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1835_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>service such collateral security, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1835_C__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>require the\nlender to hold such collateral security in trust for the authority and\nbe accountable to the authority as the trustee of an express trust. The\nauthority may also establish such additional requirements as it shall\ndeem necessary with respect to the pledging, assigning, setting aside or\nholding of such collateral security and the making of substitutions of\nor additions thereto and the disposition of income and receipts\ntherefrom.\n  8. The authority may require as a condition of any loans to lenders\nsuch representations and warranties as it shall determine to be\nnecessary to secure such loans and carry out the purposes of this\nsubtitle, and may make and execute contracts for the administration,\nservicing or collection of any loans to lenders or other financing with\na lender and may pay the reasonable value of services rendered to the\nauthority pursuant to such contracts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>