<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1853"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1853"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1853"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1853/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1853/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1853/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1853/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1853">
        <num>1853</num>
        <heading>Approval power of the governor</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1853. Approval power of the governor. 1. No action taken at any\nmeeting of the authority shall have force or effect until the governor\nshall have an opportunity to approve or veto the same.\n  2. For the purpose of procuring such approval or veto, the authority\nshall by rule designate an officer of the authority to transmit to the\ngovernor at the executive chamber in Albany a certified copy of the\nminutes of every meeting of the authority as soon after the holding of\nsuch meeting as such minutes can be written out. The governor shall,\nwithin fifteen days after such minutes shall have been delivered to the\nexecutive chamber as aforesaid, cause the same to be returned to the\nauthority either with his approval or with his veto of any action\ntherein recited as having been taken, provided, however, that if the\ngovernor shall not return the said minutes within the said period then\nat the expiration thereof any action therein recited shall have full\nforce and effect according to the wording thereof.\n  3. If the governor within the said period returns the said minutes\nwith a veto against any action recited therein, then such action shall\nbe null and void.\n  4. The governor may by order filed with the authority relieve the\nauthority from the duty of procuring his approval of its action upon any\nparticular matter or class of matters, and thereupon the authority shall\nbe relieved from reporting the same to him.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>