<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1854-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1854_C">
        <num>1854-C</num>
        <heading>Permanent disposal facilities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1854-c. Permanent disposal facilities. 1. The authority shall\nconsult and cooperate with the department of environmental conservation\nand the commission for siting low-level radioactive waste disposal\nfacilities pursuant to the provisions of article twenty-nine of the\nenvironmental conservation law and such department and commission shall\nmake available to the authority all information with respect to\npotential sites and disposal methods which may be relevant to the design\nof, or preparation of applications for state licenses, permits, or other\napprovals for, such facilities. The authority shall make preparations\nfor submitting as soon as practicable applications for any state\nlicenses, permits, or other approvals required for the construction and\noperation of permanent disposal facilities.\n  2. Upon certification by the department of environmental conservation\nof siting and disposal method selections for permanent disposal\nfacilities pursuant to section 29-0105 of the environmental conservation\nlaw, the authority shall immediately complete development of and submit,\nas soon as practicable after such certification, but no later than the\nfirst day of January nineteen hundred ninety, complete applications for\nany state licenses, permits, or other approvals required for the\nconstruction and operation of such permanent disposal facilities, in\naccordance with the siting and disposal method certification of such\ndepartment. Upon such certification, the authority shall also\nimmediately take steps to acquire and hold in the name of the state of\nNew York any property interests which it may need to obtain for such\npermanent disposal facilities.\n  3. Upon receipt of required state licenses, permits, or other\napprovals for such permanent disposal facilities and if access is not\navailable on reasonable terms to disposal facilities outside of New York\nfor low-level radioactive waste estimated to be generated within New\nYork state during the life of such permanent disposal facilities, the\nauthority is authorized and directed to immediately construct, and to\noperate and maintain, permanent disposal facilities in accordance with\nsuch licenses, permits, and other approvals. Permanent disposal\nfacilities shall be completed and begin operation no later than the\nfirst day of January nineteen hundred ninety-three.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>