<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1854-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1854-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1854_D">
        <num>1854-D</num>
        <heading>Generator reporting and fees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1854_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pursuant to this title the authority shall, pursuant\nto regulations promulgated in accordance with article two of the state\nadministrative procedure act, establish, revise, assess, and collect\nreasonable rates, charges, or other fees upon the disposal of low-level\nradioactive waste generated in New York sufficient to fully recover all\ncosts and expenses of the state and its agencies and authorities\nassociated with low-level radioactive waste management facilities. Such\nassessed rates, charges, or other fees shall be paid to the authority in\nthe manner, and accompanied by such returns, reports, or other\ndocumentation as the authority may prescribe. Fees paid shall be treated\nas expenses for purposes of recovery in rates. Surcharges collected by\nor for facilities which accept low-level radioactive waste generated in\nNew York State for disposal pursuant to the Federal Low-level\nRadioactive Waste Policy Amendments of nineteen hundred eighty-five\n(Pub. Law 99-240), but deposited in escrow pursuant to section 5</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1854_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <paragraph eId="sec_1854_D__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>\nof such law shall be paid to and received by the authority. Such\npayments shall be disbursed or transferred pursuant to this paragraph\nand shall be used for the purpose of reducing the amounts otherwise\nrecoverable as assessments imposed pursuant to paragraph c of this\nsubdivision.\n  (ii) The authority shall deposit the proceeds from such rates,\ncharges, or other fees in a separate segregated account maintained\nsolely for the purpose of holding such deposits. The authority shall\nfirst apply the proceeds of the account to payments of principal and\ninterest on bonds, notes or other obligations issued by the authority\nfor the purposes of the low-level radioactive waste management act.\nUpon appropriation or pursuant to other legislative authorization,\ndisbursements or transfers from such account shall be made solely for\nother costs and expenses incurred under the low-level radioactive waste\nmanagement act.\n  (iii) In establishing, revising, assessing, and collecting such\n...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1854_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>During the period before the commencement of operation of\npermanent disposal facilities owned or operated by the authority,\nexpenditures from appropriations to the departments of environmental\nconservation and health and the commission for siting low-level\nradioactive waste disposal facilities for the purpose of implementing\nthe low-level radioactive waste management act shall be recovered\nthrough assessment against United States nuclear regulatory commission\nlicensees for nuclear electric generating facilities located in the\nstate of New York which have full power operating licenses. For the\nstate fiscal year ending March thirty-first, nineteen hundred\neighty-seven and each successive state fiscal year until commencement of\noperation of the permanent disposal facilities, the chairman of the\nauthority shall estimate such expenditures and shall assess such\nestimated expenditures on a pro rata basis in proportion to the number\nof reactors with full power operating licenses of each such licensee.\nFor the assessment for the state fiscal year ending March thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred eighty-seven, such estimated expenditures shall be\nbased upon actual appropriations available to such state agencies for\nsuch fiscal year for such purpose and shall be billed by the authority\nas soon as practicable after the effective date of the low-level\nradioactive waste management act and paid by such licensees not later\nthan December thirty-first, nineteen hundred eighty-six. For the\nassessment for each subsequent fiscal year, such estimated expenditures\nshall be based upon the proposed appropriations to such state agencies\nfor such purpose, net of any over or under assessment for prior fiscal\nyears compared to the latest available data on such expenditures for\nsuch prior fiscal years, and shall be billed by the authority on or\nbefore February first preceding such fiscal year and paid on or before\nApril first of such fiscal year; provided, however, that a l...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1854_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority may refuse to accept at facilities established\npursuant to section eighteen hundred fifty-four-b of this title any\nlow-level radioactive waste generated by a person who has failed to\nsubmit to the authority, the one or more reports required by the\nauthority pursuant to subdivision one of this section.\n  (ii) The proceeds of any penalty or interest collected pursuant to\nsubparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1854_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph a of subdivision three of this section\nshall be remitted to the authority for the purposes of the low-level\nradioactive waste management act.\n  3. Violations. a. Any failure or refusal to file a report, return, or\nother documentation, or related information, required pursuant to the\nprovisions of this section shall be deemed a violation of the provisions\nof, and a failure to perform a duty imposed by, this section and shall\nbe subject to the following civil and criminal penalties:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1854_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>By a civil penalty, in the case of a first violation, not to\nexceed five thousand dollars, and in the case of a second or subsequent\nviolation, a civil penalty not to exceed ten thousand dollars; which\npenalty may be assessed and collected by a court in any action or\nproceeding pursuant to subparagraph (ii) of this paragraph in addition\nto any criminal penalty which may be assessed for such violation.\n  (ii) By a misdemeanor, in the case of a willful violation by a person\nhaving any of the culpable mental states defined in section 15.05 of the\npenal law, which shall be deemed a misdemeanor, and upon a first\nconviction thereof, by a fine not to exceed five thousand dollars, or by\nimprisonment for a term of not more than six months, or both such fine\nand imprisonment; and, upon a second or subsequent conviction thereof,\npunishment by a fine not to exceed ten thousand dollars, or by\nimprisonment for a term of not more than one year, or by both such fine\nand imprisonment.\n  b. The attorney general shall institute such civil proceedings as the\nauthority may request for the purpose of enforcing the provisions of\nthis section, and such criminal proceedings as the authority may request\nfor the purpose of prosecuting criminal violations of this section.\n  4. Upon appropriation or other legislative authorization and\nconsistent with a repayment agreement executed with the director of the\nbudget, the authority shall repay from the special account established\npursuant to subparagraph (ii) of paragraph a of subdivision two of this\nsection to the general fund, capital projects fund, or any other fund\nall amounts expended from appropriations made to the authority, the\ndepartment of environmental conservation, the commission for siting\nlow-level radioactive waste disposal facilities, the department of\nhealth, or the department of labor for actual and incremental expenses\nin the selection, development, licensing, construction, operation,\nmaintenance, deco...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>