<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1857"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1857"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1857"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1857/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1857/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1857/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1857/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1857">
        <num>1857</num>
        <heading>Officers and employees; transfer, promotion and seniority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1857. Officers and employees; transfer, promotion and seniority. 1.\nOfficers and employees of state departments and agencies may be\ntransferred to the authority and officers and employees of the authority\nmay be transferred to state departments and agencies without examination\nand without loss of any civil service status or rights. No such transfer\nmay, however, be made except with the approval of the head of the state\ndepartment or division involved and the director of the budget and the\nchairman of the authority and in compliance with the rules and\nregulations of the state civil service commission.\n  2. Promotions from positions in state departments and agencies to\npositions in the authority, and vice versa, may be made from\ninterdepartmental promotion lists resulting from promotion examinations\nin which both employees of the authority and employees of the state are\neligible to participate.\n  3. In computing seniority for purposes of promotion or for the\npurposes of suspension or demotion upon the abolition of positions in\nthe service of the authority or in the service of the state, in the case\nof an employee of the authority a period of prior employment in the\nservice of the state shall be counted in the same manner as though such\nperiod of employment had been in the service of the authority, and in\nthe case of an employee of the state a period of prior employment in the\nservice of the authority shall be counted in the same manner as though\nsuch period of employment had been in the service of the state. For the\npurposes of the establishment and certification of preferred lists,\nemployees suspended from the authority shall be eligible for\nreinstatement in the service of the state, and employees suspended from\nthe service of the state shall be eligible for reinstatement in the\nservice of the authority, in the same manner as though the authority\nwere a department of the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>