<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1895"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1895"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1895"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1895/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1895/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1895/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1895/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1895">
        <num>1895</num>
        <heading>Energy audits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1895. Energy audits. 1. The program shall make available to\napplicants who would be eligible to apply for financial assistance under\nthis section energy audits performed by certified auditors or auditors\nusing commonly-employed energy auditing tools and technologies, as\ndetermined appropriate by the authority. The authority shall be\nauthorized to dedicate an appropriate portion of program funds allocated\nfor the funding of energy audits pursuant to section eighteen hundred\nninety-nine-a of this title to non-residential properties that are\noccupied or used by a small business or not-for-profit corporation with\nten or fewer employees.\n  2. The authority shall establish standards for energy audits based on\nbuilding type and other relevant considerations.\n  3. The authority shall establish a schedule of fees for energy audits\nbased on the type and nature of the energy audit and other relevant\nconsiderations. The schedule shall include a sliding scale which\nprovides that audit fees shall be waived for residential applicants\nwhose demonstrated income is less than two times the median county\nhousehold income, and the full fees shall be paid by applicants whose\nmedian county household income is not less than four times the median\ncounty household income. Applicants whose demonstrated incomes fall\nbetween these levels shall pay a pro rata percentage of the audit fees.\nThe authority may provide for discounted fees for small businesses or\nnot-for-profit corporations with ten or fewer employees.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>