<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1910"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1910"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-03-29" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1910"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1910/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1910/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1910/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1910/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1910">
        <num>1910</num>
        <heading>Statement of legislative findings and intent</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>New York will need to accelerate the deployment of renewable\nenergy projects, both large-scale and distributed energy systems, in\norder to achieve the mandates of the New York state climate leadership\nand community protection act enacted as chapter one hundred six of the\nlaws of two thousand nineteen (the "CLCPA").\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In addition to the authority's procurement programs and improved\nstate permitting processes, renewable energy projects require\ncollaboration between host communities and renewable energy developers\nin order to be successfully and appropriately sited and constructed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Local land use decisions are important to meeting the goals of the\nCLCPA, but communities often do not have capacity or sufficient tools\nand information to effectively plan for renewable energy siting.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Community concerns regarding the potential impacts of large-scale\nand distributed energy systems are different, but both can provide\nenergy cost savings for residents and businesses in the community, local\ninfrastructure improvement, local tax revenue and economic benefits,\nlocal job creation, and cleaner air.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There has been a lack of information about the local benefits and\nimpacts of renewable energy technology development and the best ways for\ncommunities to maximize benefits while avoiding and mitigating impacts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A multi-pronged approach is necessary to provide communities,\nincluding disadvantaged communities as designated under the CLCPA, with\nthe information and tools necessary to support the appropriate siting\nand acceptance of renewable energy sources, including wind, solar,\nstorage and transmission and distribution upgrades.\n  2. Intent. It is the intent of the legislature in enacting this title\nto empower the authority to establish effective programs and mechanisms\nto:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Educate the public and build consensus on the benefits of a shift\nto renewable energy technologies, which will provide jobs, lower energy\ncosts and reduce price volatility, and reduce the need for fossil fuel\nbased power, bringing clean air and public health benefits and reduced\ngreenhouse gas emissions that lead to climate change and its impacts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Provide information and assistance to communities and local\nrepresentatives to promote the appropriate and successful siting of\nrenewable energy projects, including wind, solar, storage and\ntransmission and distribution system upgrades;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Equip local governments with the tools they need to effectively\nconsider natural and working lands, the potential for co-location and\ndual-use solutions, effective utilization of previously disturbed or\ndeveloped sites, and protecting disadvantaged communities when planning\nfor renewable energy projects in their communities; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1910__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Help communities develop and adopt local planning, zoning and\nother policies that support the sustainable and equitable development of\nlocal renewable energy technology through processes that ensure and\nenhance public outreach, education and engagement, particularly in\nfrontline communities that have historically been disenfranchised and\ndiscriminated against in the local land use decision-making process.\n  * NB Repealed December 31, 2031\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>