<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1941"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1941"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1941"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1941/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1941/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1941/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1941/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1941">
        <num>1941</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1941. Definitions.  As used or referred to in this title, unless a\ndifferent meaning clearly appears from the context:\n  1. "Auditorium" means the auditorium commonly known as the Utica\nmemorial auditorium located in the city of Utica, as well as surrounding\nlands, including all structures appurtenant thereto, located in the\nvicinity of Oriskany street west and Charles street, as the same may be\nreconstructed, enlarged or modified from time to time.\n  2. "Authority" means the corporation created by section one thousand\nnine hundred forty-two of this title.\n  3. "Bonds" means the bonds, notes or other evidences of indebtedness\nissued by the authority pursuant to this title, and the provisions of\nthis title relating to bonds and bondholders shall apply with equal\nforce and effect to notes and noteholders, respectively, unless the\ncontext otherwise clearly requires.\n  4. "City" means the city of Utica, Oneida county.\n  5. "Civil service commission" means the civil service commission of\nthe county of Oneida.\n  6. "Comptroller" means the comptroller of the state.\n  7. "Construction" or "Constructed" means the acquisition, erection,\nbuilding, alteration, improvement, increase, enlargement, extension,\nreconstruction, renovation or rehabilitation of the auditorium; the\ninspection and supervision thereof; and the engineering, architectural,\nlegal, fiscal and economic investigations and studies, surveys, designs,\nplans, working drawings, specifications, procedure and other actions\npreliminary or incidental thereto and claims arising therefrom.\n  8. "Cost" as applied to the auditorium, includes the cost of\nconstruction, the cost of the acquisition of all property, including\nreal property and other property, both real, personal and mixed,\nimproved and unimproved, the cost of the demolishing, removing or\nrelocating any buildings or structures on lands so acquired, including\nthe cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or structures\nmay be moved or relocated, the cost of all machinery, apparatus and\nequipment, financing charges, interest prior to, during and after\nconstruction to the extent not paid or provided for from revenues or\nother sources, the cost of engineering and architectural surveys, plans\nand specifications, the cost of consultant and legal services, the cost\nof guarantee, bond insurance or other credit support devices and the\ncost of other expenses necessary or incidental to the construction of\nthe auditorium and the acquisition of property therefor and the\nfinancing of the construction and acquisition of property, including the\namount authorized in the resolution of the authority providing for the\nissuance of bonds to be paid into any reserve or other special funds\nfrom the proceeds of such bonds and the financing of the placing of the\nauditorium in operation, including reimbursement to any municipality,\nstate agency, the state, the United States government, or any other\nperson for expenditures that would be costs of the auditorium hereunder\nhad they been made directly by the authority.\n  9. "Council" means the common council of the city.\n  10. "County" means the county of Oneida, New York.\n  11. "County executive" means the county executive of the county.\n  12. "County legislature" means the county legislature of the county.\n  13. "Governing body" means the members of the authority, constituting\nand acting as the governing body of the authority.\n  14. "Municipality" means the county and any city, town, village or\nschool district located within or partly within the service area.\n  15. "Person" means any natural person, firm, partnership, association,\njoint venture or corporation, exclusive of a public corporation as\ndefined pursuant to article two-A of the general construction law.\n  16. "Real property" means lands, structures, franchise, rights and\ninterests in land, air space, waters, lands under water, riparian\nrights, and air rights and any and all things and rights included within\nsaid term and includes not only fees simple absolute, but also any and\nall lesser interests including, but not limited to, easements,\nrights-of-way, uses, leases, licenses and all other incorporeal\nhereditaments and every estate, interest or right, legal or equitable,\nincluding terms for years and liens thereon by way of judgments,\nmortgages or otherwise.\n  17. "Revenues" means all fees, charges and other income and receipts\nderived from the operation of the auditorium including, without limiting\nthe generality of the foregoing, investment proceeds and proceeds of\ninsurance, condemnation, and sale or other disposition of assets,\ntogether with all federal, state or municipal aid, if any.\n  18. "Service area" means the area comprising the entirety of the city\nand of the towns of Deerfield, Kirkland, Marcy, New Hartford, Trenton\nand Whitestown, including all villages located entirely or partly\ntherein.\n  19. "State" means the state of New York.\n  20. "State agency" means any state office, public benefit corporation,\ndepartment, board, commission, bureau or division, or other agency or\ninstrumentality of the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>