<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1943"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1943"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1943"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1943/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1943/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1943/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1943/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1943">
        <num>1943</num>
        <heading>Powers of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1943. Powers of the authority.  Except as otherwise limited by this\ntitle, the authority shall have the power:\n  1. To sue and be sued.\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure.\n  3. To borrow money and issue bonds, notes or other obligations for its\ncorporate purposes and to provide for the rights of the holders thereof.\n  4. To enter into contracts and to execute all instruments necessary or\nconvenient or desirable for the purposes of the authority to carry out\nany powers expressly given to it in this title.\n  5. To acquire by purchase, gift, grant, transfer, contract or lease or\nby condemnation pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law, lease as\nlessee, hold, and use any property, real, personal or mixed or any\ninterest therein constituting or for use in connection with the\nauditorium, as the authority may deem necessary, convenient or desirable\nto carry out the purpose of this title and, subject to any limitations\nin any agreement entered into pursuant to this title, to sell, lease as\nlessor, transfer or otherwise dispose of any such property or interest\ntherein. In connection with the acquisition of any such property, the\nauthority may assume any obligations of the owner of such property and,\nto the extent required by the terms of any indentures or other\ninstruments under which such obligations were issued, the authority may\nassume and agree to perform covenants and observe the restrictions\ncontained in such instruments; and furthermore the owner of any property\nwhich the authority is authorized to acquire is hereby authorized to\nsell or otherwise transfer the same to the authority, whereupon the\nauthority shall become charged with the performance of all public duties\nwith respect to such property with which such owner was charged and such\nowner shall become discharged from the performance thereof.\n  6. To develop, construct, operate, maintain and manage or contract for\nthe operation, maintenance or management of, or for services to be\nperformed in connection with, the auditorium; to allow the use of the\nauditorium for the conduct of professional and amateur athletic events,\nentertainment, cultural and artistic events and, or, civic events and\nactivities related thereto; and to rent parts thereof and to grant\nconcessions, all on such terms and conditions as the authority may\ndetermine.\n  7. To apply to the appropriate agencies and officials of the federal,\nstate and local governments for such licenses, permits or approvals of\nits plans as it may deem necessary or advisable, and upon such terms and\nconditions as it may deem appropriate, and to accept, in its discretion,\nsuch licenses, permits or approvals as may be tendered to it by such\nagencies and officials.\n  8. To appoint such officers and employees as are required for the\nperformance of its duties, to fix and determine their qualifications,\nduties and compensation, and to retain or employ counsel, auditors,\nengineers and private consultants on a contract basis or otherwise for\nrendering professional or technical services and advice.\n  9. To make plans and studies necessary, convenient or desirable for\nthe effectuation of the purposes and powers of the authority and to\nprepare recommendations in regard thereto.\n  10. To enter upon such lands or premises as in the judgment of the\nauthority shall be necessary for the purpose of making surveys,\nsounding, boring and examinations to accomplish any purpose authorized\nby this title, the authority being liable only for actual damage done.\n  11. To apply for and to accept any gifts or grants or loans of funds\nor property or financial or other aid in any form from the federal\ngovernment or any agency or instrumentality thereof, or from the state\nor any agency or instrumentality thereof or from any other source, for\nany or all of the purposes specified in this title, and to comply,\nsubject to the provisions of this title, with the terms and conditions\nthereof.\n  12. To make and amend by-laws for its organization and management and\nregulation of its affairs and rules and regulations governing the\nexercise of its powers and the fulfillment of its purposes under this\ntitle. A copy of such rules, regulations and by-laws, and all amendments\nthereto, duly certified by the secretary of the authority shall be filed\nin the office of the county clerk.\n  13. To enter into cooperative agreements with other authorities, with\nmunicipalities, individuals, or corporations, within or without the\nservice area, for any lawful purposes necessary or desirable to effect\nthe purposes of this title upon such terms and conditions as the\nauthority shall be determined to be reasonable.\n  14. With the consent of the chief executive officer of municipalities\nwithin the service area, to use officers and employees of such\nmunicipalities and to pay a proper portion of compensation or costs for\nthe services of such officers or employees.\n  15. To establish, fix, revise, charge, collect and enforce fees and\ncharges for the use of the auditorium so as to provide revenues which,\ntogether with other earnings of the auditorium, if any, are at least\nsufficient at all times to pay, as the same shall become due, the\nexpense of operating and maintaining the auditorium together with proper\nreserves for maintenance, contingencies and all other obligations and\nindebtedness of the authority.\n  16. To pledge its revenues and mortgage any or all of its properties\nto secure the obligations of the authority.\n  17. To establish and maintain such reserves, special funds and\naccounts, to be held in trust or otherwise, as may be required by any\nagreement with bondholders and, or, any municipality.\n  18. For the purposes of article fifteen-A of the executive law only,\nthe authority shall be deemed a state agency as that term is used in\nsuch article, and its contracts for procurement, design, construction,\nservices, and materials shall be deemed state contracts within the\nmeaning of that term as set forth in such article.\n  19. To do all things necessary, convenient or desirable to carry out\nits purposes and for the exercise of the powers granted in this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>