<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1952"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1952"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2021-11-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1952"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1952/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1952/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1952/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1952/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1952">
        <num>1952</num>
        <heading>Troy industrial development authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1952. Troy industrial development authority. A board to be known as\nthe "Troy industrial development authority" is hereby created. Such\nboard shall be a body corporate and politic, constituting a public\nbenefit corporation and its existence shall commence upon the\nappointment of the members as herein provided. Its members shall consist\nof a chair and eight other members, all of whom shall be appointed by\nthe mayor of the city for a term of three years, and shall include two\nmembers of the common council of the city, one representative of the\ncity school board, and one representative from each of the fields of\nbusiness, industry and labor. Every appointment to the board shall be\nsubject to confirmation by the common council of the city. The chair and\neach member shall continue to serve until the appointment and\nconfirmation of his or her successor. Vacancies in such board occurring\notherwise than by expiration of term shall be filled by the mayor by\nappointment for the unexpired term subject to confirmation by the common\ncouncil of the city. The mayor may remove the chair or any member of the\nboard for inefficiency, neglect of duty or misconduct in office, after\ngiving him or her a copy of the charges against him or her and an\nopportunity of being heard in person, or by counsel, in his or her\ndefense upon not less than ten days' notice. Such removal must be\napproved by the city council of the city. The members of the board shall\nbe entitled to no compensation for their services but shall be entitled\nto reimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties. Notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovisions of law, general, special or local, no officer or employee of\nthe city shall be deemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit his or her\noffice or employment by reason of his or her acceptance of membership on\nthe board created by this section, provided, however, that a member who\nholds such other public office or employment shall receive no additional\ncompensation or allowance for services rendered pursuant to this title,\nbut shall be entitled to reimbursement for his or her actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of such services. The\npower of the authority shall be vested in and exercised by a majority of\nthe members of the board. Such a board may delegate to one or more of\nits members, or to its officers, agents and employees, such powers and\nduties as it may deem proper. Such board and its corporate existence\nshall continue in accordance with section nineteen hundred sixty-seven\nof this title. Upon its ceasing to exist, all rights and properties\nshall pass to and be vested in the city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>