<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1953"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1953"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-02-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1953"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1953/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1953/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1953/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1953/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1953">
        <num>1953</num>
        <heading>Purpose and powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1953__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>sales by a registered vendor under article twenty-eight\nof the tax law primarily engaged in the retail sale of tangible personal\nproperty, as defined in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1953__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph four of\nsubdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1953__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section eleven hundred one of the tax law; or (ii)\nsales of a service to such customers. Except, however, that tourism\ndestination projects shall not be prohibited by this paragraph. For the\npurpose of this paragraph, "tourism destination" shall mean a location\nor facility which is likely to attract a significant number of visitors\nfrom outside the economic development region as established by section\ntwo hundred thirty of the economic development law in which the project\nis located.\n  Notwithstanding the provisions of this section to the contrary, such\nfinancial assistance may, however, be provided to a project where\nfacilities or property that are primarily used in making retail sales of\ngoods or services to customers who personally visit such facilities to\nobtain such goods or services constitute more than one-third of the\ntotal project cost, where:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1953__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the predominant purpose of the project\nwould be to make available goods or services which would not, but for\nthe project, be reasonably accessible to the residents of the city of\nTroy because of a lack of reasonably accessible retail trade facilities\noffering such goods or services; or (ii) the project is located in a\nhighly distressed area. With respect to projects authorized pursuant to\nthis paragraph no project shall be approved unless the authority shall\nfind after the public hearing required by section twenty-three hundred\nseven of this chapter that undertaking the project will serve the public\npurposes of this article by preserving permanent, private sector jobs or\nincreasing the overall number of permanent, private sector jobs in the\nstate. Where the authority makes such a finding, prior to providing\nfinancial assistance to the project by the authority, the chief\nexecutive officer of the city of Troy shall confirm the proposed action\nof the authority. To carry out said purposes, the authority shall have\npower:\n  1. To sue and be sued;\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;\n  3. To acquire, hold and dispose of personal property for its corporate\npurpose;\n  4. To acquire by purchase, grant, lease, gift, condemnation, or\notherwise and to use, real property or rights or easements therein\nnecessary for its corporate purposes, and to sell, convey, mortgage,\nlease, pledge, exchange or otherwise dispose of any such property in\nsuch manner as the authority shall determine. With respect to real\nproperty conveyed to it by the city, however, such power of disposition\nshall be limited as hereinafter provided in section nineteen hundred\nfifty-five of this title;\n  5. To make by-laws for the management and regulation of its affairs\nand, subject to agreements with its bondholders, for the regulation of\nthe use of the project;\n  6. With the consent of the city, to use agents, employees and\nfacilities of the city, paying the city it...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>