<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1973"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1973"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-06-08" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1973"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1973/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1973/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1973/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1973/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1973">
        <num>1973</num>
        <heading>Battery park city authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 1973. Battery park city authority. (1) There is hereby created the\nbattery park city authority which shall be a body corporate and politic,\nconstituting a public benefit corporation. Its membership shall consist\nof seven members to be appointed by the governor with the advice and\nconsent of the senate. One of the members first appointed shall serve\nfor a term ending four years from January first next succeeding his\nappointment; one of such members shall serve for a term ending five\nyears from such date; and one of such members shall serve for a term\nending six years from such date. Provided, however, that two board\nmembers first appointed on or after the effective date of chapter seven\nhundred sixty-six of the laws of two thousand five shall serve an\ninitial term of two years; provided further that two other board members\nfirst appointed on or after the effective date of chapter seven hundred\nsixty-six of the laws of two thousand five shall serve an initial term\nof four years. Their successors shall serve for terms of six years each.\nMembers shall continue in office until their successors have been\nappointed and qualified and the provisions of section thirty-nine of the\npublic officers law shall apply. In the event of a vacancy occurring in\nthe office of a member by death, resignation or otherwise, the governor\nshall appoint a successor with the advice and consent of the senate to\nserve for the balance of the unexpired term. After the effective date of\nthe chapter of the laws of two thousand seventeen that amended this\nsubdivision, if the membership of the corporation is such that less than\ntwo of the members are residents of Battery Park city as described by\nthe Battery Park project area defined by subdivision five of section\nnineteen hundred seventy-two of this title, any appointments made shall\nbe residents of Battery Park city. Appointments shall continue in such a\nmanner until two of the members of the corporation are residents of\nBattery Park city. Thereafter, two of the corporation's members shall be\nresidents of Battery Park city.\n  (1-a) All board members shall recuse themselves from matters pending\nbefore the board in the event of a conflict of interest, consistent with\nthe provisions of subdivision three of this section and subdivision two\nof section twenty-eight hundred twenty-five of this chapter, sections\nseventy-three and seventy-four of the public officers law, and relevant\nauthorities budget office guidance.\n  (1-b) All board members appointed under the provisions of this section\nshall have relevant real estate, corporate board, financial, legal,\nurban planning and/or design, architectural, governmental or security\nexperience.\n  (2) The members shall elect the chairman of the authority from among\ntheir number. The members shall serve without salary or other\ncompensation, but each member shall be entitled to reimbursement for\nactual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of his or her\nofficial duties. Anything to the contrary contained herein\nnotwithstanding, any member who serves as an employee of the authority\nshall be entitled to receive such salary as the members may determine\nfor services as such employee.\n  (3) Such members other than those serving as employees of the\nauthority may engage in private employment, or in a profession or\nbusiness. The authority, its members, officers and employees shall be\nsubject to the provisions of sections seventy-three and seventy-four of\nthe public officers law.\n  (4) Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law, general,\nspecial or local, no officer of the state or of any civil division\nthereof shall be deemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit his office or\nemployment by reason of his acceptance of membership on the authority\ncreated by this section.\n  (5) The governor may remove any member for inefficiency, neglect of\nduty or misconduct in office after giving him a copy of the charges\nagainst him and an opportunity to be heard, in person or by counsel, in\nhis defense, upon not less than ten days notice. If any such member\nshall be removed, the governor shall file in the office of the\ndepartment of state a complete statement of the charges made against\nsuch member and his findings thereon, together with a complete record of\nthe proceedings.\n  (6) The authority in its corporate existence shall continue until\nterminated by law, provided, however, that no such law shall take effect\nso long as the authority shall have bonds, notes and other obligations\noutstanding, unless adequate provision has been made for the payment\nthereof in the documents securing the same. Upon termination of the\nexistence of the authority, all its rights and properties shall vest in\nthe state.\n  (7) A majority of the members of the authority shall constitute a\nquorum for the transaction of any business or the exercise of any power\nor function of the authority. The authority may delegate to one or more\nof its members, or to its officers, agents or employees, such powers and\nduties as it may deem proper.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>