<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1977-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1977-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="1977-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1977-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1977-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1977-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-1977-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_1977_B">
        <num>1977-B</num>
        <heading>Reserve funds and appropriations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any moneys appropriated and made available by the\nstate only for the purposes of such fund,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any proceeds of sale of\nany bonds issued to finance the Battery Park project area to the extent\nprovided in the resolution of the authority authorizing the issuance\nthereof,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any funds directed to be transferred by the authority to\nsuch fund, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>any other moneys made available to the authority only\nfor the purposes of such fund from any other source or sources. The\nmoneys held in or credited to such capital reserve fund, except as\nhereinafter provided, shall be used solely for the payment of the\nprincipal of such bonds or of the sinking fund payments hereinafter\nmentioned with respect to such bonds, the purchase or redemption of such\nbonds, the payment of interest on such bonds, or the payment of any\nredemption premium required to be paid when any of such bonds are\nredeemed prior to maturity; provided, however, that moneys in such fund\nshall not be withdrawn therefrom at any time in such amount as would\nreduce the amount of such fund to less than the amount of the Battery\nPark project area capital reserve fund requirement hereinbelow referred\nto, except for the purpose of making with respect to such bonds payment,\nwhen due, of principal, interest and the sinking fund payments\nhereinafter mentioned for the payment of which other moneys of the\nauthority are not available. Moneys in such capital reserve fund not\nrequired for immediate use or disbursement may be invested in\nobligations of the state or the United States of America or obligations\nthe principal and interest of which are guaranteed by the state or the\nUnited States of America or obligations of agencies of the United States\nof America which may from time to time be legally purchased by savings\nbanks of the state as investment of funds belonging to them or in their\ncontrol. In computing the amount of such capital reserve fund for the\npurposes of this section, securities in which all or a portion of such\nfund are invested shall be valued at par or, if purchased at less than\npar, at their cost to the authority.\n  2. The authority shall not issue any of such bonds at any time secured\nby such capital reserve fund if the amount in such capital reserve fund\nat the time of issuance does not equal or exceed the amount of said\ncap...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all interest payable during such fiscal\nyear on all such bonds outstanding on said date of computation, plus</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nthe principal amount of all such bonds outstanding on said date of\ncomputation which mature during such fiscal year, plus</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>all amounts\nspecified in any resolution of the authority authorizing any of such\nbonds as payable during such fiscal year as a sinking fund payment with\nrespect to any of such bonds which mature after such fiscal year, all\ncalculated on the assumption that bonds will after said date of\ncomputation cease to be outstanding by reason, but only by reason, of\nthe payment of bonds when due and the payment when due and application\nin accordance with the resolution authorizing those bonds of all of such\nsinking fund payments payable at or after said date of computation; and\nthere shall be annually apportioned and paid to the authority for\ndeposit in such capital reserve fund the sums so certified by the\nchairman of the authority.  All sums so apportioned and paid shall be\ndeposited by the authority in such capital reserve fund. The principal\namount of bonds secured by such capital reserve fund to which state\nfunds are apportionable pursuant to this subdivision shall be limited to\nthe total amount of bonds and notes outstanding on the effective date of\nthis act, plus the total amount of bonds and notes contracted after the\neffective date of this act to finance projects in progress on the\neffective date of this act as determined by the New York state public\nauthorities control board created pursuant to section fifty of this\nchapter whose affirmative determination shall be conclusive as to all\nmatters of law and fact solely for the purposes of the limitations\ncontained in this subdivision, but in no event shall the total amount of\nbonds so secured by such a capital reserve fund or funds exceed two\nhundred million dollars, excluding bonds issued to refund such\noutstanding bonds until the date of redemption of such outstanding\nbonds. As outstanding bonds so secured are paid, the amount so secured\nshall be reduced accordingly but the redemption of such outstanding\nbonds from the proceeds of refunding bonds shall not reduce the amount\nso secured.\n  4....</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "operating expenses" for the\nfiscal year shall mean ordinary expenditures for operation and\nadministration of the authority; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_1977_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the term "available operating\nrevenues" for the fiscal year shall mean all amounts received on account\nof rentals and fees charged by the authority, if any, and income or\ninterest earned or added to funds of the authority due to the investment\nthereof, and not required under the terms or provisions of any convenant\nor agreement with holders of any bonds or notes of the authority to be\napplied to any purposes other than payment of expenses of the authority.\n  6. This section is applicable only to the Battery Park project area\ncapital reserve fund.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>