<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2017"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2017"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2017"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2017/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2017/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2017/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2017/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2017">
        <num>2017</num>
        <heading>Onondaga county solid waste disposal authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2017. Onondaga county solid waste disposal authority. 1. A\ncorporation known as the "Onondaga county solid waste disposal\nauthority" is hereby created for the purposes and charged with the\nduties and having the powers provided in this title. The authority shall\nbe a body corporate and politic constituting a public benefit\ncorporation. It shall consist of five members, all of whom shall be\nresidents of the county, who shall be appointed by the county executive\nof the county of Onondaga subject to confirmation by a majority of the\nOnondaga county legislature. The first members shall be appointed for\nthe following terms from the effective date of this act, as follows:\ntwo for a term of three years, two for a term of two years and one for a\nterm of one year. Subsequent appointments shall be made in the same\nmanner and for terms of three years. All members shall continue to hold\noffice until their successors are appointed and qualify. The first\nchairman shall be designated by the county executive. Subsequent\nchairmen shall be elected annually by the members of the authority.\nVacancies, occurring otherwise than by expiration of term of office,\nshall be filled by appointments by the county executive for the\nunexpired terms. Members of the authority may be removed from office for\nthe same reasons and in the same manner as may be provided by law for\nthe removal of officers of the county. The members of the authority\nshall receive no compensation for their services but shall be reimbursed\nfor all their actual and necessary expenses incurred in connection with\nthe carrying out of the purposes of this title. The powers of the\nauthority shall be vested in and be exercised by the members at a\nmeeting duly called and held and three members shall constitute a\nquorum. No action shall be taken except pursuant to the favorable vote\nof at least three members. The authority may delegate to one or more of\nits members, officers, agents or employees such powers and duties as it\nmay deem proper.\n  2. The authority and its corporate existence shall continue until all\nits liabilities have been met and its bonds have been paid in full or\nsuch liabilities or bonds have otherwise been discharged and thereupon\nall rights and properties of the authority shall pass to and be vested\nin the county of Onondaga.\n  3. The officers of the authority shall consist of a chairman, a\nvice-chairman and a treasurer, who shall be members of the authority,\nand a secretary, who need not be a member of the authority. The\nvice-chairman, treasurer and secretary shall be appointed by the\nauthority and shall serve at the pleasure of the authority. The\nauthority may appoint and at pleasure remove an attorney and an\nengineer, which positions, in addition to the position of secretary,\nshall be in the exempt class of the civil service, and such additional\nofficers and employees as it may require for the performance of its\nduties, fix and determine their qualifications, duties and compensation,\nsubject to the provisions of the civil service law of the state of New\nYork. The authority may also from time to time contract for expert\nprofessional services. The treasurer shall execute a bond, conditioned\nupon the faithful performance of the duties of his office, the amount\nand sufficiency of which shall be approved by the authority and the\npremium therefor shall be paid by the authority.\n  4. It is hereby determined and declared that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers, purposes and duties are in all respects for\nthe benefit of the people of the county of Onondaga and the state of New\nYork, for the improvement of their health, welfare and prosperity and\nthat the said purposes are public purposes and that the authority is and\nwill be performing an essential governmental function in the exercise of\nthe powers conferred upon it by this title.\n  5. Upon creation of the authority, from time to time the county\nlegislature may, by resolution, appropriate sums of money to defray the\npreliminary expenses of the authority. The moneys so appropriated shall\nbe repaid by the authority to the county out of the proceeds of the\nfirst bond issue of the authority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>