<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-202"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-202"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="202"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-202/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-202/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_202">
        <num>202</num>
        <heading>Bethpage park authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 202. Bethpage park authority. A board, to be known as "Bethpage\nPark Authority, " is hereby created. Such board shall be a body\ncorporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation. It\nshall consist of the commissioners of the Long Island state park\ncommission and their successors. In case such commission shall cease to\nexist the board shall consist of three members who shall be appointed by\nthe governor, by and with the consent of the senate; the term of office\nof the first members so appointed shall be two, four and six years,\nrespectively, and thereafter the terms of office of members so appointed\nshall be six years. The president of the board shall be the president of\nthe Long Island state park commission or if the commission shall cease\nto exist shall be appointed by the governor. The members of the board\nshall be entitled to no compensation for their services, but shall be\nentitled to reimbursement for all expenses incurred or to be incurred,\nin connection with Bethpage park. The power of such corporation shall be\nvested in and exercised by the board and a majority of the members of\nthe board then in office shall constitute a quorum. The board may\ndelegate to one or more of its members, or to its agents and employees,\nsuch powers and duties as it may deem proper. The board and its\ncorporate existence shall continue only for a period of five years and\nthereafter until all its liabilities have been met and its bonds have\nbeen paid in full or such liabilities or bonds have otherwise been\ndischarged. Upon its ceasing to exist all its rights and properties\nshall pass to the state and become subject to the jurisdiction of the\ncommission. The board shall execute such instruments as may be required\nby the commission to accomplish transfer of title to the state.\n  * NB (Abolished in 1975)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>