<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2030"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2030"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2030"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2030/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2030/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2030/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2030/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2030">
        <num>2030</num>
        <heading>Contracts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2030. Contracts. All contracts, or orders, for work, material or\nsupplies performed or furnished in connection with construction shall be\nawarded by the authority pursuant to resolution. Such contracts, or\norders, for work, material or supplies needed for any particular purpose\ninvolving an expenditure of more than two thousand five hundred dollars\nshall be awarded only after inviting sealed bids or proposals therefor.\nThe notice inviting sealed proposals shall be published at least once in\na newspaper or trade paper selected by the authority for such purpose,\nsuch publication to the be at least ten days before the date for the\nreceipt of bids. If the authority shall not deem it for the interest of\nthe authority to reject all bids, it shall award the contract to the\nlowest bidder, unless the authority shall determine that it is for the\npublic interest that a bid other than the lowest bid should be accepted.\nIn any contract for work, material or supplies, there shall be inserted\nin the discretion of the authority a provision that additional work may\nbe done or material or supplies furnished for the purpose of completing\nsuch contract at an expense not exceeding fifteen per centum of the\namount of such contract if such additional work, materials or supplies\nshall be ordered by the authority. The bidder whose bid is accepted\nshall give security for the faithful performance of the contract, and\nsuch other security as the authority may require, and may be required to\nmaintain for such period as shall be stipulated any construction done\nunder the contract, all in the manner prescribed and required by the\nauthority; and the sufficiency of such security shall, in addition to\nthe justification and acknowledgment, be approved by the authority. All\nbids or proposals shall be publicly opened by the authority or its duly\nauthorized agent.  If the bidder whose bid has been accepted after\nadvertising shall neglect or refuse to accept the contract within five\ndays after written notice that the same has been awarded to him on his\nbid or proposal, or, if he accepts but does not execute the contract and\ngive proper security the authority shall have the right to declare his\ndeposit forfeited, and thereupon it shall be readvertised and relet as\nabove provided. In case any work shall be abandoned by any contractor,\nthe authority may, if the best interest of the authority be thereby\nserved, adopt on behalf of the authority any or all subcontracts made by\nsuch contractor for such work and all such subcontractors shall be bound\nby such adoption if made; and the authority shall in the manner provided\nherein readvertise and relet the work specified in the original contract\nexclusive of so much thereof as shall be provided for in the subcontract\nor subcontracts so adopted. No bid shall be accepted from or any\ncontracts awarded to, any person or corporation who is in arrears to the\nauthority, or the county of Onondaga upon any debt or contract, or is a\ndefaulter as surety or otherwise upon any obligation of the authority,\nor the county. Every contract involving an expenditure of more than two\nthousand five hundred dollars when made and entered into as herein\nprovided for shall be executed in duplicate, one copy of which shall be\nheld by the authority and one copy of which shall be delivered to the\ncontractor.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>