<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2041-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2041_O">
        <num>2041-O</num>
        <heading>Contracts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2041_O__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four and\nsubdivision seven of section one hundred twenty-w of the general\nmunicipal law. In any construction contract, the authority may provide a\nprogram for the payment of damages for delays and incentive awards in\norder to encourage timely project completion. An action, suit or\nproceeding contesting the validity of a contract awarded pursuant to\nthis section, or the validity of the procedures relating to such award,\nshall be governed by the provisions of subdivision six of section one\nhundred twenty-w of the general municipal law and the term\n"municipality" as used in such subdivision six shall mean the authority.\n  The bidder whose bid is accepted shall give security for the faithful\nperformance of the contract, and such other security as the authority\nmay require, and may be required to maintain any construction done under\nthe contract for such period as shall be stipulated, all in the manner\nprescribed and required by the authority and the sufficiency of such\nsecurity shall, in addition to the justification and acknowledgement, be\napproved by the authority. All bids or proposals shall be publicly\nopened by the governing body or its duly authorized agent. If the bidder\nwhose bid or proposal has been accepted after advertising shall neglect\nor refuse to accept the contract within five days after written notice\nthat the contract has been awarded to him on his bid proposal or, if he\naccepts but does not execute the contract and give proper security, the\nauthority shall have the right to declare his deposit forfeited. In case\nany work shall be abandoned by any contractor, the authority may, if it\ndetermines that the public interest is thereby served, adopt on behalf\nof the authority any or all subcontracts made by such contractor for\nsuch work and all such subcontractors shall be bound by such adoption if\nmade. No bid proposal shall be accepted from or any contract awarded to,\nany person or corporation who is in arrears to...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>