<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2041-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2041_F">
        <num>2041-F</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2041-f. Transfer of officers and employees. Any officer or employee\nof a participating county or of any municipality located within a\nparticipating county under civil service who is selected by the\nauthority may, with the consent of the legislative body of the employing\ncounty or municipality, be transferred to the authority and shall be\neligible for such transfer and appointment, without examination, to\napplicable offices, positions and employment under the authority. The\nsalary or compensation of any such officer or employee, after such\ntransfer, shall be paid by the authority. Any such officers or employees\nso transferred to the authority pursuant to this section who are members\nof or benefit under any existing pension or retirement fund or system\nshall continue to have all rights, privileges, obligations and status\nwith respect to such fund or system as are now prescribed by law but,\nduring this period of their employment by the authority, all\ncontributions to such fund or system heretofore made by the employing\ncounty or municipality, shall be made by the authority.  All such\nofficers or employees so transferred to the authority who have been\nappointed to positions under the rules and classifications of the\npersonnel officer of the county or any employing municipality shall have\nthe same status with respect thereto after transfer to the authority as\nthey had under their original appointment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>