<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-V"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-V"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2041-V"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2041_V">
        <num>2041-V</num>
        <heading>Transfer of environmental applications, proceedings, approvals and permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2041-v. Transfer of environmental applications, proceedings,\napprovals and permits. 1. Any application in relation to the purpose of\nor contemplated by this title or any proceeding commenced by any\nparticipating county, with the department of environmental conservation,\nthe department of transportation or any other state agency or\ninstrumentality or with the United States environmental protection\nagency or any other federal agency or instrumentality shall inure to and\nfor the benefit of the authority to the same extent and in the same\nmanner as if the authority had been a party to such application or\nproceeding and the authority shall be deemed a party thereto, to the\nextent not prohibited by any federal law. Any license, approval, permit\nor decision issued or granted pursuant to or as a result of any such\napplication or proceeding shall inure to the benefit of and be binding\nupon the authority and shall be assigned and transferred by the\nparticipating county to the authority, unless such assignment and\ntransfer is prohibited by federal law.\n  2. All such applications, proceedings, licenses, approvals, permits\nand decisions shall further inure to and for the benefit of and be\nbinding upon any person leasing, acquiring, constructing, maintaining,\nusing or occupying any facility financed in whole or in part by the\nauthority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>