<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2041-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2041-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2041_B">
        <num>2041-B</num>
        <heading>Montgomery, Otsego, Schoharie solid waste management authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2041_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Each of the counties of Montgomery, Otsego and Schoharie\nelecting to participate in the authority shall file, on or before\nOctober first of the year following the year in which this title shall\ntake effect, in the office of the secretary of state, a certificate\nsigned by the chairman of its legislative body setting forth: the name\nof the authority; the names of the members appointed by that county; and\nthe effective date of this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2041_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall be perpetual in duration and shall continue\nuntil terminated by law, except if the certificate referred to in\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2041_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision is not filed by two or more counties\non or before the date specified in such paragraph, then the corporate\nexistence of the authority shall thereupon terminate and it shall be\ndeemed to be and shall be dissolved, provided, however, that no such\ntermination shall take effect so long as the authority shall have bonds\nor other obligations outstanding unless adequate provision has been made\nfor the payment or satisfaction thereof. Upon any termination of the\nexistence of the authority, all of the rights and properties of the\nauthority then remaining shall pass to and be vested in the\nparticipating counties in accordance with such law.\n  5. It is hereby determined and declared, that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers and duties are in all respects for the\nbenefit of the people of the participating counties and the state for\nthe improvement of their health, welfare, and prosperity and that such\npurposes are public purposes and that the authority is and will be\nperforming an essential governmental function in the exercise of the\npowers conferred upon it by this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>