<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-N"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-N"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2045-N"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-N/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-N/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2045_N">
        <num>2045-N</num>
        <heading>Exemption from taxes, assessments and certain fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2045-n. Exemption from taxes, assessments and certain fees. 1. It is\nhereby determined that the creation of the agency and the carrying out\nof its corporate purposes is in all respects for the benefit of the\npeople of the county and the state and is a public purpose and the\nagency shall be regarded as performing a governmental function in the\nexercise of the powers conferred upon it by this title and shall not be\nrequired to pay any taxes or assessments upon any property owned by it\nor under its jurisdiction, control or supervision or upon its\nactivities, or any filing, recording or transfer fees or taxes in\nrelation to instruments filed, recorded or transferred by it or on its\nbehalf. The construction, use, occupation or possession of any property\nowned by the agency or the county, including improvements thereon, by\nany person or public corporation under a lease, lease and sublease or\nany other agreement shall not operate to abrogate or limit the foregoing\nexemption, notwithstanding that the lessee, user, occupant or person in\npossession shall claim ownership for federal income tax purposes. The\nagency shall be deemed a public authority for the purposes of section\nfour hundred twelve of the real property tax law.\n  2. Except in the case of a municipality in which there shall be\nlocated a solid waste management-resource recovery facility, the agency\nshall not be authorized to make any payments in lieu of real property\ntaxes or assessments. The provisions of this subdivision shall not be\ndeemed to prohibit the agency from paying for specific governmental\nservices provided to it by any municipality, fire district or fire\nprotection district, and any fire district or fire protection district\nproviding such services is hereby authorized to charge for such services\nand to receive such payments.\n  3. Any bonds issued pursuant to this title together with the income\ntherefrom as well as the property of the agency shall be exempt from\ntaxes, except for transfer and estate taxes. The state hereby covenants\nwith the purchasers and with all subsequent holders and transferees of\nbonds issued by the agency pursuant to this title, in consideration of\nthe acceptance of and payment for the bonds, that the bonds of the\nagency issued pursuant to this title and the income therefrom and all\nrevenues, moneys, and other property pledged to secure the payment of\nsuch bonds shall at all times be free from taxation, except for transfer\nand estate taxes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>