<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-V"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-V"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2045-V"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-V/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-V/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2045_V">
        <num>2045-V</num>
        <heading>Transfer of environmental applications, proceedings, approvals and permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2045-v. Transfer of environmental applications, proceedings,\napprovals and permits. 1. Any application in relation to the purposes of\nor contemplated by this title heretofore filed, or any proceeding\nheretofore commenced, by the county with the state department of\nenvironmental conservation, the department of transportation or any\nother state agency or instrumentality or with the United States\nenvironmental protection agency or any other federal agency or\ninstrumentality shall inure to and for the benefit of the agency to the\nsame extent and in the same manner as if the agency had been a party to\nsuch application or proceeding from its inception, and the agency shall\nbe deemed a party thereto, to the extent not prohibited by any federal\nlaw. Any license, approval, permit or decision heretofore or hereafter\nissued or granted pursuant to or as a result of any such application or\nproceeding shall inure to the benefit of and be binding upon the agency\nand shall be assigned and transferred by the county to the agency,\nunless such assignment and transfer is prohibited by federal law.\n  2. All such applications, proceedings, licenses, approvals, permits\nand decisions shall further inure to and for the benefit of and be\nbinding upon any person leasing, acquiring, constructing, maintaining,\nusing or occupying any facility financed in whole or in part by the\nagency.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>