<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2045-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2045_P">
        <num>2045-P</num>
        <heading>Contracts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2045_P__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four and\nsubdivision seven of section one hundred twenty-w of the general\nmunicipal law. In any construction contract, the agency may provide a\nprogram for the payment of damages for delays and incentive awards in\norder to encourage timely project completion. An action, suit or\nproceeding contesting the validity of a contract awarded pursuant to\nthis section, or the validity of the procedures relating to such award,\nshall be governed by the provisions of subdivision six of section one\nhundred twenty-w of the general municipal law and the term\n"municipality" as used in such subdivision six shall mean the agency.\n  2. The bidder whose bid is accepted shall give security for the\nfaithful performance of the contract, and such other security as the\nagency may require, and may be required to maintain any construction\ndone under the contract for such period as shall be stipulated, all in\nthe manner prescribed and required by the agency and the sufficiency of\nsuch security shall, in addition to the justification and\nacknowledgment, be approved by the agency. All bids or proposals shall\nbe publicly opened by the governing body or its duly authorized agent.\nIf the bidder whose bid or proposal has been accepted after advertising\nshall neglect or refuse to accept the contract within five days after\nwritten notice that the contract has been awarded to him on his bid or\nproposal, or, if he accepts but does not execute the contract and give\nproper security, the agency shall have the right to declare his deposit\nforfeited. In case any work shall be abandoned by any contractor, the\nagency may, if it determines that the public interest is thereby served,\nadopt on behalf of the agency any or all subcontracts made by such\ncontractor for such work and all such subcontractors shall be bound by\nsuch adoption if made. No bid or proposal shall be accepted from or any\ncontract awarded to, any person or corporation who is in arrears to the\nagency or...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>