<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2045-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2045_E">
        <num>2045-E</num>
        <heading>Powers of the agency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2045_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the agency shall not have the power of\neminent domain, (ii) the acquisition by the agency of any real property\ndesignated as the site for any facility shall be subject to prior\napproval by the county legislature, and (iii) in selecting the location\nfor any such site the agency shall give consideration to the present and\nany proposed land use character of the area in which such site is to be\nlocated and the zoning laws or regulations, if any, otherwise generally\napplicable to such area;\n  4. To receive, transport, process, dispose of, sell, store, convey,\nrecycle, and deal with, in any lawful manner and way, solid waste and\nany products or by-products thereof now or hereafter developed or\ndiscovered, including any energy generated by the operation of any solid\nwaste management-resource recovery facility. Any such disposal or sale\nmay be effected on such terms and in such manner as the agency may deem\nproper;\n  5. To plan, develop and construct projects and to pay the cost thereof\nand to have the right to contract in relation thereto with\nmunicipalities or persons within or without the county and to own and\noperate, maintain, repair, improve, reconstruct, enlarge, and extend,\nsubject to the provisions of this title, any of its projects acquired or\nconstructed under this title, and to sell, lease, mortgage or otherwise\ndispose of any project or part thereof to any person or public\ncorporation, subject to such conditions and limitations as the agency\nmay determine to be in the public interest;\n  6. To assist in the planning, development and construction of and the\nfinancing of the cost of any solid waste management-resource recovery\nfacility to be located in the county whether or not such solid waste\nmanagement-resource recovery facility is to be owned or operated by the\nagency, which assistance may include loans to any person or public\ncorporation. Any such solid waste management-resource recovery facility\nproducing either electricity or s...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2045_E__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision two of such section two\nthousand forty-five-t of this title. The agency shall in no event fix\nany such rates, rentals, fees or other charges with respect to\nmunicipalities entering into such contracts with the county subsequent\nto such date in amounts less than those fixed with respect to\nmunicipalities entering into such contracts with the county on or before\nsuch date;\n  15. To accept gifts, grants, loans or contributions from the United\nStates, the state or any agency or instrumentality of either of them, or\nany municipality or from any person, by bequest or otherwise, and to\nexpend the proceeds for any corporate purposes of the agency; and\n  16. To make payments to, and settle claims asserted by owners of\nproperty in proximity to and adversely affected by, landfill facilities\nof the agency in order to compensate such owners in whole or in part for\ndiminution of the value of their property, if any, directly resulting\nfrom the siting of the agency landfill facility or the activities\nundertaken therein. The amount and manner of such payments shall be\ndetermined by resolution of the agency, and shall be based on real\nestate market studies and/or appraisals undertaken at the direction of\nthe agency, in such form and substance satisfactory to the agency. The\nagency shall establish rules and regulations setting forth the\nspecifications pursuant to which real estate market studies and/or\nappraisals shall be conducted and such other rules and regulations as\nmay be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this subdivision. Such\nrules and regulations shall include a requirement that all property\nowners requesting payments in accordance therewith must file a claim\nwith the agency by a date specified by the agency. Any payments made\npursuant to the provisions of this subdivision shall be considered a\ncost of the agency in the computation of rates, fees, and charges in\naccordance with subdivision fourteen of this section.\n  17. To d...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>