<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2045-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2045_K">
        <num>2045-K</num>
        <heading>Moneys of the agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2045-k. Moneys of the agency. All moneys of the agency from whatever\nsource derived shall be paid to the treasurer of the agency and shall be\ndeposited forthwith in a bank or banks in the state designated by the\ngoverning body. The moneys in such accounts shall be paid out on check\nof the treasurer upon requisition by the governing body or of such other\nperson or persons as the governing body may authorize to make such\nrequisitions. All deposits of such moneys shall be secured by\nobligations of the United States or of the state or of the county of a\nmarket value equal at all times to the amount on deposit and all banks\nand trust companies are authorized to give such security for such\ndeposits. The agency shall have power, notwithstanding the provisions of\nthis section, to contract with the holders of any bonds as to the\ncustody, collection, security, investment and payment of any moneys of\nthe agency or any moneys held in trust or otherwise for the payment of\nbonds or in any way to secure bonds, and carry out any such contract\nnotwithstanding that such contract may be inconsistent with the\nprovisions of this section. Moneys held in trust or otherwise for the\npayment of bonds or in any way to secure bonds and deposits of such\nmoneys may be secured in the same manner as moneys of the agency and all\nbanks and trust companies are authorized to give such security for such\ndeposits. Any moneys of the agency not required for immediate use or\ndisbursement may, at the discretion of the agency, be invested in those\nobligations specified pursuant to the provisions of section\nninety-eight-a of the state finance law. Subject to the provisions of\nany contract with bondholders and with the approval of the comptroller,\nthe agency shall prescribe a system of accounts.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>