<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2045-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2045-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2045_G">
        <num>2045-G</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2045-g. Transfer of officers and employees. Any officer or employee\nof the county or of the Onondaga county solid waste disposal authority,\nunder civil service, selected by the agency may, with the consent of the\ncounty or such authority, be transferred to the agency and shall be\neligible for such transfer and appointment, without examination, to\napplicable offices, positions and employment under the agency. The\nsalary or compensation of any such officer or employee, after such\ntransfer, shall be paid by the agency. Any such officers or employees so\ntransferred to the agency pursuant to this subdivision, who are members\nof or benefit under any existing pension or retirement fund or system,\nshall continue to have all rights, privileges, obligations and status\nwith respect to such fund or system as are now prescribed by law, but\nduring the period of their employment by the agency, all contributions\nto such fund or system to be paid by the employer on account of such\nofficers or employees shall be paid by the agency. All such officers or\nemployees so transferred to the agency who have been appointed to\npositions under the rules and classifications of the personnel officer\nof the county shall have the same status with respect thereto after\ntransfer to the agency as they had under their original appointment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>