<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2047-K"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2047-K"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2047-K"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2047-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2047-K/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2047-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2047-K/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2047_K">
        <num>2047-K</num>
        <heading>Moneys of the agency</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2047-k. Moneys of the agency. All moneys of the agency from whatever\nsource derived shall be paid to the treasurer of the agency and shall be\ndeposited forthwith in a bank or banks in the state designated by the\ngoverning body. The moneys in such accounts shall be paid out on check\nof the treasurer upon requisition by the governing body or of such other\nperson or persons as the governing body may authorize to make such\nrequisitions. All deposits of such moneys shall be secured by\nobligations of the United States or of the state or of the county or any\nmunicipality of a market value equal at all times to the amount on\ndeposit and all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such\nsecurity for such deposits. The agency shall have power, notwithstanding\nthe provisions of this section, to contract with the holders of any\nbonds as to the custody, collection, security, investment and payment of\nany moneys of the agency or any moneys held in trust or otherwise for\nthe payment of bonds or in any way to secure bonds, and carry out any\nsuch contract notwithstanding that such contract may be inconsistent\nwith the provisions of this section. Moneys held in trust or otherwise\nfor the payment of bonds or in any way to secure bonds and deposits of\nsuch moneys may be secured in the same manner as moneys of the agency\nand all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such security\nfor such deposits. Any moneys of the agency not required for immediate\nuse or disbursement may, at the discretion of the agency, be invested in\nthose obligations specified pursuant to the provisions of section\nninety-eight-a of the state finance law. Subject to the provisions of\nany contract with bondholders and with the approval of the comptroller,\nthe agency shall prescribe a system of accounts.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>