<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2049-UU"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2049-UU"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2049-UU"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2049-UU/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2049-UU/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2049-UU/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2049-UU/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2049_UU">
        <num>2049-UU</num>
        <heading>Solid waste facility reserve fund</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2049-uu. Solid waste facility reserve fund. The legislative bodies\nof the counties may establish a special fund, to be known as solid waste\nfacility reserve fund of such county. There shall be credited to such\nreserve fund all amounts paid to such county and specifically designated\nby the payor for deposit in such reserve fund, together with such county\nmoneys as may be appropriated thereto from time to time.  Moneys in such\nreserve funds may be appropriated only for the purpose of paying amounts\ndue from the county under the terms of any contract entered into\npursuant to this title, for which an insufficient or no provision has\notherwise been made, except that upon the adoption of a resolution by at\nleast a two-third vote of the voting strength of such counties\nlegislative body, all or any portion of the moneys in such reserve fund\nmay be transferred to any other reserve fund established by the county\npursuant to the general municipal law. To the extent not inconsistent\nwith the provisions of this section, the management of such reserve fund\nand the investment of moneys therein shall be subject to the provisions\nof section six-h of the general municipal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>