<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-205"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-205"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="205"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-205/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-205/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_205">
        <num>205</num>
        <heading>Moneys of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 205. Moneys of the authority. All moneys of the authority from\nwhatever source derived shall be paid to the comptroller as agent of the\nauthority, who shall not commingle such moneys with any other moneys.\nSuch moneys shall be deposited in a separate bank account or accounts.\nThe moneys in such accounts shall be paid out on check of the\ncomptroller on requisition of the president of the authority or of such\nother person or persons as the authority may authorize to make such\nrequisitions. All deposits of such moneys shall, if required by the\ncomptroller or the authority, be secured by obligations of the United\nStates or of the state of New York of a market value equal at all times\nto the amount of the deposit and all banks and trust companies are\nauthorized to give such security for such deposits. The comptroller and\nhis legally authorized representatives are hereby authorized and\nempowered from time to time to examine the accounts and books of the\nauthority, including its receipts, disbursements, contracts, leases,\nsinking funds, investments and any other matters relating to its\nfinancial standing. This section shall not be construed as limiting the\npower of the authority to agree as to the custody and disposition of\nmoneys or fees and revenues for the security of its bonds.\n  * NB (Abolished in 1975)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>