<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-GG"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-GG"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2050-GG"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-GG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-GG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2050_GG">
        <num>2050-GG</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2050-gg. Transfer of officers and employees. In accordance with\nsection seventy of the civil service law, any officer or employee of a\nparticipating municipality under civil service who is selected by the\nauthority may, with the consent of the chief elected official of such\nmunicipality, be transferred to the authority and shall be eligible for\nsuch transfer and appointment, without examination, to applicable\noffices, positions and employment under the authority. The salary or\ncompensation of any such officer or employee, after such transfer, shall\nbe paid by the authority. Any such officers or employees so transferred\nto the authority pursuant to this section who are members of or benefit\nunder any existing pension or retirement fund or system shall continue\nto have all rights, privileges, obligations and status with respect to\nsuch fund or system as are now prescribed by law but, during the period\nof their employment by the authority, all contributions to such fund or\nsystem shall be paid by the authority. All such officers or employees so\ntransferred to the authority who have been appointed to positions under\nthe rules and classifications of the personnel officer of the applicable\nparticipating municipality shall have the same status with respect\nthereto after transfer to the authority as they had under their original\nappointment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>