<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2050-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2050-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2050_C">
        <num>2050-C</num>
        <heading>Ulster county resource recovery agency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2050_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The chairman of the county legislature shall file on or before\nJuly first, nineteen hundred eighty-seven, in the office of the\nsecretary of state, a certificate setting forth:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2050_C__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the name of the\nagency;</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2050_C__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the names of the members appointed by the chairman of the\ncounty legislature and their terms of office; and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2050_C__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>the effective date\nof this title. The agency shall be perpetual in duration, except that if\nsuch certificate is not filed with the secretary of state on or before\nsuch date then the corporate existence of the agency shall thereupon\nterminate and it shall thereupon be deemed to be and shall be dissolved.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2050_C__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as provided in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2050_C__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the\nagency and its corporate existence shall continue until terminated by\nlaw, provided, however, that no such law shall take effect so long as\nthe agency shall have bonds or other obligations outstanding unless\nadequate provision has been made for the payment or satisfaction\nthereof. Upon termination of the existence of the agency, all of the\nrights and properties of the agency then remaining shall pass to and\nvest in the county.\n  5. In addition to any powers granted to it by law, the county\nlegislature from time to time may appropriate by resolution sums of\nmoney to defray project costs or any other costs and expenses of the\nagency. Subject to the rights of bondholders, the county legislature may\ndetermine if the moneys so appropriated shall be subject to repayment by\nthe agency to the county and, in such event, the manner and time or\ntimes for such repayment.\n  6. It is hereby determined and declared, that the agency and the\ncarrying out of its powers and duties are in all respects for the\nbenefit of the people of the county and the state for the improvement of\ntheir health, welfare and prosperity and that such purposes are public\npurposes and that the agency is and will be performing an essential\ngovernmental function in the exercise of the powers conferred upon it by\nthis title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>