<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-U"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-U"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2051-U"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-U/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-U/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2051_U">
        <num>2051-U</num>
        <heading>Solid waste reserve fund</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2051-u. Solid waste reserve fund. The county legislature may\nestablish a special fund, to be known as the solid waste reserve fund of\nthe county. There shall be credited to such reserve fund all amounts\npaid to the county and specifically designated by the payor for deposit\nin such reserve fund, together with such county moneys as may be\nappropriated thereto from time to time. Moneys in such reserve fund may\nbe appropriated only for the purpose of paying amounts due from the\ncounty under the terms of any contract entered into pursuant to this\ntitle, for which an insufficient or no provision has otherwise been\nmade, except that upon the adoption of a resolution by at least a\ntwo-thirds vote of the voting strength of the county legislature, all or\nany portion of the moneys in such reserve fund may be transferred to any\nother reserve fund established by the county pursuant to the general\nmunicipal law. To the extent not inconsistent with the provisions of\nthis section, the management of such reserve fund and the investment of\nmoneys therein shall be subject to the provisions of section six-h of\nthe general municipal law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>