<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-P"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-P"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2051-P"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-P/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2051-P/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2051_P">
        <num>2051-P</num>
        <heading>Contracts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2051_P__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision four and\nsubdivision seven of section one hundred twenty-w of the general\nmunicipal law. In any construction contract, the authority may provide a\nprogram for the payment of damages for delays and incentive awards in\norder to encourage timely project completion. An action, suit or\nproceeding contesting the validity of a contract awarded pursuant to\nthis section, or the validity of the procedures relating to such award,\nshall be governed by the provisions of subdivision six of section one\nhundred twenty-w of the general municipal law and the term\n"municipality" as used in such subdivision six shall mean the authority.\n  2. The bidder whose bid is accepted shall give security for the\nfaithful performance of the contract, and such other security as the\nauthority may require, and may be required to maintain any construction\ndone under the contract for such period as shall be stipulated, all in\nthe manner prescribed and required by the authority and the sufficiency\nof such security shall, in addition to the justification and\nacknowledgement, be approved by the authority. All bids or proposals\nshall be publicly opened by the governing body or its duly authorized\nagent. If the bidder whose bid or proposal has been accepted after\nadvertising shall neglect or refuse to accept the contract within five\ndays after written notice that the contract has been awarded to him on\nhis bid or proposal or if he accepts but does not execute the contract\nand give proper security, the authority shall have the right to declare\nhis deposit forfeited. In case any work shall be abandoned by any\ncontractor, the authority may, if it determines that the public interest\nis thereby served, adopt on behalf of the authority any or all\nsubcontracts made by such contractor for such work and all such\nsubcontractors shall be bound by such adoption if made. No bid or\nproposal shall be accepted from or any contract awarded to any person or\ncorporation who is in ar...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>