<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2052-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2052_G">
        <num>2052-G</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2052-g. Transfer of officers and employees. Any public officer or\nemployee under civil service who is selected by the authority may, with\nthe consent of the commission, board or chief executive officer of the\nmunicipality by which he or she has been employed, be transferred to the\nauthority and shall be eligible for such transfer and appointment\nwithout examination to comparable offices, positions and employment\nunder the authority. The salary or compensation of any such officer or\nemployee, after such transfer, shall be paid by the authority. Any such\nofficers or employees so transferred to the authority pursuant to this\nsection, who are members of or benefit under any existing pension or\nretirement fund or system, shall continue to have all rights,\nprivileges, obligations and status with respect to such fund or system\nas are now prescribed by law, but, during the period of their employment\nby the authority, all contributions to such funds or systems to be paid\nby the employer on account of such officers or employees shall be paid\nby the authority. All such officers or employees so transferred to the\nauthority who have been appointed to positions under the rules and\nclassifications of the civil service commission shall have the same\nstatus with respect thereto after transfer to the authority as they had\nunder their original appointment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>