<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2052-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2052_B">
        <num>2052-B</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2052-b. Definitions. As used or referred to in this title, unless a\ndifferent meaning clearly appears from the context:\n  1. "Authority" means the corporation created by section two thousand\nfifty-two-c of this title.\n  2. "Board" means the members of the authority constituting and acting\nas the governing body of the authority.\n  3. "Comptroller" means the comptroller of the state.\n  4. "Construct", "construction" or "constructed" means the acquisition,\nerection, building, alteration, improvement, increase, enlargement,\nextension, reconstruction, renovation or rehabilitation of the sports\nfacility, as the case may be; the inspection and supervision thereof;\nand the engineering, architectural, legal, fiscal and economic\ninvestigations and studies, surveys, designs, plans, working drawings,\nspecifications, procedure and other actions preliminary or incidental\nthereto.\n  5. "Cost" as applied to any project, includes the cost of\nconstruction, the cost of the acquisition of all property, including\nreal property and other property, both real, personal and mixed and\nimproved and unimproved, the cost of the demolishing, removing or\nrelocating of any buildings or structures on lands so acquired,\nincluding the cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or\nstructures may be moved or relocated, the cost of the sports facility,\nmachinery, apparatus and equipment, the cost of engineering and\narchitectural surveys, plans and specifications, the cost of consultant\nand legal services, the cost of other expenses necessary or incidental\nto the construction of any project and the financing of the construction\nthereof and the financing of the placing of any project in operation,\nincluding reimbursement to the county or any municipality, state agency,\nthe state, the United States government or any other person for\nexpenditures that would be costs of a project hereunder had they been\nmade directly by the authority.\n  6. "County" means the county of Oneida.\n  7. "County executive" means the county executive of the county, being\nthe chief executive officer of the county.\n  8. "County board of legislators" means the board of legislators of the\ncounty.\n  9. "Municipality" means any county, city, town, village, or city\nschool district, union free school district, central school district or\ncommon school district, any other such instrumentality, including any\nagency or public corporation of the state, or any of the foregoing or\nany combination thereof.\n  10. "Murnane Field" means the stadium commonly known by that name,\nlocated in the city of Utica, as well as the surrounding lands,\nincluding all structures appurtenant thereto, located in the vicinity of\nSunset Avenue and Burrstone Road in the city of Utica, which shall\ninclude all of the property deeded to the city of Utica by deed dated\nFebruary third, nineteen hundred eight and thereafter conveyed to the\nUtica city school district by deed dated March fourteenth, nineteen\nhundred seventy-seven, except for any portions of the said property\nwhich have been appropriated by the state of New York or otherwise\nconveyed.\n  11. "Person" means any natural person, partnership, association, joint\nventure or corporation, exclusive of a public corporation.\n  12. "Project" means the sports facility, including the structures or\nparts thereof and appurtenances thereto, real property or any other\nproperty incidental to and included in such facility or part thereof,\nand any improvements, extensions and betterments.\n  13. "Real property" means lands, structures, franchises, rights and\ninterests in land and air rights, and any and all things and rights\nincluded within said term and includes not only fees simple absolute,\nbut also any and all lesser interests including, but not limited to,\neasements, rights-of-way, uses, leases, licenses and all other\nincorporeal hereditaments and every estate, interest or right, legal or\nequitable, including terms for years and liens thereon by way of\njudgments, mortgages or otherwise and also claims for damage to real\nestate.\n  14. "Sports facility" means Murnane Field in the city of Utica.\n  15. "State" means the state of New York.\n  16. "State agency" means any state officer, public benefit\ncorporation, department, board, commission, bureau, division or other\nagency or instrumentality of the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>