<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-E"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-E"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2052-E"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-E/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-E/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2052_E">
        <num>2052-E</num>
        <heading>Appropriations for purposes of the authority; transfer of property to authority; acquisition of property by county or other municipality ...</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2052_E__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring the\nuse of such project by the county or such municipality for a specified\nperiod of time;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2052_E__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>limiting the right, including a prohibition, of the\ncounty or any such municipality to construct a sports facility which\nwill serve the same, or substantially the same, function as the project\nowned, leased or to be constructed or leased by the authority;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2052_E__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nproviding for specified minimum periodic payments whether or not a\nproject is actually used, subject to such limitations, exceptions and\nprovisions therein; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2052_E__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>requiring the county or any such\nmunicipality to pay to the authority such amounts as shall be necessary\nto assure the continued operation of the authority. All such payments\nshall be determined and paid in such manner and at such times as may be\nprovided in such contracts.\n  4. Any gift, grant, sale, conveyance, loan, contract or lease\nauthorized by this section may be made or entered into by the county,\nany other such municipality and/or the authority and no such gift,\ngrant, sale, conveyance, loan, contract or lease shall be subject to\nreferendum, permissive or otherwise.\n  5. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, general, special\nor local to the contrary, the authority shall allow the Utica city\nschool district to use Murnane Field, and the Utica city school district\nshall be authorized to use Murnane Field, for the use of its students,\nsubject only to general rules for the use of such sports facility and\nreasonable scheduling requirements, without charge to said school\ndistrict, except for reimbursement of actual expenses occasioned by its\nuse.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>