<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2052-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2052-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2052_H">
        <num>2052-H</num>
        <heading>Moneys of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2052-h. Moneys of the authority. All moneys of the authority from\nwhatever source derived shall be paid to the treasurer of the authority,\nor to the county commissioner of finance as agent of the authority if\nthe board shall so determine, and shall be deposited forthwith in a bank\nor banks in the state designated by the board. The moneys in such\naccounts shall be paid out on check of the treasurer or county\ncommissioner of finance, as the case may be, upon requisition by the\nboard or of such other person or persons as the board may authorize to\nmake such requisitions. All deposits of such moneys shall be secured by\nobligations of the United States or of the state or of the county or of\nany other municipality within the county of a market value equal at all\ntimes to the amount on deposit and all banks and trust companies are\nauthorized to give such security for such deposits. Any moneys of the\nauthority not required for immediate use or disbursement may, at the\ndiscretion of the authority, be invested in those obligations specified\npursuant to the provisions of section ninety-eight-a of the state\nfinance law. With the approval of the comptroller, the authority shall\nprescribe a system of accounts.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>