<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2053-I"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2053-I"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2053-I"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2053-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2053-I/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2053-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2053-I/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2053_I">
        <num>2053-I</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2053-i. Transfer of officers and employees. Any officer or employee\nof the county under civil service or otherwise, selected by the\nauthority, may, with the consent of the county executive, be transferred\nto the authority and shall be eligible for such transfer and\nappointment, without examination, to applicable offices, positions and\nemployment under the authority. The salary or compensation of any such\nofficer or employee, after such transfer, shall be paid by the\nauthority. Any such officers or employees so transferred to the\nauthority pursuant to this section, who are members of or benefit under\nany existing pension or retirement fund or system, shall continue to\nhave all rights, privileges, obligations and status with respect to such\nfund or system as are now prescribed by law, but during the period of\ntheir employment by the authority, all contributions to such funds or\nsystem to be paid by the employer on account of such officers or\nemployees shall be paid by the authority. All such officers or employees\nso transferred to the authority who have been appointed to positions\nunder the rules and classifications of the personnel officer of the\ncounty shall have the same status with respect thereto after transfer to\nthe authority as they had under their original appointment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>