<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2304"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2304"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2304"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2304/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2304/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2304">
        <num>2304</num>
        <heading>Auburn industrial development authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2304. Auburn industrial development authority. A public benefit\ncorporation to be known as the "Auburn industrial development authority"\nis hereby created. Such board shall be a body corporate and politic,\nconstituting a public benefit corporation and its existence shall\ncommence upon the appointment of the members as herein provided.  Its\nmembers shall consist of a chairman and eight other members all of whom\nshall be appointed by the mayor of the city for a term of three years,\nand shall include two members of the common council of the city, one\nrepresentative of the city school board and one representative from each\nof the fields of business, industry and labor. Every appointment to the\nboard shall be subject to confirmation by the common council of the\ncity. The chairman and each member shall continue to serve until the\nappointment and confirmation of his successor. Vacancies in such board\noccurring otherwise than by expiration of term shall be filled by the\nmayor by appointment for the unexpired term subject to confirmation of\nthe common council of the city. The mayor may remove the chairman or any\nmember of the board for inefficiency, neglect of duty or misconduct in\noffice, after giving him a copy of the charges against him and an\nopportunity of being heard in person, or by counsel, in his defense upon\nnot less than ten days' notice. Such removal must be approved by the\ncommon council of the city. The members of the board shall be entitled\nto no compensation for their services but shall be entitled to\nreimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the\nperformance of their official duties. Notwithstanding any inconsistent\nprovisions of law, general, special or local, no officer or employee of\nthe city shall be deemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit his office\nor employment by reason of his acceptance of membership of the authority\ncreated by this article, provided, however, that a member who holds such\nother public office or employment shall receive no additional\ncompensation or allowance for services rendered pursuant to this title,\nbut shall be entitled to reimbursement for his actual and necessary\nexpenses incurred in the performance of such services. The power of the\nauthority shall be vested in and exercised by a majority of the members\nof the authority. The authority may delegate to one or more of its\nmembers, or to its officers, agents and employees, such powers and\nduties as it may deem proper. Such board and its corporate existence\nshall continue only for a period of ten years and thereafter until all\nits liabilities have been met and its bonds have been paid in full or\nsuch liabilities or bonds have otherwise been discharged. Upon its\nceasing to exist, all rights and properties shall pass to and be vested\nin the city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>