<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2306"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2306"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-02-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2306"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2306/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2306/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2306">
        <num>2306</num>
        <heading>Purpose and powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2306__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nsales by a registered vendor under article twenty-eight of the tax law\nprimarily engaged in the retail sale of tangible personal property, as\ndefined in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2306__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of paragraph four of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2306__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection eleven hundred one of the tax law; or (ii) sales of a service to\nsuch customers. Except, however, that tourism destination projects shall\nnot be prohibited by this paragraph. For the purpose of this paragraph,\n"tourism destination" shall mean a location or facility which is likely\nto attract a significant number of visitors from outside the economic\ndevelopment region as established by section two hundred thirty of the\neconomic development law, in which the project is located.\n  Notwithstanding the provisions of this section to the contrary, such\nfinancial assistance may, however, be provided to a project where\nfacilities or property that are primarily used in making retail sales of\ngoods or services to customers who personally visit such facilities to\nobtain such goods or services constitute more than one-third of the\ntotal project cost, where:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2306__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the predominant purpose of the project\nwould be to make available goods or services which would not, but for\nthe project, be reasonably accessible to the residents of the city of\nAuburn because of a lack of reasonably accessible retail trade\nfacilities offering such goods or services; or (ii) the project is\nlocated in a highly distressed area. With respect to projects authorized\npursuant to this paragraph no project shall be approved unless the\nauthority shall find after the public hearing required by section\ntwenty-three hundred seven of this title that undertaking the project\nwill serve the public purposes of this article by preserving permanent,\nprivate sector jobs or increasing the overall number of permanent,\nprivate sector jobs in the state. Where the authority makes such a\nfinding, prior to providing financial assistance to the project by the\nauthority, the chief executive officer of the city of Auburn shall\nconfirm the proposed action of the authority. To carry out said purpose,\nthe authority shall have power:\n  1. To sue and be sued;\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;\n  3. To acquire, hold and dispose of personal property for its corporate\npurpose;\n  4. To acquire by purchase, grant, lease, gift, condemnation, or\notherwise and to use, real property or rights or easements therein\nnecessary for its corporate purposes, and to sell, convey, mortgage,\nlease, pledge, exchange or otherwise dispose of any such property in\nsuch manner as the authority shall determine. With respect to real\nproperty conveyed to it by the city, however, such power of disposition\nshall be limited as hereinafter provided in section twenty-three hundred\nten of this title;\n  5. To make by-laws for the management and regulation of its affairs\nand, subject to agreements with its bondholders, for the regulation of\nthe use of the project.\n  6. With the consent of the city, to use agents, employees and\nfacilities of the city, paying the city its ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>