<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2307"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2307"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-03-10" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2307"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2307/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2307/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2307">
        <num>2307</num>
        <heading>Additional prerequisites to the provision of financial assistance</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2307. Additional prerequisites to the provision of financial\nassistance. Prior to providing any financial assistance of more than one\nhundred thousand dollars to any project, the authority must comply with\nthe following prerequisites:\n  1. The authority must adopt a resolution describing the project and\nthe financial assistance that the authority is contemplating with\nrespect to such project. Such assistance shall be consistent with the\nuniform tax exemption policy adopted by the agency pursuant to\nsubdivision one of section twenty-three hundred fifteen of this chapter,\nunless the agency has followed procedures for deviation from such policy\nspecified in subdivision two of such section.\n  1-a. The authority shall deliver a copy of the resolution adopted\npursuant to subdivision one of this section by certified mail, return\nreceipt requested or an electronic correspondence with a read-receipt,\nto the chief executive officer of each affected tax jurisdiction. When\nthe affected tax jurisdiction is a school district, the authority shall\ndeliver a copy of such resolution by certified mail, return receipt\nrequested or an electronic correspondence with a read-receipt, to the\ndistrict clerk and district superintendent of each affected school\ndistrict.\n  2. The authority must hold a public hearing with respect to the\nproject and the proposed financial assistance being contemplated by the\nauthority. At said public hearing, interested parties shall be provided\nreasonable opportunity, both orally and in writing, to present their\nviews with respect to the project.\n  3. The authority must give at least ten days published notice of said\npublic hearing and shall, at the same time, provide notice of such\nhearing to the chief executive officer of each affected tax\njurisidiction within which the project is located. The notice of hearing\nmust state the time and place of the hearing, contain a general,\nfunctional description of the project, describe the prospective location\nof the project, identify the initial owner, operator or manager of the\nproject and generally describe the financial assistance contemplated by\nthe authority with respect to the project.\n  4. The authority shall establish a procedure for compliance with the\nnotification requirements, including identification of the notification\nmethod, of subdivision one-a of this section and subdivision two of\nsection twenty-three hundred fifteen of this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>