<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2407"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2407"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2407"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2407/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2407/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2407/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2407/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2407">
        <num>2407</num>
        <heading>Bond limits</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2407__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an amount equal to any\noriginal issue discount from the principal amount of any bonds or notes\nissued,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2407__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bonds and notes issued to refund outstanding bonds and\nnotes, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2407__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bonds and notes not described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2407__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision issued to refund outstanding bonds and notes in accordance\nwith the provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or the Tax\nReform Act of 1986, as amended, where such bonds or notes are not\nincluded in the statewide volume cap on private purpose bonds under\nsection 146 of such code provided, however, that upon any refunding\npursuant to this paragraph or paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2407__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, such\nexclusion shall apply only to the extent that the amount of the\nrefunding bonds or notes does not exceed</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2407__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the outstanding amount of\nthe refunded bonds or notes, plus (ii) to the extent permitted by\napplicable federal tax law, costs of issuance of the refunding bonds or\nnotes to be financed from the proceeds of the refunding bonds or notes.\nNo such bond or note shall be issued by the agency on or after July\ntwenty-third, two thousand twenty-seven, excluding bonds and notes\nissued to refund outstanding bonds and notes. No more than two billion\nfour hundred million dollars of proceeds of bonds or notes issued by the\nagency pursuant to this subdivision shall be used for mortgage purposes\nby blending with proceeds of bonds issued pursuant to subdivision two of\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2407__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>In connection with the issuance of bonds for the purpose of\nfurthering programs described in this title, the agency is authorized to\ncovenant and consent that the interest on any of its bonds, notes or\nother obligations shall be includable, under the United States Internal\nRevenue Code of 1986, as amended or any subsequent corresponding\ninternal revenue law of the United States, in the gross income of the\nholders of the bonds to the same extent and in the same manner that the\ninterest on bills, bonds, notes or other obligations of the United\nStates is includable in the gross income of the holders thereof under\nsaid Internal Revenue Code or any such subsequent law. Pursuant to this\nsubdivision, the agency shall not issue bonds, notes or other\nobligations in an aggregate principal amount exceeding one billion nine\nhundred fifty million dollars, excluding from such limitation bonds,\nnotes or other obligations issued to refund outstanding bonds, notes or\nother obligations. No...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2407__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fixing of the statutory maximums in this section shall not be\nconstrued as constituting a contract between the agency and the holders\nof its bonds or notes that additional bonds and notes may not be issued\nsubsequently by the agency in the event that such statutory maximums\nshall subsequently be increased by law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>