<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2426"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2426"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2426"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2426/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2426/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2426/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2426/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2426">
        <num>2426</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2426__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\naggregate of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2426__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>such insured amounts of each category of loans and such\namount of development corporation credit support as the agency has\ndetermined to be due and payable as of such date pursuant to its\ncontracts to insure mortgages or provide development corporation credit\nsupport plus (ii) an amount equal to twenty per centum of the amounts of\neach category of loans insured under the agency's insurance contracts\nplus twenty per centum of the amounts to be insured under the agency's\ncommitments to insure less the amounts payable in each category of loans\npursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2426__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph, provided, however, that\nif the board of directors of the agency shall have established a per\ncentum for a category of loans, or for one or more loans within such\ncategories, pursuant to subdivision seven of section twenty-four hundred\ntwenty-eight of this part, such per centum shall be substituted for\ntwenty per centum in this paragraph for such category or loan, and\nprovided further, that no such new per centum shall be lower than twenty\nper centum plus (iii) an amount equal to the respective amounts\nestablished by contract with respect to each reserve and financial\nsupport fund (which may be determined by reference to percentages of\namounts required or permitted to be on deposit in said funds and may be\ndifferent for each such fund) for which the agency has determined that\nthe development corporation credit support account established under\nsection twenty-four hundred twenty-nine-b of this part is or will be a\nsource or potential source of development corporation credit support,\nless the amounts payable with respect to development corporation credit\nsupport pursuant to subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2426__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this paragraph less</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2426__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\naggregate of the amount of each reinsurance contract procured in\nconnection with agency obligations determined by the board of directors\nof the agency to be a reduction pursuant to this paragraph in\ncalculating the mortgage insurance fund requirement. For purposes of\npool insurance, in no event shall the reserve requirement be less than\ntwenty percent of the amounts insured under the agency's insurance\ncontracts.\n  6. "Mortgagee". The lender under a mortgage eligible for insurance\npursuant to section twenty-four hundred twenty-eight of this chapter,\nand its successors and assigns approved by the agency.\n  7. "Mortgagor". The original borrower under a mortgage eligible for\ninsurance pursuant to section twenty-four hundred twenty-eight of this\nchapter, and its successors and assigns approved by the agency.\n  8. "Operating expenses". All costs of administering the agency,\nincluding but not limited to salaries and wages, expenses of\nadministering staff functions, fees of consultants, legal fees, charges\nincurred for servicing insured mortgage loans, money management, office\nrents, utility charges, cost of supplies, furnishings, equipment,\nmachinery and apparatus, maintenance and repair of property and other\nexpenses incurred in connection with the foregoing.\n  9. "Region". One or more of the following named areas comprised of the\ncounties indicated:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Buffalo: Cattaraugus, Chautauqua, Erie and Niagara counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Rochester: Genesee, Livingston, Monroe, Ontario, Orleans, Seneca,\nWayne, Wyoming and Yates counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Syracuse: Cayuga, Cortland, Madison, Onondaga and Oswego counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Elmira-Binghamton: Allegany, Broome, Chemung, Chenango, Delaware,\nOtsego, Schuyler, Steuben, Tioga and Tompkins counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Mid-Hudson: Columbia, Dutchess, Greene, Orange, Putnam, Sullivan\nand Ulster counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Capital: Albany, Montgomery, Rensselaer, Saratoga, Schenectady and\nSchoharie counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Mohawk Valley-Northern: Clinton, Essex, Franklin, Fulton,\nHamilton, Herkimer, Jefferson, Lewis, Oneida, St. Lawrence, Warren and\nWashington counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Downstate: Rockland and Westchester counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Long Island: Nassau and Suffolk counties;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2426__subsec_b__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>New York City: the five counties comprising the city of New York.\n  10. "Rehabilitation". Repairs, alterations or improvements of a\nhousing accommodation designed to raise the housing standards therein\nor, in the case of other real property, designed to provide needed\nimprovements therein.\n  11. "Preservation loan". A loan extended by a financial institution\nfor the purposes of refinancing existing indebtedness secured by one or\nmore mortgages on a housing accommodation or other real property and/or\nfinancing the acquisition of a housing accommodation or other real\nproperty and which otherwise complies with the conditions established\npursuant to section twenty-four hundred twenty-eight of this chapter.\n  * 12. "Rehabilitation loan". A loan extended by a financial\ninstitution which may include the refinancing of existing indebtedness,\nif any, secured by one or more mortgages on the housing accommodation or\nother real property to be rehabilitated or financing the acquisitio...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>