<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2429-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2429-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-07-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2429-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2429-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2429-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2429-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2429-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2429_B">
        <num>2429-B</num>
        <heading>Mortgage insurance fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The agency shall create\nand establish a mortgage insurance fund. Within such fund, the agency\nshall establish:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a special account, which shall be divided into\nsub-accounts for each region as defined in subdivision nine of section\ntwenty-four hundred twenty-six of this title; (ii) a single family pool\ninsurance account; (iii) a project pool insurance account; and (iv) a\ndevelopment corporation credit support account. The single family pool\ninsurance account shall be used for all business relating to the\ninsurance of mortgages on properties with one to four dwelling units,\nthe project pool insurance account shall be used for all business\nrelating to the insurance of mortgages on properties other than those\nwith one to four dwelling units, and the development corporation credit\nsupport account shall be used for all business relating to development\ncorporation credit support. Separate sub-accounts may be established\nwithin the special account, the pool insurance accounts, and the\ndevelopment corporation credit support account as deemed appropriate by\nthe agency.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The mortgage insurance fund shall be used as a revolving fund\nfor carrying out the provisions of this title with respect to mortgages\ninsured and development corporation credit support, provided thereunder.\n(ii) The agency shall pay into such fund all moneys which may be made\navailable to the agency for the purposes of such fund from any source,\nincluding but not limited to the moneys received from recording officers\npursuant to the provisions of subdivision two of section two hundred\nsixty-one of the tax law. The agency shall credit the amount of moneys\nreceived from the recording officer of each county, pursuant to\nsubdivision two of section two hundred sixty-one of the tax law, to the\nspecial account. In any fiscal year, no more than fifty per centum of\nthe amount received from the recording officers during the consecutive\ntwelve month period ending on the preceding March thirty-first may be\nused by the agency for the purpose of insuring mortgages on property\nlocated in any one region pursuant to section two thousand four hundred\ntwenty-eight of this part, provided, however, that this provision shall\nnot include or be applied to pool insurance of mortgage loans purchased\nby the agency. The agency shall credit any other moneys which may be\nmade available to the agency for the purposes of such fund from any\nother source to the special account, the single family pool insurance\naccount, the project pool insurance account, or the development\ncorporation credit support account, as appropriate. Any income or\ninterest earned by, or increment to, the mortgage insurance fund due to\nthe investment thereof shall be credited to the special account, the\napplicable pool insurance account, or the development corporation credit\nsupport account, as appropriate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The agency may credit from the special account to the single\nfamily pool insurance account, to the project pool insurance account and\nto the development corporation credit support account such moneys as are\nrequired to satisfy the mortgage insurance fund requirement of such\naccounts, except that during any twelve-month period ending on March\nthirty-first the aggregate amount credited to the development\ncorporation credit support account (excluding amounts described in the\nlast sentence of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision) shall not exceed the\nlesser of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>fifty million dollars or (ii) the aggregate of the amounts\nrequired under the contracts executed by the agency to provide\ndevelopment corporation support.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Moneys, investments and cash equivalents of the special account,\nthe single family pool insurance account, the project pool insurance\naccount and the development corporation credit support account shall be\nkept separate and shall not be commingled with each other or with any\nother accounts which may be established from time to time, except as\notherwise authorized by this section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Moneys, investments and cash equivalents of the pool insurance\naccounts and the development corporation credit support account shall be\nexcluded from the excess balance calculation set forth in subdivision\ntwo of this section. However, if at any time the moneys, investments and\ncash equivalents (valued as determined by the agency) of either pool\ninsurance account or the development corporation credit support account\nexceed the amount necessary to attain and maintain the credit rating or,\nwith respect to development corporation credit support, credit\nworthiness (as determined by the agency) required to accomplish the\npurposes of such account the agency shall transfer such excess to the\nspecial account and such excess shall be included in the excess balance\ncalculation.\n  * NB Effective until July 23, 2027\n  * 1. The agency shall create and establish a mortgage insurance fund.\nWithin such fund, the agency shall establish a special account, which\nshall be divided into sub-accounts for each region as defined in\nsubdivision nine of section twenty-four hundred twenty-six of this part\nand a development corporation credit support account. The development\ncorporation credit support account shall be used for all business\nrelated to development corporation credit support. Separate sub-accounts\nmay be established within the development corporation credit support\naccount as deemed appropriate by the agency. The mortgage insurance fund\nshall be used as a revolving fund for carrying out the provisions of\nthis title with respect to mortgages insured and development corporation\nsupport provided thereunder. The agency shall pay into such fund all\nmoneys which may be made available to the agency for the purposes of\nsuch fund from any source, including but not limited to the moneys\nreceived from recording officers pursuant to the provisions of\nsubdivision two of section two hundred sixty-one of the tax law. The\nagency shall credit the amount of moneys recei...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in special time deposit\naccounts in, or certificates of deposit issued by, a bank, trust\ncompany, savings bank or savings and loan association located and\nauthorized to do business in this state, provided, however, that such\ntime deposit account or certificate of deposit shall be payable within\nsuch time as the proceeds may be needed to meet expenditures estimated\nto be incurred by the agency and provided further that such time deposit\naccount or certificate of deposit be secured by a pledge of obligations\nof the United States of America or obligations of the state, any city of\nthe state, or other municipal corporation, school district or district\ncorporation of the state or obligations of agencies of the federal\ngovernment; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in obligations of the United States of America or the\nstate which may from time to time be legally purchased by savings banks\nwithin the state as an investment of funds belonging to them or in their\ncontrol, or in obligations of the Federal National Mortgage Association,\nor</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in Government National Mortgage Association mortgage backed\nsecurities, provided such obligations shall be payable or redeemable at\nthe option of the owner within such times as the proceeds may be needed\nto meet expenditures estimated to be incurred by the agency.\n  5. In computing the amount of the mortgage insurance fund for the\npurposes of this section, securities in which all or a portion of such\nfund shall be invested shall be valued at par if purchased at par, or if\npurchased at other than par, at amortized value. Amortized value, when\nused with respect to securities purchased at a premium above or a\ndiscount below par, shall mean the value as of any given date obtained\nby dividing the total premiums or discount at which such securities were\npurchased by the number of interest payments remaining to maturity on\nsuch securities after such purchase and by multiplying the amount so\ncalculated by the number of interest payment dates having passed since\nthe date of such purchase; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2429_B__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of securities purchased\nat a premium by deducting the product thus obtained from the purchase\nprice, and (ii) in the case of securities purchased at a discount by\nadding the product thus obtained to the purchase price.\n  6. The agency may create and establish such other fund or funds as may\nbe necessary or desirable for the carrying out of its corporate\npurposes.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>