<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2438"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2438"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-12-02" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2438"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2438/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2438/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2438/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2438/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2438">
        <num>2438</num>
        <heading>Bond authorization</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2438__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section sixteen of chapter six hundred\nfive of the laws of two thousand, special program bonds issued to\nfinance the cost of a project for design, reconstruction or\nrehabilitation of a school building pursuant to the provisions of\nsection fourteen of the city of Syracuse and the board of education of\nthe city school district of the city of Syracuse cooperative school\nreconstruction act, special program bonds issued to finance the cost of\na project for design, construction, reconstruction or rehabilitation of\na school building pursuant to the provisions of section thirteen of the\nYonkers city school district joint schools construction and\nmodernization act, recovery act bonds, public safety communications\nbonds and bonds and notes issued to refund outstanding bonds and notes.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2438__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The agency shall not issue special school purpose bonds in an\naggregate principal amount in excess of: for the city of New York, four\nhundred thirty-five million dollars; for the city of Buffalo, four\nmillion seven hundred thousand dollars; for the city of Rochester, five\nmillion one hundred thousand dollars; for the city of Syracuse, eight\nhundred thousand dollars; and for the city of Yonkers, three hundred\nthousand dollars; or the amount of prior year claims that are due and\npayable to each such school district of each such special school purpose\nmunicipality pursuant to section thirty-six hundred four of the\neducation law. Such amount shall exclude bonds issued to fund any debt\nservice reserve fund, bonds issued to refund such special school purpose\nbonds, bonds issued to pay the costs of issuance of such special school\npurpose bonds and the amount of bonds that would constitute interest\nunder the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended. Notwithstanding any\nprovision...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2438__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The agency shall not issue special school deficit program bonds\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2438__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>prior to the time the state comptroller determines the amount of the\naccumulated projected deficit of a special school deficit program\ndistrict in its general fund at the close of its current fiscal year\nending June thirtieth, two thousand two, including any budget notes and\nrevenue anticipation notes which may be part of such deficit, as\nprovided in a chapter of the laws of two thousand two, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2438__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in\naggregate principal amount in excess of the lesser of</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2438__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the amount of\nsuch deficit as determined by the state comptroller or (ii) sixteen\nmillion five hundred thousand dollars, excluding bonds to fund any debt\nservice reserve fund, bonds issued to refund special school deficit\nprogram bonds, bonds issued to pay the costs of issuance of such special\nschool deficit program bonds and the amount of bonds that would\nconstitute interest under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2438__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The fixing of the statutory maximum in this section shall not be\nconstrued as constituting a contract between the agency and the holders\nof its bonds or notes that additional bonds and notes may not be issued\nsubsequently by the agency in the event that such statutory maximum\nshall subsequently be increased by law.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>