<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2446"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2446"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2446"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2446/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2446/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2446/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2446/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2446">
        <num>2446</num>
        <heading>Moneys of the agency</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2446__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>obligations of the United States of America or\nof the state of a market value equal at all times to the amount of the\ndeposit and all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such\nsecurity for such deposits or (ii) in such other manner as the agency\nmay require. The obligations securing such deposits shall either be\ndeposited with the comptroller of the agency or be held by a trustee or\nagent satisfactory to the agency. The comptroller or his legally\nauthorized representatives are authorized and empowered from time to\ntime to examine the accounts and books of the agency, including its\nreceipts, disbursements, contracts, leases, sinking funds, investments\nand any other records and papers relating to its financial standing.\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2446__subsec_i__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The agency shall have power to contract with holders of any of its\nbonds or notes, as to the custody, collection, securing, investment, and\npayment of any moneys of the agency, of any moneys held in trust or\notherwise for the payment of bonds or notes, and to carry out such\ncontract. Moneys held in trust or otherwise for the payment of bonds or\nnotes or in any way to secure bonds or notes and deposits of such moneys\nmay be secured in the same manner as moneys of the agency, and all banks\nand trust companies are authorized to give such security for such\ndeposits.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2446__subsec_i__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to the provisions of any contract with bondholders or\nnoteholders and to the approval of the comptroller, the agency shall\nprescribe a system of accounts.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_2446__subsec_i__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The agency shall submit to the governor, chairman of the senate\nfinance committee, chairman of the assembly ways and means committee and\nthe comptroller, within thirty days of the receipt thereof by the\nagency, a copy of the report of every external examination of the books\nand accounts of the agency other than copies of the reports of such\nexaminations made by the comptroller.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>