<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2463"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2463"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2463"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2463/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2463/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2463/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2463/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2463">
        <num>2463</num>
        <heading>New York state sports authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2463. New York state sports authority. 1. For the purpose of\neffectuating the policy declared in section twenty-four hundred\nsixty-one of this chapter, there is hereby created a corporate\ninstrumentality of the state to be known as "New York state sports\nauthority" in this title referred to as "the authority", which shall be\na body corporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation.\nThe authority shall consist of five members to be appointed by the\ngovernor, by and with the advice and consent of the senate. Of the\nmembers first appointed, one shall serve for a term ending April first,\nnineteen hundred seventy-four; one of such members shall serve for a\nterm ending one year from such date; one of such members shall serve for\na term ending two years from such date; one of such members shall serve\nfor a term ending three years from such date; and one of such members\nshall serve for a term ending four years from such date. Their\nsuccessors shall serve for terms of five years each. Each member shall\nhold office until his successor has been appointed and qualified. The\ngovernor shall designate one of the members to be chairman who shall be\nthe chief executive officer of the authority.\n  2. The chairman and the other members shall receive compensation\nwithin the amounts made available by appropriation therefor. Each\nmember, including the chairman, shall be entitled to reimbursement for\nhis actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of his\nofficial duties.\n  3. The chairman shall be the chief executive officer of the authority\nand shall be responsible for the discharge of the executive and\nadministrative functions and powers of the authority, but he shall be\nempowered to delegate any one or more of such functions or powers,\nincluding, without limitations, that of appointment, discipline and\nremoval of officers or employees, to one or more executive officers\nappointed by the board.\n  4. The authority shall be a "state agency" for the purposes of\nsections seventy-three and seventy-four of the public officers law.\n  5. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of this or any other\nlaw, general, special or local, no officer or employee of the state, or\nof any public corporation as defined in the general corporation law,\nshall be deemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit his office or\nemployment or any benefits provided under the retirement and social\nsecurity law or under any public retirement system maintained by the\nstate or any of its subdivisions by reason of his acceptance of\nmembership on or chairmanship of the authority; provided, however, a\nmember or chairman who holds such other public office or employment\nshall receive no additional compensation for services rendered pursuant\nto this title, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for his actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of such services.\n  6. The governor may remove any member for inefficiency, neglect of\nduty or misconduct in office after giving him a copy of the charges\nagainst him and an opportunity to be heard, in person or by counsel in\nhis defense, upon not less than ten days' notice. If any member shall be\nso removed, the governor shall file in the office of the department of\nstate a complete statement of charges made against such member, and his\nfindings thereon, together with a complete record of the proceedings.\n  7. The authority shall continue so long as it shall have bonds or\nother obligations outstanding and until its existence shall be\nterminated by law. Upon the termination of the existence of the\nauthority, all its rights and properties shall pass to and be vested in\nthe state.\n  * NB (Disbanded March, 1980)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>