<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2468"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2468"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2468"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2468/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2468/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2468/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2468/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2468">
        <num>2468</num>
        <heading>Bonds and notes of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2468__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\ncomptroller of the state of New York where such sale is not to such\ncomptroller, or (ii) the state director of the budget where such sale is\nto such comptroller.\n  6. The authority may issue one or more series of bonds or notes\nwhether in connection with or secured by the same or a different project\nor portion thereof except as may otherwise be provided in the\nproceedings under which such bonds or notes shall be authorized to be\nissued.\n  7. Neither the members, directors, officers or employees of the\nauthority nor any person executing the bonds or notes of the authority\nshall be liable personally on the bonds or notes or be subject to any\npersonal liability or accountability by reason of the issuance thereof.\n  8. Issuance by the authority of one or more series of bonds or notes\nfor one or more purposes shall not preclude it from issuing other bonds\nor notes in connection with the same sports facility or any other sports\nfacility, but the proceedings whereunder any subsequent bonds or notes\nmay be issued shall recognize and protect any prior pledge or lease made\nfor any prior issue of bonds or notes unless in the proceedings\nauthorizing such prior issue the right is reserved to issue subsequent\nbonds or notes on a parity with such prior issue.\n  9. All bonds or notes authorized under this section and the interest\ncoupons applicable thereto are hereby made and shall be construed to be\nnegotiable instruments.\n  10. The authority shall have power out of any funds available therefor\nto purchase (as distinguished from the power of redemption herein\nprovided) any bonds or notes of the authority, and all bonds so\npurchased shall be cancelled.\n  * NB (Disbanded March, 1980)\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>