<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2490-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2490-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2490-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2490-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2490-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2490-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2490-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2490_D">
        <num>2490-D</num>
        <heading>Purposes and powers of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2490-d. Purposes and powers of the authority. The purposes of the\nauthority shall be to construct, operate and maintain the project\nconsisting of the Saratoga Springs city center authority and facilities\nin connection therewith. To carry out the purposes the authority shall\nhave power:\n  1. To sue and be sued;\n  2. To acquire, hold and dispose of personal property for its corporate\npurposes;\n  3. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure;\n  4. To make by-laws for the management and regulation of its affairs\nand, subject to agreements with bondholders, for the regulation of the\nproject;\n  5. With the consent of the city council, to use agents, employees and\nfacilities of the city, paying to the city its agreed portion of the\ncompensation or costs;\n  6. To appoint officers, agents and employees; and to describe their\nqualifications and fix their compensation; subject, however, to the\nprovisions of the civil service law as hereinafter provided;\n  7. To make contracts and leases, and to execute all instruments\nnecessary or convenient;\n  8. To construct such buildings, structures, parking and other\nfacilities as may be necessary or convenient;\n  9. To reconstruct, improve, maintain and operate the project;\n  10. To collect rentals, fees and other charges for the use of the\nproject subject to and in accordance with such agreements with\nbondholders as may be hereinafter provided;\n  11. To contract for the services of architects, engineers, lawyers,\nfinancial and other professional advisers and to fix their compensation;\n  12. To construct, operate and maintain the project; to contract for\nthe construction, operation and maintenance of any part thereof, or for\nservices to be performed in connection therewith; to rent part thereof,\nand to grant concessions, all on such terms and conditions as it may\ndetermine; provided, however, that the location of the site of the\nproject and the plans thereof shall be subject to the prior approval of\nthe city council.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>