<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2503"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2503"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2503"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2503/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2503/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2503">
        <num>2503</num>
        <heading>New York city sports authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2503.  New York city sports authority. 1. There is hereby created\nthe New York city sports authority which shall be a corporate\ngovernmental agency, constituting a public benefit corporation. Upon\nsubmission of a plan pursuant to section twenty-four hundred sixty-five\nof the New York state sports authority act the authority shall qualify\nas a "participating municipality" within the meaning of and for the\npurposes of the New York state sports authority act. Its membership\nshall consist of sixteen members, who shall constitute the board of\ndirectors. Fifteen members shall be appointed by the governor, five of\nwhom shall be designated by the mayor and five of whom shall be\ndesignated by the city council. The remaining member shall be chief\nexecutive officer of the authority. Such chief executive officer shall\nbe chosen by the aforementioned fifteen members from persons other than\nthemselves and shall serve at the pleasure of the board of directors\nwith powers and duties as set forth in the by-laws of the authority.\nThe members shall designate from among themselves the person who shall\nbe chairman of the board of directors.\n  2. Members, except for the chief executive officers shall be appointed\nfor a term of six years from the effective dates of their appointments,\nprovided, however, that six members first appointed by the governor\nshall each serve for a six year term, two of whom shall have been\ndesignated by the mayor and two of whom shall have been designated by\nthe city council; six members first appointed by the governor shall each\nserve for a five year term, two of whom shall have been designated by\nthe mayor and two of whom shall have been designated by the city\ncouncil; and three members first appointed by the governor shall each\nserve for a four year term, one of whom shall have been designated by\nthe mayor and one of whom shall have been designated by the city\ncouncil. Each member shall continue to serve until the appointment and\nqualification of his successor. If at any time there is a vacancy in the\nmembership of the authority by reason of death, resignation,\ndisqualification or otherwise, such vacancy shall be filled for the\nunexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment.\n  3. A majority of the whole number of members then in office shall\nconstitute a quorum for the transaction of any business or the exercise\nof any power of the authority. Except as otherwise specified in this\ntitle, for the transaction of any business or the exercise of any power\nof the authority, the authority shall have power to act by a majority of\nthe members present at any meeting at which a quorum is in attendance.\nNo vote at such meeting shall be cast by proxy. The authority may\ndelegate to one or more of its members, officers, agents and employees,\nsuch powers as the members may deem proper.\n  4. The members of the authority except for the president, acting in\nhis capacity as chief executive officer of the authority, shall serve\nwithout salary, but each member shall be reimbursed for his actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of his official duties as\na member of the authority. The members of the authority may engage in\nprivate employment or in a profession or business (if not otherwise\nprohibited from so doing by virtue of any other public office), subject\nto the limitations contained in sections seventy-three and seventy-four\nof the public officers law. The authority shall, for the purposes of\nsuch sections, be a "state agency" and the members thereof shall be\n"officers" of the agency for the purpose of said sections.\n  5. The members of the authority by a majority vote of the whole number\nof members then in office may remove any member for cause, provided that\nsuch member be first furnished with a written list of charges against\nhim and given an opportunity to be heard, in person or by counsel, upon\nnot less than ten days' notice.\n  6. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of law, general,\nspecial or local, no officer or employee of the state, any city, county,\ntown or village, any other political or civil division of the state, any\nmunicipality, any governmental entity operating any public school or\ncollege, any school district or other public agency or instrumentality\nor unit of government which exercise governmental powers under the laws\nof the state, shall forfeit his office or employment by reason of his\nacceptance of appointment or service as a member, officer or agent of\nthe authority; nor shall such service as such member, officer or agent\nof the authority be deemed incompatible or in conflict with such office\nor employment.\n  7. The authority shall continue until its liabilities have been met or\notherwise discharged or provided for and until its existence shall have\nbeen terminated by law. Upon the termination of the existence of the\nauthority, all of its rights and property shall pass to and be vested in\nthe city.\n  8. On or before November fifteenth of each year, the authority shall\nsubmit to each member of the board of estimate and to the chairman of\nthe finance committee of the city council, a financial statement for the\npreceding city fiscal year, a report of its activities during that year,\nand a report on its program for both the current and next succeeding\ncity fiscal years.\n  * NB (Discontinued-Board of Directors never appointed)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>