<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2507"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2507"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2507"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2507/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2507/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2507">
        <num>2507</num>
        <heading>Employees of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2507. Employees of the authority. 1. Notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provision of this title, the appointment and promotion of\nall employees of and for the authority shall be made in accordance with\nthe provisions of the civil service law under the rules of the city\ncivil service commission. Such employees shall be under the jurisdiction\nof such city civil service commission and their compensation shall be\nfixed by the authority.\n  2. The city and the authority shall have the power to provide for the\ntransfer to the authority of agents and employees and the use of the\nfacilities of the city to enable the authority to fulfill its corporate\npurposes. Employees of the city to be transferred to the authority\npursuant to this title shall be eligible for such transfer and\nappointment to offices and positions of the authority without further\nexamination, and all such employees who have been appointed to positions\nin the city service in accordance with the provisions of the civil\nservice law under the rules of the city civil service commission shall\nhave the same status with respect thereto in the service of the\nauthority as they had in city service. Employees who are members or\nbeneficiaries of any existing pension or retirement system shall\ncontinue to have such rights, privileges, obligations or status with\nrespect to such system or systems as are prescribed by law on the date\nthis title takes effect, and all such employees who have been appointed\nto positions in city service in accordance with the provisions of the\ncivil service law under the rules of the city civil service commission\nshall have the same status with respect thereto in the service of the\nauthority as they had in city service.\n  * NB (Discontinued-Board of Directors never appointed)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>