<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2520"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2520"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2520"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2520/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2520/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2520">
        <num>2520</num>
        <heading>Actions against authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  * ยง 2520. Actions against authority. 1. Except in an action for\nwrongful death, an action against the authority for personal injury,\nreal or personal property damage or destruction or founded on tort shall\nnot be commenced more than one year and ninety days after the cause of\naction thereof shall have accrued nor unless a notice of claim shall\nhave been served on a member of the authority or officer or employee\nthereof designated by the authority for such purpose, within the time\nlimited by, and in compliance with the requirements of section fifty-e\nof the general municipal law. An action against the authority for\nwrongful death shall be commenced in accordance with the notice of claim\nand time limitation provisions of title eleven of article nine of this\nchapter.\n  2. The venue of every action, suit or special proceeding brought\nagainst the authority shall be laid in the county of New York.\n  3. No member, officer, employee or agent of the authority, while\nacting in the scope of his authority, shall be subject to any personal\nliability resulting from exercising or carrying out of any of the\nauthority's purposes or powers.\n  * NB (Discontinued-Board of Directors never appointed)\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>