<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2531"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2531"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2531"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2531/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2531/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2531/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2531/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2531">
        <num>2531</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2531. Definitions. For the purposes of this title:\n  1. "City" means the city of New York.\n  2. "Director of management and budget" means the director of\nmanagement and budget of the city of New York.\n  3. "Corporation" means the New York city stabilization reserve\ncorporation as created by this title.\n  4. "Mayor" means the mayor of the city of New York.\n  5. "Comptroller" means the comptroller of the city of New York.\n  6. "State" means the state of New York.\n  7. "Bonds" and "notes" means revenue bonds and notes respectively,\nissued by the corporation pursuant to this title.\n  8. "Revenues" means all aid, rents, fees, charges, payments and other\nincome and receipts paid or payable to the corporation or a trustee for\nthe account of the corporation, including any payment required to be\nmade to the corporation by this title.\n  9. "Operating expenses" means all expenses incurred by the corporation\nin the administration of the corporation including but not limited to\nsalaries, administrative expenses, insurance premiums, auditing and\nlegal expenses and fees and expenses incurred for professional\nconsultants and fiduciaires.\n  10. "Capital reserve fund requirement" means as of any particular date\nof computation, an amount of money equal to the amount required, for the\nthen current fiscal year of the corporation, to pay interest during such\nfiscal year on all bonds of the corporation outstanding on said date of\ncomputation, the principal amount of all bonds of the corporation\noutstanding on said date of computation which matures during such fiscal\nyear and the amount of sinking fund payments payable during such fiscal\nyear with respect to any bonds of the corporation outstanding on said\ndate of computation.\n  11. "Sinking fund payment" means the amount of money specified in the\nresolution authorizing bonds as payable into a sinking fund during a\nparticular fiscal year for the retirement of term bonds which mature\nafter such fiscal year, but shall not include any amount payable by\nreason only of the maturity of the bond.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>