<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2546"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2546"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2546"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2546/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2546/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2546/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2546/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2546">
        <num>2546</num>
        <heading>Employees of the corporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2546. Employees of the corporation. 1. Notwithstanding any\ninconsistent provisions of this act, the appointment and promotion of\nall employees of and for the corporation shall be made in accordance\nwith the provisions of the civil service law and shall be subject to the\njurisdiction of the city civil service commission and the compensation\nfor such employees shall be fixed by the corporation.\n  2. The city and the corporation shall have the power to provide for\nthe transfer to the corporation of agents, employees and facilities of\nthe city to enable the corporation to fulfill its corporate purposes.\nEmployees of the city to be transferred to the corporation pursuant to\nthis title shall be automatically appointed and transferred to the\ncorporation in the same or equivalent classification and position they\nhold at the time of the transfer. The corporation, its officers and\nemployees, shall be subject to article fourteen of the civil service law\nand for all purposes the corporation shall be deemed "public employer",\nprovided, however, that chapter fifty-four of the New York city charter\nand administrative code of the city of New York and executive orders\nnumber fifty-two, dated September twenty-ninth, nineteen hundred\nsixty-seven, as amended, promulgated by the mayor, shall apply in all\nrespects to the corporation, its officers and employees except that\nparagraph seven and paragraph eight of said executive order shall not be\napplicable to the corporation, its officers and employees. Employees who\nare members or beneficiaries of any existing pension or retirement\nsystem shall continue to have such rights, privileges, obligations or\nstatus with respect to such system as are prescribed by law on the date\nthis title takes effect, and all such employees who have been appointed\nto positions in city service in accordance with the provisions of the\ncivil service law under the rules of the city civil service commission\nshall have the same status with respect thereto in the service of the\ncorporation as they had in city service.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>