<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2562"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2562"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-08-03" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2562"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2562/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2562/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2562/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2562/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2562">
        <num>2562</num>
        <heading>Creation of the corporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2562. Creation of the corporation. 1. To effectuate the purposes and\nprovisions of this title, there is hereby created the "New York\nconvention center operating corporation", which shall be a body\ncorporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation. The\ncorporation's board of directors shall consist of twenty-one persons to\nbe appointed with the advice and consent of the senate, including\nfifteen persons appointed by the governor; two persons appointed by the\ntemporary president of the senate; one person appointed by the minority\nleader of the senate; two persons appointed by the speaker of the\nassembly; and one person appointed by the minority leader of the\nassembly. Four of the members appointed by the governor shall be\nappointed on the written recommendation of the mayor of the city of New\nYork. One of the directors shall be designated by the governor as chair\nof the board of directors to serve as such at the pleasure of the\ngovernor. Upon recommendation of the chair of the board of directors,\nthe board of directors shall appoint an executive director of the\ncorporation. Notwithstanding any general, special or local law\nconcerning the holding of dual offices, an officer or employee of the\nstate may be appointed as an officer or employee of the corporation, and\nofficers and employees of the state may be appointed as members of the\nboard of directors of the corporation, provided however, that the chair\nof the board of directors shall not be an officer or employee of the\ncorporation, and the executive director of the corporation shall not be\na member of the board of directors.\n  2. Directors of the corporation shall be appointed for a term of three\nyears from the effective date of their appointments, provided, however,\nthat two persons first appointed by the governor other than the chair\nshall have a two year term; three persons first appointed by the\ngovernor other than the chair shall have a one year term; the four\npersons appointed on the recommendation of the mayor of the city of New\nYork shall have a term coterminous with the term of office of the mayor\nof the city of New York appointing them, one person first appointed by\nthe temporary president of the senate shall have a two year term; the\nperson first appointed by the minority leader of the senate shall have a\none year term; one person first appointed by the speaker of the assembly\nshall have a two year term; and the person first appointed by the\nminority leader of the assembly shall have a one year term except for\nthose appointed on the recommendation of the mayor whose terms shall\nexpire at the expiration of the term of the mayor appointing them. The\nterms of office of their successors shall be three years. All directors\nshall continue to hold office until their successors have been appointed\nand qualified. If at any time there is a vacancy in the membership of\nthe board of directors by reason of death, resignation, disqualification\nor otherwise, such vacancy shall be filled for the unexpired term in the\nsame manner as the original appointment.\n  3. A majority of the appointed voting membership of the board of\ndirectors shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any business\nor the exercise of any power of the corporation. The powers of the\ncorporation shall be exercised, or may be delegated to one or more\ndirectors, officers, agents or employees, by a majority of the appointed\nvoting membership of the board of directors. No vote at such meeting\nshall be cast by proxy.\n  4. The directors, other than any officer of the corporation who also\nserves as a director, shall serve without a salary or other\ncompensation, but each director shall be entitled to reimbursement for\nexpenses incurred in the performance of official duties.\n  5. The governor may remove any member of the board for cause, provided\nthat such member be first furnished with a list of charges against him\nand given an opportunity to be heard, in person or by counsel, upon not\nless than ten days' notice.\n  6. The fiscal year of the corporation shall end on the date on which\nthe fiscal year of the state ends.\n  7. The existence of the corporation shall continue until terminated by\nlaw, provided, however, that no such law shall take effect so long as\nthe corporation shall have obligations outstanding, unless adequate\nprovision has been made for the payment thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>