<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2566"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2566"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2566"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2566/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2566/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2566/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2566/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2566">
        <num>2566</num>
        <heading>Appropriations</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2566. Appropriations. 1. To assure the continued operation and\nsolvency of the corporation for the carrying out of the public purposes\nof this act, there may be, notwithstanding any provision of law to the\ncontrary, annually apportioned and paid to the corporation such sum, if\nany, as shall be appropriated in the first instance by the state as\nnecessary to enable the corporation to meet all items of expense,\nincluding proper maintenance of the convention center, that are approved\nby the director of the budget to be incurred by the corporation in the\nnext succeeding state fiscal year. The chairman of the corporation shall\nannually, on or before September fifteenth, make and deliver to the\ngovernor and the director of the budget for their approval and for\nsubmission to the legislature a budget request for the operations of the\ncorporation. The request shall delineate the total amount needed for\ncorporate purposes, the source and amount of other funds that the\ncorporation expects to receive, and such other information as the\ndirector of the budget shall require. The sum or sums appropriated in\nthe first instance, or so much thereof as shall be necessary, shall be\napportioned and paid to the corporation during the course of the fiscal\nyear as needed.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law, no\npart of such appropriation shall be available for the purposes\ndesignated until a certificate of approval of availability shall have\nbeen issued by the director of the budget and a copy of such certificate\nfiled with the state comptroller, the chairman of the senate finance\ncommittee and the chairman of the assembly ways and means committee.\nSuch certificate may be amended from time to time, subject to the\napproval of the director of the budget, and a copy of each such\namendment shall be filed with the state comptroller, the chairman of the\nsenate finance committee and the chairman of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee.\n  3. The director of the budget shall not issue any certificate of\napproval of availability until the corporation has entered into a\nwritten agreement with the director of the budget providing for\nrepayment by such corporation to the state of an amount equal to the\ntotal amount expended by the state from such appropriation, on terms to\nbe determined by the director of the budget, and a copy of such\nagreement shall be filed with the state comptroller, the chairman of the\nsenate finance committee and the chairman of the assembly ways and means\ncommittee. Notwithstanding the provisions of section forty-a of the\nstate finance law and any other general or special law, such written\nagreement shall require repayment only to the extent that moneys are\navailable from the convention center operating corporation fund\nestablished in accordance with section twenty-five hundred sixty-nine of\nthis title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>