<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2569"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2569"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2569"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2569/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2569/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2569/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2569/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2569">
        <num>2569</num>
        <heading>Moneys of the corporation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2569. Moneys of the corporation. All moneys of the corporation, from\nwhatever source derived, shall be paid to the commissioner of taxation\nand finance as agent of the corporation, who shall not commingle such\nmoneys with any other moneys. Such moneys shall be deposited in a\nseparate bank account to be known as the "convention center operating\ncorporation fund". The moneys in such fund shall be expended for payment\nof any and all costs and expenditures as required for the corporate\npurposes of the corporation and authorized by appropriation or required\npursuant to repayment agreements required by section twenty-five hundred\nsixty-six of this title, provided that all expenditures from such fund\nshall be subject to the prior approval of the director of the budget.\nThe moneys in such fund when made available shall be paid out on check\nof the commissioner of taxation and finance on requisition of the\nchairman of the corporation or of such other person or persons as the\ncorporation may authorize to make such requisition. All deposits of such\nmoneys shall, if required by the commissioner of taxation and finance or\nthe corporation, be secured by obligations of the United States or of\nthe state of a market value equal at all times to the amount of the\ndeposit and all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such\nsecurity for such deposits. Any moneys of the corporation not required\nfor immediate use or disbursement may, at the discretion of the\ncorporation, be invested by the commissioner of taxation and finance in\naccordance with the provisions of section ninety-eight-a of the state\nfinance law. The state comptroller and his legally authorized\nrepresentatives are authorized and empowered from time to time to\nexamine the accounts and books of the corporation, including its\nreceipts, disbursements, contracts, leases, investments and any other\nrecords and papers relating to its financial standing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>