<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2577"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2577"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2577"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2577/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2577/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2577/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2577/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2577">
        <num>2577</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2577. Definitions. As used or referred to in this title, unless a\ndifferent meaning clearly appears from the context, the following terms\nshall mean and include:\n  1. "Authority". The corporation created by section two thousand five\nhundred seventy-eight of this title.\n  2. "City". The City of Rochester.\n  3. "Board". The members of the authority constituting and acting as\nthe governing body of the authority.\n  4. "Bonds". The bonds, notes or other evidences of indebtedness issued\nby the authority pursuant to this title, and the provisions of this\ntitle relating to bonds and bondholders shall apply with equal force and\neffect to notes and noteholders, respectively, unless the context\notherwise clearly requires.\n  5. "Construct", "construction" or "constructed". The acquisition,\nerection, building, alteration, improvement, increase, enlargement,\nextension, reconstruction, renovation or rehabilitation of a\nprofessional soccer stadium; the inspection and supervision thereof; and\nthe engineering, architectural, legal, fiscal and economic\ninvestigations and studies, surveys, designs, plans, working drawings,\nspecifications, procedures and other actions preliminary or incidental\nthereto.\n  6. "Cost". As applied to any project, means and includes the cost of\nconstruction, the cost of the acquisition of all property, including\nreal property and other property, real, personal and mixed and improved\nand unimproved, the cost of demolishing, removing or relocating of any\nbuildings or structures on lands so acquired, including the cost of\nacquiring any lands to which such buildings or structures may be moved\nor relocated, the cost of the professional soccer stadium, machinery,\napparatus and equipment, the cost of engineering and architectural\nsurveys, plans and specifications, the cost of consultant and legal\nservices, the cost of other expenses necessary or incidental to the\nconstruction of any project or facility for the purposes of professional\nsoccer and the financing of the construction thereof and the financing\nof the placing of any such project or such facility in operation,\nincluding reimbursement to the county or any municipality, state agency,\nthe state, the United States government or any other person for\nexpenditures that would be costs of a project hereunder had they been\nmade directly by the authority.\n  7. "Controller". The controller of the county of Monroe.\n  8. "County". The county of Monroe.\n  9. "County legislature". The Monroe county legislature.\n  10. "Notes". The notes authorized by the title.\n  11. "Person". Any natural person, partnership, association, joint\nventure or corporation, exclusive of a public corporation.\n  12. "Project". Any real property or improvements located within the\nstate of New York and within Monroe county, whether or not now in\nexistence or under construction, which shall be necessary or suitable\nfor use as a sports facility or for a use incidental to a sports\nfacility, including, but not limited to, machinery, equipment and other\nfacilities deemed necessary or desirable in connection therewith, or\nincidental thereto.\n  13. "Real property". Lands, including air and subsurface rights and\nlands under water, structures, franchises and interests in lands and any\nand all things usually included within the said terms, including not\nonly fees simple absolute but also any and all lesser interests, such as\neasements, rights of way, uses, leases, licenses, and all other\nincorporeal hereditaments and every estate, interest or right, legal or\nequitable, including terms of years, and liens thereon by way of\njudgments, mortgages or otherwise, and also claims for damage to real\nestate.\n  14. "Revenues". All fees, charges, tolls, rentals, rates and other\nincome and receipts derived from the operation of any sports facility\nincluding, without limiting the generality of the foregoing, investment\nproceeds and proceeds of insurance, condemnation, and sale or other\ndisposition of assets, together with all federal, state or municipal aid\nif any.\n  15. "Sports facility". Real property and improvements and structures\nthereon in the county, constituting a professional soccer stadium and\nother structures or related facilities, suitable for the holding of\nprofessional soccer events, including parking therefor.\n  16. "State". The state of New York.\n  17. "State agency". Any state office, public benefit corporation,\ndepartment, board, commission, bureau, division or other agency or\ninstrumentality of the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>