<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2578"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2578"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2578"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2578/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2578/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2578/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2578/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2578">
        <num>2578</num>
        <heading>Greater Rochester sports authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2578. Greater Rochester sports authority. 1. There is hereby created\nthe Greater Rochester sports authority. The authority shall be a body\ncorporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation. The\nauthority shall consist of three members. Two of such members shall be\nappointed by the county executive with the advice and consent of the\ncounty legislature and who shall serve at the pleasure of the county\nexecutive, and one of such members shall be appointed by the city mayor\nwith the advice and consent of the city council, and shall serve at the\npleasure of the city mayor.\n  2. All members shall continue to hold office until their successors\nare appointed and qualify. Vacancies shall be filled in the manner\nprovided for original appointments. Members may be removed from office\nfor the same reasons and in the same manner as may be provided by law\nfor the removal of officers of a county. The members of the authority\nshall receive no compensation for their services but shall be reimbursed\nfor all other actual and necessary expenses incurred in connection with\nthe carrying out of the purposes of this title. The powers of the\nauthority shall be vested in and be exercised by the members of the\nauthority at a meeting duly called and held and a majority of members\nshall constitute a quorum. Except as hereafter provided, no action shall\nbe taken except pursuant to the affirmative vote of at least two voting\nmembers. The board shall appoint from its members a chairperson,\nvice-chairperson, and a treasurer and may delegate to one or more of its\nmembers, officers, agents or employees, such powers and duties as it may\ndeem proper.\n  3. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, no officer, member or\nemployee of the state or of any public corporation shall forfeit his or\nher office, or employment, by reason of his or her acceptance of\nappointment as a member, officer or employee of the authority, nor shall\nservice as such member, officer or employee be deemed incompatible or in\nconflict with such office, membership or employment.\n  4. The authority shall be perpetual in duration, unless terminated by\nlaw. Provided, however that no such law shall take effect so long as the\nauthority shall have bonds or other obligations outstanding unless\nadequate provision has been made for the payment or satisfaction\nthereof. Upon termination of the existence of the authority, all of its\nrights and property shall pass to and be vested in such municipality or\nlegal entity as provided in said law.\n  5. It is hereby determined and declared, that the authority and the\ncarrying out of its powers and duties are in all respects for the\nbenefit of the people of the county and the state for the improvement of\ntheir health, welfare and prosperity and that such purposes are public\npurposes and that the authority is and will be performing an essential\ngovernmental function in the exercise of the powers conferred upon it by\nthis title.\n  6. Nothing in this title shall be construed to obligate the state in\nany way in connection with the operation or obligations of the\nauthority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>