<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2580"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2580"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2580"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2580/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2580/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2580/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2580/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2580">
        <num>2580</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of real property for the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2580. Acquisition of real property for the authority. 1.\nNotwithstanding the provisions of any general, special or local law or\ncharter, the county is hereby empowered to purchase or lease from the\nauthority for a term not exceeding ninety-nine years, a sports facility,\nor enter into any other agreement relating to a sports facility, upon\nsuch terms and conditions as may be agreed upon by the county and the\nauthority.\n  2. The county may enter into agreements with the authority for the\nmanagement or operation, in whole or in part, of a sports facility owned\nor acquired by the county.\n  3. The county may enter into agreements with the authority for the\noperation or maintenance, in whole or in part, of a facility for the\npurpose of minor league baseball, presently known as Frontier Field.\n  4. The county may enter into agreements with the authority to pay for\nplanning, design and feasibility studies undertaken, or caused to be\nundertaken, by the authority.\n  5. Since the authority's continued discharge of its public and\ngovernmental purposes is of benefit to the county, the county may pay,\nwithin the appropriations available therefor, if any, the expenses of\nthe establishment and continued operation of the authority.\n  6. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the county shall have\nthe power to contract indebtedness and to issue its obligations pursuant\nto the local finance law for the purpose of financing any payment\nauthorized to be made pursuant to subdivision two, three, four or five\nof this section. Any such payment shall constitute an object or purpose\nfor which the period of probable usefulness is hereby determined to be\nfive years.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>