<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2591"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2591"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2591"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2591/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2591/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2591/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2591/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2591">
        <num>2591</num>
        <heading>Contracts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2591. Contracts. 1. Construction contracts let by the authority\nshall be in conformity with the applicable provisions of section one\nhundred thirty-five of the state finance law.\n  2. The authority may, in its discretion, assign contracts for\nsupervision and coordination to the successful bidder for any\nsubdivision of work for which the authority receives bids. Any\nconstruction contract awarded by the authority shall contain such other\nterms and conditions as the authority may deem desirable. The authority\nshall not award any construction contract except to the lowest bidder\nwho, in its opinion, is qualified to perform the work required and who\nis responsible and reliable. The authority may, however, reject any or\nall bids or waive any informality in a bid if it believes that the\npublic interest will be promoted thereby. The authority may reject any\nbid, if, in its judgment, the business and technical organization,\nplant, resources, financial standing, or experience of the bidder\njustifies such rejection in view of the work to be performed.\n  3. All contracts or leases for the construction, reconstruction,\nrehabilitation or improvement of buildings let by the authority shall\ncomply with the provisions of section two hundred twenty of the labor\nlaw.\n  4. For the purposes of article fifteen-A of the executive law only,\nthe authority shall be deemed a state agency as that term is used in\nsuch article, and all contracts for procurement, design, construction,\nservices and materials shall be deemed state contracts within the\nmeaning of that term as set forth in such article.\n  5. If after consideration, the authority determines acting within its\ndiscretion and proprietary capacity that given the purpose of any\nproject and the impact of delay, the possibility of cost savings\nadvantages, and the local history of labor unrest, if any, its interest\nin obtaining the best work at the lowest possible price and preventing\nfavoritism, fraud and corruption are best met by requiring a project\nlabor agreement as an incident of any contract let by the authority\nregarding any project, it may require such a project labor agreement.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>