<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2606"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2606"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2606"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2606/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2606/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2606">
        <num>2606</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2606. Legislative findings. It is hereby found, determined and\ndeclared that there is an immediate need to institute a comprehensive,\ncoordinated program of activities utilizing the olympic facilities in\nand around Lake Placid, New York, in order to insure optimum year-round\nuse and enjoyment of these facilities to the economic and social benefit\nof the olympic region and to minimize the financial burden on the state\nand local governments in the maintenance and operation of these\nfacilities by means of maximizing revenue opportunities for their\nsupport; and to take advantage of the opportunity to improve the\nphysical fitness and athletic and recreational education of the people\nof this state and the United States by assisting in the use and\nmaintenance of these facilities. It is further declared to be desirable\nto create a state olympic regional development authority to operate,\nmanage and maintain the olympic facilities, develop, implement and\nsupervise the professional management necessary for such a\ncomprehensive, coordinated program and for the management, promotion,\nscheduling and conduct of an integrated, year-round program and a wide\nrange of national and international athletic training and competitive\nopportunities and other activities which can effectively utilize the\navailable facilities. The authority shall carry out its purposes and\nresponsibilities and utilize the facilities through agreements with\nstate and local agencies which have jurisdiction over the various\nolympic facilities in the olympic region.  It is further declared to be\ndesirable that the authority develop, construct, operate, manage and\nmaintain facilities, or participate therein, for the training and\nhousing of amateur athletes in connection with the United States olympic\ncommittee's training center program and the authority's conduct of\nnational and international sports events. It is further declared that\nthe authority shall be created as a public benefit corporation and that\nthe corporate programs and powers conferred under this title and the\nexpenditures of public moneys pursuant thereto are in furtherance of\nserving a valid public interest and public purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>