<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2608"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2608"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2608"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2608/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2608/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2608">
        <num>2608</num>
        <heading>New York state olympic regional development authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2608. New York state olympic regional development authority. 1. For\nthe purposes of effectuating the policy declared in section twenty-six\nhundred six of this title, there is hereby created the "New York state\nolympic regional development authority", referred to in this title as\n"the authority", which shall be a body corporate and politic\nconstituting a public benefit corporation. The authority shall consist\nof twelve members who shall be the commissioner of environmental\nconservation, the commissioner of economic development, the commissioner\nof parks, recreation and historic preservation and nine persons to be\nappointed by the governor, by and with the advice and consent of the\nsenate. Of the nine persons appointed by the governor, by and with the\nadvice and consent of the senate, one each shall be appointed upon the\nrecommendation of the temporary president of the senate and the speaker\nof the assembly. Three of the persons appointed by the governor, by and\nwith the advice and consent of the senate shall be appointed upon the\nrecommendation of the town board of the town of North Elba and shall be\nresidents of the park district. Two persons shall be appointed by the\ngovernor, by and with the advice and consent of the senate, one of whom\nshall reside in Ulster county and the other of whom shall reside in\nDelaware county. One of the persons appointed by the governor, by and\nwith the advice and consent of the senate, shall be a resident of Warren\ncounty. The governor shall appoint a chairperson, a vice-chairperson and\na second vice-chairperson from among any of the members of the authority\nand such chairperson, vice-chairperson and second vice-chairperson shall\nserve at the pleasure of the governor, provided, however, that the\nvice-chairperson shall be appointed on the recommendation of the town\nboard of North Elba; and the second vice-chairperson shall be appointed\nupon the recommendation of the town boards of the town of Shandaken in\nUlster county and the town of Middletown in Delaware county; and must be\na resident of Ulster or Delaware counties; with a majority vote of the\ncombined two town boards determining who shall be recommended to the\ngovernor for appointment of that position. From among any candidates\nrecommended by the chairman, the members shall appoint a president/chief\nexecutive officer of the authority.\n  The members first appointed by the governor shall be appointed within\nthirty days of the effective date of this title. The members appointed\nas a result of the enactment of the chapter of the laws of two thousand\ntwelve which amended this section, consisting of the eleventh and\ntwelfth board members, shall be appointed within ninety days of the\neffective date of such chapter. The first members appointed by the\ngovernor upon the recommendation of the temporary president of the\nsenate and the speaker of the assembly shall serve terms of three years\nrespectively from January first next succeeding their appointment. The\nremaining four members first appointed by the governor shall serve terms\nof one, two, four and five years respectively from January first next\nsucceeding their appointment. The fifth member appointed by the governor\nshall serve a term of two years from January first, next succeeding his\nor her appointment. Each appointment of a member following the\nexpiration of the original terms of the appointment shall be for a term\nof five years. The members appointed by the governor who are required to\nreside in either Delaware or Ulster counties shall be appointed for\nterms of four years. Members shall continue to hold office until their\nsuccessors have been appointed and qualified. In the event of a vacancy\noccurring during the term of a member's appointment, by reason of death,\nresignation, disqualification or otherwise, such vacancy shall be filled\nfor the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment.\n  2. The members of the authority shall not receive a salary or other\ncompensation for their services as members of the authority but each\nmember shall be allowed reimbursement for the necessary and actual\nexpenses which he or she shall incur in the performance of his or her\nduties under this title.\n  3. The president/chief executive officer shall serve at the pleasure\nof the members and shall be responsible for the discharge of the\nexecutive and administrative functions and exercise of any power or\nfunction of the authority.\n  4. Seven members of the authority shall constitute a quorum for the\ntransaction of any business or the exercise of any power or function of\nthe authority. The authority may delegate to one or more of its members,\nofficers, agents and employees, such powers and duties as it may deem\nproper. The commissioner of environmental conservation, the commissioner\nof economic development, the commissioner of parks and recreation and\nany other member of the authority who is a full time employee of the\nstate or who holds public office may designate one person from his\ndepartment or from the public corporation in which he holds a public\noffice to represent him at all meetings of the authority from which such\nmember may be absent. Any representative so designated shall have the\npower to attend and to vote at any meeting of the authority from which\nthe member so designating him is absent, with the same force and effect\nas if the member designating him were present and voting. Such\ndesignation shall be by written notice filed with the chairman of the\nauthority by the member making the designation and shall be for a term\nof one year or until such representative shall resign or shall no longer\nbe employed by the department of which such member making the\ndesignation is an employee or by the public corporation of which such\nmember making the designation holds a public office or until revoked by\nthe person making such designation. Such designation shall not limit the\npower of the member making the designation to attend and vote in person\nat any meeting of the authority.\n  5. The authority shall be a "state agency" for the purposes of\nsections seventy-three and seventy-four of the public officers law.\n  6. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of this or any other\nlaw, general, special or local, no officer or employee of the state, as\ndefined in the public officers law, or of the park district shall be\ndeemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit his office of employment or\nany benefits provided under the retirement and social security law or\nunder any public retirement system maintained by the state or any of its\nsubdivisions by reason of his acceptance of membership on or\nchairmanship of the authority; provided, however, a member or chairman\nwho holds such other public office of employment shall receive no\nadditional compensation for services rendered pursuant to this title,\nbut shall be entitled to reimbursement for his actual and necessary\nexpenses incurred in the performance of such services.\n  7. The governor may remove any member of the authority for cause,\nother than the commissioner of environmental conservation, the\ncommissioner of economic development and the commissioner of parks and\nrecreation, after giving him a copy of the charges against him and an\nopportunity to be heard, in person or by counsel in his defense, upon\nnot less than ten days' notice. If any member shall be so removed, the\ngovernor shall file in the office of the department of state a complete\nstatement of charges made against such member, and his findings thereon,\ntogether with a complete record of the proceedings.\n  8. The principal office of the authority shall be located in the town\nof North Elba and the authority shall establish a second office at the\nBelleayre Mountain ski center.\n  9. Nothing shall preclude the use of meetings and votes by video\nconference or other conferencing which permits conferees to see the\nother members during board meetings through television or the internet.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>