<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2609"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2609"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2609"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2609/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2609/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2609/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2609/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2609">
        <num>2609</num>
        <heading>Community advisory panel</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2609. Community advisory panel. 1. Within ninety days following the\nappointment of the members of the authority, the members shall appoint\nan advisory panel to act as consultants to the authority for the purpose\nof advising and assisting the authority in procuring international and\nnational athletic sporting events and competition.\n  2. The advisory panel shall consist of nineteen persons, ten of whom\nshall be appointed upon the recommendation of the North Elba sports\ncouncil, a council created by the park district, two of whom shall be\nappointed upon the recommendation of the legislature of the county of\nDelaware and two of whom shall be appointed upon the recommendation of\nthe legislature of the county of Ulster. Such ten members of the panel\nshall have knowledge of athletic competition and winter and summer\nsports and recreation events and activities. The members of the panel\nshall serve for a period of two years. In the event of a vacancy\noccurring during a panel member's appointment, by reason of death,\nresignation, disqualification or otherwise, such vacancy shall be filled\nfor the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment.\n  3. The members of the panel shall serve without compensation, except\nthat each member of the panel shall be allowed the necessary and actual\nexpenses which he shall incur in the performance of his duties within\nthe state under this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>