<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2620"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2620"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2620"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2620/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2620/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2620/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2620/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2620">
        <num>2620</num>
        <heading>Public bidding</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2620. Public bidding. 1. Construction contracts let by the authority\nshall be in conformity with the applicable provisions of sections one\nhundred thirty-five and one hundred forty-four of the state finance law.\n  2. The authority may assign contracts for supervisions and\ncoordination to the successful bidder for any subdivision of work for\nwhich the authority receives bids. Any construction contract award by\nthe authority shall contain such other terms and conditions as the\nauthority may deem desirable. The authority shall not award any\nconstruction contract except to the lowest bidder who, in its opinion,\nis qualified to perform the work required and who is responsible and\nreliable. The authority may, however, reject any or all bids or waive\nany informality in a bid if it reasonably believes that the public\ninterest will be promoted thereby. The authority may reject any bid if,\nin its judgment, the business and technical organization, plant,\nresources, financial standing, or experience of the bidder justifies\nsuch rejection in view of the work to be performed.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>