<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2628"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2628"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2628"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2628/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2628/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2628/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2628/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2628">
        <num>2628</num>
        <heading>Temporary assignment and transfer of employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2628. Temporary assignment and transfer of employees. Whenever in\nthe opinion of the authority it would be in the public interest, it may,\nafter prior approval of the director of the budget, request the\ntemporary assignment and transfer of certain employees of any board,\ncommission, agency or department of the state or its political\nsubdivisions, and said board, commission, agency or department shall, if\nin its opinion such transfer will not interfere with the performance of\nits duties and functions, make such assignment and transfer of said\nemployees to the authority for a period of up to one year, with one\nextension of one year permitted if the authority so requests and said\nboard, commission, agency or department which permanently employs such\nperson consents. Such assignment and transfer or extension thereof shall\nnot in any way affect the civil service status, continuity of service,\nretirement plan status, rights to compensation, grade or compensation or\nother rights or privileges of any employee so transferred. Any employee\ntransferred under the authority of this section shall be paid as total\nreimbursement for expenses in the course of their duties incurred only\nthe actual and necessary expenses incurred up to the maximum rates as\nestablished by the New York state department of audit and control.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>