<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2629"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2629"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2629"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2629/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2629/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2629/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2629/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2629">
        <num>2629</num>
        <heading>Transfer of officers and employees</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2629__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Within thirty days of execution of the agreement, entered into\npursuant to subdivision four of section twenty-six hundred fourteen of\nthis title, provision shall be made for the transfer to the olympic\nregional development authority of all current employees engaged in\ncarrying out such functions with respect to the operation, maintenance\nand management of the Belleayre Mountain ski center. Such employees\nshall be transferred without further examination or qualifications and\nshall retain their respective civil service classifications, status,\nsalary, wages and negotiating unit, if any. No individual who is\ntransferred shall gain any additional rights as a result of such\ntransfer. However, once the employment of any transferred employee who\nis currently placed within a negotiating unit as defined by article\nfourteen of the civil service law is terminated or otherwise ceases, by\nany means, any individual hired to fill such vacancy shall not be placed\nin the same negotiating unit of the former incumbent but rather shall be\nplaced in the negotiating unit that contains employees of the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2629__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The salary or compensation of any such employees, after such\ntransfer, shall be paid by the authority. Notwithstanding the provisions\nof this section, any such employees so transferred to the authority,\npursuant to the provisions of this section, who are members of or\nbeneficiaries under any existing pension or retirement system, shall\ncontinue to have all rights, privileges, obligations and status with\nrespect to such fund system or systems as are prescribed by law, but\nduring the period of their employment by the authority, all\ncontributions to any pension or retirement fund or system to be paid by\nthe employer on account of such employees, shall be paid by the\nauthority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>