<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2631"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2631"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2631"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2631/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2631/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2631/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2631/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2631">
        <num>2631</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2631. Definitions. As used in this title, unless the context\notherwise requires:\n  1. "Commission" shall mean the Hudson-Mohawk urban cultural park\ncommission created pursuant to section two thousand six hundred\nthirty-two of this title.\n  2. "Board" shall mean the members of the commission.\n  3. "Municipality" shall mean the cities of Troy, Cohoes and\nWatervliet, the town of Waterford and the villages of Green Island and\nWaterford.\n  4. "Management plan" shall mean the management plan prepared pursuant\nto section 35.05 of the parks, recreation and historic preservation law.\n  5. "Urban cultural park" shall mean the Hudson-Mohawk urban cultural\npark designated pursuant to section 35.03 of the parks, recreation and\nhistoric preservation law and recognized pursuant to section 13.27 of\nsuch law.\n  6. "Bonds" shall mean the bonds authorized by this title.\n  7. "Project" shall mean any land, any building or other improvement,\nand all real and personal properties located within or partially within\nand partially without the urban cultural park for whose benefit the\ncommission is created, including but not limited to, facilities deemed\nnecessary or desirable in connection therewith, whether or not now in\nexistence, which may include a recreational, educational or urban\ncultural facility, a transportation or service facility related to the\nplans and needs of the urban cultural park or any economic use in a\nfacility, the preservation of which is a feature of the urban cultural\npark.\n  8. "Real property" shall mean lands, structures, franchises, and\ninterest in lands, and any and all things usually included within the\nsaid term, and includes not only fees simple absolute but also any and\nall lesser interest, such as easements, rights of way, uses, leases,\nlicenses, and all other incorporeal hereditaments and every estate,\ninterest or right, legal or equitable, including terms of years, and\nliens thereon by way of judgments, mortgages or otherwise, and also\nclaims for damage to real estate, in the area of the urban cultural\npark.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>