<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2634"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2634"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2634"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2634/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2634/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2634/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2634/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2634">
        <num>2634</num>
        <heading>Cooperation with municipalities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2634. Cooperation with municipalities. 1. The commission is a\ncooperative regional organization of six municipalities to implement and\nmanage an urban cultural park encompassing all or part of each of their\nterritory and based upon the mutual assent and participation of each\nmunicipality. The activities of the commission shall be coordinated with\nthe local planning, cultural and park activities of each municipality.\nNo real property may be acquired or project undertaken by the commission\nin a municipality without the written approval for such action of the\nmember of the board from such municipality.\n  2. Each municipality may provide the commission with the services of\nits agents, employees and facilities without charge to the corporation.\nPersons serving as officers or employees of the commission may be\nemployees of a municipality and the commission, in such case, may pay\nthe municipality an agreed portion of the compensation or costs.\n  3. For purposes of implementing the management plan, any individual\nmunicipality may act with the agreement of the commission to carry out\nan individual project in its own name or acquire real property for a\nproject in the name of the commission at the cost and expense of the\ncommission. In case the commission shall have the use and occupancy of\nany real property which it shall determine is no longer required for a\nproject then, if such property was acquired at the cost and expense of a\nmunicipality, the commission shall have the power to surrender its use\nand occupancy thereof to the municipality, or, if such real property was\nacquired at the cost and expense of the commission, then the commission\nshall have power to sell, lease or otherwise dispose of said real\nproperty at public sale, and shall retain and have the power to use the\nproceeds of sale, rentals, or other moneys derived from the disposition\nthereof for its purposes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>