<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-M"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-M"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2642-M"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-M/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-M/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2642_M">
        <num>2642-M</num>
        <heading>Contracts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2642-m. Contracts. 1. All contracts for the construction,\nreconstruction, rehabilitation or improvement of buildings let by the\nauthority shall comply with the provisions of section two hundred twenty\nof the labor law and shall also be subject to the provisions of law\napplicable to contracts let by a municipal corporation, except as\notherwise provided herein.\n  2. All contracts for the construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation\nor improvement of buildings let by the authority shall be in conformity\nwith the applicable provisions of section one hundred thirty-five of the\nstate finance law.\n  3. The authority may, in its discretion, assign contracts for\nsupervision and coordination to the successful bidder for any\nsubdivision of work for which the authority receives bids. Any\nconstruction contract awarded by the authority shall contain such other\nterms and conditions as the authority may deem desirable. The authority\nshall award any construction contract involving an expenditure of more\nthan five thousand dollars to the lowest bidder who, in its opinion, is\nqualified to perform the work required and who is responsible and\nreliable. The authority may, however, reject any or all bids or waive\nany informality in a bid if it believes that the public interest will be\npromoted thereby. The authority may reject any bid, if, in its judgment,\nthe business and technical organization, plant, resources, financial\nstanding, or experience of the bidder justifies such rejection in view\nof the work to be performed.\n  4. For the purposes of article fifteen-A of the executive law only,\nthe authority shall be deemed a state agency as that term is used in\nsuch article, and all contracts for procurement, design, construction,\nservices and materials shall be deemed state contracts within the\nmeaning of that term as set forth in such article.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>