<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-G"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-G"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2642-G"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-G/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2642-G/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2642_G">
        <num>2642-G</num>
        <heading>Cooperation and assistance of other agencies</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2642-g. Cooperation and assistance of other agencies. 1. To avoid\nduplication of effort and in the interests of economy, the authority may\nmake use of existing studies, surveys, plans, data and other materials\nin the possession of any state agency or any municipality or political\nsubdivision of the state. Each such agency, municipality or subdivision\nlocated in or serving some portion of the state is hereby authorized to\nmake the same available to the authority and otherwise to assist it in\nthe performance of its functions. At the request of the authority, each\nsuch agency, municipality or subdivision located in or serving some\nportion of the state which is engaged in railroad or other\ntransportation activities or in land use or development planning, or\nwhich is charged with the duty of providing or regulating any\ntransportation facility or any other public facility, is further\nauthorized to provide the authority with information regarding its plans\nand programs affecting railroad transportation within the participating\ncounties so that the authority may have available to it current\ninformation with respect thereto. The officers and personnel of such\nagencies, municipalities or subdivisions, and of any other government or\nagency whatever, may serve at the request of the authority upon such\nadvisory committees as the authority shall determine to create and such\nofficers and personnel may serve upon such committees without forfeiture\nof office or employment and with no loss or diminution in the\ncompensation, status, rights and privileges which they otherwise enjoy.\n  2. Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, every municipality\nlocated in the counties of Chautauqua, Cattaraugus, Allegany or Steuben\nis authorized and empowered to consent to the use by the authority of\nany real or personal property owned by any such municipality and\nnecessary, convenient or desirable in the opinion of the authority for\nany of the facilities or projects authorized under this title, including\nsuch real property as has already been devoted to a public use, and as\nan incident to such consent, to lease or otherwise transfer and convey\nto the authority any such real or personal property upon such terms as\nmay be determined by the authority and any such municipality. Every such\nmunicipality also is authorized and empowered, as an incident to such\nconsent, to vest in the authority the control, possession, operation,\nmaintenance, rents, charges and any and all other revenues of any\nfacilities now owned by any such municipality, the title to such\nfacilities remaining in such municipality.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>