<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2651"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2651"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2651"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2651/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2651/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2651/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2651/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2651">
        <num>2651</num>
        <heading>Statement of legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2651. Statement of legislative findings.  It is hereby found,\ndetermined and declared that there is an immediate need to institute a\ncomprehensive, coordinated program of economic development activities in\nthe Route 5 and Route 7 corridors of Schenectady county, especially in\nthe downtown region of the city of Schenectady.\n  It is further found, determined and declared to be desirable to create\na Schenectady metroplex development authority to provide the state of\nNew York, and the county of Schenectady, with the capability to\neffectively and efficiently develop, renovate and optimize the economic\nand social activities of the Route 5 and Route 7 corridors of\nSchenectady county.\n  It is also hereby found, determined and declared that existing\nfacilities in the Route 5 and Route 7 corridors of Schenectady county,\nfor conventions, trade exhibitions, public shows, public entertainment,\nhotel accommodations, transportation, historic preservation, tourism,\nsporting events, social and educational centers, and retail, business,\ncommercial and government office space, including services for the\noperation and maintenance thereof, are inadequate.\n  It is further found, determined and declared that the construction and\noperation of such new facilities to adequately accommodate such\nactivities would generate new business, create employment opportunities,\nprovide new sources of tax revenue, and promote effective and orderly\nredevelopment in the vicinity of the Route 5 and Route 7 corridors of\nSchenectady county, all of which would serve the interests of the state\nof New York, and the county of Schenectady.\n  It is also found, determined and declared that the area in the\nvicinity of the Route 5 and Route 7 corridors of Schenectady county is\nan area characterized by deteriorated industrial and commercial\nstructures, uncoordinated and incompatible commercial uses, inadequate\npublic facilities, and substandard conditions, all of which are\ndetrimental to the economic and social well-being of residents of the\nstate of New York and the county of Schenectady, and that the\nconstruction and operation of such new facilities in such area will\nserve as a catalyst for redevelopment, and a rejuvenation of civic pride\nand accomplishment.\n  It is further found, determined and declared that the construction and\noperation of such new facilities will provide significant economic and\nsocial benefits to the state of New York, the county of Schenectady, and\nthe entire capital district region, and that, consistent with social,\neconomic, environmental and other essential considerations of state\npolicy, locating these new facilities in the Route 5 and Route 7\ncorridors of Schenectady county is in the public interest, given the\nconvenience and accessibility of the location, the elimination of\nsubstandard conditions, the nature and economic characteristics of\nvarious other sites considered, and the immediacy of the needs of the\npeople of the state for the realization of the significant economic and\nsocial benefits to be derived from this development.\n  It is also found, determined and declared that the development of the\nRoute 5 and Route 7 corridors of Schenectady county is a matter of\nessential state and county concern, and that the establishment and\ncreation of a Schenectady metroplex development authority is necessary\nto provide for the economic prosperity, health, safety and general\nwelfare of the people of the county of Schenectady and the state of New\nYork, through the construction, development, location and operation of\nthese new facilities.\n  It is further found, determined and declared that is the intent of the\nlegislature that the Schenectady metroplex development authority shall\ncarry out its purposes and responsibilities directly and through\nagreements with federal, state and local entities and authorities, and\nthat the Schenectady metroplex development authority shall be created as\na public benefit corporation and that the corporate programs and powers\nconferred under this title and the expenditures of public moneys\npursuant thereto, are in furtherance of a valid public interest and\npublic purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>