<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2653"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2653"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2653"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2653/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2653/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2653/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2653/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2653">
        <num>2653</num>
        <heading>Schenectady metroplex development authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2653. Schenectady metroplex development authority. 1. The\nSchenectady metroplex development authority is hereby created. Such\nauthority shall be a body corporate and politic constituting a public\nbenefit corporation. The governing body of the authority shall be a\nboard. The authority shall consist of eleven members who are residents\nof Schenectady county, appointed by a majority vote of the county\nlegislature. Nominations for appointment by the county legislature shall\nbe submitted as follows: one upon the recommendation of the mayor of the\ncity of Schenectady, one upon the recommendation of the city council;\none upon the recommendation of the supervisor of the town of Niskayuna,\none upon the recommendation of the supervisor of the town of Glenville,\none upon the joint recommendation of the supervisors of the towns of\nPrincetown and Duanesburg, one upon the recommendation of the supervisor\nof the town of Rotterdam, one upon the recommendation of the minority\nleader of the county legislature, two upon the recommendation of the\nchairman of the county legislature and two by the joint recommendation\nof the county legislature. The members appointed upon the recommendation\nof the chair of the county legislature, the minority leader of the\ncounty legislature and the joint recommendation of the county\nlegislature shall serve for a term of five years each, and the members\nappointed by the county legislature upon the recommendation of the city\nor town officers shall serve for a term of four years each,\nrespectively, with each term commencing from the first day of January\nnext succeeding their appointment. Each member unless removed for good\ncause by a two-thirds vote of the county legislature shall hold office\nuntil a successor has been appointed and qualified.\n  2. No person holding an elected or management/confidential-exempt\nposition in any county government may be appointed to the authority\nexcept for the Schenectady county commissioner of economic development\nand planning. No member of the state legislature may be appointed to the\nauthority. No person holding, or who has held within the previous four\nyears, the position of chairperson of a village, town, city or county\npolitical party as defined by article two of the election law shall be\nappointed to the authority.\n  3. A member of the board shall be designated as chairman by a majority\nvote of all the members of the county legislature and shall be chairman\nof such board until his or her term as member expires. A member of the\nboard shall also be so designated as vice-chairman of the board until\nhis or her term as member expires. The chairman shall be the chief\nexecutive officer of the authority and shall be primarily responsible\nfor the discharge of the administrative functions of the authority. The\nchairman may appoint an executive director of the authority, upon advice\nand consent of the board, to which such administrative functions may be\ndelegated. The executive director shall be deemed an employee of the\nauthority, and as such be an exempt management confidential employee,\nwho is a public officer and entitled to an annual salary as established\nby the authority board.\n  4. The power of such corporation shall be vested in and exercised by\nthe board. Such board may delegate to one or more of its members or its\nofficers, agents and employees such powers and duties as it may deem\nproper.\n  5. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue until its\nexistence shall be terminated by law. Upon the termination of the\nexistence of the authority all its rights and properties shall pass to\nand be vested in the county of Schenectady.\n  6. Six members of the board shall constitute a quorum for the\ntransaction of business. A majority of the members of the board present\nat any meeting at which a quorum shall be present, shall be sufficient\nto pass any resolution, except as otherwise specified in this title. All\npropositions requiring the expenditure of money or affecting contract\nrights or property, shall be presented to the board in writing. No\nresolution containing such a proposition shall pass unless it receives\napproval of at least six board members in office.\n  7. The board shall hold at least one regular meeting every month. The\nchairman, or in his absence the vice-chairman, or any five members, may\ncall a special meeting by notice as specified by the board. All meetings\nof the board shall be subject to article seven of the public officers\nlaw.\n  8. Members of the board shall be entitled to no compensation for their\nservices, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties.\n  9. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, no officer or employee of the state, or of any\nmunicipality, as defined in the public officers law, the county law or\nthe town law, shall be deemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit his\npublic office or any benefits provided under the retirement and social\nsecurity law or under any public retirement system maintained by the\nstate or any of its subdivisions by reason of his acceptance of\nmembership on or chairmanship or vice-chairmanship of the authority;\nprovided, however, a member or chairman who holds such other public\noffice shall receive no additional compensation for services rendered\npursuant to this title, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for\nactual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of such\nservices.\n  10. The principal office of the authority shall be located in the\ncounty of Schenectady.\n  11. The comptroller may conduct periodic audits of the authority and\nreport the results of such audits to the governor, the chairman of the\nsenate finance committee, and the chairman of the assembly ways and\nmeans committee.\n  12. Subject to the provisions of this title, members of the authority\nmay engage in private employment, or in a profession or business.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>