<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2655-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2655_A">
        <num>2655-A</num>
        <heading>Bylaws of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2655-a. Bylaws of the authority. 1. The board shall draft proposed\nbylaws for the organization and procedure of the authority. Such bylaws\nshall be consistent with the provisions of this title and all other\nstate and federal laws, and shall contain a provision that such bylaws\nmay only be amended after final adoption by a two-thirds vote of all the\nvoting members of the board. Upon the drafting of such proposed bylaws,\nthe board shall conduct a public hearing on such proposed bylaws and\nsolicit public comment on the same. After the public hearing and comment\nhas been conducted and solicited, the board shall adopt such proposed\nbylaws, with any amendments made thereto in response to the public\nhearing and comment, and shall thereafter file the adopted proposed\nbylaws with the clerk of the county legislature.\n  2. Within thirty days of the filing of such adopted proposed bylaws\nwith the clerk of the county legislature, the county legislature may, by\na two-thirds vote of all the members of the county legislature, reject\nthe proposed bylaws so filed and return them to the authority for\npossible amendment and redrafting. If the county legislature does not\nreject the proposed bylaws by such two-thirds vote within thirty days of\nthe filing of the same, then such proposed bylaws so filed shall be\ndeemed adopted and in full force and effect. If the county legislature\nrejects the proposed bylaws by such two-thirds vote, then the authority\nshall amend the proposed bylaws as deemed appropriate. Such amended\nbylaws shall be filed with the clerk of the county legislature,\nwhereupon the county legislature may again consider the amended bylaws\nas in the same manner as if such bylaws had been originally filed\npursuant to subdivision one of this section.\n  3. In the absence of bylaws which are deemed adopted and in full force\nand effect, the authority shall operate and be governed by the\nprovisions of this title and the most recently revised edition of\nRoberts Rules of Order.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>