<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2655-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2655_D">
        <num>2655-D</num>
        <heading>Reports of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2655-d. Reports of the authority.  1. In addition to any other\nreport required by this title, the authority, through its chairman,\nshall annually deliver, in oral and written form, a report to the county\nlegislature. Such report shall be presented by March fifteenth of each\nyear to the county legislature's standing committee on economic\ndevelopment. The report shall describe in detail the projects undertaken\nby the authority during the past year, the monies expended by the\nauthority during the past year, the administrative activities of the\nauthority during the past year, and the authority's compliance with the\nprovisions of subdivision three of section twenty-six hundred fifty-six\nof this title. At the conclusion of the report, the chairman of the\nauthority board shall be prepared to answer the questions of the county\nlegislators with respect to the projects undertaken by the authority\nduring the past year, the monies expended by the authority during the\npast year, and the administrative activities of the authority during the\npast year.\n  2. In addition to any other report required by this title, each board\nmember appointed upon the recommendation of a municipality other than\nthe county, shall annually deliver, in oral and written form, a report\nto the municipality from which such board member was appointed. In the\ncase of the city of Schenectady, both members so appointed shall jointly\ndeliver such report. Such report shall be presented at a meeting as\ndesignated by the municipality's town board or city council. The report\nshall describe in detail the projects undertaken by the authority during\nthe past year, the monies expended by the authority during the past\nyear, and the administrative activities of the authority during the past\nyear. At the conclusion of the report, the board member or members shall\nbe prepared to answer the questions of the supervisor, mayor, town board\nand/or city council with respect to the projects undertaken by the\nauthority during the past year, the monies expended by the authority\nduring the past year, and the administrative activities of the authority\nduring the past year, or any other activities of the authority which\nhave been conducted or which may be proposed for performance with the\nmunicipality.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>