<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2655-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2655-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2655_C">
        <num>2655-C</num>
        <heading>Capital plan of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2655-c. Capital plan of the authority. On or before the first day of\nMarch, the authority shall annually produce, and present at a public\nhearing for public comment, a five-year capital projects plan, outlining\nthe vision of its intended capital projects for the next five years.\nWith respect to each project proposed in the plan, the authority shall\nprovide a detailed description of the:\n  1. overall nature, purpose and extent of the project;\n  2. proposed amount and sources of capital funding to complete the\nproject;\n  3. proposed amount and sources of operating funding necessary to\noperate the project;\n  4. urban and community planning performed or which needs to be\nperformed;\n  5. economic development potential of the project;\n  6. financial feasibility of the project;\n  7. geographic location and impact of the project;\n  8. impact of the project on the community's natural resources;\n  9. tourism, entertainment and arts development potential of the\nproject;\n  10. human and physical infrastructure requirements and impact of the\nproject; and\n  11. other factors which have been considered for the purpose of\nenhancing the viability of the county.\n  An annual presentation of this five-year capital plan shall further be\nmade to the county legislature. After the presentation of the first\nfive-year capital plan, any subsequent plan presented shall describe any\nchanges from, modifications to, and the current status of, projects\nincluded in the previous plans. In developing and maintaining such plan,\nthe authority shall, from time to time, enter into contracts with any\nand all outside experts it may deem necessary for the plan's successful\nproduction, presentation and development.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>