<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2658"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2658"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2658"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2658/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2658/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2658/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2658/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2658">
        <num>2658</num>
        <heading>Code of ethics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall accept other employment, which will\nimpair his or her independence of judgment in the exercise of his or her\nofficial duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall accept employment or engage in any\nbusiness or professional activity which will require the employee to\ndisclose confidential information which he or she has gained by reason\nof his or her official position or authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall disclose confidential information\nacquired by the employee in the course of his or her official duties nor\nuse such information to further his or her personal interests.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall use or attempt to use his or her\nofficial position to secure unwarranted privileges or exemptions for him\nor herself or others.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall engage in any transaction as\nrepresentative or agent of the authority with any business entity in\nwhich he or she has a direct or indirect financial interest that might\nreasonably tend to conflict with the proper discharge of his or her\nofficial duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall not by his or her conduct give\nreasonable basis for the impression that any person can improperly\ninfluence such employee or unduly enjoy his or her favor in the\nperformance of his or her official duties, or that he or she is affected\nby the kinship, rank, position or influence of any party or person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall abstain from making personal\ninvestments in enterprises which he or she has reason to believe may be\ndirectly involved in decisions to be made by the employee or which will\notherwise create substantial conflict between his or her duty in the\npublic interest and his or her private interest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall endeavor to pursue a course of conduct\nwhich will not raise suspicion among the public that he or she is likely\nto be engaged in acts that are in violation of his or her trust.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee employed on a full-time basis nor any firm\nor association of which such an employee is a member nor corporation a\nsubstantial portion of the stock of which is owned or controlled\ndirectly or indirectly by such employee, shall sell goods or services to\nany person, firm, corporation or association which is licensed or whose\nrates are fixed by the authority in which such employee serves or is\nemployed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2658__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any authority employee shall have a financial interest, direct\nor indirect, having a value of ten thousand dollars or more in any\nactivity which is subject to the jurisdiction of a regulatory agency, he\nor she shall file with the secretary of state a written statement that\nhe or she has such a financial interest in such activity which statement\nshall be open to public inspection.\n  4. In addition to any penalty contained in any other provision of law\nany such authority employee who shall knowingly and intentionally\nviolate any of the provisions of this section may be fined, suspended or\nremoved from office or employment.\n  5. The authority shall ensure that all employees or applicants for\nemployment are afforded equal employment opportunity without\ndiscrimination.\n  6. All board members and employees of the authority shall be deemed to\nbe public officers and shall, notwithstanding any other ethical\nrequirements established by state or local law, and when not\ninconsistent with the provisions of this title, comply with sections\nseventy-three, seventy-three-a and seventy-four of the public officers\nlaw. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the filing of a\nSchenectady county financial disclosure statement with the Schenectady\ncounty board of ethics by a board member shall constitute and be deemed\nin compliance with the financial disclosure requirements imposed by this\nsection and section seventy-three-a of the public officers law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>