<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2659"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2659"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2659"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2659/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2659/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2659/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2659/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2659">
        <num>2659</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of land</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2659. Acquisition of land. The authority, upon the terms and\nconditions approved by resolution of the authority, shall have the power\nto acquire real property located within the service district by\npurchase, lease or condemnation to accomplish its lawful purposes. It\nshall also have the power to sell, lease or otherwise dispose of real\nproperty and shall retain and have the power to use the proceeds of such\nsale, rentals or other monies derived from the disposition thereof for\nits lawful purposes.  A resolution of the authority to condemn real\nproperty shall require a two-thirds majority of the board for approval.\n  Claims for the value of the real property condemned and for legal\ndamages caused by any such condemnation shall be adjusted and determined\nby the chairman with the approval of the board, or by the supreme court\nof Schenectady county as provided in section twenty-six hundred seventy\nof this title. When a claim has been filed with the supreme court, the\nclaimant shall cause a copy of such claim to be served upon the\nauthority and the authority shall have the right to be represented and\nheard before said court. All awards and judgments arising from such\nclaims shall be paid out of moneys of the authority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>