<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2669-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2669-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2669-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2669-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2669-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2669-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2669-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2669_B">
        <num>2669-B</num>
        <heading>Agreement with county</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2669_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Nothing contained in this title shall be deemed to restrict the\nright of the county to repeal the sales and compensating use taxes\nimposed pursuant to the authority of section twelve hundred ten-C of the\ntax law, provided such county imposes sales and compensating use taxes\npursuant to the authority of section twelve hundred ten of the tax law\nat a rate not less than one-half of one percent, or, if the county does\nnot impose such taxes pursuant to the authority of section twelve\nhundred ten-C of the tax law, to reduce the rate of such taxes imposed\npursuant to the authority of such section twelve hundred ten of the tax\nlaw to a rate not less than one-half of one percent, or to amend, modify\nor otherwise alter such taxes or appropriations relating thereto or to\namend, modify, repeal or otherwise alter other taxes or fees or\nappropriations relating thereto.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2669_B__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The authority shall not include in any resolution, contract or\nagreement with the holders of its bonds, or such persons or public\nauthorities who may enter into contracts with the authority, any\nprovision stating that, as a result of the county exercising its right\nto reduce, as described in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2669_B__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the rate\nof, amend, modify or otherwise alter such sales and compensating use\ntaxes or related appropriations, or its right to amend, repeal, modify\nor otherwise alter any such other tax, fee or appropriation a default\nwill occur.\n  3. Nothing in this title shall be deemed to obligate the county to\nmake additional payments or impose any taxes to satisfy the debt service\nobligations of the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>