<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2675-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2675_F">
        <num>2675-F</num>
        <heading>Preliminary study of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2675-f. Preliminary study of the authority. Prior to commencing any\npurchase, lease or transfer of any real property, in whole or part, the\nauthority shall formulate a plan for the creation and development of the\nconvention facility. After passage of a resolution approving such plan,\nit shall be submitted to the governor, comptroller, temporary president\nof the senate, speaker of the assembly, county executive and mayor. Such\nresolution shall require at least six affirmative votes of the board for\npassage. Any plan submitted will include, but not be limited to: a\ndetailed accounting of expected revenues and financing; an estimate of\nexpenditures necessary for construction and maintenance; a description\nof the geographic location of anticipated construction sites, with\nsupporting information on the impact such construction would have on\nexisting structures in the vicinity; a depiction of any and all\nstructures anticipated for construction; an assessment of anticipated\nenvironmental impacts; a plan for inclusion of historic preservation\nmeasures to be undertaken; a structure for involvement of the community;\nthe report of results from public hearings held, pursuant to section\ntwenty-six hundred seventy-five-g of this title; and, a timeline for\nexpected development.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>