<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-08-04" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2675-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2675_D">
        <num>2675-D</num>
        <heading>Albany convention center authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2675-d. Albany convention center authority. 1. A corporation known\nas the Albany convention center authority is hereby created for the\npublic purpose and charged with the duties and having the powers\nprovided in this title. The authority shall be a body corporate and\npolitic constituting a public benefit corporation. The governing body of\nthe authority shall be a board. The authority shall consist of nine\nmembers.  Three members shall be appointed by the governor. One member\nshall be appointed by the temporary president of the senate. One member\nshall be appointed by the speaker of the assembly. Two members shall be\nappointed by the mayor with the advice and consent of the common\ncouncil. Two members shall be appointed by the county executive with the\nadvice and consent of the county legislature. All members of the board\nshall serve at the pleasure of their appointing authority.\n  2. A member of the board shall be designated as chairperson by a\nmajority vote of all the members of the board, provided that the initial\nchairperson must be one of the members appointed by the governor. A\nmember of the board shall also be so designated as vice-chairperson of\nthe board. The chairperson may appoint an executive director of the\nauthority, upon advice and consent of the board, who shall be primarily\nresponsible for the discharge of the administrative functions of the\nauthority. The executive director shall be deemed an employee of the\nauthority, and, as such, be an exempt management confidential employee,\nwho is a public officer and entitled to an annual salary as established\nby the authority board, such salary not to exceed the salary of the\nmayor or county executive, whichever is higher.\n  3. The powers of such corporation shall be vested in and exercised by\nthe board.\n  4. The authority and its corporate existence shall continue until its\nexistence shall be terminated by law, provided, however, that no such\ntermination shall take effect so long as the authority shall have bonds\nor other obligations outstanding unless adequate provision has been made\nfor the payment or satisfaction thereof.\n  5. Five members of the board shall constitute a quorum for the\ntransaction of business. At least four of the members of the board\npresent at any meeting at which a quorum shall be present, shall be\nnecessary to pass any resolution, except as otherwise specified in this\ntitle. All propositions requiring the expenditure of money or affecting\ncontract rights or property, shall be presented to the board in writing.\nNo resolution containing such a proposition shall pass unless it\nreceives approval of at least a majority of the whole board.\n  6. The board shall hold at least one regular meeting quarterly. The\nchairperson, or in his or her absence the vice-chairperson, or any four\nmembers, may call a special meeting by notice as specified by the board.\nAll meetings of the board shall be subject to article seven of the\npublic officers law.\n  7. Members of the board shall be entitled to no compensation for their\nservices, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties.\n  8. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, no officer or employee of the state or of any\nmunicipality, as defined in the public officers law, the second class\ncities law, or the general city law, shall be deemed to have forfeited\nor shall forfeit his or her public office or any benefits provided under\nthe retirement or social security law or under any public retirement\nsystem maintained by the state or any of its subdivisions by reason of\nhis or her acceptance of membership on or chairpersonship or\nvice-chairpersonship of the authority.\n  9. The principal office of the authority shall be located in the city\nof Albany.\n  10. Subject to the provisions of this title, members of the authority\nmay engage in private employment, or in a profession or business.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>