<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2675-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2675_O">
        <num>2675-O</num>
        <heading>Remedies for bond holders</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2675_O__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by suit, action or proceeding in accordance with the civil\npractice law and rules, enforce all rights of the holders of the\nauthority's bonds, and include the right to require the authority to\ncollect fees and charges and interest adequate to carry out any\nagreements as to, or pledge or assignment of or lien upon, such fees and\ncharges and interest, on properties and to require the authority to\ncarry out any other agreements with the holders of such bonds to perform\nits duties under this title;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2675_O__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>bring suit upon such bonds;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2675_O__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by action or suit, require the authority to account as if it were\nthe trustee of an express trust for the holders of such bonds;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2675_O__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>by action or suit, enjoin any acts or things which may be unlawful\nor in violation of the rights of the holders of such bonds;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2675_O__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>declare all such bonds due and payable, and if all defaults shall\nbe made good, then with the consent of the holders of the twenty-five\nper centum of the principal amount of such bonds then outstanding, to\nannul such declaration and its consequences.\n  3. Such trustee shall in addition to the foregoing have and possess\nall of the powers necessary and appropriate for the exercise of any\nfunctions specifically set forth herein or incident to the general\nrepresentation of the holders of the authority's bonds in the\nenforcement and protection of their rights.\n  4. The Supreme Court shall have jurisdiction of any suit, action or\nproceeding by the trustee on behalf of such holders of the authority's\nbonds. The venue of any such suit, action or proceeding shall be laid in\nthe city in which the principal office of the authority is located.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>