<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2675-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2675_C">
        <num>2675-C</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2675-c. Definitions. As used or referred to in this title, unless a\ndifferent meaning appears from the context:\n  1. "Authority" shall mean the public benefit corporation created by\nsection twenty-six hundred seventy-five-d of this title.\n  2. "Board" shall mean the members of the authority created in section\ntwenty-six hundred seventy-five-d of this title.\n  3. "Bonds" shall mean hotel revenue bonds, notes, and other evidence\nof indebtedness issued by the authority pursuant to this title.\n  4. "City" shall mean the city of Albany.\n  5. "Common council" shall mean the common council of the city of\nAlbany.\n  6. "Comptroller" shall mean the comptroller of the state of New York.\n  7. "Convention facility" shall mean a convention center complex\ncomprised of facilities for trade exhibition, hotel accommodations,\ntransportation infrastructure, tourism, retail business, commercial\noffice space and/or parking of which the ownership, lease, transfer,\ndesign, development, planning, financing, creation, siting,\nconstruction, renovation, administration, operation, management and/or\nmaintenance is authorized to be undertaken, in whole or part, by the\nauthority pursuant to this title.\n  8. "County executive" shall mean the county executive of the county of\nAlbany.\n  9. "County legislature" shall mean the county legislature of the\ncounty of Albany.\n  10. "Director of the budget" shall mean the director of the budget for\nthe state of New York.\n  11. "Downtown" shall mean the area within the boundaries of the city\nof Albany located within one mile of the State Capitol or Empire State\nPlaza.\n  12. "Governor" shall mean the governor of the state of New York.\n  13. "Mayor" shall mean the mayor of the city of Albany.\n  14. "Municipality" shall mean a county, town, city or village.\n  15. "Person" shall mean any natural person, partnership, limited\nliability company, association, joint venture or corporation, exclusive\nof a public corporation.\n  16. "Personal property" shall mean chattels and other tangible things\nof a moveable or removable nature.\n  17. "Property" shall mean both real and personal property.\n  18. "Real property" shall mean lands, structures, franchises and\ninterests in land, airspace, waters, lands under water, riparian rights,\nair rights, any fixtures, equipment and articles of personal property\naffixed to or used in connection therewith, and any and all things and\nrights included within said term and includes not only fees simple\nabsolute but also any and all lesser interests including but not limited\nto easements, rights-of-way, uses, leases, licenses and all other\nincorporeal hereditaments and every estate, interest or right, legal or\nequitable, including terms for years and liens thereon by way of\njudgments, mortgages, or otherwise.\n  19. "State" shall mean the state of New York.\n  20. "Theatre facilities" shall mean a building or part of a building\nwith one or more performance areas and one or more audience seating\nareas used primarily for the presentation of dramatic or musical\ntheatre.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>