<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2675-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2675-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2675_B">
        <num>2675-B</num>
        <heading>Statement of legislative findings</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2675-b. Statement of legislative findings. It is hereby found,\ndetermined and declared that there is an immediate need to institute a\ncomprehensive, coordinated program of convention activities in the city\nof Albany. It is further found, determined and declared to be desirable\nto create an Albany convention center authority to provide the city of\nAlbany with the capability to effectively and efficiently develop,\nrenovate and undertake certain transformational economic developmental\nprojects in the historic downtown area to optimize the economic and\nsocial activities of the city and its environs. It is further found,\ndetermined and declared that the construction, transformation and\nimprovement of new and existing facilities for a convention center\nconsisting of trade exhibition, hotel accommodations, transportation\ninfrastructure, tourism, theatre facilities, retail business, commercial\noffice space facilities, including services for the operation and\nmaintenance thereof, will provide significant economic and social\nbenefits to the city and county of Albany and the entire capital\ndistrict region and, that, consistent with social, economic,\nenvironmental and other essential considerations of state policy,\nlocating and renovating these new and improved facilities in the\nhistoric downtown area of the city of Albany is in the public interest,\ngiven the convenience and accessibility of the city, its significance in\nthe history of the state and nation, its designation as a heritage area,\nits stature as the capital city of the state and the seat of state\ngovernment, and the immediacy of the needs of the people of the state\nfor the realization of the significant economic and social benefits to\nbe derived from this convention center.\n  It is further found, determined and declared that the development of\nthe area is a matter of essential state and city concern, and that the\nestablishment and creation of an Albany convention center authority is\nnecessary to provide for the economic prosperity and general welfare of\nthe people of the city of Albany and the state of New York for the\nconstruction, development, location and operation of a convention center\nconsisting of these facilities.\n  It is further found, determined and declared to be the intent of the\nlegislature that the Albany convention center authority shall carry out\nits purposes and responsibilities directly and through agreements with\nlocal entities, and that the Albany convention center authority shall be\ncreated as a public benefit corporation and that the corporate programs\nand powers conferred under this title and the expenditure of public\nmonies pursuant thereto, are in furtherance of a valid public interest\nand public purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>