<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-O"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-O"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2676-O"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-O/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-O/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2676_O">
        <num>2676-O</num>
        <heading>Exemption from taxes, assessments and certain fees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2676-o. Exemption from taxes, assessments and certain fees. 1. The\nauthority shall not be required to pay any fees, taxes, special ad\nvalorem levies, or assessments, whether state or local, including but\nnot limited to fees, taxes, special ad valorem levies, or assessments on\nreal property, franchise taxes, sales taxes, or other excise taxes, upon\nany property owned by it or under its jurisdiction, control or\nsupervision, or upon the uses thereof, or upon its activities in the\noperation and maintenance of its facilities or any rentals, rates,\ncharges, fees, revenues, or other income received by the authority.\nNotwithstanding the previous sentence, the authority shall be required\nto pay water and pure water fees or charges as may be negotiated by any\npublic corporation. The authority shall at all times be exempt from any\nfiling, mortgage recording, or transfer fees or taxes in relation to\ninstruments filed, recorded, or transferred by it or on its behalf. The\nconstruction, use, occupation, or possession of any property owned by\nthe authority or the county, including improvements thereon, by any\nperson or public corporation under a lease, lease and sublease, or any\nother agreement shall not operate to abrogate or limit the foregoing\nexemption, notwithstanding that the lessee, user, occupant, or person in\npossession shall claim ownership for federal income tax purposes.\n  2. Any bonds issued pursuant to this title together with the income\ntherefrom as well as the property of the authority shall at all times be\nexempt from taxes, except for transfer and estate taxes. The state\nhereby covenants with the purchasers and with all subsequent holders and\ntransferees of bonds issued by the authority pursuant to this title, in\nconsideration of the acceptance of and payment for the bonds, that the\nbonds of the authority issued pursuant to this title and the income\ntherefrom and all revenues, monies, and other property pledged to secure\nthe payment of such bonds shall at all times be free from taxation,\nexcept for transfer and estate taxes.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>