<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-C"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-C"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2676-C"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-C/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-C/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2676_C">
        <num>2676-C</num>
        <heading>Albany county pine hills land authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2676-c. Albany county pine hills land authority. 1. There is hereby\ncreated the Albany county pine hills land authority. The authority shall\nbe a body corporate and politic constituting a public benefit\ncorporation. The authority shall consist of seven members who shall be\nresidents of the county of Albany. Such members shall be appointed in\nthe following manner: four shall be appointed by the county executive,\ntwo shall be appointed by the chairperson of the county legislature, and\none shall be appointed by the mayor of the city of Albany. Of the\nmembers of the authority initially appointed by the county executive,\ntwo shall serve for a term ending December thirty-first, two thousand\ntwenty-eight and two shall serve for a term ending December\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty-nine. Of the members of the authority\ninitially appointed by the chairperson of the county legislature, one\nshall serve for a term ending December thirty-first, two thousand\ntwenty-eight and one shall serve for a term ending December\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty-nine. The member of the authority\ninitially appointed by the mayor of the city of Albany shall serve for a\nterm ending December thirty-first, two thousand twenty-eight.\nThereafter, each member of the authority shall serve a term of four\nyears. The members of the authority, once appointed, shall designate one\nof the seven members of the authority to serve as the chairperson of the\nauthority. The authority may provide for such officers as may be\ndetermined necessary and the same need not be members of the authority.\n  2. All members of the authority shall continue to hold office until\ntheir successors are appointed and qualify. Except as otherwise provided\nin subdivision three of this section, vacancies of members of the\nauthority shall be filled in the manner provided for original\nappointment. Such vacancies, occurring otherwise than by expiration of\nterm of office, shall be filled for the unexpired terms. Members of the\nauthority may be removed from office for the same reasons and in the\nsame manner as may be provided by law for the removal of officers of the\ncounty. The members of the authority shall receive no compensation for\ntheir services but shall be reimbursed for all their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in connection with the carrying out of the\npurposes of this title. The powers as set forth in the by-laws of the\nauthority shall be established and vested in and be exercised by the\nmembers of the authority at an initial meeting duly called and held and\nfour members of the authority shall constitute a quorum. No action shall\nbe taken at the initial meeting of the authority or any adjournment\nthereof except pursuant to the favorable vote of at least four members\nof the authority. Any amendment to the powers of the authority as set\nforth in the by-laws of the authority shall only become effective upon\nthe favorable vote of at least four members of the authority.\n  3. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, no officer, member, or\nemployee of the state or of any public corporation shall forfeit such\nofficer's, member's, or employee's office or employment by reason of\nsuch officers', member's, or employee's acceptance of appointment as a\nmember, officer, or employee of the authority, nor shall service as such\nmember, officer, or employee be deemed incompatible or in conflict with\nsuch office, membership, or employment.\n  4. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution, or charter, no officer, member,\nelected official or employee of the county of Albany or the city of\nAlbany shall be eligible to serve as a member of the authority.\n  5. All members of the authority shall be required to comply with the\nAlbany county code of ethics and to complete all disclosure forms\nrequired by such code of ethics.\n  6. The authority and its corporate existence shall continue until\nterminated by law, provided, however, that no such termination shall\ntake effect so long as the authority shall have bonds or other\nobligations outstanding unless adequate provision has been made for the\npayment or satisfaction thereof. Upon termination of the existence of\nthe authority, all of the rights and properties of the authority then\nremaining shall pass to and vest in the county of Albany in such a\nmanner as prescribed by law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>