<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2676-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2676_A">
        <num>2676-A</num>
        <heading>Statement of legislative findings and purpose</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to promote accessible,\nefficient and economically productive use of the facilities;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to\nacquire, construct, reconstruct, continue, develop, equip, expand,\nimprove, maintain, finance, and operate the college of Saint Rose\nfacilities and services within the county of Albany;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to stimulate\nand promote economic development; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to make contracts and leases\nand to execute all instruments necessary or convenient for its corporate\npurposes.\n  6. Such purposes are in all respects public purposes for the benefit\nof the people of the state of New York and for which public funds may be\nexpended and both the county and the authority in carrying out their\nrespective powers and duties under this title shall be deemed to be\nacting in a governmental capacity. The acquisition, construction,\nreconstruction, development, expansion, improvement, equipping,\noperation and maintenance of any project financed or undertaken by the\nauthority or the county shall be deemed to be the performance of an\nessential governmental function by the authority or the county acting in\nits governmental capacity, whether such project shall be owned or\noperated by the authority or by any person or public corporation.\n  7. It is hereby found and declared that it has been and remains the\npolicy of the state of New York to promote equal opportunity in\nemployment for all persons, without discrimination on account of race,\ncreed, color, national origin, sex, age, disability or marital status,\nto promote equality of economic opportunity for minority group members\nand women, and minority and women-owned business enterprises.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>