<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-R"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-R"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2676-R"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-R/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-R/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2676_R">
        <num>2676-R</num>
        <heading>Code of ethics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall accept other employment\nwhich will impair such authority employee's independence of judgment in\nthe exercise of such authority employee's official duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall accept employment or engage in any\nbusiness or professional activity which will require such authority\nemployee to disclose confidential information which such authority\nemployee has gained by reason of such authority employee's official\nposition or authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall disclose confidential information\nacquired by such authority employee in the course of such authority\nemployee's official duties nor use such information to further such\nauthority employee's personal interests.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall use or attempt to use such authority\nemployee's official position to secure unwarranted privileges or\nexemptions for such authority employee or others.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall engage in any transaction as\nrepresentative or agent of the authority with any business entity in\nwhich such authority employee has a direct or indirect financial\ninterest that might reasonably tend to conflict with the proper\ndischarge of such authority employee's official duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall not by such authority employee's\nconduct give reasonable basis for the impression that any person can\nimproperly influence such authority employee or unduly enjoy such\nauthority employee's favor in the performance of such authority\nemployee's official duties, or that such authority employee is affected\nby the kinship, rank, position or influence of any party or person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall abstain from making personal\ninvestments in enterprises which such authority employee has reason to\nbelieve may be directly involved in decisions to be made by such\nauthority employee or which will otherwise create substantial conflict\nbetween such authority employee's duty in the public interest and such\nauthority employee's private interest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall endeavor to pursue a course of conduct\nwhich will not raise suspicion among the public that such authority\nemployee is likely to be engaged in acts that are in violation of such\nauthority employee's trust.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee employed on a full-time basis nor any firm\nor association of which such authority employee is a member nor\ncorporation a substantial portion of the stock of which is owned or\ncontrolled directly or indirectly by such authority employee, should\nsell goods or services to any person, firm, corporation or association\nwhich is licensed or whose rates are fixed by the authority in which\nsuch authority employee serves or is employed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2676_R__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any authority employee shall have a financial interest, direct\nor indirect, having a value of ten thousand dollars or more in any\nactivity which is subject to the jurisdiction of a regulatory agency,\nsuch authority employee shall file with the secretary of state a written\nstatement that such authority employee has such a financial interest in\nsuch activity which statement shall be open to public inspection.\n  4. Violations. In addition to any penalty contained in any other\nprovision of law any such authority employee who shall knowingly and\nintentionally violate any of the provisions of this section may be\nfined, suspended, or removed from office or employment.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>