<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2676-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2676_D">
        <num>2676-D</num>
        <heading>Advances on behalf of the authority; transfer of property to the authority; acquisition of property by county for the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2676-d. Advances on behalf of the authority; transfer of property to\nthe authority; acquisition of property by county for the authority. 1.\nIn addition to any powers granted to it by law, the county may, from\ntime to time, appropriate by resolution sums of money to defray project\ncosts or any other costs and expenses of the authority including\noperating expenses. Subject to the rights of bond holders, the county\nmay determine if the monies so appropriated shall be subject to\nrepayment by the authority to the county and, in such event, the manner\nand time or times for such repayment.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, any public corporation\nmay, by a majority vote of its governing body and the approval of its\nchief executive officer, give, grant, sell, convey, loan, license the\nuse of, or lease to the authority any property or facilities, including\nthe college of Saint Rose facilities, which are useful in connection\nwith the exercise by the authority of its powers under this title. Any\nsuch gift, grant, sale, conveyance, loan, license, or lease shall be\nupon such terms and conditions, and for such term or terms of years,\nsubject to the rights of the holders of any bonds, as the authority and\nsuch public corporation may agree. Any such gift, grant, sale,\nconveyance, lease, loan, or license shall not be subject to referendum,\npermissive or mandatory. In the event that any public corporation gives,\ngrants, sells, conveys, loans, licenses, or leases any of the college of\nSaint Rose facilities to the authority, such public corporation may\ncontract with the authority to lease, borrow, license, operate,\nmaintain, manage, and provide services for such facilities upon such\nterms and conditions and for such term or terms of years, subject to the\nrights of holders of bonds, as the authority and such public corporation\nmay agree. The authority, in furtherance of any purchase, conveyance, or\nlease of any property or facility from any public corporation, may\nassume the primary responsibility for the payment of the principal and\ninterest on any bonds or notes issued by such public corporation for\nsuch property or facility. For purposes of section 136.00 of the local\nfinance law, any agreement by the authority to assume the primary\nresponsibility for the payment of the principal and interest on any\nbonds or notes issued by any such public corporation shall, so long as\nsuch agreement shall continue to be honored by the authority, cause such\nbonds or notes to be deemed to have been refunded and any such public\ncorporation may deduct from its gross indebtedness any outstanding\nindebtedness contracted for such property or facility to be acquired by\nthe authority.\n  3. The county may acquire by purchase, grant, lease, gift, or\ncondemnation pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law, real property\nin the name of the county for any corporate purpose of the authority.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, general, special,\nor local, real property acquired by the authority or the county from the\nstate may be used for any corporate purpose of the authority provided,\nhowever, no non-hazardous solid waste, toxic, or hazardous waste site,\ncenter, consolidated collection, or transfer area, shall be located or\nmaintained at the college of Saint Rose facilities or lands adjacent\nthereto that are used in support of the college of Saint Rose operations\nas contained in any layout plan in existence upon the effective date of\nthis title or in the future.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>