<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-07-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2676-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2676-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2676_B">
        <num>2676-B</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2676-b. Definitions. As used or referred to in this title, unless a\ndifferent meaning clearly appears from the context:\n  1. "Authority" shall mean the Albany county pine hills land authority\ncreated by this title.\n  2. "City" shall mean the city of Albany.\n  3. "The college of Saint Rose facilities" shall mean any facility or\nland including but not limited to any athletic facility, educational\nfacility, performing arts facility, or residential facility owned or\noperated by the college of Saint Rose, and shall include such other\nfacilities, equipment, property, structures and appurtenances as may be\nnecessary or convenient in the operation, maintenance, development or\nimprovement of, leased by the authority to persons, engaged in the\nproduction or development of the facilities or land.\n  4. "Bonds" shall mean the bonds, notes or other evidences of\nindebtedness issued by the authority pursuant to this title and the\nprovisions of this title relating to bonds and bond holders which shall\napply with equal force and effect to notes and note holders unless the\ncontext otherwise clearly requires.\n  5. "Construction" shall mean the acquisition, erection, building,\nalteration, repair, improvement, increase, enlargement, extension,\ninstallation, reconstruction, renovation or rehabilitation of a project\nincluding any appurtenances thereto which may be necessary or desirable\nto promote the efficiency or effectiveness of such project; the\ninspection and supervision thereof; and the engineering, consulting,\narchitectural, legal, fiscal and economic and environmental\ninvestigations and studies, surveys, designs, plans, working drawings,\nspecifications, procedures and other actions incidental thereto and\nclaims arising therefrom.\n  6. "Cost", as applied to any project, shall include the cost of the\nacquisition of all property both real and personal, improved and\nunimproved, the cost of demolishing, removing or relocating any\nbuildings or structures on lands so acquired, including the cost of\nrelocating tenants or other occupants of the buildings or structures on\nsuch land and the cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or\nstructures may be moved or relocated, the cost of all systems,\nfacilities, machinery, apparatus and equipment, financing charges,\ninterest prior to, during and after construction to the extent not paid\nor provided for from revenues or other sources, the cost of\nconstruction, the cost of engineering and architectural surveys, plans\nand specifications, the cost of consultants and legal services, the cost\nof lease, guarantees, credit enhancement or bond insurance, other\nexpenses necessary or incidental to the construction of such project,\nand the financing of the construction thereof, including the amount\nauthorized in the resolution of the authority providing for the issuance\nof bonds to be paid into any reserve or other special fund from the\nproceeds of such bonds and the financing of the placing of any project\nin operation, including reimbursement, to any public corporation, the\nstate, the federal government, or any other person for expenditures,\nthat would be costs of such project had they been made directly by the\nauthority.\n  7. "County" shall mean the county of Albany.\n  8. "Facility" shall include, but not be limited to, properties,\nstructures, appurtenances, utilities, and such other works.\n  9. "Federal government" shall mean the United States of America, and\nany department, board, commission, bureau, division, corporation,\nagency, or instrumentality thereof.\n  10. "Joint service arrangements" shall mean agreements between or\namong the authority and any person, the state, the county, any other\npublic corporation including the advance Albany county alliance, the\nfederal government, any other state or agency or instrumentality\nthereof, relating to property, buildings, structures, facilities,\nservices, rates, classification, divisions, allowances or charges, or\nrules or regulations pertaining thereto.\n  11. "Minority and women-owned business enterprise" or "minority or\nwomen-owned business enterprise" shall mean a minority-owned business\nenterprise and/or a women-owned business enterprise, as such terms are\ndefined by section three hundred ten of the executive law.\n  12. "Municipality" shall mean a county, city, town, village, or school\ndistrict.\n  13. "Person" shall mean any natural person, firm, partnership\nassociation, joint venture, or corporation, exclusive of a public\ncorporation.\n  14. "Personal property" shall mean chattels and other tangible things\nof a moveable or removable nature.\n  15. "Property" shall mean both real and/or personal property.\n  16. "Project" shall mean any property or improvements located within\nthe state of New York and within or outside or partially outside the\ncounty of Albany, including, but not limited to, machinery, equipment,\nand other facilities deemed necessary or desirable in connection\ntherewith, or incidental thereto, whether or not in existence or under\nconstruction upon the effective date of this title, which shall be\nnecessary or suitable for purposes and redevelopment of the college of\nSaint Rose facilities provided, however, the authority shall not use its\nfunds in respect of any part of a project located wholly or partially\noutside the county without the prior consent thereto by the governing\nbody of any other county in which a part or parts of such project is, or\nis to be located.\n  17. "Public corporation" shall mean a county, city, town, village,\nschool district or special district, any public benefit corporation,\nagency or instrumentality of the state or of any municipality, or two or\nmore of any of the foregoing acting jointly.\n  18. "Real property" shall mean lands, structures, franchises and\ninterests in land, airspace, waters, lands under water, riparian rights,\nrights, any fixtures, equipment and articles of personal property\naffixed to or used in connection therewith, and any and all things and\nrights included within such term and includes not only fees simple\nabsolute but also any and all lesser interests including but not limited\nto easements, rights of way, uses, leases, licenses and all other\nincorporeal hereditaments and every estate, interest or right, legal or\nequitable, including terms for years and liens thereon by way of\njudgments, mortgages, or otherwise.\n  19. "Revenues" shall mean all rates, fees, rents, revenues, charges,\nand other income derived by the authority from the operation, leasing,\nsale, or other disposition of the college of Saint Rose related\nfacilities.\n  20. "State" shall mean the state of New York.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>