<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2701"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2701"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2701"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2701/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2701/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2701">
        <num>2701</num>
        <heading>Statement of legislative findings and purposes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2701. Statement of legislative findings and purposes. It is hereby\nfound, determined and declared that there is an immediate need to\ninstitute a comprehensive, coordinated program of economic development\nactivities in the three county area comprised of the counties of\nJefferson, Lewis and St. Lawrence which surround the United States Army\nbase at Fort Drum in order to provide the region with the capability to\neffectively plan and develop the infrastructure needs of the region\nrequired by the population increase forecast due to the expansion of the\nUnited States Army facilities at Fort Drum. It is further declared to be\ndesirable to create a regional development authority of the north county\nto provide the region with the capability to effectively and efficiently\ncommunicate with the United States Army to optimize the economic and\nsocial impact on the region of the Army's plans to locate the 10th\nMountain Division at Fort Drum. It is further found and declared that\nsuch needs are a matter of essential state concern and that such\nauthority is necessary to provide for the health, safety and welfare of\nthe people of the participating counties and the state. The authority\nshall carry out its purposes and responsibilities directly and through\nagreements with state and local entities, authorities and the United\nStates Department of the Army. It is further declared that the authority\nshall be created as a public benefit corporation and that the corporate\nprograms and powers conferred under this title and the expenditures of\npublic moneys pursuant thereto are in furtherance of a valid public\ninterest and public purpose.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>