<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2705"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2705"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2705"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2705">
        <num>2705</num>
        <heading>Special powers with regard to planning</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2705. Special powers with regard to planning. The authority shall\nprepare or cause to be prepared a report on the impact of the expansion\nof the Fort Drum Military Reservation on existing projects and community\nfacilities within the participating counties. Based upon the findings of\nsuch report, the authority shall prepare or cause to be prepared a plan\nfor the development or construction of projects, including projects\ndefined in title one of article eighteen-A of the general municipal law\nwhich the authority intends to finance or assist in the financing of,\nand community facilities necessary to meet the needs of individuals,\nbusiness enterprises, and governmental facilities, including military\nfacilities within the participating counties. In formulating such plan\nor plans, the authority shall consult and cooperate with the planning\nauthorities in the area of its operations. The authority may request and\nuse existing studies, plans, surveys, data and other materials completed\nby or under development by any state agency or municipality. The\nauthority shall file copies of such plan with the common council of the\ncity of Watertown and the county legislatures or board of supervisors of\nthe participating counties and the governing body of any municipality\nwithin the participating counties affected by such plan and any\nauthorities or industrial development agencies within the participating\ncounty if such entity is substantially affected by the plan in relation\nto its property or projects. The plan or plans shall contain information\nregarding the facilities that the authority intends to provide or\nproposes be provided by other means and information regarding the\nservices the authority contemplates providing or proposes be provided by\nother means and the estimated costs and the proposed method of\nfinancing. During sixty days after the filing of any plan, said plan\nshall be available for public inspection at the office or offices of the\nauthority and at such other places in the areas affected, within the\nparticipating counties, as the authority may designate. Not earlier than\nthirty days after the filing of said plan, a public hearing on said plan\nshall be held by the authority. Notice of such a hearing shall be given\nto the legislative bodies and affected entities aforesaid by publication\nonce a week for two weeks prior to the said hearing at the time and\nplace fixed by the authority in newspapers of general circulation within\nthe areas affected, to be selected by the authority. The last\npublication date shall not be less than five days before said hearing.\nAny amendments that the authority may adopt to the plan shall be adopted\nonly after complying with the filing notice and hearing requirements\nprovided for in this section. Within thirty days following the adoption\nof any plan or amendments, the authority shall provide a copy of such\nplan or amendments of such hearing to the legislative bodies and\naffected entities as aforesaid.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>