<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2753"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2753"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2753"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2753/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2753/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2753/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2753/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2753">
        <num>2753</num>
        <heading>Monroe county airport authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2753. Monroe county airport authority. 1. There is hereby created\nthe Monroe county airport authority. The authority shall be a body\ncorporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation. The\nauthority shall consist of seven members appointed by the county\nexecutive, provided that two of such members shall be appointed upon the\nwritten recommendation of the president of the county legislature and\none of such members shall be appointed upon the written recommendation\nof the minority leader of the county legislature. No more than five\nmembers may be registered members of the same political party. All\nappointments by the county executive shall be confirmed by a majority\nvote of the county legislature. The county executive shall designate the\nchairperson of the authority who shall serve at the pleasure of the\ncounty executive. The member initially appointed upon the written\nrecommendation of the minority leader of the county legislature shall\nserve for a term ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nninety-one. Of the members initially appointed upon the written\nrecommendation of the president of the county legislature, one shall\nserve for a term ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nninety-two; and one shall serve for a term ending December thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-three. Of the remaining members initially\nappointed by the county executive other than the chairperson, one shall\nserve for a term ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nninety-one; one shall serve for a term ending December thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-two; and one shall serve for a term ending\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-three. Thereafter each\nmember, other than the chairperson, shall serve a term of four years.\n  2. All members shall continue to hold office until their successors\nare appointed and qualify. Vacancies shall be filled in the manner\nprovided for original appointment. Vacancies, occurring otherwise than\nby expiration of term of office, shall be filled for the unexpired\nterms.  Members may be removed from office for the same reasons and in\nthe same manner as may be provided by law for the removal of officers of\nthe county. The members of the authority shall receive no compensation\nfor their services but shall be reimbursed for all their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in connection with the carrying out of the\npurposes of this title. The powers of the authority shall be vested in\nand be exercised by the members of the authority at a meeting duly\ncalled and held and a majority of directors shall constitute a quorum.\nNo action shall be taken except pursuant to the favorable vote of at\nleast a majority of directors. The members of the authority may delegate\nto one or more of its members, officers, agents or employees such powers\nand duties as it may deem proper.\n  3. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, no officer, member or\nemployee of the state or of any public corporation shall forfeit his or\nher office or employment by reason of his or her acceptance of\nappointment as a member, officer or employee of the authority, nor shall\nservice as such member, officer or employee be deemed incompatible or in\nconflict with such office, membership or employment.\n  4. The authority shall continue for a term of one year after all its\nbonds have been fully paid and discharged. Upon termination of the\nexistence of the authority, all of its rights and property shall pass to\nand be vested in the county.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>