<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2779"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2779"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2779"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2779/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2779/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2779/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2779/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2779">
        <num>2779</num>
        <heading>Albany county airport authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2779__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>There is hereby\ncreated the Albany county airport authority. The authority shall be a\nbody corporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation.\nThe authority shall consist of seven members who shall be residents of\nAlbany county. The members shall be appointed in the following manner:\nthree shall be appointed by the county executive and four shall be\nappointed by the majority leader of the county legislature. All\nappointments must be confirmed by the county legislature within thirty\ndays of the appointment. No more than four members may be enrolled\nmembers of the same political party. Of the members initially appointed\nby the county executive two each shall serve for a term ending December\nthirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-six and one shall serve for a term\nending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-seven. Of the\nmembers initially appointed by the majority leader of the county\nlegislature, one shall serve for a term ending December thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-five; two each shall serve for a term ending\nDecember thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-six and one shall serve\nfor a term ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred ninety-seven.\nEach member shall serve a term of four years. The majority leader and\ncounty executive shall jointly designate one of the seven members to\nserve as the chairperson of the authority. The authority may provide for\nsuch officers as may be determined necessary and the same need not be\nmembers of the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2779__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2779__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this\nsubdivision the majority leader and county executive shall jointly\nsubmit to the county legislature the initial seven members of the\nauthority. Within thirty days, the county legislature must approve or\ndisapprove the appointment of the entire group of nominees but may not\nreject an individual member nor may it modify in any way the proposed\ngroup of members.\n  2. All members shall continue to hold office until their successors\nare appointed and qualify. Except as otherwise provided in subdivision\nthree of this section, vacancies shall be filled in the manner provided\nfor original appointment. Vacancies, occurring otherwise than by\nexpiration of term of office, shall be filled for the unexpired terms.\nMembers may be removed from office for the same reasons and in the same\nmanner as may be provided by law for the removal of officers of the\ncounty. The members of the authority shall receive no compensation for\ntheir services but shall be reimbursed for all their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in connection with the carrying out of the\npurposes of this title. The powers as set forth in the by-laws of the\nauthority shall be established and vested in and be exercised by the\nmembers of the authority at an initial meeting duly called and held and\nfive members shall constitute a quorum. No action shall be taken at the\naforementioned initial meeting or any adjournment thereof except\npursuant to the favorable vote of at least five members of the\nauthority. Any amendment to the aforementioned powers as set forth in\nthe by-laws shall only become effective upon the favorable vote of at\nleast five members of the authority.\n  3. The authority shall have a regional advisory board consisting of\nnot less than six non-voting members. The membership shall include, but\nnot be limited to, the chairperson of the airline affairs committee of\nthe Albany county airport and other members, one of whom shall be\nappointed by the legislative body of t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>