<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2780"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2780"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2780"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2780/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2780/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2780/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2780/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2780">
        <num>2780</num>
        <heading>Advances on behalf of the authority; transfer of property to authority; acquisition of property by county for authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2780. Advances on behalf of the authority; transfer of property to\nauthority; acquisition of property by county for authority.  1. In\naddition to any powers granted to it by law, the county may, from time\nto time, appropriate by resolution sums of money to defray project costs\nor any other costs and expenses of the authority including operating\nexpenses.\n  Subject to the rights of bond holders, the county may determine if the\nmonies so appropriated shall be subject to repayment by the authority to\nthe county and, in such event, the manner and time or times for such\nrepayment.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, any public corporation\nmay, by a majority vote of its governing body and the approval of its\nchief executive officer, give, grant, sell, convey, loan, license the\nuse of or lease to the authority any property or facilities, including\naviation facilities and pollution control facilities, which are useful\nin connection with the exercise by the authority of its powers under\nthis title. Any such gift, grant, sale, conveyance, loan, license or\nlease shall be upon such terms and conditions, and for such term or\nterms of years, subject to the rights of the holders of any bonds, as\nthe authority and such public corporation may agree. Any such gift,\ngrant, sale, conveyance, lease, loan or license shall not be subject to\nreferendum, permissive or mandatory. In the event that any public\ncorporation gives, grants, sells, conveys, loans, licenses or leases any\naviation facilities or pollution control facilities to the authority,\nsuch public corporation may contract with the authority to lease,\nborrow, license, operate, maintain, manage and provide services for such\nfacilities upon such terms and conditions and for such term or terms of\nyears, subject to the rights of holders of bonds, as the authority and\nsuch public corporation may agree. The authority, in furtherance of any\npurchase, conveyance or lease of any property or facility from any\npublic corporation, may assume the primary responsibility for the\npayment of the principal and interest on any bonds or notes issued by\nsuch public corporation for such property or facility. For purposes of\nsection 136.00 of the local finance law, any agreement by the authority\nto assume the primary responsibility for the payment of the principal\nand interest on any bonds or notes issued by any such public corporation\nshall, so long as such agreement shall continue to be honored by the\nauthority, cause such bonds or notes to be deemed to have been refunded\nand any such public corporation may deduct from its gross indebtedness\nany outstanding indebtedness contracted for such property or facility to\nbe acquired by the authority.\n  3. The county may acquire by purchase, grant, lease, gift or\ncondemnation pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law real property\nin the name of the county for any corporate purpose of the authority.\n  4. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, general, special\nor local, real property acquired by the authority or the county from the\nstate may be used for any corporate purpose of the authority provided,\nhowever, no non-hazardous solid waste, toxic, or hazardous waste site,\ncenter, consolidated collection or transfer area, shall be located or\nmaintained at the airport, or on lands adjacent to the airport that are\nused in support of airport operations as contained in any present or\nfuture airport layout plan approved by the New York state department of\ntransportation or the federal aviation administration and no\nnon-hazardous solid waste, toxic, or hazardous waste site, center,\nconsolidated collection or transfer area, shall be located or maintained\non any other lands made available by the county in support of airport\noperations by way of any agreement between the county and the airport\noperator. The storage of materials, which by federal definition may be\nclassified as hazardous materials, but are acquired by the airport\noperator, its agent, or assignee, solely in support of airport\noperations or airport facility maintenance shall be exempt from the\nprovisions of this subdivision. The inventory, storage and use of such\nmaterials shall be in accordance with all applicable federal and state\nregulations.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>