<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2788"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2788"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2788"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2788/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2788/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2788/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2788/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2788">
        <num>2788</num>
        <heading>Monies of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2788. Monies of the authority. All monies of the authority from\nwhatever source derived shall be paid to the treasurer of the authority\nand shall be deposited forthwith in a bank or banks designated by the\nauthority. The monies in such accounts shall be paid out on check of the\ntreasurer upon requisition by such person or persons as the authority\nmay authorize to make such requisitions. All deposits of such monies\nshall be secured by obligations of the United States or of the state or\nof any municipality of a market value equal at all times to the amount\non deposit and all banks and trust companies are authorized to give such\nsecurity for such deposits. To the extent practicable, consistent with\nthe cash requirements of the authority, all such monies shall be\ndeposited in interest bearing accounts. The authority shall have power,\nnotwithstanding the provisions of this section, to contract with the\nholders of any bonds as to the custody, collection, security, investment\nand payment of any monies of the authority or any monies held in trust\nor otherwise for the payment of bonds or any way to secure bonds, and\ncarry out any such contract notwithstanding that such contract may be\ninconsistent with the provisions of this section. Monies held in trust\nor otherwise for the payment of bonds or in any way to secure bonds and\ndeposits of such monies may be secured in the same manner as monies of\nthe authority and all banks and trust companies are authorized to give\nsuch security for such deposits. Any monies of the authority not\nrequired for immediate use or disbursement may, at the discretion of the\nauthority, be invested in those obligations specified pursuant to the\nprovision of section ninety-eight-a of the state finance law. Subject to\nthe provisions of any contract with bond holders and with the approval\nof the state comptroller, the authority shall prescribe a system of\naccounts.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>