<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2795"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2795"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2795"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2795/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2795/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2795/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2795/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2795">
        <num>2795</num>
        <heading>Code of ethics</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2795. Code of ethics. 1. Definition. As used in this section the\nterm "authority employee" shall mean any member, officer or employee of\nthe authority.\n  2. Rule with respect to conflicts of interest. No authority employee\nshould have any interest, financial or otherwise, direct or indirect, or\nengage in any business or transaction or professional activity or incur\nany obligation of any nature, which is in substantial conflict with the\nproper discharge of his or her duties in the public interest.\n  3. Standards.\n  a. No authority employee should accept other employment which will\nimpair his or her independence of judgment in the exercise of his or her\nofficial duties.\n  b. No authority employee should accept employment or engage in any\nbusiness or professional activity which will require the employee to\ndisclose confidential information which he or she has gained by reason\nof his or her official position or authority.\n  c. No authority employee should disclose confidential information\nacquired by the employee in the course of his or her official duties nor\nuse such information to further his or her personal interests.\n  d. No authority employee should use or attempt to use his or her\nofficial position to secure unwarranted privileges or exemptions for\nhimself or herself or others.\n  e. No authority employee should engage in any transaction as\nrepresentative or agent of the authority with any business entity in\nwhich he or she has a direct or indirect financial interest that might\nreasonably tend to conflict with the proper discharge of his or her\nofficial duties.\n  f. An authority employee should not by his or her conduct give\nreasonable basis for the impression that any person can improperly\ninfluence such employee or unduly enjoy his or her favor in the\nperformance of his or her official duties, or that he or she is affected\nby the kinship, rank, position or influence of any party or person.\n  g. An authority employee should abstain from making personal\ninvestments in enterprises which he or she has reason to believe may be\ndirectly involved in decisions to be made by the employee or which will\notherwise create substantial conflict between his or her duty in the\npublic interest and his or her private interest.\n  h. An authority employee should endeavor to pursue a course of conduct\nwhich will not raise suspicion among the public that he or she is likely\nto be engaged in acts that are in violation of his or her trust.\n  i. No authority employee employed on a full-time basis nor any firm or\nassociation of which such an employee is a member nor corporation a\nsubstantial portion of the stock of which is owned or controlled\ndirectly or indirectly by such employee, should sell goods or services\nto any person, firm, corporation or association which is licensed or\nwhose rates are fixed by the authority in which such employee serves or\nis employed.\n  j. If any authority employee shall have a financial interest, direct\nor indirect, having a value of ten thousand dollars or more in any\nactivity which is subject to the jurisdiction of a regulatory agency, he\nor she should file with the secretary of state a written statement that\nhe or she has such a financial interest in such activity which statement\nshall be open to public inspection.\n  4. Violations. In addition to any penalty contained in any other\nprovision of law any such authority employee who shall knowingly and\nintentionally violate any of the provisions of this section may be\nfined, suspended or removed from office or employment.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>