<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-GGGG"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-GGGG"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-GGGG"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-GGGG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-GGGG/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-GGGG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-GGGG/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_GGGG">
        <num>2799-GGGG</num>
        <heading>Equal employment opportunities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-gggg. Equal employment opportunities. 1. The corporation shall\nnot discriminate against employees or applicants for employment because\nof race, creed, color, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, age,\ndisability or marital status, and will undertake or continue programs of\naffirmative action to ensure that minority group persons and women are\nafforded equal employment opportunity without discrimination. Such\naction shall be taken with reference, but not be limited, to\nrecruitment, employment, job assignment, promotion, upgrading, demotion,\ntransfer, layoff, termination, rate of pay or other forms of\ncompensation, and selections for training or retraining, including\napprenticeship and on-the-job training.\n  2. The corporation shall request each employment agency, labor union,\nor authorized representative of workers with which it has a collective\nbargaining or other agreement or understanding, to furnish a written\nstatement that such employment agency, labor union or representative\nshall not discriminate because of race, creed, color, national origin,\nsex, sexual orientation, age, disability or marital status and that such\nunion or representative will cooperate in the implementation of the\ncorporation's obligations hereunder.\n  3. The corporation shall state, in all solicitations or advertisements\nfor employees placed by or on behalf of the corporation, that all\nqualified applicants will be afforded equal employment opportunity\nwithout discrimination because of race, creed, color, national origin,\nsex, sexual orientation, age, disability or marital status.\n  4. The corporation shall seek meaningful participation by minority\nbusiness enterprises in the programs of the corporation and shall\nactively and affirmatively promote and assist their participation in the\ncorporation's programs, so as to facilitate the award of a fair share of\ncontracts to such enterprises. For purposes hereof, "minority business\nenterprise" shall mean any business enterprise which is at least\nfifty-one per centum owned by, or in the case of publicly owned\nbusiness, at least fifty-one per centum of the stock of which is owned\nby, citizens or permanent resident noncitizens who are Black, Hispanic,\nAsian, American Indian or women, and such ownership interest is real,\nsubstantial and continuing.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>