<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-KKKK"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-KKKK"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-KKKK"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-KKKK/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-KKKK/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-KKKK/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-KKKK/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_KKKK">
        <num>2799-KKKK</num>
        <heading>Open space development prohibited</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-kkkk. Open space development prohibited. Notwithstanding any\nother provision of this title, or any other law to the contrary, on or\nafter the effective date of this section, no further development or\nconstruction for other than park purposes shall be permitted on any real\nproperty which is identified as open space areas in the general\ndevelopment plan as amended May tenth, nineteen hundred ninety, and as\nsubsequently amended, and approved by the board of estimate of the city\nof New York on August seventeenth, nineteen hundred ninety and referred\nto in the lease defined in subdivision six of section twenty-seven\nhundred ninety-nine-bbbb of this title, and on such real property shall\nremain open space areas for the duration of the lease unless such\ndevelopment or construction includes the reconstruction, restoration,\nrehabilitation or preservation of the historic landmarks located in such\nopen space areas and furthers the use of the areas surrounding the\nhistoric landmarks as open space areas. Open space areas, as used in\nthis section shall be limited to Lighthouse Park, Octagon Park,\nBlackwell Park, and South Point Park.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>