<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-CCCC"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-CCCC"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-CCCC"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-CCCC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-CCCC/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-CCCC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-CCCC/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_CCCC">
        <num>2799-CCCC</num>
        <heading>Establishment of the corporation; organization of the board</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-cccc. Establishment of the corporation; organization of the\nboard. 1. To effectuate the purposes and provisions of this title, there\nis hereby created the "Roosevelt Island operating corporation", which\nshall be a body corporate and politic constituting a public benefit\ncorporation and a political subdivision of the state of New York.\n  2. The board of directors of the corporation shall be composed of nine\nmembers. One member shall be the commissioner, who shall serve as the\nchair; one member shall be the director of the budget; and seven public\nmembers shall be appointed by the governor with the advice and consent\nof the senate. Of the seven public members, two members, one of whom\nshall be a resident of Roosevelt Island, shall be appointed upon the\nrecommendation of the mayor of the city; and four additional members\nshall be residents of Roosevelt Island. Each member shall serve for a\nterm of four years and until his or her successor shall have been\nappointed and shall have qualified, except that the commissioner and the\ndirector of the budget shall serve so long as they continue to hold\ntheir respective offices. Any action taken by the directors of the\ncorporation shall be taken by majority vote of the directors then in\noffice. The elected public officials who represent Roosevelt Island\nshall be representatives to the board of directors of the corporation\nentitled to receive notice of and attend all meetings of such board but\nshall not be entitled to vote. Failure to give such notice shall not\naffect the validity of any action taken at a meeting of such board.\n  3. The governor may fill any vacancy which occurs on the board of\ndirectors of the corporation in a manner consistent with the original\nappointment. Any member of the corporation may be removed by the\ngovernor for cause, but not without an opportunity to be heard, in\nperson or by counsel, in his or her defense, upon not less than ten\ndays' written notice.\n  4. The commissioner and the director of the budget may each designate\nan officer or employee of his or her respective division to represent\nsuch member at meetings of the corporation. Such designation shall be by\nwritten notice filed with the chair or the secretary of the corporation\nby the member making the designation, and may be revoked at any time by\nsimilar notice. Any representative so designated shall have the power to\nattend and to vote at any meeting of the corporation from which the\nmember making the designation is absent with the same force and effect\nas if the member making the designation were present and voting. No such\ndesignation shall limit the right of the member making the designation\nto attend and vote in person at any meeting of the corporation.\n  5. A member of the corporation who is not an officer or employee of\nthe state or the city shall not receive a salary or other compensation,\nbut shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses\nincurred in the performance of official duties as a member. A member of\nthe corporation who is not an officer or employee of the state or the\ncity may engage in private employment, or in a profession or business,\nunless otherwise prohibited by law from doing so. Notwithstanding any\nother provision of law, general, special, or local, no officer or\nemployee of the state or any civil division thereof shall be deemed to\nhave forfeited, or shall forfeit such office of employment because of\nacceptance of membership in the corporation, or by virtue of being an\nofficer, employee or agent thereof.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>