<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-EEEE"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-EEEE"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-EEEE"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-EEEE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-EEEE/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-EEEE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-EEEE/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_EEEE">
        <num>2799-EEEE</num>
        <heading>Rules and regulations; approval of development plan amendments; applicability of local laws</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-eeee. Rules and regulations; approval of development plan\namendments; applicability of local laws. 1. The corporation shall\npromulgate such rules and regulations as it shall deem appropriate to\nprovide an opportunity for residents of Roosevelt Island to comment upon\nany major amendment of the development plan for Roosevelt Island\nreferred to in the lease at a public hearing held prior to its adoption\nby the corporation.\n  2. Any amendment of the development plan for Roosevelt Island referred\nto in the lease shall be subject to the review and approval of the\ndirector of the budget, and the corporation shall not enter into any\nagreement for the design or construction of any improvement provided for\nin any such amendment prior to such approval.\n  3. The requirements of all local laws, ordinances, codes, charters or\nregulations shall be applicable to the construction, alteration or\nimprovement of any building or structure on Roosevelt Island, provided\nthat the corporation may, in lieu of such compliance, determine that the\nrequirements of the New York state uniform fire prevention and building\ncode, formulated by the state fire prevention and building code council\npursuant to article eighteen of the executive law, shall be applicable\nto such work. In the event of such compliance with the New York state\nuniform fire prevention and building code, the city shall have no power\nto modify any drawings, plans or specifications for such work or for the\nplumbing, heating, lighting or other mechanical branches thereof, or to\nrequire that any person, firm or corporation employed on any such work\nperform the same except as provided by such plans and specifications or\nobtain any additional authority, approval, permit or certificate from\nthe city in connection therewith.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>