<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-FFFF"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-FFFF"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-FFFF"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-FFFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-FFFF/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-FFFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-FFFF/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_FFFF">
        <num>2799-FFFF</num>
        <heading>Powers and duties of urban development corporation; lease and tramway franchise</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2799_FFFF__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the prompt\npayment directly to the urban development corporation of all sums from\ntime to time due from lessees under the development subleases and all\nsums received by the corporation from the city in connection with the\ntermination of the lease, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2799_FFFF__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the amending or supplementing of\nthe development subleases to the extent, if any, necessary to protect\nthe rights of the holders of any mortgages on the leasehold interests\ncreated thereunder. Nothing in this title shall constitute or authorize\nan assignment by the urban development corporation, or any subsidiary\nthereof, of any mortgage or security interest held by the urban\ndevelopment corporation, or any such subsidiary, on any real or personal\nproperty or interest therein on Roosevelt Island or any rights or\nobligations of the urban development corporation, or any such\nsubsidiary, arising under any such mortgage or security agreement,\nrelieve the urban development corporation of any of its obligations\nunder any bonds heretofore issued by the urban development corporation,\nor otherwise affect the interests of the holders of any such bonds.\n  3. All revenues, other than state appropriations, derived from the\ncontracts, leases, agreements or instruments assigned to or assumed by\nthe corporation pursuant to subdivision two of this section shall be\napplied first to the payment of those obligations assigned to or assumed\nby the corporation.\n  4. The urban development corporation and the corporation are hereby\nauthorized to enter into such agreements with the city as the\ncorporation shall determine to be appropriate to amend, reform or\nsupplement the lease, including the development plan referred to\ntherein, and the tramway franchise in order to carry out the purposes of\nthis title. The provisions of any general, special or local law\nnotwithstanding, the city is hereby authorized to enter into any such\nagreements with the corporation and the urban development corporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>