<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DD"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DD"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-DD"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_DD">
        <num>2799-DD</num>
        <heading>Administration of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-dd. Administration of the authority. 1. The authority shall be\nadministered by five directors, consisting of the director of management\nand budget, the commissioner of finance of the city, the commissioner of\nthe department of design and construction of the city, the comptroller\nand the speaker of the council.\n  2. The director of management and budget shall serve as chairperson of\nthe authority. The chairperson or his or her alternate shall preside\nover all meetings of the directors and shall have such other duties as\nmay be fixed by the directors.\n  3. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, no officer, member or\nemployee of the state of New York, any city, county, town or village,\nany governmental entity operating any public school or college, any\nschool district or any other public agency or instrumentality which\nexercises governmental powers under the laws of the state, shall forfeit\nhis or her office or employment by reason of his or her acceptance of\nappointment as a director, officer or employee of the authority, nor\nshall service as such director, officer or employee of the authority be\ndeemed incompatible or in conflict with such office or employment.\n  4. Three directors shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of\nany business or the exercise of any power of the authority. No action\nshall be taken by the authority except pursuant to a favorable vote of\nat least three directors present at a meeting at which such action is\ntaken. Any director may, by written instrument, filed with and approved\nas to form by the authority, designate an alternate or alternates to\nperform, in the absence of such director, his or her duties unde this\ntitle. The term "director" as used in this title shall include such\nalternates, except that no alternate may designate an alternate pursuant\nto this subdivision. The designation of such alternates shall be deemed\ntemporary only and shall not affect the civil service or retirement\nrights of any persons so designated.\n  5. The authority shall appoint a treasurer and may appoint officers\nand agents as it may require and prescribe their duties.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>