<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DDD"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DDD"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-12-30" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-DDD"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DDD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DDD/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DDD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-DDD/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_DDD">
        <num>2799-DDD</num>
        <heading>Syracuse regional airport authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-ddd. Syracuse regional airport authority. 1. There is hereby\ncreated the Syracuse regional airport authority. The authority shall be\na body corporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation.\nThe authority shall consist of eleven members who shall be appointed as\nfollows: seven shall be appointed by the mayor of the city of Syracuse,\none shall be appointed by the county executive of Onondaga county, one\nshall be appointed by the town board of the town of Dewitt, one shall be\nappointed by the board of education of the East Syracuse Minoa Central\nSchool District, and one shall be appointed for a period of one year,\nalternately, by the board of education of the North Syracuse Central\nSchool District and the town board of the town of Salina, Cicero or\nClay. The member initially appointed by the county executive and two of\nthe members initially appointed by the mayor shall serve for a term\nending December thirty-first, two thousand fourteen. Two of the members\ninitially appointed by the mayor shall serve for a term ending December\nthirty-first, two thousand fifteen. Three members initially appointed by\nthe mayor, the member appointed by the town board of the town of Dewitt,\nand the member appointed by the board of education of the East Syracuse\nMinoa Central School District, shall serve for a term ending December\nthirty-first, two thousand sixteen. The first member appointed by the\ntown board of the town of Salina, Cicero or Clay, or by the board of\neducation of the North Syracuse Central School District, shall be\nappointed by the town board of the town of Cicero and shall serve for a\nterm ending December thirty-first, two thousand thirteen. Following the\nexpiration of such member's two year term, the subsequently appointed\nmember shall be appointed by the town board of the town of Salina.\nFollowing the expiration of such member's two year term, the\nsubsequently appointed member shall be appointed by the town board of\nthe town of Clay. Following the expiration of such member's two year\nterm, the subsequently appointed member shall be appointed by the board\nof education of the North Syracuse Central School District. Thereafter,\neach subsequent member shall be appointed alternately by each town or\nthe board of education in the same order as the initial appointments.\nThe mayor shall designate one of the eleven members to serve as\nchairperson of the authority. With the exception of the member appointed\nby the board of education of the North Syracuse Central School District\nor by the town board of the town of Salina, Cicero or Clay, who shall\nserve a two year term, and those initial appointees whose terms are\nthree years or less, each member shall serve a term of four years.\n  2. All members shall continue to hold office until their successors\nare appointed and qualify. Provided that upon a new mayor of the city\ntaking office, the incoming mayor may replace the city appointee with\nthe shortest remaining term with a new appointee. Vacancies shall be\nfilled in the manner provided for original appointment. Vacancies,\noccurring otherwise than by expiration of term of office, shall be\nfilled for the unexpired terms. Members may be removed from office for\nthe same reasons and in the same manner as may be provided by section\ntwenty-eight hundred twenty-seven of this chapter. The members of the\nauthority shall receive no compensation for their services but shall be\nreimbursed for all their actual and necessary expenses incurred in\nconnection with the carrying out of the purposes of this title. The\npowers of the authority shall be vested in and be exercised by the\nmembers of the authority at a meeting duly called and held and a\nmajority of directors shall constitute a quorum. No action shall be\ntaken except pursuant to the favorable vote of at least a majority of\nmembers. The members of the authority may delegate to one or more of its\nmembers, officers, agents or employees such powers and duties as it may\ndeem proper.\n  3. The authority shall have a regional advisory board consisting of\neight non-voting members. The membership shall include one member\nappointed by the county executive of Oneida county, one member each\nappointed by the chairpersons of the county legislatures of Onondaga,\nOswego, Cortland, Cayuga, and Jefferson counties, one member appointed\nby the chairperson of the board of supervisors of Madison county, and\none member appointed by the Common Council of the City of Syracuse.\nMembers will be appointed for two year terms and may be reappointed.\n  4. Appointments to the authority and to the non-voting advisory board\nshall be geographically diverse and include representatives from\nbusiness, finance, and labor.\n  5. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, no officer, member or\nemployee of the state or of any public corporation shall forfeit his or\nher office or employment by reason of his or her acceptance of\nappointment as a member, officer or employee of the authority, nor shall\nservice as such member, officer or employee be deemed incompatible or in\nconflict with such office, membership or employment.\n  6. All members of the authority will be required to comply with the\nprovisions of this chapter and to complete all disclosure forms required\nby this chapter.\n  7. The authority shall continue for a term of one year after all its\nbonds have been fully paid and discharged. Upon termination of the\nexistence of the authority, all of its rights and property shall pass to\nand be vested in the city.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>