<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-MM"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-MM"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-MM"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-MM/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-MM/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-MM/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-MM/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_MM">
        <num>2799-MM</num>
        <heading>Actions against the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2799_MM__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it shall appear by and as an\nallegation in the complaint or moving papers that a notice of claim\nshall have been made and served upon the authority, within the time\nlimit prescribed by and in compliance with section fifty-e of the\ngeneral municipal law,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2799_MM__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it shall appear by and as an allegation in\nthe complaint or moving papers that at least thirty days have elapsed\nsince the service of such notice and that adjustment or payment thereof\nhas been neglected or refused, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2799_MM__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the action or proceeding shall be\ncommenced within one year after the happening of the event upon which\nthe claim is based. An action against the authority for wrongful death\nshall be commenced in accordance with the notice of claim and time\nlimitation provisions of title eleven of article nine of this chapter.\n  2.  Wherever a notice of claim is served upon the authority, it shall\nhave the right to demand an examination of the claimant relative to the\noccurrence and extent of the injuries or damages for which claim is\nmade, in accordance with the provisions of section fifty-h of the\ngeneral municipal law.\n  3.  The authority may require any person presenting for settlement an\naccount or claim for any cause whatever against the authority to be\nsworn before a director, counsel or an attorney, officer or employee\nthereof designated for such purpose, concerning such account or claim\nand when so sworn, to answer orally as to any facts relative to such\naccount or claim.  The authority shall have power to settle or adjust\nany claims in favor of or against the authority.\n  4.  The rate of interest to be paid by the authority upon any judgment\nfor which it is liable, other than a judgment on bonds, shall not exceed\nthe rate of interest on judgments and accrued claims against municipal\nauthorities as provided in the general municipal law.  Interest on\npayments of principal or interest on any bonds in default shall accrue\nat the rate specified in the general municipal law until paid or\notherwise satisfied.\n  5.  The venue of every action, suit or special proceeding brought\nagainst the authority shall be laid in the county of New York.\n  6. Neither any director of the authority nor any officer, employee, or\nagent of the authority, while acting within the scope of his or her\nauthority, shall be subject to any liability resulting from exercising\nor carrying out of any of the powers expressly given in this title. A\ndirector, officer or employee of th...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>