<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-PP"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-PP"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-PP"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-PP/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-PP/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-PP/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-PP/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_PP">
        <num>2799-PP</num>
        <heading>Assistance to the authority; employees of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-pp. Assistance to the authority; employees of the authority.\n1. With the consent of any public corporation, the authority may use\nagents, employees and facilities thereof, paying to such public\ncorporation its agreed proportion of the compensation or costs.\n  2. Officers and employees of city agencies may be transferred to the\nauthority and officers and employees of the authority may be transferred\nto appropriate city agencies without examination and without loss of any\ncivil service or retirement status or rights. Any officer or employee of\nthe authority who heretofore acquired or shall hereafter acquire such\nposition status by transfer and who at the time of such transfer was a\nmember of the New York city employees' retirement system shall continue\nto be a member of such system as long as he or she continues in such\nservice, and shall continue to have all the rights, privileges and\nobligations of membership in such system. Employment by the authority\nshall constitute city-service for the purposes of chapter one of title\nthirteen of the administrative code of the city of New York. Transfers\nshall be in accordance with section seventy of the civil service law and\nthe rules of the civil service commission of the city. No such transfer\nshall be made except with the approval of the head of the agency\ninvolved and the chairperson of the authority and in compliance with\napplicable collective bargaining agreements and the rules and\nregulations of the civil service commission of the city.\n  3. A transferred employee shall remain in the same collective\nbargaining unit as was the case prior to his or her transfer, consistent\nwith the provisions of article fourteen of the civil service law and the\ncollective bargaining law of the city.\n  4. Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the rights of\nemployees pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement.\n  5. Employees newly appointed by the authority to a same or similar\nposition or title as those represented by public employee organizations\nsubject to the New York city collective bargaining law shall be placed\nin the same collective bargaining unit as such same or similar position\nor title and shall be represented by the duly certified employee\norganization representing that unit.\n  6. The commissioner of labor relations of the city shall be the\nauthority's representative for purposes of the New York city collective\nbargaining law.\n  7. Employees of the authority shall be subject to chapter sixty-eight\nof the New York city charter, as amended from time to time.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>