<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-NNNN"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-NNNN"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-NNNN"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-NNNN/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-NNNN/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-NNNN/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-NNNN/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_NNNN">
        <num>2799-NNNN</num>
        <heading>Operation of motor vehicles</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-nnnn. Operation of motor vehicles. In addition to any other\npower conferred upon it by this title, the corporation is hereby\nauthorized to prescribe rules and regulations governing the operation,\nincluding the parking, standing or stopping of vehicles on Roosevelt\nIsland; provided however, that such rules and regulations shall not\nrestrict access to any city facilities situated on Roosevelt Island nor\nunreasonably restrict parking by city of New York employees, their\nvisitors and invitees. The violation of such rules or regulations shall\nbe an offense punishable upon a first conviction thereof by a fine of\nnot more than fifty dollars, upon a second within a period of eighteen\nmonths by a fine of not more than one hundred fifty dollars, and upon a\nthird or subsequent conviction thereof within a period of eighteen\nmonths by a fine of not more than one hundred fifty dollars. For\npurposes of enforcement and administration of such rules and\nregulations, including but not limited to conferring jurisdiction with\nrespect thereto upon the applicable courts and administrative tribunals,\nall provisions of law relating to, and rules or regulations of, the New\nYork city department of transportation not inconsistent with this title\nshall be applicable.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>