<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-QQQQ"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-QQQQ"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2799-QQQQ"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-QQQQ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-QQQQ/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-QQQQ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2799-QQQQ/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2799_QQQQ">
        <num>2799-QQQQ</num>
        <heading>Transfer of funds</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2799-qqqq. Transfer of funds. 1. Notwithstanding the provisions of\nany general or special law, the director of the budget is authorized to\ntransfer to the corporation from funds appropriated to the division for\nthe fiscal year beginning April first, nineteen hundred eighty-four, the\namount he or she determines necessary to carry out the provisions of\nthis title, including providing for Roosevelt Island operations, capital\nimprovement program and any other appropriate management expenses.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of any general or special law, no\npart of such appropriations shall be available for the purposes\ndesignated until a certificate of approval of availability shall have\nbeen issued by the director of the budget and a copy of such certificate\nis filed with the state comptroller, the chair of the senate finance\ncommittee and the chair of the assembly ways and means committee. Such\ncertificate may be amended from time to time, subject to the approval of\nthe director of the budget, and a copy of each such amendment shall be\nfiled with the state comptroller, the chair of the senate finance\ncommittee and the chair of the assembly ways and means committee.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>