<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2807"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2807"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2807"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2807/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2807/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2807">
        <num>2807</num>
        <heading>Reporting for searchable state subsidy and aggregate economic development benefits database</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2807. Reporting for searchable state subsidy and aggregate economic\ndevelopment benefits database. Notwithstanding any other provision of\nlaw to the contrary, every state authority shall submit to the urban\ndevelopment corporation, and update quarterly, in the form and manner\nprescribed by the urban development corporation, any and all data and\ninformation as necessary for developing, updating, and maintaining the\ndatabase established in section fifty-eight of section one of chapter\none hundred seventy-four of the laws of nineteen hundred sixty-eight,\nconstituting the New York state urban development corporation act,\nregarding economic development benefits, as such term is defined in such\nsection, awarded by such state authority. A state authority may request\nand shall receive any data from an individual, business, limited\nliability corporation or any other entity that has applied for and\nreceived approval for, or is the beneficiary of, any such economic\ndevelopment benefits, as is necessary and required to comply with this\nsection.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>