<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2824-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2824-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2824-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2824-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2824-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2824-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2824-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2824_A">
        <num>2824-A</num>
        <heading>Mission statement and measurement report</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2824-a. Mission statement and measurement report. Each state\nauthority shall submit to the authorities budget office on or before\nMarch thirty-first, two thousand ten, and each local authority shall\nsubmit to the authorities budget office on or before March thirty-first,\ntwo thousand eleven, a proposed authority mission statement and proposed\nmeasurements which the authorities budget office shall post on its\nwebsite. The proposed authority mission statement and proposed\nmeasurements shall have the following components: a brief mission\nstatement expressing the purpose and goals of the authority, a\ndescription of the stakeholders of the authority and their reasonable\nexpectations from the authority, and a list of measurements by which\nperformance of the authority and the achievement of its goals may be\nevaluated. Each authority shall reexamine its mission statement and\nmeasurements on an annual basis, and publish a self-evaluation based on\nthe stated measurements; provided, however, such reexamination may be\nwaived pursuant to a determination by the director of the authorities\nbudget office that such undertaking is unnecessary for an individual\nauthority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>