<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2851"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2851"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2851"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2851/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2851/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2851/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2851/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2851">
        <num>2851</num>
        <heading>Age not to be bar to employment by public authorities</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2851. Age not to be bar to employment by public authorities. No\npublic authority shall hereafter prohibit, prevent, disqualify or\ndiscriminate against any person applying for employment by, such\nauthority, who is physically and mentally qualified, or from competing,\nparticipating or registering for a position, or be penalized in a final\nrating for any position, by reason of his or her age. Any existing rule,\nregulation, penalty or requirement resolution preventing the hiring of\npersons because of age shall be void, except that nothing herein\ncontained, shall prevent any public authority from adopting reasonable\nminimum or maximum age requirements for positions such as police\nofficer, firefighter, guard or other positions which require\nextraordinary physical effort except where age limits for such positions\nare already prescribed by law.\n  Notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary, no person who is\nphysically or mentally qualified may be disqualified from, competing,\nparticipating or registering for a promotional examination or be\npenalized in a final rating or barred from promotion after having passed\nsuch promotion examination by reason of his or her age, by any public\nauthority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>