<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2877-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2877-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-04-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2877-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2877-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2877-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2877-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2877-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2877_A">
        <num>2877-A</num>
        <heading>The New York state buy American salt act</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2877_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, when\nsoliciting a contract for the purchase of rock salt or sodium chloride,\nany public authority may award such contract to the responsible and\nreliable bidder offering to supply rock salt or sodium chloride that is\nmined or hand harvested in the United States, and which offer is within\nten percent of the lowest price or best value offer, rather than to the\nlowest responsible and reliable bidder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2877_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If it has been determined by a court or federal or state agency\nthat any person intentionally:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2877_A__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>affixed a label bearing a "Made in America" inscription, or any\ninscription with the same meaning, to any rock salt, or sodium chloride\nproduct used in projects to which this section applies, sold in or\nshipped to the United States that was not mined or hand harvested in the\nUnited States; or\n  (ii) represented that any rock salt, or sodium chloride product\nprocured in a contract to which this section applies that was not\nproduced in the United States, was produced in the United States; then\nthat person shall be ineligible to receive any contract or subcontract\nwith this state pursuant to the debarment or suspension provisions\nprovided under section one hundred thirty-nine-a of the state finance\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2877_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>This section shall be applied in a manner consistent with the\nstate's obligations under any applicable international agreements\npertaining to government procurement.\n  2. Definitions. For the purposes of this section, the following words\nshall have the following meanings unless specified otherwise:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2877_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Public authority" means a state, local or interstate authority as\nthose terms are defined in section two of this chapter;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2877_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Mined or hand harvested in the United States" means: extracted or\ncollected from land or ponds within the boundary of the United States,\nfrom the initial separation from the earth through the addition of any\nadditives necessary for commercial sale;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2877_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"United States" means the United States of America and includes\nall territory, continental or insular, subject to the jurisdiction of\nthe United States.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>