<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2878-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2878-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2878-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2878-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2878-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2878-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2878-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2878_B">
        <num>2878-B</num>
        <heading>Source separation of wastes</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 2878-b. Source separation of wastes. 1. No later than September\nfirst, nineteen hundred eighty-nine each public authority, corporation\nor commission shall devise and institute a program to source separate\nwaste paper generated within its facilities.\n  Such program shall include marketing arrangements and appropriate\nprocedures to ensure the recovery of discarded paper in a\nnoncontaminated condition. This program may be phased in, utilizing\nthose office facilities most conducive to operation of a source\nseparation program, but shall be fully implemented by July first,\nnineteen hundred ninety.\n  2. No later than July first, nineteen hundred ninety, each public\nauthority, corporation or commission shall devise and institute a\nprogram to source separate all other waste generated within its\nfacilities that is not covered by this section. Such program shall\ninclude marketing arrangements and appropriate procedures to ensure the\nrecovery of waste for which the full avoided costs of proper collection,\ntransportation and disposal of source separated materials are equal to\nor greater than the cost of collection, transportation and sale of said\nmaterial less the amount received from the sale of said material. This\nprogram may be phased in, utilizing those office facilities most\nconducive to operation of a source separation program but shall be fully\nimplemented by July first, nineteen hundred ninety-one.\n  3. A public authority, corporation or commission occupying facilities\nmade available or provided by the office of general services may comply\nwith the provisions of this section by participating in a program\nconducted by the office of general services pursuant to subdivisions\nfour and five of section one hundred seventy-seven of the state finance\nlaw.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>