<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2896"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2896"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2896"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2896/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2896/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2896/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2896/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2896">
        <num>2896</num>
        <heading>Duties of public authorities with respect to the disposal of property</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2896__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ndetail the public authority's operative policy and instructions\nregarding the use, awarding, monitoring and reporting of contracts for\nthe disposal of property, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2896__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>designate a contracting officer who\nshall be responsible for the public authority's compliance with, and\nenforcement of, such guidelines. Such guidelines shall be consistent\nwith, and shall require the public authority's contracting activities to\ncomply with this section, the authorities enabling legislation and any\nother applicable law for the disposal of property, except that such\nguidelines may be stricter than the provisions of this section, the\nauthorities enabling legislation and any other applicable law for the\ndisposal of property if the public authority determines that additional\nsafeguards are necessary to assure the integrity of its disposition\nactivities. Guidelines approved by the public authority shall be\nannually reviewed and approved by the governing body of the public\nauthority. On or before the thirty-first day of March in each year, the\npublic authority shall file with the comptroller a copy of the\nguidelines most recently reviewed and approved by the public authority,\nincluding the name of the public authority's designated contracting\nofficer. At the time of filing such guidelines with the comptroller,\nevery public authority shall also post such guidelines on the public\nauthority's internet website. Guidelines posted on the public\nauthority's internet website shall be maintained on such website at\nleast until the procurement guidelines for the following year are posted\non such website.\n  2. Each public authority shall:\n  a. maintain adequate inventory controls and accountability systems for\nall property under its control;\n  b. periodically inventory such property to determine which property\nshall be disposed of;\n  c. produce a written report of such property in accordance with\nsubdivision three of this section;\n  d. transfer or dispose of such property as promptly as possible in\naccordance with section twenty-eight hundred ninety-seven of this title.\n  3. a. Each public authority shall publish, not less frequently t...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>