<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2985"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2985"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-09-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2985"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2985/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2985/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2985/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2985/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2985">
        <num>2985</num>
        <heading>Owner liability for failure of operator to comply with toll collection regulations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is the beneficial or\nequitable owner of such vehicle; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>has title to such vehicle; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>is the registrant or co-registrant of such vehicle which is\nregistered with the department of motor vehicles of this state or any\nother state, territory, district, province, nation or other\njurisdiction; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>subject to the limitations set forth in subdivision\nten of this section, uses such vehicle in its vehicle renting and/or\nleasing business; and includes</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a person entitled to the use and\npossession of a vehicle subject to a security interest in another\nperson. For purposes of this section, the term "photo-monitoring system"\nshall mean a vehicle sensor installed to work in conjunction with a toll\ncollection facility which automatically produces one or more\nphotographs, one or more microphotographs, a videotape or other recorded\nimages of each vehicle at the time it is used or operated in violation\nof toll collection regulations. For purposes of this section, the term\n"toll collection regulations" shall mean: those rules and regulations of\na public authority providing for and requiring the payment of tolls\nand/or charges prescribed by such public authority for the use of\nbridges, tunnels or highways under its jurisdiction or those rules and\nregulations of a public authority making it unlawful to refuse to pay or\nto evade or to attempt to evade the payment of all or part of any toll\nand/or charge for the use of bridges, tunnels or highways under the\njurisdiction of such public authority. For purposes of this section, the\nterm "vehicle" shall mean every device in, upon or by which a person or\nproperty is or may be transported or drawn upon a highway, except\ndevices used exclusively upon stationary rails or tracks.\n  4. A certificate, sworn to or affirmed by an agent of the public\nauthority which charged that the violation occurred, or a facsimile\nthereof, based upon inspection of photographs, microphotographs,\nvideotape or other recorded images produced by a photo-monitoring system\nshall be prima facie evidence of the facts contained therein and shall\nbe admissible in any proceeding charging a violation of toll collection\nregulations, provided that any photographs, microphotographs, videotape\nor other recorded images evidencing such a violation shall be available\nfor inspection and admission into evidence in any proceeding to\nadjudicate the liability for such violation.\n  5. An owner found li...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A notice of liability shall be sent by first class mail to each\nperson alleged to be liable as an owner for a violation of toll\ncollection regulations. Such notice shall be mailed no later than thirty\ndays after the alleged violation. Personal delivery on the owner shall\nnot be required. A manual or automatic record of mailing prepared in the\nordinary course of business shall be prima facie evidence of the mailing\nof the notice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>A notice of liability shall contain the name and address of the\nperson alleged to be liable as an owner for a violation of toll\ncollection regulations pursuant to this section, the registration number\nof the vehicle involved in such violation, the location where such\nviolation took place, the date and time of such violation and the\nidentification number of the photo-monitoring system which recorded the\nviolation or other document locator number.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The notice of liability shall contain information advising the\nperson charged of the manner and the time in which he may contest the\nliability alleged in the notice. Such notice of liability shall also\ncontain a warning to advise the persons charged that failure to contest\nin the manner and time provided shall be deemed an admission of\nliability and that a default judgment may be entered thereon.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The notice of liability shall be prepared and mailed by the public\nauthority having jurisdiction over the toll facility where the violation\nof toll collection regulations occurred.\n  8.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Adjudication of the liability imposed upon owners by this\nsection shall be by the entity having jurisdiction over violations of\nthe rules and regulations of the public authority serving the notice of\nliability or where authorized by an administrative tribunal and all\nviolations shall be heard and determined in the county in which the\nviolation is alleged to have occurred, or in New York city and upon the\nconsent of both parties, in any county within New York city in which the\npublic authority operates or maintains a facility, and in the same\nmanner as charges of other regulatory violations of such public\nauthority or pursuant to the rules and regulations of such\nadministrative tribunal as the case may be.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Upon exhaustion of remedies pursuant to this section or section\ntwenty-nine hundred eighty-five-a of this title, as applicable, the New\nYork state bridge authority, thruway authority, triborough bridge and\ntunnel authority, metropolitan transportation authority, and port\nauthority of New York and New Jersey, a bi-state agency created by\ncompact set forth in chapter one hundred fifty-four of the laws of\nnineteen hundred twenty-one, shall have the power to enter judgments for\nunpaid liabilities, provided that such unpaid liabilities include the\nfailure to pay tolls, fees, or other charges or the failure to have such\ntolls, fees or other charges dismissed or transferred in response to\nthree or more notices of violation issued within a five year period\ncharging the registrant of a motor vehicle with a violation of toll\ncollection regulations, and to enforce such judgments, without court\nproceedings, in the same manner as the enforcement of money judgments in\ncivil actions in any court of competent jurisdiction or any other place\nprovided for the entry of civil judgment within the state of New York,\nafter a period of notice pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision.\nThe applicable tolling authority shall not enforce such judgments until\nthirty days have elapsed from issuing a notice pursuant to paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof this subdivision.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Prior to entering judgments for unpaid liabilities pursuant to\nparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_2985__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, the applicable tolling authority\nshall notify the person subject to such judgment, by first class mail,\nthat such person is at risk of entry of a judgment against them if they\nfail to pay such unpaid liabilities. The form and content of such notice\nshall be prescribed by the applicable tolling authority, and shall\ncontain a warning to advise the person that failure to pay the\napplicable unpaid liabilities within a period of not less than thirty\ndays of such notice will result in the enforcement of a judgment against\nthem, and shall further contain information about the process to dispute\nsuch liabilities, consistent with this section or section twenty-nine\nhundred eighty-five-a of this title, as applicable.\n  9. If an owner receives a notice of liability pursuant to this section\nfor any time period during which the vehicle was reported to the police\ndepartment as having been stolen, it shall be a valid defense to an\nallegation of liability for a violation of toll collection regulations\nthat the vehicle had been reported to the police as stolen prior to the\ntime the violation occurred and had not been recovered by such time. If\nan owner receives a notice of liability pursuant to this section for any\ntime period during which the vehicle was stolen, but not as yet reported\nto the police as having been stolen, it shall be a valid defense to an\nallegation of liability for a violation of toll collection regulations\npursuant to this section that the vehicle was reported as stolen within\ntwo hours after the discovery of the theft by the owner. For purposes of\nasserting the defense provided by this subdivision it shall be\nsufficient that a certified copy of the police report on the stolen\nvehicle be sent by first class mail to the court or other entity having\njurisdiction.\n  10. An owner who is a lessor of a vehicle to which a notice of\nliability was issued pursuant to subdivision seven of this section shall\nnot be liable for...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>