<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2987"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2987"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="2987"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2987/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2987/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2987/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-2987/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_2987">
        <num>2987</num>
        <heading>Lobbying contacts</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_2987__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the adoption or rejection of any rule or regulation having the\nforce and effect of law by a public authority, and\n  (ii) the outcome of any rate making proceeding by a public authority.\n  c. "contact" shall mean any conversation, in person or by telephonic\nor other remote means, or correspondence between any lobbyist engaged in\nthe act of lobbying and any person within a state authority who can make\nor influence a decision on the subject of the lobbying on behalf of the\nauthority, and shall include, at a minimum, all members of the governing\nboard and all officers of the state authority.\n  2. Every state authority shall maintain a record of all lobbying\ncontacts made with such authority.\n  3. Every member, officer or employee of a state authority who is\ncontacted by a lobbyist shall make a contemporaneous record of such\ncontact containing the day and time of the contact, the identity of the\nlobbyist and a general summary of the substance of the contact.\n  4. Each state authority shall adopt a policy implementing the\nrequirements of this section. Such policy shall appoint an officer to\nwhom all such records shall be delivered. Such officer shall maintain\nsuch records for not less than seven years in a filing system designed\nto organize such records in a manner so as to make such records useful\nto determine whether the decisions of the authority were influenced by\nlobbying contacts.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>