<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3033"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3033"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3033"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3033/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3033/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3033/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3033/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3033">
        <num>3033</num>
        <heading>Creation of the municipal assistance corporation for the city of New York; authorized indebtedness</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nbonds and notes issued to refund outstanding bonds and notes and (ii)\nnotes issued for the purpose described in subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section\nthree thousand thirty-seven of the this article, provided, however, that\nno bonds or notes shall be issued for any purpose other than to pay for\nitems which are permitted by law to be included in the city's capital\nbudget or to make deposits into the capital reserve funds established\npursuant to sections three thousand thirty-six and three thousand\nthirty-six-a of this article if at the time such bonds or notes are\nissued or as a result of their issuance the aggregate principal amount\nof bonds and notes issued by the corporation, exclusive of bonds and\nnotes issued for any purpose described in clause</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>or (ii) of this\nsubdivision, exceeds eight billion eight hundred million dollars.\n  2-a. In addition to the authority provided in subdivision two of this\nsection, the corporation may, until June thirtieth, nineteen hundred\nseventy-eight, issue notes in an aggregate principal amount which the\nmayor certifies to the corporation is required by the city to provide,\nwithout interruption, services essential to its inhabitants while\nmeeting its obligation to the holders of its outstanding securities to\nJune thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, but not to exceed five\nhundred million dollars. Such notes shall finally mature no later than\nJune thirtieth, nineteen hundred seventy-eight. Such notes shall not be\nrenewable. The terms of issuance of such notes shall not contain any\nprovision creating rights in the holders of such notes to convert such\nnotes to or exchange such notes for bonds of the corporation. The\ncorporation shall pay the proceeds of such notes to the city to be used\nto provide services essential to its inhabitants without regard to the\nprovisions of section three thousand thirty-seven of this title.\n  2-b. In addition to the authority provided in subdivisions two and\ntwo-a of this section, the corporation may, not later than June\nthirtieth, nineteen hundred ninety-seven issue bonds and notes in an\naggregate principal amount not to exceed one billion five hundred\nmillion dollars (excluding any bonds or notes issued to fund the bond\nreserve fund established pursuant to section three thousand thirty-six-b\nof this title and any bonds or notes issued to refund outstanding bonds\nor notes) for the purpose of funding capital projects within the city\npursuant to section three thousand thirty-seven-a of this title;\nprovided, however, that such authority shall decrease from time to time\nby such amounts as the city shall have made available to fund such\ncapital projects; and provided further, that the authority provided in\nthis subdivisi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No note or bond</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>shall mature more than thirty years from\nthe date of the original issue of such note or bond and, in any event,\nnot later than July first, two thousand eight or (ii) shall be issued on\na date later than December thirty-first, nineteen hundred eighty-four,\nunless such note or bond is a renewal or refunding of an outstanding\nnote or bond.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No bond shall be issued by the corporation for a purpose set forth\nin subparagraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section three thousand thirty-seven of this\narticle and any note issued for such a purpose shall mature not later\nthan the end of the fiscal year in which it is originally issued.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever all or a portion of a series of notes or bonds of the\ncorporation is issued for a purpose set forth in section three thousand\nthirty-seven of this article, to the extent that the payment of the\nproceeds of such series is evidenced by a bond or bonds of the city, not\nmore than one year following a scheduled payment of principal on any\nsuch city bond (including sinking fund installments), a substantially\nequal payment of principal (including sinking fund installments) shall\nbe scheduled with respect to the notes or bonds included in such series\nof the corporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3033__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Whenever all or a portion of a series of bonds or notes of the\ncorporation is issued for a purpose set forth in section three thousand\nthirty-seven-a of this title, the payment of the proceeds of such series\nof bonds or notes to the city shall be evidenced by a bond or bonds of\nthe city issued in accordance with applicable provisions of the state\nconstitution and local finance law then in effect at the time any such\nbond or bonds are issued; provided, however, that principal payments on\nany such issue of city bonds shall in no event be scheduled to fall on a\ndate later than the date on which falls a corresponding amount of\nscheduled principal payments on the series of bonds of the corporation\noriginally issued to provide such proceeds or issued to refund notes of\nthe corporation issued to provide such proceeds.\n  4. If the bond resolution or other resolution pursuant to which any\nobligations of the corporation are issued shall designate, with the\napproval of any emergency financial control board then established for\nthe city or, if none, then with the approval of the mayor, the\ncorporation may hereafter issue obligations which shall, upon maturity,\nat the election of the holder thereof if so provided in such\nobligations, be receivable at full face value and in lieu of cash in\npayment of any tax of the city, any installment of estimated tax of the\ncity, or any interest or penalties thereon. Any obligations of the\ncorporation so received in payment of any such tax or installment of\nestimated tax or interest or penalties shall be presented to the\ncorporation for payment to the city.\n  * NB The corporation shall continue for a term ending the later of\nJuly 1, 2008 or one year after its liabilities have been fully paid and\ndischarged per sub 1.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>