<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3058"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3058"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3058"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3058/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3058/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3058/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3058/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3058">
        <num>3058</num>
        <heading>Conditions on extension of benefits to the city</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3058__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nrepresenting that the city is in compliance with the conditions\ndescribed below in this section as the corporation may specify,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3058__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nundertaking to comply with any of such specified conditions as the\ncorporation may then require, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3058__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>stating that all local legislative\nand executive action then required to permit such compliance by the city\nhas been taken. The corporation may require the delivery with such\ncertificate of an opinion of the city's corporation counsel that all\nsuch legislative and executive action has been taken.\n  2. For the fiscal year ending December thirty-first, nineteen hundred\nninety-six, and for each fiscal year thereafter, the city's budgets\nshall be prepared in accordance with the provisions of chapter seven\nhundred twenty-one of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-four, as\namended from time to time.\n  3. Each fiscal year the city shall take such action as may be\nnecessary to enable an independent certified public accounting firm\nselected and retained by the city at its cost to perform an annual audit\nand to furnish to the corporation an annual report upon the financial\nstatements of the city. Each such report shall be prepared in accordance\nwith the generally accepted accounting principles. The city shall make\navailable for inspection and copying all books, records, work papers and\nother data and material as required by the independent certified public\naccounting firm conducting such audit and the city shall make its\nofficers and employees available to and shall cooperate with such\nauditors so as to permit such annual audit to be completed and the\nreport issued to the city and to the corporation within one hundred\ntwenty days after the close of the fiscal year. Such report shall be\nmade available to the public promptly thereafter.\n  4. Beginning with the fiscal year ending December thirty-first,\nnineteen hundred ninety-six and for each fiscal year thereafter, the\ncity shall deliver its proposed budgets to the corporation. Delivery to\nthe corporation shall be made concurrently with the initial submission\nof the proposed budgets to the city council, but in any event not later\nthan fifty days prior to the beginning of such fiscal year or such oth...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3058__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a statement setting forth in\ndetail the assumptions of income and expense used in preparation, and\n(ii) a certificate of the chief executive officer stating that such\nassumptions are reasonable and that operation within the budgets is\nfeasible. Subject to and in accordance with the provisions of chapter\nseven hundred twenty-one of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-four, as\nthe same may be amended from time to time, the city shall in every\nfiscal year adopt and maintain budgets in which the total of all revenue\nitems equals or exceeds the total of all expenditure items.\n  5. If after the adoption of the budgets for any fiscal year, any\nincrease therein, or an increase in total expenditures shall be\nproposed, the chief executive officer shall cause such proposal to be\nsubmitted to the corporation concurrently with its submission to the\ncity council, together with a statement of the source of current\nrevenues or other identifiable and currently available funds required\nfor the payment of such additional amounts.\n  6. Commencing at such time as the corporation may specify, but not\nlater than February first, nineteen hundred ninety-six, the city budget\ndirector shall deliver to the corporation, not less than thirty days\nbefore each fiscal quarter (except, within thirty days after the\ncommencement of the first fiscal quarter), an expenditure plan to\nimplement the city budgets for such fiscal quarter and within amounts\nbased on current income or other identifiable and currently available\nfunds. The city budget director shall deliver to the corporation within\nthirty days after the end of each such fiscal quarter covered by an\nexpenditure plan, an operations report reflecting results of city\noperations for such fiscal quarter and whether the city has operated\nwithin the related expenditure plan. Each expenditure plan and\noperations report shall be in such form as the corporation may specify\nand shall be certified by the city budget director and...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>