<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3102-D"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3102-D"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3102-D"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3102-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3102-D/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3102-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3102-D/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3102_D">
        <num>3102-D</num>
        <heading>Technology development organization program</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"Technology development organizations" shall mean any\nnot-for-profit corporation or other nonprofit organization, association,\nor agency which is organized for the purpose of the promotion,\nattraction, stimulation, development and expansion of science and\ntechnology-oriented economic activity in a particular region of the\nstate or in one or more counties or cities. For the purposes of this\nsection, a technology development organization shall include\nnot-for-profit corporations or other nonprofit organizations,\nassociations, or agencies which are organized for the stated purpose\neither prior to or following the effective date of this section,\nincluding such organization which had begun operations prior to said\ndate.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>"In-kind services" shall mean the donation of quantifiable goods\nand services including but not limited to professional services and\ntime, equipment, material and office space for use by a technology\ndevelopment organization in furtherance of its stated purposes or\nprovided on behalf of the technology development organization to others\nfor such purposes and for which there is no monetary remuneration. Any\nsuch in-kind services must have prior approval by the foundation to\nsatisfy the matching requirement of the technology development\norganization program.\n  2. The foundation is hereby authorized to award grants on a\ncompetitive basis, from such funds as may be appropriated for this\npurpose by the legislature, to match funds expended by technology\ndevelopment organizations for the purposes set forth in this section and\nin accordance with rules and regulations promulgated by the foundation\npursuant to this section.\n  3. Matching funds shall be provided only for purposes which are\nrelated to the realization of the technological development potential of\na particular region of the state in accordance with the findings of the\nfoundation pursuant to subdivision five of section thirty-one hundred\ntwo of this chapter. Among the activities for which matching funds may\nbe provided are the following:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sponsoring and conducting regional conferences and studies,\ncollecting and disseminating information and issuing periodic reports\nrelating to scientific and technological research, development and\neducation in the region;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Preparing and periodically issuing a register of scientific and\ntechnological research facilities in the region;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Assisting small and emerging science and technology-oriented\nbusinesses within the region in applying for federal or state research\ngrants or procurement contracts and disseminating information on the\navailability of such grants and contracts;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Collecting and disseminating information on financial, technical,\nmarketing, management and other services available to small and emerging\nscience and technology-oriented businesses within the region and\narranging access to such services on a free or for-hire basis from\nuniversities, private for-profit businesses and nonprofit organizations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Providing technical assistance including management, marketing and\nfinancial packaging assistance to, and collecting and disseminating\ninformation regarding inventions for the benefit of, inventors\ninterested in having their ideas developed and commercialized and\nentrepreneurs interested in the commercialization of new products and\nprocesses;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Supporting university-industry collaboration in applied research,\nthe promotion of incubator facilities and the generation of brokering of\nventure capital to support regional new enterprise development;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishing or updating a technology development strategy for the\nregion;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Establishing regional data base services, linked through the\nfoundation into a statewide data base, which identify resources\navailable from colleges, universities and technical service providers\nand which provide information, including venture capital sources and\nlabor market statistics, of interest to and for use by entrepreneurs and\ntechnology-oriented businesses;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Sponsoring or working with regional industrial extension services\nto provide technological information to industry and to communicate\nindustrial needs to universities and others, brokering joint\nuniversity-industry investigations to aid industry, and assisting in the\nprovision of productivity improvements to mature industries;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Projecting the need for the technical and professional workforce\nwithin the region and assisting others in planning for projected\ndislocations and retraining; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Assisting the foundation and the department of economic\ndevelopment in identifying and contacting eligible applicants, as\ndefined in paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section two hundred\ntwenty-four of the economic development law, and sponsoring, in\nconjunction with the foundation and the department of economic\ndevelopment, conferences, seminars, counseling sessions and other\noutreach efforts aimed at improving the competitive position of\napplicants in international markets by promoting exporting.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3102_D__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Conducting such other appropriate activities as may be established\nby the foundation for the purpose of realizing the technological\ndevelopment potential of the region served by the applicant.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other law, grants made by the foundation\npursuant to this section shall be equally matched by the technology\ndevelopment organization except that up to fifty percent of the match\nmade by the technology development organization may be of in-kind\nservices as approved by the foundation.\n  5. The foundation may establish such requirements as it deems\nappropriate for the format and content of applications for matching\ngrants pursuant to this section and shall set reasonable deadlines for\nthe submission of applications for such support.\n  6. The foundation may select from competing applications, those which\nit judges to be of greatest benefit to the welfare of the people of the\nstate and may approve or reject any or all of the competing\napplications. The foundation shall notify all applicants of the approval\nor rejection of their applications in a timely fashion.\n  7. The foundation shall require periodic but at least semi-annual\nreports and other such documents and information as it deems necessary\nto monitor and review the performance of each technology development\norganization awarded a grant and shall conduct an annual evaluation of\nthe program which shall include the quality of the activities performed\nand conformity thereof to the grant provisions and the purposes and\nprovisions set forth in this section.\n  8. The foundation shall submit a report by May first, nineteen hundred\neighty-eight, and each December thirty-first thereafter, to the\ngovernor, the temporary president of the senate and the speaker of the\nassembly, detailing the activities that each technology development\norganization has undertaken during the reporting year. Such reports\nshall include but not be limited to, the composition of the\norganization, the amo...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>