<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3105-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3105-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3105-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3105-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3105-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3105-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3105-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3105_A">
        <num>3105-A</num>
        <heading>Roster of retired scientists, engineers and other experts</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3105-a. Roster of retired scientists, engineers and other experts.\n  1. The corporation shall establish a roster of retired scientists,\nengineers and other experts who are willing to volunteer to assist\nsmall, emerging technology oriented businesses in reviewing, analyzing\nand assisting in technological and organizational problems.\n  2. The roster of retired scientists, engineers and other experts shall\nbe composed of retired persons with scientific research and development\nexpertise or such relevant managerial experience as may be useful to\nemerging business.\n  3. The corporation shall make the establishment of the roster known to\nsuch retired scientists, engineers and other experts who may be willing\nto volunteer their services, and solicit their assistance on behalf of\nemerging businesses that request assistance from such persons.\n  4. The corporation shall make the names and accompanying areas of\nexpertise known to inventors and small and emerging technology oriented\nbusinessmen for the purpose of gaining from the advice and expertise of\nsuch retired volunteers.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>