<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3153"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3153"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3153"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3153/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3153/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3153/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3153/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3153">
        <num>3153</num>
        <heading>Capital investments innovation fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3153__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Projects eligible for capital investment\nfund financing may include, but not be limited to, those that enhance\ninnovation or increase competitiveness in emerging or high-technology\nindustries, and other industries.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3153__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Capital investment innovation funds may be utilized for projects\nwhich include, but may not be limited to, the following: the development\nof industrial facilities and parks, manufacturing facilities, business\nparks and incubators, office facilities and parks, warehouse and\ndistribution facilities, and, high-technology and biotechnology\nresearch, development and related commercialization facilities.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3153__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Projects intended primarily for the development of retail or\npersonal service facilities shall not be eligible.\n  3. Eligible costs. Capital investment innovation funds may be utilized\nfor purposes including but not limited to the following: infrastructure\ndevelopment, including water, sewer, highway, rail access, electric\npower, gas and telecommunications; energy efficiency improvements; site\nacquisition, site investigation, site clearance, building demolition and\nsite preparation; construction, reconstruction, and renovation, and,\nmachinery and equipment.\n  4. Project cost. Total project cost shall be a minimum of two hundred\nfifty thousand dollars, unless the board determines that circumstances\nmerit a waiver of such minimum threshold. At least two-thirds of the\nproject cost shall consist of private sector, local, or federal funding.\nHowever, those projects which offer exceptional opportunities for\nlong-term private sector job creation and retention may be eligible for\na waiver of this requirement.\n  5. Applications. Applications may be submitted to the foundation by\nthe regional partnerships on behalf of municipalities, nonprofit\norganizations, businesses, special districts, institutions of higher\neducation, or other organizations. The foundation may provide grants,\nloans or combinations thereof, provided that projects be evaluated on\nthe basis of the amount of economic impact on New York state, the\nfeasibility of business plans and long-term sustainability, as\ndetermined by the foundation, in consultation with the urban development\ncorporation.\n  6. Program rules and regulations. Following consultation with\nappropriate state and local agencies and other organizations, the\nfoundation shall promulgate rules and regulations for the award of the\ncapital investments innovation fund financing through the regional\npartnerships, provided however, that the foundation board shall oversee\nthe distribution of all funds appropriated to the capi...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>