<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3165"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3165"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3165"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3165/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3165/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3165/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3165/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3165">
        <num>3165</num>
        <heading>Transfer of appropriation</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3165. Transfer of appropriation. Transfer of appropriations\nheretofore made to the New York state office of science, technology and\nacademic research. Upon the transfer pursuant to section thirty-one\nhundred fifty-six of this title of the functions and powers possessed by\nand all of the obligations and duties of the New York state office of\nscience, technology and academic research as established pursuant to\narticle ten-B of the executive law to the foundation as prescribed by\nsection thirty-one hundred fifty-six of this title, all appropriations\nand reappropriations which shall have been made available as of the date\nof such transfer to the New York state office of science, technology and\nacademic research or segregated pursuant to law, to the extent of\nremaining unexpended or unencumbered balances thereof, whether allocated\nor unallocated and whether obligated or unobligated, shall be\ntransferred to and made available for use and expenditure by the\nfoundation and when appropriate made available to the regional\npartnerships for the same purposes for which originally appropriated or\nreappropriated and shall be payable on vouchers certified or approved by\nthe commissioner of taxation and finance, on audit and warrant of the\ncomptroller. Payments of liabilities for expenses of personal service,\nmaintenance and operation which shall have been incurred as of the date\nof such transfer by the New York state office of science, technology and\nacademic research, and for liabilities incurred and to be incurred in\ncompleting its affairs shall also be made on vouchers certified or\napproved by the executive director of the foundation, on audit and\nwarrant of the comptroller. All of the assets and liabilities of the\nsmall business technology investment fund transferred from the New York\nstate science and technology foundation to the urban development\ncorporation pursuant to subdivision two of section two hundred nine-f of\nthe executive law shall be transferred to the New York state foundation\nfor science, technology and innovation established pursuant to this\ntitle.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>