<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3234"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3234"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3234"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3234/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3234/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3234">
        <num>3234</num>
        <heading>Administration of the corporation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3234__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The corporation\nshall be administered by seven directors, one of whom shall be the\ncomptroller, one of whom shall be the director of the budget and five of\nwhom shall be appointed by the governor. The comptroller and the\ndirector of the budget shall be entitled to designate a representative\nor representatives to attend meetings of the board in their place, and\nto vote or otherwise act on their behalf in their absence. Notice of\nsuch designation shall be furnished in writing to the board by the\ndesignating director. A representative shall serve at the pleasure of\nthe designating director during the director's term of office. A\nrepresentative shall not be authorized to delegate any of his or her\nduties or functions to any other person. A director who is not a state\nofficial shall serve for a term expiring at the end of the term actually\nserved by the officer making the appointment and may be removed for\ncause by such officer after hearing on ten days notice.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3234__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The secretary to the senate finance committee and the secretary to\nthe assembly ways and means committee shall be nonvoting representatives\nwho shall receive notice of and be entitled to attend all meetings of\nthe directors and who shall also receive the same supporting and other\ndocumentation related to each vote to be taken by the directors at each\nmeeting as is provided to the directors, at the same time as it is\nprovided to the directors. The comments of the nonvoting representatives\nshall be entered upon the record of the meeting.\n  2. The governor shall designate a chairperson and a vice-chairperson\nfrom among the directors. The chairperson shall preside over all\nmeetings of the directors and shall have such other duties as the\ndirectors or the corporation may direct. The vice-chairperson shall\npreside over all meetings of the directors in the absence of the\nchairperson and shall have such other duties as the directors of the\ncorporation may prescribe.\n  3. The directors of the corporation shall serve without salary, but\neach director shall be reimbursed for actual necessary expenses incurred\nin the performance of such director's official duties as a director of\nthe corporation. The directors of the corporation may engage in private\nemployment or in a profession or business if not otherwise prohibited\nfrom so doing by virtue of any other public office.\n  4. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of law, general,\nspecial or local, no officer or employee of the state of New York, any\ncity, county, town or village, any other political or civil division of\nthe state, any municipality, any governmental entity operating any\npublic school or college, any school district or any other public agency\nor instrumentality or unit of government which exercises governmental\npowers under the laws of the state, shall forfeit office or employment\nby reason of acceptance of appointment as a director, representative,\nofficer or agent of the corpor...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>