<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3301"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3301"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3301"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3301/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3301/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3301">
        <num>3301</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3301. Legislative findings and purpose. The legislature hereby finds\nand declares as follows:\n  1. Currently, the Westchester County Medical Center is a public\nhospital owned and operated by the county of Westchester.\n  2. The Westchester County Medical Center encompasses the Medical\nCenter Hospital, the Ruth Taylor Geriatric and Rehabilitation Institute,\nthe Psychiatric Institute and the Westchester Institute for Human\nDevelopment.\n  3. The Medical Center Hospital is the tertiary care facility for\nWestchester and the six other counties of the lower Hudson Valley.\n  4. The needs of the residents of the state of New York and of the\ncounty of Westchester can best be served by the operation of the\nWestchester County Medical Center by a public benefit corporation having\nthe legal, financial and managerial flexibility to take full advantage\nof opportunities and challenges presented by the evolving health care\nenvironment.\n  5. In order to accomplish the purposes recited in this section to\nprovide health care services and health facilities for the benefit of\nthe residents of the state of New York and the county of Westchester,\nincluding persons in need of health care services without the ability to\npay as required by law, a public benefit corporation to be known as the\nWestchester county health care corporation shall be created to provide\nsuch services and facilities and to otherwise carry out such purposes;\nthat the creation and operation of the Westchester county health care\ncorporation, as hereinafter provided, is in all respects for the benefit\nof the people of the state of New York and of the county of Westchester,\nand is a state, county and public purpose; and that the exercise by such\ncorporation of the functions, powers and duties as hereinafter provided\nconstitutes the performance of an essential public and governmental\nfunction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>