<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3405"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3405"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3405"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3405/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3405/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3405">
        <num>3405</num>
        <heading>Special powers of the corporation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Except as otherwise provided in any applicable law or\nregulation, to exercise and perform all or part of its purposes, powers,\nduties, functions or activities through one or more subsidiary entities\nowned or controlled wholly or in part by the corporation, which shall be\nformed pursuant to the business corporation law, the limited liability\ncompany law, or the not-for-profit corporation law, in each case subject\nto all the limitations provided in this article.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any such subsidiary may be authorized to act as a general or\nlimited partner in a partnership or as a member of a limited liability\ncompany, and enter into an arrangement calling for an initial and\nsubsequent payment by such subsidiary in consideration of an interest in\nrevenues or other contractual rights.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An entity shall be deemed a subsidiary whenever and so long as</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nmore than half of any voting shares of such subsidiary are owned or held\nby the corporation or (ii) a majority of the directors, trustees or\nmembers of such subsidiary are designees of the corporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The corporation may transfer to any subsidiary entity any monies,\nreal or personal or mixed property in order to carry out the purposes of\nthis title, subject to the rights of the holders of any bonds of the\ncorporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any subsidiary which provides health care services previously\nprovided by the county and transferred by the corporation to the\nsubsidiary shall comply with and be subject to subdivision nine of this\nsection and subdivisions seven through ten inclusive of section\nthirty-four hundred two, sections thirty-four hundred ten, thirty-four\nhundred sixteen, thirty-four hundred seventeen and thirty-four hundred\neighteen of this title as applicable. The transfer of any monies, real\nor personal or mixed property to a subsidiary shall be governed by any\nrestrictions or limitations as the county may establish in the agreement\nbetween the county and the corporation as described in subdivision two\nof section thirty-four hundred six of this title.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any material change in the operation of a health facility that\noccurs pursuant to a transfer or agreement between the corporation and\nany of its subsidiaries shall require the board of such corporation or\nsubsidiary to provide written notice of such transfer or agreement to\nthe county executive and majority leader and minority leader of the\ncounty legislature within seven days of such transfer.\n  6. To contract with the county for related public health services to\nbe determined by the county and the corporation.\n  7. To negotiate and make any payments in lieu of taxes with any\npolitical subdivision where the corporation holds real estate.\n  8. To contract with the county to provide, in whole or in part, health\ncare services, and to operate facilities and programs which provide\nhealth care services.\n  9. To provide uncompensated care to persons in need of health care\nservices without the ability to pay.\n  10.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In carrying out its health care purposes through the exercise\nof the special powers exercised pursuant to this section and the general\npowers exercised pursuant to section thirty-four hundred four of this\ntitle, the corporation is authorized to engage in arrangements,\ncontracts, information sharing and other collaborative activities with\npublic or private entities and individuals irrespective of the\ncompetitive consequences of these activities and notwithstanding that\nthese activities may have the effect of displacing competition in the\nprovision of hospital, physician, or other health care-related services.\nThese collaborative activities may include without limitation: joint\nventures; joint negotiations with physicians, hospitals and payors,\nwhether such negotiations result in separate or combined agreements;\nleases; and/or agreements which involve delivery system network creation\nand operation, provided that, the corporation shall exercise state\noversight by determining whether particular collaborations with public\nor private entities and individuals further the interests of the state\nas set forth in this subdivision and in subdivision three of section\nthirty-four hundred one of this title. In undertaking these\ncollaborative activities, the corporation and the public or private\nentities and individuals with which it collaborates shall be immunized\nfrom liability under the federal and state antitrust laws.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3405__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, the corporation\nand its collaborators shall remain subject to generally applicable\nprovisions of the public health law and regulations thereunder. In\naddition, the corporation shall file an annual report with the state\ndepartment of health, as additional state oversight, concerning the\nimpact of the collaborations authorized under this section on the\nadvantages and disadvantages identified by the department of health in\nits request for applications for HEAL NY Phase 21, entitled\n"Restructuring Initiatives in Medicaid Redesign," and concerning the\nimpact on reimbursement to the corporation's facilities by managed care\norganizations with respect to commercial plan members, including the\nextent to which rates have been negotiated that more fairly compensate\nthe corporation's facilities for the cost of providing services to\ncommercial enrollees, without cross-subsidy from medicaid or other\ngovernmental programs. In response to the report, the department of\nhealth shall have sixty days after the report has been filed to request,\nin writing, that the corporation make changes to its policies to ensure\nthat the collaborations authorized under this section further the\ninterests of the state.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>