<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-352"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-352"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="352"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-352/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-352/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-352/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-352/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_352">
        <num>352</num>
        <heading>New York State thruway authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 352. New York State thruway authority. 1. A board to be known as\n"New York state thruway authority" is hereby created. Such board shall\nbe a body corporate and politic constituting a public corporation. It\nshall consist of seven members appointed by the governor by and with the\nadvice and consent of the senate. The members first appointed shall\nserve for terms ending three, six and nine years, respectively from\nJanuary first next succeeding their appointment. Provided, however, that\ntwo board members first appointed on or after the effective date of the\nchapter of the laws of two thousand five which amended this subdivision\nshall serve an initial term of two years; provided further that two\nother board members first appointed on or after the effective date of\nthe chapter of the laws of two thousand five which amended this\nsubdivision shall serve an initial term of three years. Their successors\nshall be appointed for terms of nine years each. A member to be\ndesignated as chairman in his or her appointment as a member shall be\nchairman of such board until his or her term as member expires. The\nchairman and the other members shall serve without salary or other\ncompensation, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their actual\nand necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official\nduties.\n  2. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provisions of law, general,\nspecial or local, no officer or employee of the state, or of any civil\ndivision thereof, shall be deemed to have forfeited or shall forfeit his\noffice or employment by reason of his acceptance of membership on the\nboard created by this section; provided, however, a member who holds\nsuch other public office or employment shall receive no additional\ncompensation for services rendered pursuant to this title.\n  3. The power of such corporation shall be vested in and exercised by a\nmajority of the members of the board then in office. Such board may\ndelegate to one or more of its members or its officers, agents and\nemployees such powers and duties as it may deem proper.\n  4. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue so long as it\nshall have notes, bonds or other obligations outstanding (including\nnotes, bonds or obligations hereafter issued or incurred) and until its\nexistence shall be terminated by law. Upon the termination of the\nexistence of the authority, all its rights and properties shall pass to\nand be vested in the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>