<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-355"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-355"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-01-13" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="355"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-355/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-355/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-355/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-355/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_355">
        <num>355</num>
        <heading>Officers and employees; transfer, promotion and seniority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 355. Officers and employees; transfer, promotion and seniority. 1.\nOfficers and employees of state departments, agencies, or divisions may\nbe transferred to the authority and officers, agents and employees of\nthe authority may be transferred to state departments, agencies, or\ndivisions, without examination and without loss of any civil service\nstatus or rights. No such transfer from the authority to any state\ndepartment, agency, or division may, however, be made except with the\napproval of the head of the state department, agency, or division\ninvolved and the director of the budget and in compliance with the rules\nand regulations of the state civil service commission.\n  2. Promotions from positions in state departments and agencies to\npositions in the authority, and vice versa, may be made from\ninterdepartmental promotion lists resulting from promotion examinations\nin which employees of the authority and employees of the state are\neligible to participate.\n  3. In computing seniority for purposes of promotion or for purposes of\nsuspension or demotion upon the abolition of positions in the service of\nthe authority or in the service of the state, in the case of an employee\nof the authority a period of prior employment in the service of the\nstate shall be counted in the same manner as though such period of\nemployment had been in the service of the authority, and in the case of\nan employee of the state a period of prior employment in the service of\nthe authority shall be counted in the same manner as though such period\nof employment had been in the service of the state. For the purposes of\nthe establishment and certification of preferred lists, employees\nsuspended from the authority shall be eligible for reinstatement in the\nservice of the state, and employees suspended from the service of the\nstate shall be eligible for reinstatement in the service of the\nauthority, in the same manner as though the authority were a department\nof the state.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>