<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3557"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3557"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3557"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3557/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3557/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3557/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3557/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3557">
        <num>3557</num>
        <heading>Officers and employees; compensation; transfer</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3557. Officers and employees; compensation; transfer.  1. On the\neffective date of the transfer of the operations of the Roswell Park\nCancer Institute to the corporation pursuant to an agreement between the\nstate and the corporation as authorized in this title, officers and\nemployees of the state employed in Roswell Park Cancer Institute shall\nbecome officers and employees of the corporation; such persons\ntransferred shall be deemed public officers or public employees as the\ncase may be, in the civil service.\n  2.  The civil service rights of such persons continuing in service of\nthe corporation at the time of such transfer and for persons entering\nthe service of Roswell Park Cancer Institute corporation following the\ndate of transfer shall be governed by the civil service law and\nassociated regulations except as otherwise provided pursuant to this\ntitle.\n  3. The salary or compensation of any such officer or employee, after\nsuch transfer, shall be paid by the corporation.\n  4. The corporation shall, upon transfer, acknowledge and give credit\nfor all leave balances held by such officers and employees of the state\nwho become officers or employees of the corporation on the date of\ntransfer.\n  5. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law for purposes of\neligibility for promotional examinations offered for state employees\ngenerally, an employee of the corporation shall be entitled to all the\nrights thereto as if such employee was a state employee subject to the\npertinent provisions of the civil service law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>