<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-356"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-356"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2017-07-07" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="356"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-356/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-356/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-356/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-356/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_356">
        <num>356</num>
        <heading>Thruway sections and connections; assuming jurisdiction</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 356. Thruway sections and connections; assuming jurisdiction. At any\ntime after this title shall become effective the authority may adopt a\nresolution assuming jurisdiction for its corporate purposes of any or\nall of the thruway sections or connections below described and such\nconnections with highways, hereinafter referred to as "highway\nconnections," as the authority may deem advisable in the interest of the\npublic to serve traffic needs, and the authority shall continue to have\nsuch jurisdiction so long as its corporate existence shall continue.\n  Pending the adoption of such resolution, the commissioner shall have\nall the powers herein conferred upon the authority to construct,\nreconstruct, improve, maintain, and operate such thruway sections and\nconnections, and highway connections, and to acquire in the name of the\nstate real property therefor. Subject to such deviations therefrom as\nthe authority may deem advisable in the interest of the public to serve\ntraffic needs, such thruway sections and connections shall be as\nfollows:\n  1. Southern Westchester connection. Beginning at the northerly\nterminus of the Major Deegan expressway in the vicinity of Jerome avenue\nat the New York city corporate line, thence extending in a general\nnortherly direction through the city of Yonkers to connect with the\nsoutherly end of the Hudson section at a point in the vicinity of\nTuckahoe road to be determined by the commissioner. No fees or other\ncharges may be imposed for vehicular use of this connection.\n  2. The Hudson section. Beginning at the northerly end of the southern\nWestchester connection at or near Tuckahoe road, thence in a general\nnortherly and westerly direction crossing the Hudson river at a point\nsouth of Highland Falls, which crossing shall be known as "The Governor\nMario M. Cuomo Bridge", including a highway connection between "The\nGovernor Mario M. Cuomo Bridge" and the New England section of the\nthruway presently known as interstate route two hundred eighty-seven,\nthence in a general westerly direction to intersect with existing route\nnumber seventeen or to a connection with that route, including a thruway\nconnection from that portion of the section west of the Hudson river,\ngenerally southerly to a point to be determined by the authority on the\nNew York-New Jersey boundary line.\n  3. The Catskill section. Beginning at the northerly end of the Hudson\nsection, extending in a general northerly direction in the vicinity of\nCentral Valley, Highland Mills, Woodbury Falls, Vails Gate, thence\nthrough or passing Newburgh on the west, including a highway connection\nwhich runs from the Pennsylvania line at Port Jervis to the Connecticut\nborder east of Brewster, presently known as interstate route 84, except\nfor that portion of the highway connection between the interchange with\nthe easternmost state highway on the west shore of the Hudson river\n(currently designated state touring route 9W) and the interchange with\nthe westernmost state highway on the east shore of the Hudson river\n(currently designated state touring route 9D) which is subject to the\njurisdiction of the New York state bridge authority, thence northerly\npast Plattekill and New Paltz, thence passing through or near the city\nof Kingston and continuing northerly to the west of Saugerties and\nCatskill, continuing northerly passing in the vicinity of West Coxsackie\nand Ravena, thence northerly passing the Feura Bush railroad yards in\nthe vicinity of either their easterly or westerly extremities, thence\ncontinuing northerly passing to the west or through the westerly part of\nthe city of Albany, and intersecting United States route number twenty\nin the vicinity of McKownville.\n  4. The Mohawk section. Starting at the northerly end of the Catskill\nsection on United States route number twenty in the vicinity of\nMcKownville, continuing in a northwesterly direction toward the city of\nSchenectady, and thence around the southerly side of Schenectady,\ncontinuing through or along the Mohawk Valley by-passing or passing\nthrough the city of Utica, thence westerly passing in the vicinity of\nWhitesboro and continuing to the north of the city of Oneida, thence\nwesterly to the south of the Cicero swamp to a point on United States\nroute number eleven north of the village of Liverpool.\n  5. The Ontario section. Starting at the westerly end of the Mohawk\nsection at a point on United States route number eleven north of the\nvillage of Liverpool, thence westerly north of Onondaga lake, thence in\na westerly direction passing in the vicinities of Warners, Memphis,\nJordan and Weedsport, crossing the New York Central and West Shore\nrailroads in the vicinity of the village of Port Byron, thence\nsouthwesterly crossing the Seneca river in the vicinity of May's Point,\nthence westerly north of the villages of Seneca Falls and Waterloo and\npassing in the vicinities of West Junius, Phelps, Clifton Springs and\nManchester, passing north of Victor and in the vicinity of Fisher and\nSeverance, continuing westerly to a point in the vicinity of the city of\nBatavia, thence westerly to a point in the vicinity of Williamsville,\nincluding a spur to Main street, in the vicinity of Kensington Avenue in\nthe town of Amherst, thence southerly generally parallel to and west of\nUnion road to a point south of the Lehigh Valley railroad tracks, thence\nsouthwesterly to a point at the junction of the Erie and Niagara\nsections in the vicinity of the crossing of Dingens street and the\nLehigh Valley railroad in the town of Cheektowaga.\n  6. The Erie section. Starting at its junction with the Niagara section\nat a point in the vicinity of the crossing of Dingens street and the\nLehigh Valley railroad in the town of Cheektowaga, thence southerly\ngenerally paralleling the Lehigh Valley railroad to Cazenovia creek and\nextending southerly and southwesterly to a point north of the village of\nHamburg, thence in a southwesterly direction generally paralleling the\nexisting Southwestern Boulevard to a point near the village of Irving,\nthence bypassing the village of Silver Creek to the south, thence\nextending in a general southwesterly direction to the Pennsylvania state\nline on a location lying in the vicinity of United States route number\ntwenty and state touring route number five.\n  7. The New England section. Beginning at or near the point of\nintersection of the Bronx and Pelham parkway and the extension of\nBruckner boulevard in New York city, extending in a generally northerly\ndirection to a point on or near east two hundred twenty-second street,\nthence generally in an eastern direction to the New York\ncity-Westchester county line north of Pelham Bay park, thence generally\nin a northeasterly direction through the town of Pelham, the city of New\nRochelle, the town of Mamaroneck, the village of Mamaroneck, the town of\nHarrison, the city of Rye, the town of Rye and the village of Port\nChester, to a point on the New York-Connecticut state line.\n  8. The Niagara section. Starting at the junction of the Erie and the\nOntario sections at a point in the vicinity of the crossing of Dingens\nstreet and the Lehigh Valley railroad in the town of Cheektowaga, thence\ngenerally in a westerly direction to Erie street in the city of Buffalo,\nthence continuing in a general northwesterly direction to the Front,\nthence through the Front and north between Niagara street and the ship\ncanal to the right of way of the abandoned Erie canal near the northern\nend of such ship canal, thence generally along such right of way,\ndeviating therefrom to make a connection with the easterly approach of\nthe South Grand Island bridge, thence across the Niagara river,\nutilizing the existing South Grand Island bridge or constructing another\nbridge parallel to such bridge, or both, thence along or parallel to\nexisting Grand Island boulevard, across the Niagara river, utilizing the\nexisting North Grand Island bridge, or constructing another bridge\nparallel to such bridge, or both.\n  9. The Berkshire section. Starting at a point or points on the\nCatskill section northeast of Becker's Corners, thence easterly to a\npoint on the West bank of the Hudson river, which point shall be more\nthan fifteen miles north of the Rip Van Winkle bridge, thence across a\nbridge to be constructed by the authority and which crossing shall be\nknown as "The Castleton-on-Hudson Bridge"; and thence generally in a\nsoutheasterly direction and passing in the vicinity of the hamlets of\nBrookview, North Chatham, Old Chatham, and East Chatham to a point on\nthe New York-Massachusetts boundary line near the hamlet of State Line.\n  The thruway constructed along the routes designated in this section\nshall be known as "The Governor Thomas E. Dewey Thruway".\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>