<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2016-04-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="357-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_357_A">
        <num>357-A</num>
        <heading>State police and state payment for services</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 357-a. State police and state payment for services. 1. Enforcement\nassistance provided by the division of state police at the request of\nthe authority shall be reimbursed by the authority to the division of\nstate police from the general reserve fund established by the authority\nunder its agreement with bondholders, after payment of any amounts due\non any bonds or notes of the authority. The comptroller is hereby\nauthorized and directed to deposit to the New York state thruway\nauthority account, revenues received from the authority as reimbursement\nfor personal service expenses including general state charges. In\naddition, the authority shall reimburse the division of state police for\nnon-personal service expenses connected with such assistance. Such\nreimbursement shall be made from such general reserve fund. The\nauthority shall deposit said reimbursement funds for non-personal\nservice expenses to the credit of the division of state police. No\npayments made by the authority under this subsection shall be deemed\noperating expenses of the authority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>