<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="357-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-357-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_357_B">
        <num>357-B</num>
        <heading>Sharing employees, services and resources</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 357-b. Sharing employees, services and resources. A shared services\nagreement may be executed between the authority and the department only\nfor an emergency situation or extreme weather conditions, to share\nemployees, services or resources as deemed appropriate including, but\nnot limited to, for the performance of work and activities by the\ndepartment on the facilities and property under the jurisdiction of the\nauthority, and for the performance of work and activities by the\nauthority on the facilities and property under the jurisdiction of the\ndepartment. Such agreement or any project undertaken pursuant to such\nagreement shall not be deemed to impair the rights of bondholders and\nmay provide for, but not be limited to, the management, supervision and\ndirection of such employees' performance of such services. Such\nagreement shall provide that the term shall not be longer than ten days.\nAll shared employees shall remain employees of their respective\nemployers and all applicable collectively bargained agreements shall\nremain in effect for the entire length of the shared service agreement.\nFurther, such shared services agreement shall not amend, repeal or\nreplace the terms of any agreement that is collectively negotiated\nbetween an employer and an employee organization, including an agreement\nor interest arbitration award made pursuant to article fourteen of the\ncivil service law.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>