<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3573"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3573"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3573"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3573/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3573/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3573/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3573/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3573">
        <num>3573</num>
        <heading>Moneys received; department of health</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3573.  Moneys received; department of health.  Notwithstanding any\nprovision of this article or any other provision of law to the contrary,\nso long as bonds issued by the dormitory authority on or before March\nthirty-first, two thousand twenty-five to make loans to the department\nof health of the state of New York to finance state hospital facilities\nlisted in section four hundred three of the public health law remain\noutstanding as defined in the bond resolution under which such bonds\nwere issued, the following provisions shall be applicable:\n  1.  All moneys derived or resulting from the care, maintenance and\ntreatment of patients at Roswell Park Cancer Institute or any other\nhealth facility owned or operated by the corporation or a subsidiary\nthereof, together with moneys received from fees, including parking\nfees, refunds, reimbursements, sales of property and miscellaneous\nreceipts of the corporation or its subsidiaries attributable to Roswell\nPark Cancer Institute and other revenues of the corporation or its\nsubsidiaries (other than gifts, grants, bequests and moneys received\nunder research contracts, and clinical practice income received pursuant\nto a clinical practice plan established pursuant to subdivision fourteen\nof section two hundred six of the public health law) and any other net\nrevenues received by the corporation from any of its subsidiaries or\nother entities shall be moneys of the department of health, whether\ncollected or received by such corporation or any of its subsidiaries,\nand shall be paid into the health income fund as required by section\nfour hundred nine of the public health law.  Such corporation or any\nsubsidiary created hereunder shall receive any moneys of the department\nof health described herein as agent of the department of health and\nshall pay such moneys to the commissioner for deposit into the health\nincome fund.\n  2.  Neither the corporation nor any subsidiary thereof shall create or\npermit to be created any pledge, assignment, encumbrance or security\ninterest in any moneys of the department of health required to be\ndeposited or maintained in the department of health income fund pursuant\nto section four hundred nine of the public health law or any agreement\nbetween the department of health and the dormitory authority, including\ninvestments and proceeds thereof, or the right of the department of\nhealth to receive or collect the same.\n  3.  The state shall not give, grant, sell or convey, loan, license the\nuse of or lease any property to the corporation or any subsidiary\nthereof except in compliance with the terms of any lease, sublease or\nother agreement between the dormitory authority and the department of\nhealth of the state of New York.\n  4.  Neither the corporation nor any subsidiary thereof shall take any\naction, or suffer any action to be taken, which would adversely affect\nthe exclusion of interest on any of the bonds issued by the dormitory\nauthority to finance facilities for the department of health of the\nstate of New York from gross income for purposes of federal income\ntaxation.  The department of health shall provide oversight of the\ncorporation's adherence to this subdivision as more fully described in\nthe agreement set forth in subdivision two of section four hundred three\nof the public health law.\n  5.  No power conferred upon the corporation or any subsidiary thereof\nby this article or any other provision of law shall be exercised in a\nmanner that is inconsistent with the terms of any lease, sublease or\nother agreement between the dormitory authority and the department of\nhealth of the state of New York.\n  6. No lien granted by the corporation or any subsidiary thereof\npursuant to this title shall give any lienor the right to compel the\nsale of any health facility which is currently owned by the state or the\ndormitory authority and which comprises the Roswell Park Cancer\nInstitute.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>