<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3601"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3601"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3601"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3601/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3601/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3601">
        <num>3601</num>
        <heading>Legislative findings and purpose</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3601. Legislative findings and purpose. The legislature hereby finds\nand declares as follows:\n  1. Currently, the Clifton-Fine Hospital is a public hospital owned and\noperated by the town of Clifton and the town of Fine.\n  2. The needs of the residents of the state of New York and of the\ntowns of Clifton and Fine in St. Lawrence County can best be served by\nthe operation of the Clifton-Fine Hospital by a public benefit\ncorporation having the legal, financial and managerial flexibility to\ntake full advantage of opportunities and challenges presented by the\nevolving health care environment.\n  3. In order to accomplish the purposes recited in this section to\nprovide health care services and health facilities for the benefit of\nthe residents of the state of New York and the towns of Clifton and Fine\nincluding persons in need of health care services without the ability to\npay as required by law, a public benefit corporation to be known as the\nClifton-Fine health care corporation shall be created to provide such\nservices and facilities and to otherwise carry out such purposes; that\nthe creation and operation of the Clifton-Fine health care corporation,\nas hereinafter provided, is in all respects for the benefit of the\npeople of the state of New York and of the towns of Clifton and Fine and\nis a state, municipal and public purpose; and that the exercise by such\ncorporation of the functions, powers and duties as hereinafter provided\nconstitutes the performance of an essential public and governmental\nfunction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>