<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-361-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-361-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2015-11-27" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="361-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-361-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-361-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-361-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-361-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_361_A">
        <num>361-A</num>
        <heading>Restriction and regulation of advertising devices</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To provide for maximum visibility along the thruway system and\nconnecting roads or highways;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To prevent unreasonable distraction of operators of motor\nvehicles;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To prevent confusion with regard to traffic lights, signs or\nsignals or otherwise interfere with the effectiveness of traffic\nregulations;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To preserve and enhance the natural scenic beauty or the aesthetic\nfeatures of the thruway system and adjacent areas;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>To promote maximum safety, comfort and well-being of the users of\nthe thruway.\n  4. To effectuate the purposes of this section, the authority may limit\nthe application of any regulation adopted hereunder to exclude or\ninclude, in whole or in part:\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Specified areas of the thruway system based upon use, population\ndensity, nature of the surrounding community, special conditions\nprevailing therein, or such other factors as may make differentiation or\nseparate classification or regulation necessary, proper or desirable;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Particular types or classes of advertising devices based upon\nsize, design, lighting or such other factors as may make differentiation\nor separate classification or regulation necessary, proper or desirable;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The erection or maintenance of advertising devices on particular\nsections or portions of the thruway system.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of this section, the\nauthority shall permit the erection of not more than nine advertising\nbillboard signs in the city of New Rochelle along interstate route\nninety-five where the location and erection of such signs are:\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_361_A__subsec_d__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>consistent with and part of an urban renewal program which\ndecreases the total number of advertising billboard signs in the renewal\narea;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_361_A__subsec_d__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>approved by such city;\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_361_A__subsec_d__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>part of the subject of a United States District Court settlement\norder regarding the regulation of such signs within such city; and\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_361_A__subsec_d__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>consistent with the size, lighting, spacing and all other\nrequirements of federal law, including those established in the\nagreements entered into by the state pursuant to sections eighty-six and\neighty-eight of the highway law.\n  5. Application for permits or renewals thereof shall be on forms\nprescribed by the authority and shall contain such information as the\nauthority may require. The authority may by regulation adopt, modify,\namend or repeal permit application fees, annual permit fees and permit\nrenewal fees, provided, however, that such fees shall not exceed the\nadvertising device fees established by regulation by the commissioner of\ntransportation. Each permit shall be valid for a period to be\nestablished by the authority and may be renewed from time to time for\nsuch periods, as established by the authority, within thirty days of the\nexpiration date thereof upon payment to the authority of the renewal\nfee.\n  6. The permit or renewal thereof shall be revocable at a...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Advertising devices which are to be erected or maintained on\nproperty for the purpose of setting forth or indicating\n</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_361_A__subsec_a__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name and address of the owner, lessee or occupant of such\nproperty, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_361_A__subsec_a__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The name or type of business or profession conducted on such\nproperty, or\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_361_A__subsec_a__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Information required or authorized by law to be posted or\ndisplayed thereon.\n</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Advertising devices which are not visible from any traveled\nportion of the thruway system;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Advertising devices indicating the sale or leasing of the property\nupon which they are placed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_361_A__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Directional or other official signs and signals erected or\nmaintained by the state or other public agency having jurisdiction.\n  8. Nothing in this section shall apply with respect to any property\nwhich is owned or leased by the state of New York or any agency thereof\nor with respect to which the state of New York or any agency thereof has\nor shall have a valid easement or covenant with the owner thereof\nconcerning the restriction, removal or prohibition of advertising\ndevices.\n  9. Nothing in this section shall be construed to abrogate or affect\nthe provisions of any municipal ordinance, regulation or resolution\nwhich are more restrictive concerning advertising devices than the\nprovisions of this section or of the regulations adopted hereunder.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>