<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3627"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3627"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3627"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3627/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3627/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3627/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3627/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3627">
        <num>3627</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3627. Definitions. As used or referred to in this title, unless a\ndifferent meaning clearly appears from the context:\n  1. "Board" means the board of directors of the corporation established\nby section thirty-six hundred twenty-eight of this title.\n  2. "Bonds" means the bonds, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness\nissued by the corporation pursuant to this title, and the provisions of\nthis title relating to bonds and bondholders shall apply with equal\nforce and effect to notes and noteholders, respectively, unless the\ncontext otherwise clearly requires.\n  3. "Corporation" means the public benefit corporation created by\nsection thirty-six hundred twenty-eight of this title, known as the Erie\nCounty Medical Center Corporation.\n  4. "County" means the county of Erie.\n  5. "Health facility" means a building, structure, or unit, or any\nimprovement to real property, including all necessary and usual\nattendant and related equipment, facilities, or fixtures, or any part or\nparts thereof, or any combination or combinations thereof, including,\nbut not limited to, a general hospital, psychiatric hospital, ambulatory\nclinic or center, chronic disease hospital, nursing home, extended-care\nfacility, dispensary, or laboratory, or any other related facility, or\nany combination of the foregoing, constructed, acquired, or otherwise\nprovided by or for the use of the corporation or the county in providing\nmedical research and health and medical services to the public.\n  6. "Director" means a voting director appointed to the corporation\npursuant to section thirty-six hundred twenty-eight of this title.\n  7. "Network" shall mean the Erie County Medical Center healthcare\nnetwork.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>