<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3632"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3632"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3632"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3632/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3632/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3632/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3632/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3632">
        <num>3632</num>
        <heading>Transfer of property; relationship with county; certain gifts, loans, and guarantees by the county</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3632__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The county may give, grant,\nsell, convey, lend, license the use of, or lease to the corporation, and\nthe corporation may accept any property (except monies appropriated by\nthe county and payable to the corporation pursuant to subdivision three\nof this section) which are useful in connection with the exercise by the\ncorporation of any of its powers under this title in order to transfer\nthe facilities and operations of the Erie County Medical Center\nhealthcare network to the corporation by agreement between the county\nand the corporation and any subsequent renewal or amendment thereof, by\nlocal law adopted by a majority vote of the Erie county legislature,\nnotwithstanding any general, special, or local law, ordinance,\nresolution, or charter.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3632__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any such gift, grant, sale, conveyance, loan, license, or lease\nshall be upon such terms and conditions, for such consideration, if any,\nand for such term or terms of years, subject to the rights of the\nholders of any bonds, as the corporation and the county may agree. No\nreal property of the county consisting of any health facility operated\non the effective date of this title by the Erie County Medical Center\nhealthcare network shall be transferred to the corporation in fee,\nexcept under such restrictions regarding rights of first refusal in\nfavor of the county and subject to a right of reverter in the event that\nthe corporation should cease to use such property for the provision of\nresearch, education, and health care, or other rights, to repurchase the\nproperty as the Erie county legislature shall approve by act, and\nsubject to a restrictive covenant prohibiting the corporation from\npledging or mortgaging the fee interest in the property. In the event\nthat the county gives, grants, sells, conveys, lends, licenses, or\nleases any facilities to the corporation, the county may contract with\nthe corporation to lease, borrow, license, operate, maintain, manage,\nand provide services for such facilities upon such terms and conditions\nand for such term or terms of years, subject to the rights of holders of\nbonds, as the corporation and the county may agree. The corporation, in\nfurtherance of any purchase, conveyance, or lease of any property or\nfacility from the county, may assume the primary responsibility for the\npayment of the principal and interest on any bonds or notes issued by\nthe county for such property or facility.\n  2. The county may acquire by purchase, grant, lease, gift, or\ncondemnation, pursuant to the eminent domain procedure law, real\nproperty in the name of the county for any corporate purpose of the\ncorporation.\n  3. In addition to any other powers granted to it by law and consistent\nwith the constitution and other provision...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3632__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding any general, special, or local law or charter\nprovisions to the contrary, the county of Erie shall have the power and\nis hereby authorized, pursuant to section seven of article seventeen of\nthe state constitution, to lend its money or credit to or in aid of the\ncorporation or any subsidiary thereof for the purpose of providing\nhealth related facilities or hospital facilities for the prevention,\ndiagnosis, or treatment of human disease, pain, injury, disability,\ndeformity, or physical condition, and for facilities incidental or\nappurtenant thereto, as may be prescribed by law. The county is hereby\nauthorized to prescribe such facilities by local law. The corporation or\nany such subsidiary thereof, as a condition to any such loan of money or\ncredit, shall enter into a regulatory agreement with the county as to\nits charges, profits, dividends, and disposition of its property or\nfranchises, which agreement shall be binding and enforceable by the\ncounty insofar as such agreement regulates such charges, profits,\ndividends, and disposition of property. The county may elect in such\nregulatory agreement to refrain from exercising all or any portion of\nits authority to so regulate such charges, profits, dividends, and\ndisposition of property to the extent such charges, profits, dividends,\nand disposition of property are regulated by the state or any agency\nthereof. The county shall authorize such regulatory agreement by local\nlaw.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3632__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In pursuance of the authority granted in this title, the county of\nErie shall have the power and is hereby authorized, from time to time,\nto issue its bonds, notes, or other obligations in such principal\namounts as it shall deem necessary, after taking into account other\nmonies which may be available for the purposes set forth in this title.\nSuch bonds, notes, or obligations shall be issued for the purpose of\nmaking loans to the corporation or any subsidiary thereof, paying\ninterest on such bonds, notes, or other obligations, establishment of\nreserves to secure such notes, bonds, or other obligations, and paying\nall other obligations and expenditures incidental to and necessary or\nconvenient for the making of such loans. Such bonds, notes, or\nobligations shall be issued in accordance with the applicable provisions\nof this chapter, the local finance law, and applicable local laws.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3632__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any guarantee by the county made pursuant to the authority granted\nin this section shall be authorized by act or acts of the county in the\nsame manner as such act or acts authorizing the issuance of bonds of the\ncounty for the purposes for which such guarantee is undertaken.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3632__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The county is also authorized to enact laws governing the\nconditions under which such loans, commitments, and guarantees shall be\nmade.\n  7. For purposes of subdivision four of paragraph a of section 25.00 of\nthe local finance law, amounts to be derived by the county of Erie from\nthe corporation, or any subsidiary thereof, shall be included in the\nterm "other income".\n  8.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3632__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other state or local law\nto the contrary, including, but not limited to, sections six-n and six-j\nof the general municipal law, with the approval of the Erie county\nlegislature, amounts deposited for or on behalf of the Erie County\nMedical Center healthcare network in the liability and casualty and\nworkers' compensation reserve funds established by the county pursuant\nto such sections of the general municipal law, and investment earnings\nthereof, may be withdrawn by the county from such funds and transferred\nto the corporation and shall be used by the corporation for the purposes\nfor which such funds were established.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3632__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No amounts shall be withdrawn and transferred to the corporation\npursuant to this subdivision unless, prior to such withdrawal or\ntransfer, the corporation has agreed in writing to indemnify and hold\nharmless the county, and provide defense, for all claims, cases,\nproceedings, actions, or other matters against the county arising out of\nthe properties, facilities, operations, or employees of the corporation,\nwhether commenced before or after the date of transfer of such amounts,\nand to provide such other security for such obligation as the county may\nreasonably require.\n  9. The county shall be responsible for the payment of all outstanding\nbonded indebtedness of the Erie County Medical Center healthcare network\nthat was accumulated prior to the creation of the public benefit\ncorporation.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>