<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3644"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3644"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3644"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3644/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3644/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3644/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3644/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3644">
        <num>3644</num>
        <heading>Transfer of applications, proceedings, approvals, and permits</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3644. Transfer of applications, proceedings, approvals, and permits.\n1. Any application, review, or process in relation to or in furtherance\nof the purposes of or contemplated by this title heretofore filed or\nundertaken, or any proceeding heretofore commenced, or any\ndetermination, finding, or award made, by the county or by the county\nwith the federal government, the state department of health, or any\nother public corporation shall inure to and for the benefit of the\ncorporation to the same extent and in the same manner as if the\ncorporation has been a party to such application, review, process, or\nproceeding from its inception, and the corporation shall be deemed a\nparty thereto, to the extent not prohibited by any federal law. Any\nlicense, approval, permit, determination, finding, award, or decision\nheretofore or hereafter issued or granted pursuant to or as a result of\nany such application, review, process, or proceeding shall inure to the\nbenefit of and be binding upon the corporation and shall be assigned and\ntransferred by the county to the corporation, unless such assignment and\ntransfer is prohibited by federal law.\n  2. All such applications, proceedings, licenses, approvals, permits,\ndeterminations, findings, awards, and decisions shall further inure to\nand for the benefit of and be binding upon any person leasing,\nacquiring, financing, constructing, maintaining, operating, using, or\noccupying any facility transferred by the county to the corporation\npursuant to this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>