<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3653"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3653"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2022-04-15" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3653"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3653/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3653/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3653/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3653/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3653">
        <num>3653</num>
        <heading>Administration of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3653. Administration of the authority. 1. The authority shall be\nadministered by seven directors appointed by the governor. Of the seven\ndirectors, one each shall be appointed on the written recommendation of\nthe majority leader of the state senate, the speaker of the state\nassembly and the state comptroller, respectively. Two of the members\nappointed directly by the governor and the members appointed on the\nrecommendation of the majority leader of the state senate, the\nrecommendation of the speaker of the state assembly and the\nrecommendation of the state comptroller shall be residents of the county\nof Nassau. Each director shall be appointed for a term of four years,\nprovided however, that two of the directors first appointed by the\ngovernor shall serve for a term ending December thirty-first, two\nthousand four, and the five other directors first appointed shall serve\nfor the following terms: the directors appointed on recommendation of\nthe majority leader of the state senate, the speaker of the state\nassembly and the state comptroller shall serve for a term ending\nDecember thirty-first, two thousand five and the two remaining directors\nfirst appointed directly by the governor shall serve for a term ending\non December thirty-first, two thousand six. Each director shall hold\noffice until his or her successor has been appointed and qualified.\nThereafter each director shall serve a term of four years, except that\nany director appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve only until the\nexpiration of his or her predecessor's term.\n  2. The governor shall designate a chairperson and a vice-chairperson\nfrom among the directors. The chairperson shall preside over all\nmeetings of the directors and shall have such other duties as the\ndirectors may prescribe. The vice-chairperson shall preside over all\nmeetings of the directors in the absence of the chairperson and shall\nhave such other duties as the directors may prescribe.\n  3. The directors of the authority shall serve without salary, but each\ndirector shall be reimbursed for actual necessary expenses incurred in\nthe performance of such director's official duties as a director of the\nauthority.\n  4. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, no officer, member or\nemployee of the state of New York, any city, county, town or village,\nany governmental entity operating any public school or college, any\nschool district or any other public agency or instrumentality which\nexercises governmental powers under the laws of the state, shall forfeit\nhis or her office or employment by reason of his or her acceptance of\nappointment as a director, officer or employee of the authority, nor\nshall service as such director, officer or employee of the authority be\ndeemed incompatible or in conflict with such office or employment.\n  5. Four directors shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any\nbusiness or the exercise of any power of the authority. No action shall\nbe taken by the authority except pursuant to a favorable vote of at\nleast four directors participating in a meeting at which such action is\ntaken.\n  6. The authority shall appoint a treasurer and may appoint officers\nand agents as it may require and prescribe their duties.\n  7. At least annually, commencing no more than one year after the date\non which authority bonds are first issued, the authority shall report to\nthe county executive, county legislature, the county comptroller, the\ndirector of the budget, the speaker of the assembly, the temporary\npresident of the senate and the state comptroller on the costs financed\nby the authority and the amount of such financing for each such cost\nover the past year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>