<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3666"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3666"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3666"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3666/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3666/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3666/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3666/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3666">
        <num>3666</num>
        <heading>2000 fiscal year budget modification</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3666__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the county executive, after approval by the legislature, shall have\nsubmitted to the authority a modification to the county's budget for the\n2000 fiscal year, as in effect on May tenth, two thousand; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3666__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nauthority shall have determined that such modification when implemented\nwill ensure a reduction of the projected gap, through recurring or\nnonrecurring actions, for the 2000 fiscal year and, together with any\nbudget modifications prior to May tenth, two thousand, through recurring\nactions, for the three next succeeding fiscal years, in an amount not\nless than fifty million dollars per year.\n  2. In order that such budget modification be effective on or before\nJune thirtieth, two thousand, the county executive shall within seven\ndays following the effective date of this title submit a proposed\nmodification to the legislature. Within seven days thereafter, the\nlegislature shall approve such modification or a substitute\nmodification. Upon approval by the legislature, the county executive\nshall submit such modification to the authority. Not later than ten days\nafter such budget modification shall have been submitted to the\nauthority, the authority shall approve or disapprove such modification,\nprovided that the authority may approve such modification only upon its\ndetermination that such modification when implemented will ensure such\nreduction of the projected gap for each fiscal year as required by\nsubdivision one of this section.\n  3. In the event the authority shall disapprove such budget\nmodification based on disapproval of certain actions or assumptions, the\nauthority shall promptly thereafter notify the county executive of its\nreasons.  The county executive shall thereafter, after approval by the\nlegislature, resubmit a budget modification, based on actions or\nassumptions other than those that have been disapproved by the\nauthority, for consideration by the authority and in sufficient time for\nthe authority to have a seven day review period prior to June thirtieth,\ntwo thousand.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>