<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-381"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-381"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="381"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-381/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-381/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-381/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-381/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_381">
        <num>381</num>
        <heading>Further additional powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_381__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to\nissue bonds and notes and to incur obligations secured by the moneys as\nprovided in the service contracts authorized pursuant to section\nfourteen of the chapter of the laws of nineteen hundred ninety-one which\nenacted this section; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_381__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to make available the proceeds from the\nsale of such bonds and notes, net of all costs to the authority in\nconnection therewith, to provide moneys to the authority to achieve the\nsame corporate purposes as set forth in section three hundred sixty-five\nof this chapter. The authority is further authorized to issue such\nobligations in an aggregate principal amount not to exceed eighty\nmillion dollars, exclusive of the principal amount of bonds, notes or\nother obligations issued and applied</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_381__subsec_b__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to fund any related debt\nservice fund, or other reserve funds as may be needed,</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_381__subsec_b__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to provide\ncapitalized interest, and</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_381__subsec_b__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>to provide fees and other charges and\nexpenses, including underwriters' discount and the purchase of any\ncredit or liquidity enhancement facilities, related to the issuance of\nbonds, notes or other obligations and the maintenance of such reserves,\nall as determined by the authority and excluding bonds, notes or other\nobligations issued to refund or otherwise repay bonds, notes or other\nobligations theretofore issued pursuant to this section. In computing\nthe total principal amount of bonds, notes or other obligations that may\nat any time be issued for any purpose under this section, the amount of\nthe outstanding bonds, notes or other obligations that constitutes\ninterest under the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as\namended to the effective date of this section, shall be excluded.\nProvided, however, that upon any refunding or repayment, except in\nconnection with the termination of the existence of the authority or if\notherwise authorized by the legislature, th...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>