<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3862"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3862"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3862"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3862/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3862/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3862/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3862/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3862">
        <num>3862</num>
        <heading>Bonds, notes or other obligations of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to pay reasonable costs of issuance, as\ndetermined by the authority,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to establish debt service reserve\nfunds,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to refund or advance refund any outstanding bonds or notes of\nthe city or the authority, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>as cash flow borrowings shall not\ncount against the above limit on outstanding bonds, notes or other\nobligations of the authority, nor shall any accretion of principal of\nbonds that would constitute interest under the Internal Revenue Code of\n1986, as amended, count against such limit; provided, however, that the\naggregate principal amount of cash flow borrowings outstanding at any\none time shall not exceed one hundred forty-five million dollars.\n  2. The authority may issue bonds, notes or other obligations to refund\nbonds, notes or other obligations previously issued, but in no event\nshall the final maturity of any bonds, notes or other obligations of the\nauthority be later than June thirtieth, two thousand thirty-seven. No\nbond of the authority shall mature more than thirty years from the date\nof its issue, or after June thirtieth, two thousand thirty-seven,\nwhichever date is earlier.\n  3. Bonds, notes or other obligations of the authority may be issued,\namortized, redeemed and refunded without regard to the provisions of the\nlocal finance law.\n  4. The directors may delegate to the chairperson or other director or\nofficer of the authority the power to set the financial terms of bonds,\nnotes or other obligations.\n  5. The authority in its sole discretion shall determine that the\nissuance of its bonds, notes or other obligations is appropriate. Bonds,\nnotes or other obligations shall be authorized by resolution of the\nauthority. Bonds shall bear interest at such fixed or variable rates and\nshall be in such denominations, be in such form, either coupon or\nregistered, be sold at such public or private sale, be executed in such\nmanner, be denominated in United States currency, be payable in such\nmedium of payment, at such place and be subject to such terms of\nredemption as the authority may provide in such resolution. No bonds,\nnotes or other obligations of the authority may be sold at private sale\nunless such sale and the terms thereof ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the state comptroller where such sale is not to the state\ncomptroller, or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the director of the budget, where such sale is to\nthe state comptroller.\n  6. Any resolution or resolutions authorizing bonds, notes or other\nobligations or any issue of bonds, notes or other obligations may\ncontain provisions which may be a part of the contract with the holders\nof the bonds, notes or other obligations thereby authorized as to:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\npledging all or part of the authority's revenues, together with any\nother moneys, securities or contracts, to secure the payment of the\nbonds, notes or other obligations, subject to such agreements with\nbondholders as may then exist;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the setting aside of reserves and the\ncreation of sinking funds and the regulation and disposition thereof;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>limitations on the purposes to which the proceeds from the sale of\nbonds, notes or other obligations may be applied;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>limitations on the\nissuance of additional bonds, notes or other obligations, the terms upon\nwhich additional bonds, notes or other obligations may be issued and\nsecured and the refunding of bonds, notes or other obligations;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the\nprocedure, if any, by which the terms of any contract with bondholders\nmay be amended or abrogated, including the proportion of bondholders\nwhich must consent thereto and the manner in which such consent may be\ngiven;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>vesting in a trustee or trustees such properties, rights,\npowers and duties in trust as the authority may determine, which may\ninclude any or all of the rights, powers and duties of the trustee\nappointed by the bondholders pursuant to section thirty-eight hundred\nsixty-three of this title and limiting or abrogating the rights of the\nbondholders to appoint a trustee under such section or limiting the\nrights, duties and powers of such trustee; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3862__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>defining the acts or\nomissions of the authority to act which may constitute a default in the\nobligations and duties of the authority to the bondholders and providing\nfor the rights and remedies of the bondholders in the event of such\ndefault, including as a matter of right the appointment of a receiver;\nprovided, however, that such acts or omissions of the authority to act\nwhich may constitute a default and such rights and remedies shall not be\ninconsistent with the general laws of the state and other provisions of\nthis title.\n  7. In addition to the powers conferred upon the authority in this\nsection to secure its bonds, notes or other obligations, the authority\nshall have power in connection with the issuance of bonds, notes or\nother obligations to enter into such agreements for the benefit of the\nbondholders as the authority may deem necessary, convenient or desirable\nconcerning the use or disposition of its revenues or other moneys,\nincluding the entrusting, pledging or creation of any other security\ninterest in any such revenues, moneys and the doing of any act,\nincluding refraining from doing any act, which the authority would have\nthe right to do in the absence of such agreements. The authority shall\nhave power to enter into amendments of any such agreements within the\npowers granted to the authority by this title and to perform such\nagreements. The provisions of any such agreements may be made a part of\nthe contract with the holders of bonds, notes or other obligations of\nthe authority.\n  7-a. Whenever a series of bonds, notes or other obligations of the\nauthority is issued pursuant to this section for purposes other than\ndeficit financing authorized by section thirty-eight hundred fifty-seven\nof this title, the payment of the proceeds of such series of bonds,\nnotes or other obligations to the city may be, at the request of the\nauthority, evidenced by obligations of the city issued in accordance\nwith applicable provisions of the...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>