<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3864"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3864"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3864"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3864/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3864/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3864/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3864/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3864">
        <num>3864</num>
        <heading>Intercept of city tax revenues, school district tax revenues and state aid revenues</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_3864__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the period beginning upon the\neffective date of this title through June thirtieth, two thousand\nthirty-seven, city tax revenues and,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3864__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>for the period beginning July\nfirst, two thousand four, and ending June thirtieth, two thousand\nthirty-seven, during which the county sets aside net collections for\neducational purposes pursuant to the authority of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3864__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection twelve hundred sixty-two of the tax law, school district tax\nrevenues. During the period beginning on the effective date of this\ntitle through June thirtieth, two thousand thirty-seven, the county\nshall impose such taxes pursuant to the authority of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3864__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection twelve hundred ten of the tax law at a rate of no less than\nthree percent. In addition, during such periods, respectively, the state\ncomptroller shall pay to the authority</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3864__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>city tax revenues pursuant to\nthe then current agreement under subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3864__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twelve\nhundred sixty-two of the tax law among the county and the cities in the\ncounty and (ii) school district tax revenues; provided however, in the\nevent that such agreement among the county and such cities shall have\nexpired or been terminated during such period, notwithstanding any other\nprovision of general, special or local law to the contrary, the state\ncomptroller shall make such payments of city tax revenues to the\nauthority pursuant to the provisions of paragraph two of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_3864__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\nof section twelve hundred sixty-two of the tax law.\n  2. Commencing on the effective date of this title, and until June\nthirtieth, two thousand thirty-seven, the state comptroller shall pay\nstate aid revenues to the authority.\n  3. The city shall have no right, title, or interest in the city tax\nrevenues or state aid revenues paid to the authority pursuant to this\nsection; and the school district shall have no right, title, or interest\nin the school district tax revenues paid to the authority pursuant to\nthis section.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>