<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3953"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3953"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="3953"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3953/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3953/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3953/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-3953/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_3953">
        <num>3953</num>
        <heading>Administration of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 3953. Administration of the authority. 1. The authority shall be\nadministered by seven directors appointed by the governor. Of the seven\ndirectors, one each shall be appointed on the written recommendation of\nthe temporary president of the state senate, the speaker of the state\nassembly and the state comptroller, respectively. One member appointed\ndirectly by the governor and the members appointed on the recommendation\nof the temporary president of the state senate, the recommendation of\nthe speaker of the state assembly and the recommendation of the state\ncomptroller shall be residents of the county. Each director shall be\nappointed for a term of four years, provided however, that two of the\ndirectors first appointed by the governor shall serve for a term ending\nDecember thirty-first, two thousand nine, and the remaining five\ndirectors first appointed shall serve for the following terms: the\ndirectors appointed on recommendation of the temporary president of the\nstate senate, the speaker of the state assembly and the state\ncomptroller shall serve for a term ending December thirty-first, two\nthousand ten and the two remaining directors first appointed directly by\nthe governor shall serve for a term ending on December thirty-first, two\nthousand eleven. Each director shall hold office until his or her\nsuccessor has been appointed and qualified. Thereafter each director\nshall serve a term of four years, except that any director appointed to\nfill a vacancy shall serve only until the expiration of his or her\npredecessor's term.\n  2. The governor shall designate a chairperson and a vice-chairperson\nfrom among the directors. The chairperson shall preside over all\nmeetings of the directors and shall have such other duties as the\ndirectors may prescribe. The vice-chairperson shall preside over all\nmeetings of the directors in the absence of the chairperson and shall\nhave such other duties as the directors may prescribe.\n  3. The directors of the authority shall serve without salary, but each\ndirector shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred\nin the performance of such director's official duties as a director of\nthe authority.\n  4. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of any general, special\nor local law, ordinance, resolution or charter, no officer, member or\nemployee of the state, any city, county, town or village, any\ngovernmental entity operating any public school or college, any school\ndistrict or any other public agency or instrumentality which exercises\ngovernmental powers under the laws of the state, shall forfeit his or\nher office or employment by reason of his or her acceptance of\nappointment as a director, officer or employee of the authority; nor\nshall service as such director, officer or employee of the authority be\ndeemed incompatible or in conflict with such office or employment.\n  5. Four directors shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any\nbusiness or the exercise of any power of the authority. No action shall\nbe taken by the authority except pursuant to a favorable vote of at\nleast four directors participating in a meeting at which such action is\ntaken.\n  6. The authority shall appoint a treasurer and may appoint officers\nand agents as it may require and prescribe their duties.\n  7. At least annually, commencing no more than one year after the date\non which authority bonds, notes or other obligations are first issued,\nthe authority shall report to the county executive, legislature,\ncomptroller, the director of the budget, the chair of the state senate\nfinance committee, the chair of the state assembly ways and means\ncommittee and the state comptroller on the amount of financing and the\ncost savings for the county over the past year.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>