<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-51"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-51"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-04-19" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="51"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-51/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-51/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_51">
        <num>51</num>
        <heading>Powers, functions and duties of the New York state public authorities control board; limitations</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_51__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>seven days following the receipt by the\nstate comptroller of such application or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_51__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the receipt by the board of\nthe state comptroller's comments on the application or his consent to an\nearlier determination by the board. Reference to the state comptroller\nin this subdivision shall include any authorized representative of the\nstate comptroller.\n  3. The board may approve applications only upon its determination\nthat, with relation to any proposed project, there are commitments of\nfunds sufficient to finance the acquisition and construction of such\nproject.  In determining the sufficiency of commitments of funds, the\nboard may consider commitments of funds, projections of fees or other\nrevenues and security, which may, in the discretion of the board,\ninclude collateral security sufficient to retire a proposed indebtedness\nor protect or indemnify against potential liabilities proposed to be\nundertaken. A copy of such determination shall be submitted to the chief\nexecutive officer of the appropriate public benefit corporation and the\nstate comptroller.\n  3-a. The board shall not approve recovery act bonds applications\nprovided by the state of New York municipal bond bank agency unless the\nboard finds sufficient interest rate and other savings to each\nparticipating municipality.\n  4. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, the\nrequirements of subdivisions one, two and three of this section shall\nnot apply with regard to any project of the New York state environmental\nfacilities corporation, the New York state housing finance agency, the\nNew York state medical care facilities finance agency or the dormitory\nauthority in progress on the first day of April, nineteen hundred\nseventy-six, with regard to any project of the New York state project\nfinance agency or the New York state urban development corporation in\nprogress on the first day of April, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, with\nregard to any project of the job development authority or the battery\npark city authority in progress on the first day of July, nine...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>