<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-527"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-527"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2020-04-17" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="527"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-527/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-527/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-527/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-527/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_527">
        <num>527</num>
        <heading>New York State Bridge Authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 527. New York State Bridge Authority. 1. The board known as the "New\nYork State Bridge Authority," is hereby continued. Such board shall be a\nbody corporate and politic, shall have a corporate seal and be capable\nof suing and being sued. It shall consist of seven members who shall be\nappointed by the governor by and with the advice and consent of the\nsenate. The present members of the board shall continue in office,\nunless a vacancy occurs, for the remainder of the time for which they\nwere respectively appointed. Of the additional members, one shall be\nappointed for a term to expire February first, nineteen hundred\nfifty-one, and one for a term to expire February first, nineteen hundred\nfifty-two. Their successors and any additional appointees shall be\nappointed, one annually, for terms of five years each from the first day\nof February; provided that the person appointed as successor to the\nmember heretofore appointed for a three year term which expired February\nfirst, nineteen hundred forty-seven, shall be appointed for a term to\nexpire February first, nineteen hundred fifty. Vacancies in the office\nof such board occurring otherwise than by expiration of term also shall\nbe filled by the governor by appointment by and with the advice and\nconsent of the senate for the unexpired term, and the provisions of\nsection thirty-nine of the public officers law relating to recess\nappointments shall apply to such board. Such board shall choose from its\nmembers a chairman. The members of such board shall be paid or\nreimbursed for their necessary expenses incurred under this title, but\nshall receive no compensation for their services.\n  2. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue so long as it\nshall have bonds or other obligations outstanding (including bonds or\nobligations hereafter issued or incurred) and until its existence shall\nbe terminated by law. Upon ceasing to exist all of its rights and\nproperties shall pass to the state.\n  3. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of this section, on the\neffective date of this subdivision the term of each board member\ncurrently in office, or any vacant position, shall be deemed expired,\nand each such board members may continue to serve in holdover status\nuntil their successor is appointed by the governor and with the advice\nand consent of the senate and the provisions of section thirty-nine of\nthe public officers law relating to recess appointments shall apply to\nsuch appointments. Initial appointments made pursuant to this\nsubdivision shall be for the following terms, the first three of such\ninitial appointments shall be for a term of three years, the second two\nof such initial appointments shall be for a term of five years, and\nfinal two of such initial appointments shall be for a term of seven\nyears. After these initial terms have expired, board members shall be\nappointed for a term of five years, provided, however, that each board\nmember may serve in holdover until a successor board member is\nappointed. Vacancies in the office of such board occurring otherwise\nthan by expiration of term also shall be filled by the governor by\nappointment by and with the advice and consent of the senate for the\nunexpired term, and the provisions of section thirty-nine of the public\nofficers law relating to recess appointments shall apply to such board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>