<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-528"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-528"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2019-01-11" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="528"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-528/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-528/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_528">
        <num>528</num>
        <heading>Powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_528__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsubdivision thirty-four of section 1.20 of the criminal procedure law\nand shall have, within the limits of the cities, towns and villages\nwithin which any part of a bridge, or any ferry property, operated by\nthe authority shall be located, all the powers of a constable, marshal,\npolice constable or police officer of a city, town or village in the\nexecution of criminal processes; and criminal process issued by any\ncourt or magistrate of a county, town, city or village within which any\npart of a bridge or any ferry property operated by the authority shall\nbe located, may be directed to and executed by any such patrolman\nnotwithstanding the provisions of any local or special act, ordinance or\nregulation.\n  15. To do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers\nexpressly given in this title.\n  16. To accept grants, loans or contributions from the United States of\nAmerica, the state of New York, or any agency or instrumentality of\neither of them and, subject to any agreement with bondholders or\nnoteholders, to enter into contracts and to execute all instruments\nnecessary or convenient or desirable in connection therewith, including,\nits bonds, notes or other obligation evidencing any such loan from the\nUnited States of America, the state of New York or any agency or\ninstrumentality of either of them.\n  17. To enter into a lease or operating agreement, for a period not to\nexceed ninety-nine years, with the office of parks, recreation and\nhistoric preservation for all or a portion of the walkway over the\nHudson bridge for the purpose of a state park. Such agreement may assign\nor allocate responsibility for the construction, operation, maintenance,\nreplacement and management of the deck and approaches and structures\nproviding public access to the state park, but the authority shall\nretain responsibility for maintaining the superstructure of the walkway\nover the Hudson bridge. The office of parks, recreation and historic\npreser...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>