<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-552-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-552-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="552-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-552-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-552-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-552-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-552-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_552_A">
        <num>552-A</num>
        <heading>Consolidation</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_552_A__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Triborough bridge authority, the\ncorporation created pursuant to section five hundred fifty-two of this\nchapter, as originally enacted, and the New York city parkway authority,\nthe corporation created by section two hundred seventy-seven of this\nchapter, are hereby consolidated into a single corporation to be known\nas Triborough bridge authority, which shall be a continuance of the\ncorporate existence of the authorities so consolidated.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_552_A__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Triborough bridge authority, the corporation as consolidated\npursuant to paragraph one-a of this section, and New York city tunnel\nauthority, the corporation created pursuant to section six hundred\ntwenty-seven of this chapter, are hereby consolidated into a single\ncorporation to be known as Triborough bridge and tunnel authority, which\nshall be a continuance of the corporate existence of the authorities so\nconsolidated.\n  2. In this section the words "original authorities" refer to\nauthorities which are consolidated pursuant to subsection one of this\nsection before their consolidation, and the words "consolidated\nauthority" refer to the single authority resulting from consolidation.\n  3. The board created by section five hundred fifty-two of this chapter\nshall be the board of the consolidated authority and all powers of the\nconsolidated authority shall be vested in and exercised by said board.\n  4. All property, rights and powers of each of the original authorities\nare hereby vested in and shall be exercised by the consolidated\nauthority, subject, however, to all pledges, covenants, agreements and\ntrusts made or created by the original authorities, respectively.\n  5. All debts, liabilities, obligations, agreements and covenants of\nthe original authorities are hereby imposed upon the consolidated\nauthority.\n  6. All bondholders and other creditors of the original authorities and\npersons having claims against or contracts with the original authorities\nof any kind or character may enforce such debts, claims and contracts\nagainst the consolidated authority in the same manner as they might have\nagainst the original authorities respectively, and the rights and\nremedies of such bondholders, creditors and persons having claims or\ncontracts shall not be limited or restricted in any manner by this\ntitle.\n  7. In continuing the functions and carrying out the contracts,\nobligations and duties of any of the original authorities, the\nconsolidated a...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>