<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-J"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-J"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-05-16" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="553-J"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-J/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-J/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_553_J">
        <num>553-J</num>
        <heading>Metropolitan transportation authority capital lockbox fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the "2020 to 2024 capital program account" and (ii) the "2025 to\n2029 capital program account".\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The 2020 to 2024 capital program account shall consist of all\nmonies received by the authority pursuant to article forty-four-C of the\nvehicle and traffic law, subdivision twelve-a of section five hundred\nfifty-three of this title, and revenues of the real estate transfer tax\ndeposited pursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section fourteen hundred\ntwenty-one of the tax law, and sales tax pursuant to subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of\nsection eleven hundred forty-eight of the tax law, subparagraph (B) of\nparagraph five of subdivision</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of section twelve hundred sixty-one of\nthe tax law, and funds appropriated from the central business district\ntrust fund established pursuant to section ninety-nine-ff of the state\nfinance law.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The 2025 to 2029 capital program account shall consist of all\nmonies deposited pursuant to subdivision four of section twelve hundred\nseventy-h of this chapter.\n  2. Monies in the 2020 to 2024 capital program account shall be\napplied, subject to agreements with bondholders and applicable federal\nlaw, to the payment of operating, administration, and other necessary\nexpenses of the authority, or to the city of New York subject to the\nmemorandum of understanding executed pursuant to subdivision two-a of\nsection seventeen hundred four of the vehicle and traffic law properly\nallocable to such program, including the planning, designing,\nconstructing, installing or maintaining of the central business district\ntolling program, including, without limitation, the central business\ndistrict tolling infrastructure, the central business district tolling\ncollection system and the central business district tolling customer\nservice center, and the costs of any metropolitan transportation\nauthority capital projects included within the 2020 to 2024 MTA capital\nprogram or any successor programs. Monies in the 2020 to 2024 capital\nprogram account may be:</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pledged by the authority to secure and be\napplied to the payment of the bonds, notes or other obligations of the\nauthority to finance the costs of the central business district tolling\nprogram, including, without limitation, the central business district\ntolling infrastructure, the central business district tolling collection\nsystem and the central business district tolling customer service\ncenter, and the costs of any metropolitan transportation authority\ncapital projects included within the 2020 to 2024 MTA capital program or\nany successor programs, including debt service, reserve requirements, if\nany, the payment of amounts required under bond and note facilities or\nagreements related thereto, the payment of federal government loans,\nsecurity or credit arrangements or other agreements related thereto; or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>used by the authority for the payment of such capital costs of the\ncentral business district tolling program and the costs of any\nmetropolitan transportation authority capital projects included within\nthe 2020 to 2024 MTA capital program or any successor programs; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>\ntransferred to the metropolitan transportation authority and</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_553_J__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>pledged\nby the metropolitan transportation authority to secure and be applied to\nthe payment of the bonds, notes or other obligations of the metropolitan\ntransportation authority to finance the costs of any metropolitan\ntransportation authority capital projects included within the 2020 to\n2024 MTA capital program or any successor programs, including debt\nservice, reserve requirements, if any, the payment of amounts required\nunder bond and note facilities or agreements related thereto, the\npayment of federal government loans, security or credit arrangements or\nother agreements related thereto, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_553_J__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>used by the metropolitan\ntransportation authority for the payment of or to reimburse the costs,\nincluding debt service, of any metropolitan transportation authority\ncapital projects included within the 2020 to 2024 MTA capital program or\nany successor programs. Such revenues shall only supplement and shall\nnot supplant any federal, state, or local funds expended by the\nauthority or the metropolitan transportation authority, or such\nauthority's or metropolitan transportation authority's affiliates or\nsubsidiaries for such respective purposes. Central business district\ntoll revenues may be used as required to obtain, utilize, or maintain\nfederal authorization to collect tolls on federal aid highways.\n  2-a. Monies in the 2025 to 2029 capital program account shall be\napplied, subject to agreements with bondholders and applicable federal\nlaw, to the payment of the costs of any metropolitan transportation\nauthority capital projects included within the 2025 to 2029 MTA capital\...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>pledged by the authority to secure and be\napplied to the payment of the bonds, notes or other obligations of the\nauthority to finance the costs of any metropolitan transportation\nauthority capital projects included within the 2025 to 2029 MTA capital\nprogram or any successor programs, including debt service, reserve\nrequirements, if any, the payment of amounts required under bond and\nnote facilities or agreements related thereto, the payment of federal\ngovernment loans, security or credit arrangements or other agreements\nrelated thereto; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>used by the authority for the payment of such\ncapital costs of any metropolitan transportation authority capital\nprojects included within the 2025 to 2029 MTA capital program or any\nsuccessor programs; or</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553_J__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>transferred to the metropolitan\ntransportation authority and</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_553_J__subsec_c__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>pledged by the metropolitan\ntransportation authority to secure and be applied to the payment of the\nbonds, notes or other obligations of the metropolitan transportation\nauthority to finance the costs of any metropolitan transportation\nauthority capital projects included within the 2025 to 2029 MTA capital\nprogram or any successor programs, including debt service, reserve\nrequirements, if any, the payment of amounts required under bond and\nnote facilities or agreements related thereto, the payment of federal\ngovernment loans, security or credit arrangements or other agreements\nrelated thereto, or</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_553_J__subsec_c__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>used by the metropolitan transportation\nauthority for the payment of or to reimburse the costs, including debt\nservice, of any metropolitan transportation authority capital projects\nincluded within the 2025 to 2029 MTA capital program or any successor\nprograms. Such revenues shall only supplement and shall not supplant any\nfederal, state, or local funds expended by the authority or the\nmetropolitan transportation authority, or such authority's or\nmetropolitan transportation authority's affiliates or subsidiaries for\nsuch respective purposes.\n  3. Any monies deposited in the fund shall be held in the fund free and\nclear of any claim by any person arising out of or in connection with\narticle forty-four-C of the vehicle and traffic law, subdivision\ntwelve-a of section five hundred fifty-three of this title, and article\ntwenty-three of the tax law. Without limiting the generality of the\nforegoing, no person paying any amount that is deposited into the fund\nshall have any rig...</p>
            </content>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>