<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-F"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-F"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2018-10-05" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="553-F"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-F/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-F/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_553_F">
        <num>553-F</num>
        <heading>Tokens</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 553-f. Tokens. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law,\nbut subject to agreements with noteholders and bondholders, the\nauthority shall offer for sale tokens with respect to residents of the\ncounty of Richmond and may, except as otherwise provided herein,\nregulate the use thereof. Tokens for residents of the county of Richmond\nshall entitle the purchaser to crossings over the Verrazzano-Narrows\nbridge at a reduced cost of eighty per centum of the regular crossing\nfare imposed on nonresidents of the county of Richmond. In the event the\nauthority shall impose a surcharge in addition to the regular toll for\ncrossings over the Verrazzano-Narrows bridge, such surcharge shall not\nbe deemed a part of the regular crossing fare for purposes of this\nsection, and the tokens offered for sale to the residents of the county\nof Richmond as herein provided shall also entitle the purchaser to a\npermanent exemption from the payment of any such surcharge in an amount\nequal to the amount of any such surcharge imposed during calendar year\nnineteen hundred ninety-three. Application for such tokens or other\npayment devices shall be made in such manner as prescribed by the\nauthority and shall contain such information as the authority may\nreasonably require.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>