<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-H"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-H"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="553-H"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-H/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553-H/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_553_H">
        <num>553-H</num>
        <heading>Tokens</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 553-h. Tokens. Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of law,\nbut subject to agreements with noteholders and bondholders, the\nauthority shall offer for sale tokens and may, except as otherwise\nprovided herein, regulate the use thereof. Such tokens shall entitle the\npurchaser to crossings over the Cross-Bay Veteran's Memorial bridge at a\nreduced cost of sixty-six and two-thirds per centum of the regular\ncrossing fare imposed. In the event the authority shall impose a\nsurcharge in addition to the regular toll for crossings over the\nCross-Bay Veteran's Memorial bridge, such surcharge shall not be deemed\na part of the regular crossing fare for purposes of this section, and\nthe tokens or other payment devices offered for sale shall also entitle\npurchasers who are residents of Broad Channel or the Rockaway peninsula\nto a permanent exemption from the payment of any such surcharge in an\namount equal to the amount of any such surcharge imposed during calendar\nyear nineteen hundred ninety-three. Application for such tokens or other\npayment devices shall be made in such manner as prescribed by the\nauthority and shall contain such information as the authority may\nreasonably require.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>