<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2023-05-12" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="553"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-553/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_553">
        <num>553</num>
        <heading>Powers of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to surrender such real property to the board of estimate of the\ncity for other public use or purpose of such city, or\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to sell and convey or lease in behalf of such city any real\nproperty acquired by the city at the expense of the authority. The\nproceeds of any such sale or lease shall be paid to the authority and\napplied to its corporate purpose. Any such lease shall run for a term\nnot to exceed ten years, and a renewal thereof for a term not to exceed\nten years.\n  4-b. To apply for and receive and accept grants of property, money and\nservices and other assistance offered or made available to it by any\nperson, government or agency whatever, which it may use to meet capital\nor operating expenses and for any other use within the scope of its\npowers, and to negotiate for the same upon such terms and conditions as\nthe authority may determine to be necessary, convenient or desirable.\nSubject to the rights of the holders of any outstanding bonds, notes or\nother obligations of the authority, metropolitan transportation\nauthority, and New York city transit authority, and to facilitate the\nefficient financial management of the authority, metropolitan\ntransportation authority, its subsidiary corporations, and New York city\ntransit authority and its subsidiary corporations (the "affiliated\nentities"), the authority may, and may permit and direct any affiliated\nentity to, transfer revenues, subsidies and other monies or securities\nto one or more funds or accounts of another affiliated entity for use by\nsuch other affiliated entity, provided at the time of such transfer it\nis reasonably anticipated that the monies and securities so transferred\nwill be reimbursed, repaid or otherwise provided for by the end of the\nnext succeeding calendar year if reimbursement or repayment is required\nby law or by any agreement to which any of the affected affiliated\nentities is subject. Any revenues of an affiliated entity that are\ntransferred to another affiliated entity, which transfer was not\nauthorized by a provision of law other than this subdivision, shall be\nconsidered to be ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bridge heretofore constructed, known as Robert F. Kennedy\nbridge, over the East river from the borough of Queens to the boroughs\nof Manhattan and the Bronx, over and across Ward's island and Randall's\nisland in said river, together with such incidental bridges and\nstructures as shall be necessary or convenient in order to give access\nfrom the bridge to both of said islands, together with approaches to\nsaid bridges (herein collectively referred to as the "Robert F. Kennedy\nbridge project"); and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bridge heretofore constructed, known as Bronx-Whitestone bridge,\nover the East river from a point at or near Whitestone in the borough of\nQueens to the borough of the Bronx, together with approaches to such\nbridge (herein collectively referred to as the "Whitestone bridge\nproject"); and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bridge heretofore constructed, known as Henry Hudson bridge,\nacross the Harlem river ship canal together with approaches to such\nbridge and together with so much of the parkway known as Henry Hudson\nparkway as extends southerly from said bridge through Inwood Hill park\nto the northerly end of Riverside drive, (as it was before the\nconstruction of said parkway) (herein collectively referred to as the\n"Henry Hudson bridge project"); and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bridge heretofore constructed, known as Marine parkway bridge,\nto be known hereafter as the Marine parkway-Gil Hodges memorial bridge,\nfrom the borough of Brooklyn across the waters of Rockaway inlet to\nJacob Riis park in the borough of Queens, together with the approaches\nto such bridge and together with the parkway of which said bridge is a\npart, (and the parking field connected therewith), from and including\nthe toll plaza north of said bridge extending eastwardly from said\nbridge to the easterly boundary of Jacob Riis park (herein collectively\nreferred to as the "Marine parkway bridge project"); and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a bridge heretofore constructed known as Cross Bay parkway bridge,\nto be known hereafter as the Cross Bay Veterans Memorial bridge, from\nBig Egg marsh in Jamaica bay in the borough of Queens across the waters\nof Beach channel to Rockaway peninsula in said borough, together with\nthe parkway known as Cross Bay parkway, of which said bridge is a part,\nfrom and including the toll plaza north of said bridge southerly to the\nright of way of the Long Island railroad on Rockaway peninsula (herein\ncollectively referred to as the "Cross Bay parkway bridge project"); and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a vehicular tunnel or tunnels heretofore constructed, known as\nQueens Midtown tunnel, under the East river from the borough of\nManhattan to the borough of Queens, together with such incidental\nbridges and tunnels, including but not limited to, a tunnel or tunnels\nor bridge across Newtown creek from the borough of Queens to the borough\nof Brooklyn and such other structures, appurtenances, facilities and\napproaches as shall be necessary or convenient; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a vehicular tunnel or tunnels under construction, known as Hugh L.\nCarey tunnel, under the East river from the southerly end of the borough\nof Manhattan to the general vicinity of Hamilton avenue in the borough\nof Brooklyn, together with such incidental tunnels and such other\nstructures, appurtenances, facilities and approaches as shall be\nnecessary or convenient; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a vehicular tunnel or tunnels or bridge, herein called the\nBrooklyn Richmond project, under or across New York bay from the borough\nof Richmond to the borough of Brooklyn, together with such incidental\ntunnels, bridges and such other structures, appurtenances, facilities\nand approaches as shall be necessary or convenient; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a vehicular tunnel or tunnels or arterial highway across the\nborough of Manhattan connecting the Queens Midtown tunnel with the\nLincoln (Midtown Hudson) tunnel, together with such incidental tunnels\nand such other structures, appurtenances, facilities and approaches as\nshall be necessary or convenient; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Bus stations or terminals or automobile parking garages at or in\nthe vicinity of the Columbus circle in the borough of Manhattan and of\nthe Manhattan plazas of the Queens Midtown and Hugh L. Carey tunnels.\nAny such project may, subject to zoning restrictions, include space and\nfacilities for any or all of the following: public recreation, business,\ntrade and other exhibitions, sporting and athletic events, public\nmeetings, conventions and all kinds of assemblages, and in order to\nobtain additional revenues, space and facilities for business and\ncommercial purposes. Whenever the authority deems it to be in the public\ninterest, the authority may lease any such project or any part or parts\nthereof or contract for the management and operation thereof or of any\npart or parts thereof. Any such lease or contract may be for a period of\nnot exceeding ten years, or, if any of the revenues therefrom are or are\nto be pledged to secure bonds then such lease or contract may be for a\nperiod extending not later by more than one year than the last maturity\nof such bonds.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_k">
          <num>(k)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to and in accordance with all contract provisions with\nrespect to any bonds and the rights of the holders of bonds, a vehicular\nbridge across the East river between the boroughs of the Bronx and\nQueens, east of the Bronx-Whitestone bridge, together with such\nincidental bridges and other structures, appurtenances, facilities and\napproaches as shall be necessary or convenient (herein collectively\nreferred to as the "Throgs Neck bridge project"). With the consent of\nthe United States of America, the Throgs Neck bridge project or a\nportion thereof, if deemed necessary or convenient by the authority, may\nbe constructed upon or pass over any part of the military reservation\nknown as Fort Schuyler and owned by the United States of America. No\nlands, easements or rights in land shall be acquired by the authority\nfor the purposes of this paragraph without the prior consent of the\nboard of estimate of the city.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_l">
          <num>(l)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to section five hundred fifty-three-b of this title, a\nconvention and exhibition center, including facilities ancillary or\nfunctionally related thereto, to be built in New York county at a\nlocation generally bounded by thirty-ninth street on the north,\nthirtieth street on the south, eleventh avenue on the east and twelfth\navenue on the west (herein referred to as the convention center).\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to section five hundred fifty-three-c of this title, the\nacquisition of new rapid transit cars and the transfer of the same to\nthe New York city transit authority for a nominal consideration. The\nauthority shall have no obligation to operate, repair, maintain or\nreconstruct such cars subsequent to their acquisition and transfer nor\nshall it be liable to the New York city transit authority by reason of\nany warranty, express or implied, in respect to such cars. Manufacturers\nor other warranties furnished to the authority in connection with the\npurchase of such cars shall be assigned to the New York city transit\nauthority for enforcement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to section five hundred fifty-three-c of this title, the\nrehabilitation of existing rapid transit cars of the New York city\ntransit authority upon such terms and conditions as shall be agreed to\nby the parties. The authority shall have no obligation to operate,\nrepair, maintain or reconstruct such cars subsequent to the\nrehabilitation and transfer back to the New York city transit authority\nnor shall it be liable to the New York city transit authority by reason\nof any warranty, express or implied, in respect to such cars.\nManufacturers or other warranties furnished to the authority in\nconnection with the purchase of parts or materials for such cars shall\nbe assigned to the New York city transit authority for enforcement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to section five hundred fifty-three-c of this title, the\nacquisition of new diesel self-propelled railroad passenger cars and the\ntransfer of the same to the metropolitan transportation authority, for a\nnominal consideration, for use on commuter railroads owned or controlled\nby the metropolitan transportation authority. The authority shall have\nno obligation to operate, repair, maintain or reconstruct such cars\nsubsequent to their acquisition and transfer, nor shall it be liable to\nthe metropolitan transportation authority by reason of any warranty,\nexpress or implied, in respect of such cars. Manufacturers or other\nwarranties furnished to the authority in connection with the purchase of\nsuch cars shall be assigned to the metropolitan transportation authority\nfor enforcement.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_p">
          <num>(p)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Subject to section five hundred fifty-three-c of this title, the\nacquisition of land in the name of the authority in the vicinity of Penn\nStation in the city of New York and/or the improvement of such land for\nthe benefit of the Long Island Rail Road for a lay-up yard and other\nrailroad purposes and the transfer of the said land and any improvements\nthereon to the metropolitan transportation authority, parent corporation\nof the said railroad, for a nominal consideration. The authority shall\nhave no obligation to operate, repair, maintain or reconstruct such land\nor its improvements subsequent to such transfer.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_r">
          <num>(r)</num>
          <content>
            <p>In its discretion and subject to and in accordance with all\ncontract provisions with respect to any bonds and the rights of the\nholders of bonds, at the request of the New York city transit authority\nor the metropolitan transportation authority,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the planning for and\nthe design, acquisition, construction, improvement, reconstruction or\nrehabilitation, in the name of the authority, of any capital asset,\nwhether in the nature of personal or real property (or any interest\ntherein) which is used or useful for a transit or transportation purpose\nother than a marine or aviation purpose of the requesting authority or\nits designated subsidiary (and in the case of such assets then owned,\noperated by or under lease to the requesting authority or its designated\nsubsidiary, the receipt by the authority of the use, occupancy, control\nor possession of such assets for the purpose of planning, designing,\nconstructing, improving, reconstructing or rehabilitating the same) and\nthe transfer or transfer back of such asset to the requesting authority,\nits designated subsidiary or other designee for a nominal consideration\nupon its acquisition or upon the completion of such improvement,\nconstruction, reconstruction or rehabilitation; or, alternatively or in\ncombination with the foregoing, (ii) the making of capital grants to the\nrequesting authority or its designated subsidiary to permit it to\nundertake and to finance such planning, design, acquisition,\nimprovement, construction, reconstruction or rehabilitation, or,\nalternatively or in combination with the foregoing, (iii) the financing\nof all or any part of the costs to the authority or to any other person\nor entity, public or private, of such planning, design, acquisition,\nconstruction, improvement, reconstruction or rehabilitation of any such\ncapital asset through or accompanied by a leasing of the asset by such\nperson or entity to the authority or through or accompanied by a sale by\nthe authority to any such person or entity and leaseback to the\nauthority, in each case for subleasing to the requesting authority, its\ndesignated subsidiary or other designee for a nominal rental, except\nthat such leasing or leaseback from such person or entity may be...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_m">
          <num>(m)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_n">
          <num>(n)</num>
          <content>
            <p>,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_o">
          <num>(o)</num>
          <content>
            <p>and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_p">
          <num>(p)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision without regard to any limitations set\nforth in section five hundred fifty-three-c of this title. The authority\nshall have no obligation to operate or, except as may otherwise be\nprovided in any lease to which it may be a party as aforesaid, repair or\nmaintain any capital asset after its acquisition, construction,\nimprovement, reconstruction or rehabilitation and subsequent transfer,\nlease or sublease, nor shall it be liable to the transferee, lessee or\nsublessee by reason of any warranty, express or implied, in respect\nthereof. Warranties furnished in connection with such acquisition,\nimprovement, construction, reconstruction or rehabilitation shall be\nassignable and assigned as directed by the requesting authority and\napproved by the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_s">
          <num>(s)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The central business district tolling program to the extent\nspecified in article forty-four-C of the vehicle and traffic law and in\nthis title.\n  The word "approaches" shall include all structures necessary or\nconvenient to give access to the project from connecting streets and\nroads;\n  10. In its discretion\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>in the case of the Robert F. Kennedy bridge project and the\nWhitestone bridge project to pay to the city not exceeding thirty-five\nper centum of the cost (including awards for damages and expenses) of\nthe acquisition of land for the widening of existing roads, streets,\nparkways or avenues and for new roads, streets, parkways or avenues,\nconnecting with the approaches.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to purchase from the persons, partnerships, associations or\ncorporations who were the owners of any land acquired for the widening\nof existing roads, streets, parkways or avenues or for new roads,\nstreets, parkways or avenues connecting with the approaches or of any\ninterest in such land at the date title to such land was vested in the\ncity in any proceeding heretofore or hereafter instituted for the\nacquisition thereof by condemnation, or from their successors in\ninterest or legal representatives, their right, title, interest and/or\nclaim in and to the award or awards or any part thereof to be made in\nsuch proceeding after the date of such purchase, and to take an\nassignment thereof to the authority, provided, however, that in the case\nof the Robert F. Kennedy bridge project and the Whitestone bridge\nproject the aggregate amount expended by the authority on account of all\nsuch purchases together with the aggregate amount paid to the city in\naccordance with paragraph</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of this subdivision, shall not exceed\nthirty-five per centum of the cost (including awards for damages and\nexpenses) of the acquisition of land for the widening of existing roads,\nstreets, parkways or avenues, and for new roads, streets, parkways or\navenues, connecting with the approaches,\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to construct, in whole or in part, an elevated parkway in the\nborough of Brooklyn from the southerly terminus of the Gowanus creek\nbridge project to a point at or near Owls Head park connecting with the\nGowanus creek bridge project, and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>with the consent of the city to construct and develop for the\npurpose of public parks so much of the area of lands, selected as in\nthis title provided, or otherwise acquired or to be acquired and used in\nconnection with the project and with new or existing roads, streets,\nparkways or avenues connecting with such projects, and so much of the\narea of lands now owned by the city to be used in connection with such\nprojects or with new or existing roads, streets, parkways or avenues\nconnecting with such projects, as shall be agreed upon under a contract\nor contracts hereby authorized to be entered into between the authority\nand the city, at the sole expense of the authority and done under\nconstruction contracts let and supervised by the authority, pursuant to\nplans and specifications prepared by the authority, the commissioner of\nparks and recreation of the city or other agency.\n  The city shall maintain such connecting roads, streets, parkways and\navenues as provided by law. The public parks and the parkways herein\nreferred to as connecting with the approaches, any part of the cost of\nwhich is paid by the authority, shall be under the jurisdiction of the\ndepartment of parks and recreation of the city and shall be maintained\nby that department. Service roads appurtenant to said parkways shall be\nunder the jurisdiction of the city commissioner of transportation and\nshall be maintained by him;\n  11. To design and with the consent of the city, to construct new\nparks, parkways or highways or improvements to existing parks, parkways\nor highways either connecting directly or indirectly with the project or\nfor the purpose of attracting or facilitating traffic or improving\napproaches to and connections with the project. The authority shall have\nno jurisdiction or control over any new parks, parkways or highways\nconstructed by it pursuant to the provisions of this paragraph eleven\nafter the completion of the construction thereof. The general powers\nco...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to\nacquire real property by purchase, gift, devise or condemnation in the\nmanner provided in this title, and as the agent of the city, for the\npurpose of providing new sites on which such dwellings or other\nstructures may be relocated;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to sell such dwellings or other\nstructures or to provide for the removal, relocation and improvement of\nsuch dwellings or other structures on new foundations at such new sites\nby contract or by its own labor force or by a combination of methods;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to contract for the installation of water, sewer, gas and electrical\nfacilities and other necessary appurtenances required for the completion\nand restoration of such dwellings or other structures;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to landscape\nsuch new sites;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to contract with any person, firm or corporation or\nwith the city for the improvement or installation of streets, sewers,\nwater lines or other facilities in connection with the relocation of\nsuch dwellings or other structures and to pay the cost thereof;</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to\ncontract with the several owners of such property for the conveyance of\nthe new sites with improvements thereon to such owner in settlement in\npart or in whole of the compensation and damage to which they are\nentitled; and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>to sell such sites with or without dwellings or other\nstructures and improvements thereon.\n  The authority may agree with the owners of property acquired, in\nsettlement in part or in whole of the damages to which they are\nentitled, to compensate such owners for the cost of acquiring new sites,\nremoving dwellings thereto on new foundations, the installation of\nwater, sewer, gas and electrical facilities and other necessary\nappurtenances required for the complete restoration of such dwellings or\nother structures and landscaping of the new site.\n  For the purposes of this subdivision, the term "structures" shall mean\nand include buildings used as and for hospitals, schools, community and\nreligious institutions, cultural and recreational and other neighborhood\nand community facilities, but shall exclude retail stores, factories and\ncommercial and industrial establishments of any kind.\n  17. To do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers\nexpressly given in this title and to assist and cooperate with the\nmetropolitan transportation authority to carry out the powers of the\nmetropolitan transportation authority in furtherance of the purposes and\npowers of the authority as provided in this article, including, without\nlimitation, the transactions described in sections twelve hundred\nsixty-six-c, twelve hundred sixty-nine, and twelve hundred seventy-d of\nthis chapter.\n  18. A copy of any report submitted by the authority pursuant to\nsections twenty-eight hundred, twenty-eight hundred one and twenty-eight\nhundred two of this chapter shall be submitted contemporaneously to the\nmayor of the city.\n  19. To acquire in its own name certain real or personal property, or\nany interest therein, including leasehold interests, air and subsurface\nrights, easements and lands under water at a site located in New York\ncounty and generally bounded by thirty-third street on the north,\nthirtieth street on the south, tenth avenue on the east and ele...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_r">
          <num>(r)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision nine of this section, not including any\nseries resolution or resolutions, and prior to the adoption of any\namendment to a general resolution, whenever adopted, pursuant to which\nit is authorized to issue any general or special obligation bonds or\nnotes for such purpose, not including a series resolution or\nresolutions, the authority shall submit a copy of such proposed\nresolution to the metropolitan transportation authority capital program\nreview board (hereinafter referred to as the "board"). Within fifteen\ndays of such submission, the board may notify the authority of its\nunanimous approval of the same by the members entitled to vote thereon,\nor if the resolution is not approved and no individual member of the\nboard who is entitled to vote on such resolution has notified the\nauthority in writing of his disapproval, the resolution shall be deemed\nto have been approved. Neither the board nor any member thereof shall\ndisapprove a proposed resolution by reason of any covenant requiring the\nauthority to charge and fix tolls, rentals and other charges sufficient\nto pay its operating expenses and the debt service, including the\nfunding of requisite reserves, on the bonds and notes authorized by such\nresolution. If the board or any member thereof entitled to vote thereon\nshall disapprove a proposed resolution, the authority may, at any time,\nresubmit a reformulated resolution. Within ten days of the submission of\nsuch reformulated resolution the board may notify the authority of its\nunanimous approval of the same by the members entitled to vote thereon,\nor, if the reformulated resolution is not approved and no individual\nmember of the board who is entitled to vote thereon has notified the\nauthority in writing of his disapproval within such period, the\nreformulated resolution shall have been deemed to have been approved.\nAny individual member of the board who votes against a resolution or a\nreformulated resolution or who notifies ...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_553__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>a contract for services in the actual or estimated\namount of less than one hundred thousand dollars shall not require\napproval by the board of the authority regardless of the length of the\nperiod over which the services are rendered, and provided further that a\ncontract for services in the actual or estimated amount of one hundred\nthousand dollars or more shall require approval by the board of the\nauthority regardless of the length of the period over which the services\nare rendered unless such a contract is awarded to the lowest responsible\nbidder after obtaining sealed bids and (ii) the board of the authority\nmay by resolution adopt guidelines that authorize the award of contracts\nto small business concerns, to service disabled veteran owned businesses\ncertified pursuant to article seventeen-b of the executive law, or\nminority or women-owned business enterprises certified pursuant to\narticle fifteen-a of the executive law, or purchases of goods or\ntechnology that are recycled or remanufactured, in an amount not to\nexceed four hundred thousand dollars without a formal competitive\nprocess and without further board approval. The board of the authority\nshall adopt guidelines which shall be made publicly available for the\nawarding of such contract without a formal competitive process.\n  * NB Repealed June 30, 2028\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>