<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-555"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-555"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="555"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-555/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-555/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-555/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-555/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_555">
        <num>555</num>
        <heading>Selection of site</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 555. Selection of site. Notwithstanding any provisions of any other\nstatute, the authority in conjunction with the commissioner of parks of\nthe city or his successor, the commissioner of parks and recreation, and\nwith the approval of the board of estimate of such city and with the\nseparate approval of the mayor thereof, is hereby authorized to select\nsites in the boroughs of the Bronx and Queens of the city for the\nWhitestone bridge project and parkways connecting therewith, which sites\nmay be in or through existing public parks, and to select sites for new\npublic parks contiguous to such project or contiguous to the roads,\nstreets, parkways or avenues connecting with such project. A site or\nsites may be selected for any or all of the aforementioned purposes and\nthereafter the use thereof shall be allocated by the commissioner of\nparks and recreation as herein provided. The property so selected solely\nfor such project, not already owned by the city, shall be acquired at\nthe sole expense of the authority in the manner provided for under this\ntitle. The property so selected solely for new public parks shall be\nacquired by the city at its sole expense. The cost of the property so\nselected for such project, combined with any other aforementioned\npurposes the use of which is to be thereafter determined, shall be\ndivided between the city and the authority as may be determined by a\ncontract or contracts hereby authorized to be entered into between the\ncity and the authority, subject to the approval of the board of estimate\nof the city. So much of the sites so selected and acquired or such\neasements or rights of way therein as may be necessary or convenient for\nthe corporate purposes of the authority may be assigned by the\ncommissioner of parks and recreation of the city to the authority for\nits use so long as its corporate existence shall continue.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>