<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-557-A"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-557-A"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="557-A"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-557-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-557-A/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-557-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-557-A/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_557_A">
        <num>557-A</num>
        <heading>Lands, easements and rights in land</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 557-a. Lands, easements and rights in land. 1. Lands in fee simple,\neasements and rights in land, including the right to cut off light, air\nand access (any and all of which are in this section referred to as\n"lands") shall after January first, nineteen hundred forty be acquired\nas provided in this section for the project and other authorized\npurposes, and the provisions of sections five hundred fifty-five, five\nhundred fifty-six and five hundred fifty-seven of this chapter shall not\napply.\n  2. The authority may acquire lands for said project in the name of the\ncity at the cost and expense of the authority by purchase or\ncondemnation pursuant to the condemnation law. The authority shall have\nthe use and occupancy of such lands so long as its corporate existence\nshall continue.\n  3. The city may, by resolution of the board of estimate, or by deed\nauthorized by such a resolution, convey, with or without consideration,\nto the authority for the project the use and occupancy, for so long as\nits corporate existence shall continue, of any lands then owned by the\ncity including lands which, by any other law, are inalienable by the\ncity, and such conveyance may reserve to the city such rights as shall\nnot restrict the authority in the construction, reconstruction,\noperation and maintenance of the project.\n  4. The city may acquire lands in the name of the city for the project\nor for the widening of existing roads, streets, parkways, avenues or\nelevated highways or for new roads, streets, parkways, avenues or\nelevated highways connecting with said project, or partly for such\npurposes and partly for other city purposes, by purchase or condemnation\nin the manner provided by law for the acquisition of land by the city.\nContracts may be entered into between the city and the authority\nproviding for the lands to be acquired by the city, and the part or\nproportion of the cost and expense to be paid by the authority, the\nbalance to be paid by the city, and terms and conditions of payment to\nbe made by the authority. Such contracts may also determine the\nimprovements and construction to be done by the authority. Such roads,\nstreets, parkways, avenues and elevated highways connecting with the\nproject shall be operated, maintained, and reconstructed by the city,\nand except for the original construction and improvement thereof by the\nauthority, the city shall have exclusive jurisdiction over them.\n  5. The mayor may authorize a contract between the city and the\nauthority and no other authorization on the part of the city for such a\ncontract shall be necessary. Any such contract may be so authorized and\nentered into by the city and the payments required to be made by the\ncity may be made and financed notwithstanding that no provision therefor\nshall have first been made in the capital budget of the city. All\ncontractual or other obligations of the city incurred in carrying out\nthe provisions of this title shall be included in and provided for by\nsuch capital budget of the city thereafter made, to the extent that they\nmay appropriately be included therein.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>