<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-569-B"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-569-B"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="569-B"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-569-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-569-B/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-569-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-569-B/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_569_B">
        <num>569-B</num>
        <heading>Restrictions on signs and billboards</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 569-b. Restrictions on signs and billboards. 1. No outdoor\nadvertising sign or device which refers to any subject other than the\nbusiness actually conducted on the premises or to sale or rental of such\npremises and no such outdoor advertising sign or device exceeding ten\nfeet in height above the sidewalk adjacent to the property on which such\nsign or device is located, shall be erected, reconstructed, painted, or\nrepainted, after the applicable date hereinafter specified in this\nsection, within five hundred feet of the Whitestone bridge project, the\nThrogs Neck bridge project, the Narrows bridge project or the Hugh L.\nCarey tunnel project or the approaches and connections of such projects,\nif within view thereof.\n  2. In the case of the Whitestone bridge project, the applicable date\nshall be April three, nineteen hundred thirty-nine, except that with\nrespect to reconstruction, painting or repainting of any such sign or\ndevice within view of such bridge project, the applicable date shall be\nthe effective date of this subdivision two.\n  3. In the case of the Throgs Neck bridge project, the Narrows bridge\nproject and the Hugh L. Carey tunnel project, the applicable date shall\nbe the effective date of this subdivision three.\n  4. A violation of any of the provisions of this section may be\nrestrained at the suit of the authority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>