<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-577"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-577"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="577"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-577/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-577/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-577/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-577/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_577">
        <num>577</num>
        <heading>Thousand Islands Bridge Authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 577. Thousand Islands Bridge Authority. 1. A board to be known as\n"Thousand Islands Bridge Authority" is hereby created. Such board shall\nbe a body corporate and politic constituting a public benefit\ncorporation. It shall consist of five members who shall be appointed by\nthe chairman of the board of supervisors subject to the approval of the\nsupervisors.\n  2. The term of office of the members of the board hereby created who\nare first appointed shall be one, two, three, four and five years\nrespectively, dating from January first, nineteen hundred thirty-three,\nand thereafter the term of office of members shall be five years. In\naddition, at any time when the authority has control of properties\nphysically situated in Canada, the number of members of such board may,\nat the option of the supervisors, be increased to seven, any three of\nwhom may be residents or citizens of Canada, with such additional two\nmembers to be appointed in the same manner. Members shall hold office\nuntil their successors are appointed and qualify. An appointment to fill\na vacancy shall be for the unexpired term. The chairman, vice-chairman\nand secretary of such board shall be elected annually by such board. The\nmembers of the board shall be entitled to such compensation, if any, for\ntheir services as shall be fixed by the supervisors and shall be\nentitled to reimbursement for their actual and reasonable expenses\nincurred in the performance of their official duties. The power of such\ncorporation shall be vested in and exercised by a majority of the\nmembers of such board then in office. Such board may delegate to one or\nmore of its members, or to its agents and employees, such powers and\nduties as it may deem proper.\n  3. Such board and its corporate existence shall continue until all of\nits indebtedness created prior to April first, nineteen hundred\neighty-one, and all notes and bonds issued as provided in this title\nshall have been paid in full, and thereafter until such existence is\nterminated by formal action of the supervisors, which shall specifically\nprovide for the assumption by and agreement of the county to pay any and\nall liabilities, indebtedness and obligations of the authority.\n  4. The authority's right to own, control and operate properties or\nfacilities situated within the Dominion of Canada depends and shall\ncontinue to depend upon grants in its favor by the federal government of\nCanada and the government of the province of Ontario, agreements between\nthe authority and such foreign governments, or political subdivisions\nthereof and by the laws of such foreign jurisdictions.\n  5. When all of its notes and bonds have been paid in full and all of\nits other liabilities and obligations have either been met or paid in\nfull or assumed by the county and when the existence of the authority\nhas been terminated by the supervisors as hereinabove provided, then all\nits rights and properties, so far as the same are located in the United\nStates, including the right to fix, charge and collect tolls for the use\nof the American channel bridge or bridges, shall be conveyed without\ncost or expense to the county and all its rights and properties, so far\nas the same are located in the Dominion of Canada, shall be conveyed\nwithout cost or expense to the province of Ontario, or otherwise as the\nlieutenant-governor in council thereof may designate. Such conveyance to\nthe province of Ontario may also be made in the same manner at any time\nwhen the authority's right to own or control or operate properties or\nfacilities in Canada has been terminated even though its existence and\nright to operate in the state or county may be unimpaired.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>