<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-579"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-579"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="579"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-579/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-579/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-579/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-579/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_579">
        <num>579</num>
        <heading>Transfer of real property to and by the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 579. Transfer of real property to and by the authority. 1.  Title to\nany real property which has heretofore been or may hereafter be acquired\nby or for the authority, whether with the proceeds of bonds issued\npursuant to this title or otherwise, shall be vested in the authority.\n  2. Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the governing body\nor the supervisors of any county, the town board of any town, or the\ntrustees of any village, without any election or meeting of the\ntaxpayers or voters or other authorization are hereby authorized to\nconvey to the authority any land, easement or interest in land,\nincluding a public highway, which the authority may deem necessary.\n  3. The authority shall have the right to convey to the state of New\nYork or the province of Ontario, or to any county, town or front\nthereof, any road or any part of any road which lies within the\nterritorial boundary of the grantee whenever such grantee shall\nundertake to maintain the same as a public highway. Notwithstanding the\nabove the authority shall not convey real property in Canada to any unit\nof government in the United States nor shall it convey land in the\nUnited States to any unit of government in Canada.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>