<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-587"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-587"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="587"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-587/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-587/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-587/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-587/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_587">
        <num>587</num>
        <heading>Actions against the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 587. Actions against the authority. 1. In a case founded upon tort,\na notice of claim shall be required as a condition precedent to the\ncommencement of an action or special proceeding against the authority or\nany officer, appointee, agent or employee thereof, and the provisions of\nsection fifty-e of the general municipal law shall govern the giving of\nsuch notice.\n  2. Except in an action for wrongful death, no action or special\nproceeding shall be commenced more than one year and ninety days after\nthe cause of action therefor shall have accrued, nor until at least\nthirty days have elapsed since the notice of claim referred to in the\npreceding subdivision was so served upon the authority, and the\ncomplaint or petition in any such action or special proceeding shall\ncontain an affirmative allegation to that effect and must also allege\nthat the authority has neglected or refused to make an adjustment or\npayment of such claim or otherwise satisfy the same for thirty days\nafter such service. An action against the authority for wrongful death\nshall be commenced in accordance with the notice of claim and time\nlimitation provisions of title eleven of article nine of this chapter.\n  3. All actions by or against the authority of whatsoever nature shall\nbe brought in the county or where it has facilities involved in the\naction.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>