<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-652"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-652"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="652"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-652/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-652/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-652/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-652/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_652">
        <num>652</num>
        <heading>Definitions</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 652. Definitions. As used or referred to in this title, unless a\ndifferent meaning clearly appears from the context,\n  1. The term "authority" shall mean the corporation created by section\nsix hundred fifty-three of this chapter;\n  2. The term "county" shall mean the county of Nassau;\n  3. The term "bonds" shall mean the bonds authorized in this title;\n  4. The term "board" shall mean the members of the authority;\n  5. The term "real property" shall mean lands, structures, franchises,\nand interests in land, including lands under water and riparian rights,\nand any and all things and rights usually included within the said term,\nand includes not only fees simple absolute but also any and all lesser\ninterests, such as easements, rights of way, uses, leases, licenses and\nall other incorporeal hereditaments and every estate, interest or right,\nlegal or equitable, including terms of years, and liens thereon by way\nof judgments, mortgages or otherwise, and also claims for damage to real\nestate;\n  6. The term "Reynolds channel" shall mean the waterway on the\nnortherly side of the island of Long Beach, extending easterly from East\nRockaway inlet and includes said inlet;\n  6-a. The term "Bannister creek" shall mean the waterway known by that\nname in the county of Nassau connected with Reynolds channel.\n  7. The term "Atlantic Beach bridge" shall mean the existing bridge\nknown by that name crossing Reynolds channel;\n  8. The term "project" shall mean Atlantic Beach bridge and any new\nbridge constructed by the authority across Reynolds channel, or either\nof said bridges, and any park, playground, beach or other recreational\nfacility created or acquired by the authority, including any land within\nthe county of Nassau which has been acquired by the authority for such\npurposes, together with such structures, appurtenances, facilities and\napproaches as may be necessary or convenient in connection therewith;\n  9. The term "approaches" shall mean all structures necessary or\nconvenient to give access to the bridge from connecting streets, roads\nand parkways;\n  10. The term "connections" shall mean all roads, streets, parkways or\navenues connecting with the approaches.\n  11. The terms "note" or "notes" shall mean bond anticipation notes as\nauthorized in this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>