<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-653"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-653"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="653"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-653/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-653/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-653/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-653/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_653">
        <num>653</num>
        <heading>Nassau county bridge authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 653. Nassau county bridge authority. A board to be known as "Nassau\ncounty bridge authority" is hereby created. Such board shall be a body\ncorporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation, and its\nexistence shall commence upon the appointment of the members as herein\nprovided. It shall consist of a chairman and four other members who\nshall be appointed by the county executive of the county with the\napproval of the county legislature. The original appointments shall be\nmade in such manner that the term of one member shall expire on the\nDecember thirty-first next after the appointment of the board and one\nmember on the second December thirty-first after the appointment of the\nboard and one member on the third December thirty-first after the\nappointment of the board. Their successors shall be appointed one\nannually for terms of five years each from the first day of January\nfollowing the end of the term of his or her predecessor. Each member\nshall continue to serve until the appointment and qualification of his\nor her successor. Vacancies in such board occurring otherwise than by\nthe expiration of term shall be filled for the unexpired term. The\nmembers of the board shall choose from their number a vice-chairman. The\ncounty executive may remove any member of the board for inefficiency,\nneglect of duty or misconduct in office, giving him or her a copy of the\ncharges against him or her and an opportunity of being heard in person,\nor by counsel, in his or her defense upon not less than ten days'\nnotice. The members of the board shall be entitled to such compensation,\nif any, for their services as shall be fixed by ordinance of the county\nlegislature and shall be entitled to reimbursement for their actual and\nnecessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties.\nThe powers of the authority shall be vested in and exercised by a\nmajority of the members of the board then in office. Such board may\ndelegate to one or more of its members or to its officers, agents and\nemployees such powers and duties as it may deem proper. Such board and\nits corporate existence shall continue until March first of the year\nnineteen hundred eighty-five, and thereafter until all its liabilities\nhave been met and its notes and bonds have been paid in full or such\nliabilities or notes and bonds have otherwise been discharged. Upon its\nceasing to exist, all its rights and properties shall pass to the\ncounty.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>