<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-655"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-655"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="655"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-655/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-655/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-655/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-655/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_655">
        <num>655</num>
        <heading>Civil service status of officers and employees</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 655. Civil service status of officers and employees. Officers and\nemployees of any board, commission or department of the county may be\ntransferred to the authority in accordance with the provisions of the\ncivil service law and shall be eligible for such transfer and\nappointment without examination to offices and positions under the\nauthority. Officers and employees of the county who are members or\nbeneficiaries of any existing pension or retirement system shall\ncontinue to have the rights, privileges, obligations and status with\nrespect to such system or systems as are now prescribed by law, and all\nsuch employees who have been appointed to positions in the service of\nthe county under the rules of the county civil service commission shall\nhave the same status with respect thereto after transfer to the\nauthority as they had under their original appointments. The appointment\nand promotion of all employees of the authority shall be made in\naccordance with the provisions of the civil service law and the rules of\nthe county civil service commission.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>