<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-656"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-656"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="656"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-656/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-656/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-656/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-656/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_656">
        <num>656</num>
        <heading>Acquisition of land by the county for the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 656. Acquisition of land by the county for the authority. The county\nshall have power to acquire by purchase or by condemnation title in its\nname to any real property which may be needed or convenient for the\nproject or in connection therewith, including real property of municipal\ncorporations, public utility corporations and railroad corporations. Any\nmunicipal corporation may convey, with or without consideration, to the\ncounty any right, title or interest in real property without any\nelection or vote of the electors, taxpayers or freeholders. Payment for\nreal property so acquired by the county may be made by the authority.\nThe power to acquire real property hereby granted shall include the\npower to acquire the Atlantic beach bridge and any or all rights or\nfranchises connected with the operation of said bridge which it may be\nnecessary or convenient for the authority to acquire. The power hereby\nconferred upon the county shall not limit or restrict the power of the\nauthority itself to acquire real property in the name of the county.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>