<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-702"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-702"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="702"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-702/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-702/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_702">
        <num>702</num>
        <heading>Ogdensburg bridge authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 702. Ogdensburg bridge authority. A board to be known as "Ogdensburg\nbridge authority" is hereby created. Such board shall be a body\ncorporate and politic constituting a public benefit corporation. It\nshall consist of seven members who shall be appointed by the governor.\nThe terms of office of the members shall be five years except as\nhereinafter provided. Of the two members first appointed to fill a\nvacancy created by reason of the increase in the membership of the\nauthority to seven in number one shall be appointed for an initial term\nof three years and one for an initial term of four years. Each of the\nabove terms provided for shall commence on the first day of January in\nthe year in which the vacancy occurs. Each member shall hold office\nuntil the appointment and qualification of his successor. An appointment\nto fill a vacancy shall be for the unexpired term. The board shall elect\nannually a chairman, a vice-chairman, a secretary and a treasurer of the\nboard. The members of the board shall not be entitled to compensation\nfor their services but shall be entitled to reimbursement for all\nexpenses necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties. The\npowers of the authority shall be vested in and exercised by a majority\nof the members of the board then in office. The board may delegate to\none or more of its members or to its officers, agents or employees such\npowers and duties as it may deem proper. When all its liabilities shall\nhave been met and its bonds shall have been paid in full, all its rights\nand properties, so far as the same are located in the United States of\nAmerica, including the right to charge tolls, shall be conveyed without\ncost or expense to the state of New York, and all its rights and\nproperties so far as the same are located in the Dominion of Canada,\nincluding the right to charge tolls, shall be conveyed without cost or\nexpense to the province of Ontario or otherwise disposed of in\naccordance with the laws of the Dominion of Canada. The authority and\nits corporate existence shall continue until all its liabilities shall\nhave been met and its bonds paid in full and until all its rights and\nproperties shall have been conveyed as hereinabove provided.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>