<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-704"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-704"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="704"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-704/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-704/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_704">
        <num>704</num>
        <heading>Consent of state</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 704. Consent of state. 1. The state of New York hereby authorizes\nthe commissioner of general services to consent, in his discretion, to\nthe use and occupation by the authority of any unappropriated lands of\nthe state of New York including the land under the waters of the Saint\nLawrence river, necessary for the construction and operation of the\nbridge and approach roads herein authorized upon such terms and\nconditions as such commissioner may deem appropriate.\n  2. The state hereby further authorizes the commissioner of general\nservices, with the consent of the commissioner of mental hygiene and\napproval of the director of the budget, to grant to the authority a\nportion of the lands of the Saint Lawrence state hospital located in the\ncounty of Saint Lawrence, upon such terms and conditions, including\nconsideration, as such commissioner may determine. The portion of such\nlands of such hospital herein authorized to be granted shall be taken\nfrom the westerly end of the hospital property on the northerly side of\nProctor avenue and to be bounded on the south by the northerly line of\nProctor avenue, on the north and northwest by the high water line of the\nSaint Lawrence river, on the west by the westerly boundary line of said\nhospital property and on the east by a line running from the northerly\nline of Proctor avenue northerly to the high water line of the Saint\nLawrence river so as to contain within said bounds approximately\nseventy-five acres of land together with a triangular parcel of land\nbetween Proctor avenue and the northerly line of arterial route\nthirty-seven, bounded on the west by a westerly boundary line of said\nhospital grounds, on the south and east by the northerly boundary of\narterial route thirty-seven, and on the north by the south side of\nProctor avenue, excepting therefrom any and all lands taken and devoted\nto highway purposes of the state of New York. The department of\ntransportation shall make an accurate survey of the parcels so to be\ngranted and the grants to the authority may describe the land according\nto such surveys. The commissioner of general services in determining the\namount of the consideration for such grants shall take into account the\nobsolescence of the improvements on the land conveyed, the cost to the\nauthority, as estimated by the commissioner of transportation, of\ndemolition of such facilities as are considered obsolete, and providing\nsuch improvement to the Saint Lawrence state hospital property as the\ncommissioner of mental hygiene with the approval of the director of the\nbudget, deems necessary in consequence of the grants herein authorized\nand such grants shall contain appropriate conditions to ensure the\nproviding of such improvements by the authority at its cost and expense.\nActual payment of the consideration for the grants, as determined by the\ncommissioner of general services, shall not be required as a condition\nprecedent to the grants, but the amount thereof shall be certified by\nthe commissioner to the state comptroller and shall be deemed an advance\nto the authority by the state to be repaid in the same manner as\nprovided in section seven hundred fifteen of this article for repayment\nof appropriations made by the state to the authority.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>