<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-705"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-705"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="705"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-705/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-705/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_705">
        <num>705</num>
        <heading>Moneys of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 705. Moneys of the authority. 1. All moneys received by the\nauthority from the bridge and all other moneys received from any other\nsource whatsoever pertaining to the operations of the authority shall be\npaid to the state comptroller as agent of the authority and deposited in\na separate bank account or accounts to be known as the "Ogdensburg\nbridge fund. " The moneys in such fund shall be available subject to the\napproval of the director of the budget of the state of New York for\npayment of any and all costs and expenditures as may be necessary for\nthe corporate purposes of the authority. The moneys of the Ogdensburg\nbridge fund when made available shall be paid from such fund on the\naudit and warrant of the comptroller on vouchers approved solely by the\nchairman of the authority or his properly designated officer.\n  2. All moneys in such fund in excess of the sum of two hundred and\nfifty thousand dollars shall on the first day of each month be paid by\nthe authority to the state comptroller provided, however, that effective\nJune thirty, nineteen hundred seventy-eight, the director of the budget\nand the authority shall establish within the provisions of a written\nagreement between the authority and the director providing for the\nrepayment to the state by the authority of state advances the maximum\namount of moneys which the authority may retain in the Ogdensburg bridge\nfund. The comptroller is hereby authorized to receive from the authority\nsuch amounts as shall be paid to the comptroller pursuant to the\nprovisions of this section and to credit all such amounts to the capital\nconstruction fund. Upon certification by the state comptroller that all\nmoneys due the state have been paid in full, the remaining balance of\nsuch fund shall be available to such authority and may be used by such\nauthority for any corporate purpose. The accounts of the authority shall\nbe subject to examination by the state comptroller. The state\ncomptroller is hereby authorized and empowered to examine the accounts\nand books of the authority at such periods of time as he may deem\nnecessary, including its receipts, disbursements, contracts, leases and\nany other matters relating to its financial standing.\n  3. Nothing in this section shall prevent the authority and the state\nfrom entering into an agreement for the establishment of a revolving\nfund to be used to pay part of or all of the authority's operating\nexpenses. This revolving fund shall be initially funded with moneys\nadvanced from the Ogdensburg bridge fund and shall be replenished from\ntime to time from such funds upon the audit and warrant of the\ncomptroller.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>