<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-733"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-733"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="733"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-733/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-733/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-733/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-733/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_733">
        <num>733</num>
        <heading>Funds of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 733. Funds of the authority.  Notwithstanding the reconstitution and\ncontinuation of the Ogdensburg bridge authority and the abolition of the\nOgdensburg port authority, effectuated by this title, or any other\nprovision of this chapter, moneys constituting the fund or funds of\neither the Ogdensburg bridge authority or the Ogdensburg port authority\nmay be merged for the payment of debts and obligations, but separate\naccounting records shall be maintained.\n  Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and except as hereinafter\nprovided in section thirteen hundred eighty-seven of this chapter, all\nmoneys hereafter received by the Ogdensburg bridge and port authority\npursuant to the provisions of title eight of article three of this\nchapter, and all moneys hereafter received pursuant to the provisions of\ntitle three of article six of this chapter, may be merged for the\npayment of debts and obligations, but separate accounting records shall\nbe maintained.\n  Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, titles eight and nine\nof article three and title three of article six or any other provisions\nof this chapter, any moneys in either the "Ogdensburg bridge fund" or\nthe "Ogdensburg port fund" not necessary or required for cash\nexpenditures, as may be determined and certified from time to time by\nthe state director of the budget, shall, in amounts also to be\ndetermined and certified by him, be available for and may be loaned to\nor from either of the funds above mentioned. Amounts so loaned between\nsuch funds shall be repaid without interest into the fund from which\neach such loan was made.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>