<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-735"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-735"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="735"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-735/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-735/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-735/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-735/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_735">
        <num>735</num>
        <heading>Actions against the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 735. Actions against the authority. 1. In every action against the\nauthority for damages, for injuries to real or personal property, or for\nthe destruction thereof, or for personal injuries, the complaint shall\ncontain an allegation that at least thirty days have elapsed since the\ndemand, claim or claims upon which such action is founded were presented\nto a member of the authority, or to its secretary, or to its chief\nexecutive officer and that the authority has neglected or refused to\nmake an adjustment or payment thereof for thirty days after such\npresentment.\n  2. An action against the authority for damages for injuries to real or\npersonal property, or for the destruction thereof, or for personal\ninjuries, alleged to have been sustained shall not be commenced more\nthan one year and ninety days after the cause of action therefor shall\nhave accrued, nor unless a notice of claim shall have been served within\nthe time limit established by, and in compliance with all requirements\nof section fifty-e of the general municipal law.\n  3. An action against the authority for wrongful death shall be\ncommenced in accordance with the notice of claim and time limitation\nprovisions of title eleven of article nine of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>