<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-827"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-827"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="827"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-827/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-827/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-827/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-827/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_827">
        <num>827</num>
        <heading>Board of directors</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 827. Board of directors. The board of directors of the authority,\nhereinafter in this title referred to as "the board," shall consist of\nseventeen voting members, as follows: The commissioner of agriculture\nand markets or the commissioner's representative. The board of\nsupervisors of each of the counties in the district shall each name\ndirectors as follows: Onondaga, three; Oswego, two; Cayuga, two;\nMadison, two; Cortland, one; Oneida, one, and Wayne, one. Additionally,\nthe following shall have appointments to the board: the county executive\nof Onondaga county, two; and the mayor of the city of Syracuse, two; One\nmember from each of the above-named counties may be either a producer or\nnon-producer of agricultural products; the other members named by the\nboard of supervisors of the counties in the district entitled to\nadditional directors shall be persons engaged in farming and deriving a\ngreater part of their income therefrom, and all such appointments made\nafter May first, nineteen hundred forty-four, shall be producers who\nactually sell all or part of their produce on the Central New York\nRegional Market.\n  Each member shall continue as a member during the pleasure of the body\nappointing such member, and upon a vacancy occurring by the filing with\nthe secretary of the authority of a duly certified copy of the\nresolution signifying that an appointment has been terminated, or upon\nresignation of a member, or a vacancy occurring in any other manner, it\nshall be filled in a manner corresponding to the original appointment.\nEach member shall, before entering upon the duties of office, take the\nconstitutional oath of office and file the same in the office of the\nsecretary of state. One more than one half of the duly qualified members\nshall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business and shall be\nnecessary to the validity of any resolution, order or, determination.\nAny member may be removed by the governor for inefficiency, neglect of\nduty or misconduct in office, after a hearing upon charges and an\nopportunity to be heard in person or by counsel upon not less than ten\ndays' notice. The members shall not receive a salary or other\ncompensation, but shall be paid actual expenses incurred in attending\nmeetings of the board and in performing committee work assigned to them\nby the board. Expenses for travel shall not exceed the per mile rate\nallowed state employees for use of personal cars. Expenses of a special\nor extraordinary nature may be allowed by resolution of the board.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>