<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-841"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-841"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="841"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-841/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-841/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-841/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-841/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_841">
        <num>841</num>
        <heading>Actions against authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 841. Actions against authority. 1. In any case founded upon tort a\nnotice of claim shall be required as a condition precedent to the\ncommencement of an action or special proceeding against the authority\nand the provisions of section fifty-e of the general municipal law shall\napply.\n  2. An action against the authority for damages for injuries to real or\npersonal property, or for the destruction thereof, or for personal\ninjuries, alleged to have been sustained shall not be commenced more\nthan one year and ninety days after the cause of action therefor shall\nhave accrued, nor unless a notice of intention to commence such action\nand of the time when and place where the damages were incurred or\nsustained, together with a verified statement showing in detail the\nproperty alleged to have been damaged or destroyed and the value\nthereof, or the personal injuries alleged to have been sustained and by\nwhom, shall have been filed in the principal office of the authority\nwithin ninety days after such cause of action shall have accrued.\n  3. An action against the authority for wrongful death shall be\ncommenced in accordance with the notice of claim and time limitation\nprovisions of title eleven of article nine of this chapter.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>