<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-843"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-843"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2024-12-20" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="843"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-843/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-843/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-843/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-843/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_843">
        <num>843</num>
        <heading>Code of ethics</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall accept other employment which will\nimpair such employee's independence of judgment in the exercise of any\nofficial duties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall accept employment or engage in any\nbusiness or professional activity which will require the employee to\ndisclose confidential information which such employee has gained by\nreason of official position or authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall disclose confidential information\nacquired by the employee in the course of official duties nor use such\ninformation to further personal interests.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall use or attempt to use an official\nposition to secure unwarranted privileges or exemptions for such\nemployee or others.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee shall engage in any transaction as\nrepresentative or agent of the authority with any business entity in\nwhich such employee has a direct or indirect financial interest that\nmight reasonably tend to conflict with the proper discharge of official\nduties.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall not by conduct give reasonable basis\nfor the impression that any person can improperly influence such\nemployee or unduly enjoy favor in the performance of official duties, or\nthat such employee is affected by the kinship, rank, position or\ninfluence of any party or person.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall abstain from making personal\ninvestments in enterprises which such employee has reason to believe may\nbe directly involved in decisions to be made by the employee or which\nwill otherwise create substantial conflict between duty in the public\ninterest and such employee's private interest.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>An authority employee shall endeavor to pursue a course of conduct\nwhich will not raise suspicion among the public that such employee is\nlikely to be engaged in acts that are in violation of trust.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_i">
          <num>(i)</num>
          <content>
            <p>No authority employee employed on a full-time basis nor any firm\nor association of which such an employee is a member, where a\nsubstantial portion of the stock of which is owned or controlled\ndirectly or indirectly by such employee, shall sell goods or services to\nany person, firm, authority or association which is licensed or whose\nrates are fixed by the authority in which such employee serves or is\nemployed.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_843__subsec_j">
          <num>(j)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If any authority employee shall have a financial interest, direct\nor indirect, having a value of ten thousand dollars or more in any\nactivity which is subject to the jurisdiction of a regulatory agency,\nsuch authority employee shall file with the secretary of state a written\nstatement that such authority employee has such a financial interest in\nsuch activity which statement shall be open to public inspection.\n  5. In addition to any penalty contained in any other provision of law\nany such authority employee who shall knowingly and intentionally\nviolate any of the provisions of this section may be fined, suspended or\nremoved from office or employment.\n  6. The provisions of section seventy-three of the public officers law\nshall be applicable to all board members and employees of the authority.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>