<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-878"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-878"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="878"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-878/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-878/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-878/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-878/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_878">
        <num>878</num>
        <heading>Genesee Valley Regional Market Authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_878__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The commissioner of agriculture and markets, or his representative\ndesignated in writing by him, shall be a member ex officio.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_878__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The county legislative body of each county shall appoint the\nnumber of members as follows, who shall be residents of the county:\nMonroe county, three members; Livingston county, two members; Ontario\ncounty, two members; Wayne county, two members who shall be residents of\nthat part of Wayne county lying west of the new pre-emption line;\nGenesee county, one member; Orleans county, one member; Steuben county,\none member; Wyoming county, one member; and Yates county, one member.\n  3. One member of the board from each county may be either a producer\nor non-producer of agricultural products; other members from each\ncounty, if any, shall be persons engaged in farming and deriving a\ngreater part of their income therefrom; provided, however, that all\npersons appointed as members of the board after May first, nineteen\nhundred sixty-one, shall be producers of agricultural products who\nactually sell all or part of their produce at regional market facilities\nmaintained and operated by the Genesee Valley Regional Market Authority.\n  4. A member of the board shall continue in office during the pleasure\nof the body appointing him or her. Any vacancy which may occur by reason\nof the death, disqualification, resignation or removal of a member shall\nbe filled by the body which appointed such member. Each member of the\nboard shall, before entering upon the duties of office, take the\nconstitutional oath of office and file the same in the office of the\nsecretary of state. Any member may be removed by the governor for\ninefficiency, neglect of duty or misconduct in office, after a hearing\nupon charges and an opportunity to be heard in person or by counsel upon\nnot less than ten days' notice. The members of the board shall not\nreceive a salary or other compensation, but shall be paid actual\nexpenses incurred in attending meetings of the board and executive\ncommittee and in performing committee work assigned to them by the\nboard, and shall be reimbursed for travel...</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_878__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>of subdivision one of section\ntwenty-eight hundred of this chapter as well as to the department of\nagriculture and markets, within ninety days after the end of its fiscal\nyear.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>