<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-879"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-879"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="879"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-879/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-879/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-879/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-879/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_879">
        <num>879</num>
        <heading>Purposes and powers of the authority</heading>
        <content>
          <p>  ยง 879. Purposes and powers of the authority. The purposes of the\nauthority shall be to assist in the establishment and development of\nagriculture and agriculturally related businesses in the district, and\nto acquire, construct, reconstruct, improve, equip, operate and maintain\nadequate regional market facilities within the district for the buying\nand selling of agricultural products and to conduct such other business\nactivities as reasonably are incidental to and in furtherance of the\nconvenient, efficient, profitable and successful operation of such\nregional market facilities. For the purposes of this title,\n"agriculturally related business" shall include, but not be limited to,\nagricultural economic development projects in the district for\nproduction, manufacturing, processing, warehousing, distribution,\nmarketing, training, research and diagnostics related to sale of crops,\nlivestock and livestock products as defined in section three hundred one\nof the agriculture and markets law. Project costs may include, but not\nbe limited to, land, buildings, machinery, equipment, processed or\npartially processed agricultural commodities, root stock, livestock,\nother personal property, materials, working capital, or stock in trade\nrequired to establish such project. Not-for-profit corporations,\nagricultural cooperative corporations, public benefit corporations,\nmunicipalities and educational institutions serving the district shall\nbe eligible to apply for support under this title. To enable the\nauthority to carry out such purposes, the authority shall have power:\n  1. To sue and be sued.\n  2. To have a seal and alter the same at pleasure.\n  3. To acquire, hold, lease, sell, convey and dispose of any property,\nreal or personal, or interest therein, for its corporate purposes.\n  3-a. To lease real property heretofore acquired and now held by it and\nnot required for regional market facilities for agricultural, business,\ncommercial or industrial uses.\n  4. To condemn real property which shall be necessary for its corporate\npurposes, in the manner provided in the condemnation law.\n  5. To determine the location, type, size, construction and equipment\nof requisite regional market facilities within the district.\n  6. To prepare a plan for financing the acquisition, construction,\nequipment and operation of such facilities.\n  7. To make such investigations and hold hearings and conferences as\nmay be necessary or convenient to formulate, adopt and revise programs\nand plans for financing, building, acquiring and operating such\nfacilities.\n  8. To acquire, erect, construct, reconstruct, improve, equip, maintain\nand operate such buildings, structures and facilities as may be\nnecessary or convenient.\n  9. To appoint officers, agents and employees and fix and determine\ntheir qualifications, duties and compensation, subject to the provisions\nof the civil service law of the state of New York and such rules as the\ncivil service commission of the county of Monroe may adopt and make\napplicable to public authorities.\n  10. To contract for expert and other professional services.\n  11. To make contracts and leases, and to execute all instruments\nnecessary or convenient.\n  12. To fix and collect rentals, fees and other charges for the use of\nits property or facilities, subject to the provisions of section eight\nhundred eighty of this title.\n  13. To make by-laws for the organization, management and regulation of\nits affairs.\n  14. To borrow money and to issue negotiable bonds and notes and to\nprovide for the rights of the holders thereof.\n  15. To do all things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers\nexpressly given by this title.\n</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>