<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-881"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-881"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="881"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-881/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-881/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-881/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-881/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_881">
        <num>881</num>
        <heading>Bonds of the authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_881__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Pledging all or any part of the gross or net revenues of the\nauthority to secure the payment of the bonds, subject to such agreements\nwith bond holders as may then exist;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_881__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The rentals, fees and other charges to be charged for the use of\nmarket facilities, and the amounts to be raised in each year thereby,\nand the use and disposition of revenues of the authority;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_881__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The setting aside of reserves or sinking funds and the regulation\nand disposition thereof;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_881__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Limitations on the right of the authority to restrict and regulate\nthe use of market facilities;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_881__subsec_e">
          <num>(e)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Limitations on the purpose to which the proceeds of the sale of\nany issue of bonds then or thereafter to be issued may be applied;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_881__subsec_f">
          <num>(f)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Limitations on the issuance of additional bonds, including the\nterms upon which additional bonds may be issued and secured;\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_881__subsec_g">
          <num>(g)</num>
          <content>
            <p>The procedure, if any, by which the terms of any contract with\nbondholders may be amended or abrogated, the amount of bonds the holders\nof which must give consent thereto, and the manner in which such consent\nmay be given; and\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_881__subsec_h">
          <num>(h)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any other matters, of like or different character, which in any\nway affect the security or protection of the bonds.\n  4. Any pledge of revenues or other moneys made by the authority shall\nbe valid and binding from the time when the pledge is made. The revenues\nor other moneys so pledged and thereafter received by the authority\nshall be immediately subject to the lien of such pledge without any\nphysical delivery thereof or further act. The lien of any such pledge\nshall be valid and binding as against all parties having claims of any\nkind in tort, contract or otherwise against the authority irrespective\nof whether such parties have notice thereof. Neither the resolution nor\nany other instrument by which a pledge is created need be recorded.\n  5. Neither the members of the authority nor any person executing the\nbonds shall be liable personally on the bonds or be subject to any\npersonal liability by reason of the issuance thereof, excepting solely\nfor things willfully done or willfully omitted to be done with an intent\nto defraud.\n  6. The authority shall have power out of any funds available therefor\nto purchase any of its outstanding bonds at a price not more than the\nprincipal amount thereof and accrued interest. All bonds so purchased\nshall be cancelled.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>