<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="PBA">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ny-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-913"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-913"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2014-09-22" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ny-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ny"/>
          <FRBRnumber value="913"/>
          <FRBRname value="PBA"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-913/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-913/eng@2025-12-31"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-913/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ny/act/pba/section-913/eng@2025-12-31/main.xml"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#arch"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#arch">
        <TLCOrganization eId="arch" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico Arch"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="ny-legislature" href="https://legislation.nysenate.gov" showAs="New York State Legislature"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_913">
        <num>913</num>
        <heading>Actions against authority</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_913__subsec_a">
          <num>(a)</num>
          <content>
            <p>notice of claim shall have been made and served upon the authority\nwithin the time limit set by and in compliance with section fifty-e of\nthe general municipal law,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_913__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>it shall appear by and as an allegation\nin the complaint or moving papers that at least thirty days have elapsed\nsince the service of such notice and that adjustment or payment thereof\nhas been neglected or refused,</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_913__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>the action or special proceeding\nshall be commenced within one year and ninety days after the happening\nof the event upon which the claim is based, and</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_913__subsec_d">
          <num>(d)</num>
          <content>
            <p>an action, against\nthe authority for wrongful death shall be commenced in accordance with\nthe notice of claim and time limitation provisions of title eleven of\narticle nine of this chapter.\n  2. Whenever a notice of claim is served upon the authority, it shall\nhave the right to demand an examination of the claimant relative to the\noccurrence and extent of the injuries or damages for which claim is\nmade, in accordance with the provisions of section fifty-h of the\ngeneral municipal law.\n  3. The authority shall have power to settle or adjust all claims in\nfavor of or against the authority.\n  4. Any action or proceeding to which the authority or the people of\nthe state may be parties, in which any question arises as to the\nvalidity of this title, shall be preferred over all other civil causes\nof action or cases, except election causes of action or cases, in all\ncourts of the state and shall be heard and determined in preference to\nall other civil business pending therein except election causes,\nirrespective of position on the calendar. The same performance shall be\ngranted upon application of the authority or its counsel in any action\nor proceeding questioning the validity of this title in which the\nauthority may be allowed to intervene. The venue of any such action or\nproceeding shall be in the supreme court of the county of Suffolk.\n  5. The rate of interest to be paid by the authority upon any judgment\nfor which it is liable, other than a judgment on its bonds, shall be the\nrate prescribed by section five thousand four of the civil practice law\nand rules. Interest on payments of principal or interests on any bonds\nin default shall accrue at the rate borne by such bonds from the due\ndate thereof until paid or otherwise satisfied.\n  6. All actions or proceedings against the authority of whatever nature\nshall be brought in the county.\n</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>